- Hello, lovely students,
and welcome back to "English with Lucy."
Today's video is perfect for you
if you're looking to improve
your business English
or your professional English.
Today, my husband is going to ask me
100 of the most common
business English questions.
I'm going to give genuine answers
so that you can learn real English.
As always, there is a free PDF
that goes with today's video.
It's got all of the questions
so you can use them to practise yourself,
plus a transcript of my answers
and extra information and activities.
If you'd like to download that PDF,
just click on the link
in the description box,
you enter your name
and your email address,
you sign up to my mailing list,
and the PDF will arrive
directly in your inbox.
After that, you'll automatically receive
my free weekly lesson PDFs
along with all my news,
course offers, and updates.
Hey, future Lucy here.
I wanted to tell you about
something really exciting
that I've been working
on for quite a while.
I know that lots of you
want to improve your English
in order to get a job
or improve your career prospects.
I also know that lots of you have an aim
to sound professional and experienced
when you speak,
nearly all of you want to use vocabulary
that is appropriate and
relevant for the work place.
Those are the reasons why I have created
my 30-Day Business English Challenge.
This Business English challenge
will teach you to speak and understand
professional English in context
using a really fun, interesting,
and effective methodology
that will help you to retain and remember
what you've learned.
In the challenge, we cover 10 topics,
each topic lasts for three days,
and in those three days,
I will teach you between 22 and 40
new vocabulary words and phrases,
business vocabulary.
Every three days,
you get two video days
and one listening day,
so that's two reading
and vocabulary video days
and one listening practise day.
On the reading and vocabulary days,
I read you a text
that contains lots of relevant vocabulary.
We then discuss all of the vocabulary,
their meanings, examples,
how you use them.
Because you're listening
to me reading the texts,
you're not only improving your vocabulary
but also your pronunciation.
On each of these days,
you also receive 20 exercise questions
testing you on the vocabulary
that you've just learned
and importantly,
the vocabulary that you've
learned in previous days.
This is really important
for helping you to remember
and retain at vocab.
You also have extra reading opportunities
discussing English workplace culture.
On the listening days, you'll participate
in some amazingly effective
listening exercises
using the vocabulary you've just learned
so it'll be further
cementing it in your brain.
Every day for the 30-day challenge,
you can access the comment section
and ask questions to me and my teachers,
and we can give you feedback.
By the end of the 30 days,
you will have learned over
280 new vocabulary phrases,
including idioms, phrasal verbs,
collocations, slang terms, you name it.
You'll have taken over
400 vocabulary exercises
and 230 listening exercises.
Imagine the progress that you'll make
in just 30 days.
But don't worry,
if 30 days is too intense for you
or you can't start immediately,
you have lifetime access
to the course content.
Once you buy it, it's yours to keep.
Another nice feature
is that when you complete the course,
you get a digital
certificate of completion.
Previous challenge
students love to use this
alongside their CV
to prove that they've taken
a certain amount of classes.
Now, the price of this
Business English Challenge
will be $129 plus taxes.
However, as it's new,
I'm doing a special introductory offer
and it's a big discount. (chuckles)
You can save $40, taking
the price down to $89
plus your country's tax.
If you want to claim this discount,
you have to apply the code 40BIZYT.
There is a deadline.
The challenge starts
on the 1st of May 2022
and after that first day,
the code will expire and
enrollment will close.
Thousands and thousands of students
have participated in
my previous challenges
and they have the most amazing feedback.
It has been wonderful meeting them all.
I love having that
smaller group of students
that I can talk to,
I can recognise their names.
Don't miss out.
Sign up before the 1st of May,
invest in yourself,
and enjoy the benefits of the
Business English Challenge.
Right, let's get started
with the questions.
- [Will] Where do you work?
- I work for teaching company.
- [Will] What is your job title?
- CEO.
- [Will] Do you like your job?
- I love my job.
- [Will] What is the most
important part of your job?
- I love teaching my wonderful students.
- [Will] How many days a week do you work?
- Five to seven.
- [Will] Do you have a boss?
- I am my boss, but I
work with my husband.
Sometimes, he bosses me around.
- [Will] What was your first job?
- I was a waitress at the local pub.
- [Will] What job would
you never, ever do?
- I don't think I'd like to be a chef.
It's too much pressure.
- [Will] Would you like a new job?
- No, I'm really happy with this one.
- [Will] Would you recommend
your line of work to others?
- If you enjoy teaching,
then I think it's a fabulous career path.
- [Will] What did you do this weekend?
- This weekend, we did
a little bit of work
in the morning, and then we relaxed.
- [Will] What will you do after work?
- Well, it's quite late right now.
I think we'll eat dinner and go to bed.
- [Will] How was traffic today?
- I didn't drive today.
I work from home.
- [Will] When are you taking time off?
- We are going away
next month on a holiday.
- [Will] What will you do on your holiday?
- Relax, explore, and
hopefully visit some vineyards.
- [Will] Any plans for the weekend?
- This weekend, it's Easter
and we're going to see our families.
- [Will] What will you do for lunch?
- Normally, I have a salad for lunch.
- [Will] Would you like
to go to lunch with me?
- With you?
Every day. (chuckles)
- [Will] Are you working late tonight?
- Yes. I'm working unusually late tonight.
- [Will] What time did
you clock in this morning?
- I started work at
around 8:30 this morning.
- [Will] Did you find a good parking spot?
- I didn't have to park.
(chuckles) I work from home.
- [Will] What time do
you get home from work?
- I normally try to finish working
at around five to six o'clock.
- [Will] How do you get to work?
- I leave my bed, go downstairs,
and sit down at the table.
- [Will] Would you get
public transport to work?
- If I didn't work from home,
I would absolutely get
public transport to work.
- [Will] How are your kids?
- I don't have any, yet. (chuckles)
- [Will] Do you ever work overtime?
- Yes. I think it's the nature
of running your own business.
- [Will] How many meetings
do you attend in a week?
- Probably 7 to 10.
- [Will] Did you receive training?
- Yes. I did receive training.
- [Will] Do you think
the company is run well?
- I hope so. (chuckles)
- [Will] How long have
you been working here?
- I started this business in January 2016.
So is that six years?
- [Will] Have you received a promotion?
- No. I've always been the CEO. (laughs)
- [Will] How often do you get a raise?
- I like to pay myself
slightly more each year.
- [Will] How well do you
get on with your boss?
- With my business partner, my husband?
Extremely well.
- [Will] Do you get on
with your coworkers?
- I have a lovely team.
- [Will] What does your
average day look like?
- I like to break up my day
with exercise and dog walks.
- [Will] Would you change
anything about your daily routine?
- Yes. I'd like slightly more free time.
- [Will] Do you get to travel for work?
- Before the pandemic,
I travelled quite a lot.
It's starting to pick up now.
- [Will] What is the most
challenging part of your job?
- Receiving criticism from strangers.
- [Will] Do you have to
work at the weekends?
- Sometimes I do.
In fact, oftentimes I do.
- [Will] Does management support you?
- My husband is very supportive.
- [Will] How did you find this job?
- I think I was very lucky
and a bit lost as a 21-year-old.
- [Will] Are you interested in a full-time
or a part-time position?
- I enjoy working in a full-time position,
but one day, I might like to move
to a part-time position.
- [Will] Did you bring your CV?
- Do you know what?
I don't have a CV or a resume.
Maybe I should make one.
- [Will] Do you have a degree?
- Yes, I do have a degree.
- [Will] What is your degree?
- It is a first-class honours
in marketing communications.
- [Will] What was your last job?
- My last job was an English teacher.
- [Will] How long did you work there?
- I worked as an English
teacher for three years
before starting my business.
- [Will] Why did you leave your last job?
- It was a natural progression.
- [Will] Do you have references?
- I'm sure I could ask some
of my previous bosses for you.
- [Will] Do you work well with others?
- I'd like to think I do,
but I do like being alone.
- [Will] Can you work in a group setting?
- I can, but I'd prefer not to.
- [Will] What is your biggest strength?
- I think I'm very creative.
- [Will] What is your biggest weakness?
- Sometimes I get a bit stressed.
- [Will] Have you always worked
in the education industry?
- No, before I was a teacher,
I worked in marketing.
- [Will] Do you like to work outdoors?
- No, because the wind
makes an awful noise with my camera.
- [Will] Are you an organised person?
- In my work life, yes.
In my personal life, no.
- [Will] What are your short-term goals?
- I would like to release
a fantastic intermediate English course.
- [Will] What are your long-term goals?
- To live a happy life.
- [Will] Why should we hire you?
- I think I'm proactive,
creative, and enthusiastic.
- [Will] When can you start?
- Immediately!
- [Will] Are you comfortable
using a computer?
- I'm very comfortable using a computer.
- [Will] Can you use Microsoft Office?
- Yes, I can use that quite well.
- [Will] Are you proficient
in using spreadsheet software?
- Yes, I have quite a lot of
experience using spreadsheets.
- [Will] How fast can you type?
- Very quickly!
- [Will] What other software
are you familiar with?
- You name it; I've probably tried it.
- [Will] Do you own a laptop?
- I do! Grey. (laughs)
- [Will] Are you comfortable
using social media?
- Oh, I guess so.
- [Will] Have you managed
a social media account?
- Yes, I've managed
quite a few in my time.
- [Will] Can you edit videos?
- Yes, I started off
editing my own videos.
- [Will] Have you ever used Photoshop?
- I have. I wouldn't say
it's my biggest strength.
- [Will] How do you plan your days?
- I use Google Calendar,
and I put everything I need to do in it.
- [Will] How are you with time management?
- I'm quite good; I could be better.
- [Will] Do you always
meet your deadlines?
- Not always, but I try my best.
- [Will] Are you
comfortable asking for help?
- I always ask for help.
- [Will] Do you like helping people?
- Yes, It's my job! (laughs)
- [Will] Do you often feel overwhelmed?
- I sometimes feel overwhelmed,
but I think I'm quite good at managing it.
- [Will] Do you consider
yourself to be a good leader?
- I'm new to being a leader,
and I'm learning a lot.
- [Will] How do you balance
your work and personal life?
- With a bit of difficulty,
but I'm working on it.
- [Will] How do you prioritise tasks?
- When's the nearest deadline?
- [Will] How do you handle stress at work?
- I go on a dog walk,
and I talk to my husband.
- [Will] Are you optimistic?
- I'd say I'm very optimistic,
sometimes too optimistic.
- [Will] Do you enjoy public speaking?
- I don't enjoy the build-up,
but I enjoy having done it.
- [Will] Do you finish what you start?
- Not always.
If I don't see some
something as going somewhere,
then why finish it?
- [Will] Would your friends
describe you as trustworthy?
- Yes, I think most of my friends
would describe me as trustworthy.
- [Will] Is your personality
suited for this job?
- I think so.
Otherwise, I would've given up
- [Will] What makes a good friend?
- I think good friends are people
that you can go a long
time without seeing,
but you see each other,
and it's like no time has passed at all.
- [Will] Are you easy to anger?
- No, but if you repeatedly disappoint me,
then I will become angry.
- [Will] What makes you angry?
- Bad customer service
and overpromising and underdelivering.
- [Will] Is there an
absolute right and wrong?
- Hardly ever.
- [Will] Do you pay your bills on time?
- I always pay my bills on time.
- [Will] Do you prefer variety or routine?
- I like a bit of both,
but probably more of a routine.
- [Will] Do you prefer to work
quickly or focus on details?
- It depends what I'm doing,
but in general, I prefer to work quickly.
- [Will] Is it ever okay to lie?
- Yes, it's sometimes okay to lie
if it stops people from
having their feelings hurt.
- [Will] What traits
are important in a boss?
- Patience, good communications skills,
the ability to teach, and
the ability to praise.
- [Will] What makes a good leader?
- Somebody who leads by example.
- [Will] Who is a business
leader that you admire?
- I really admire Marcia Kilgore.
- [Will] Describe yourself in one word.
- Happy.
- [Will] What is your
greatest achievement?
- Creating a business
that helps people around the world.
- [Will] If you could have
dinner and talk with anyone,
who would it be?
- Probably Phoebe Waller-Bridge.
She seems hilarious.
- [Will] If you could go back
and change anything in your life,
what would it be?
- I don't think I would change anything
because I'm happy with how
everything is right now.
- [Will] Your email address?
- Email address?
- [Will] Would you like to
carpool karaoke (indistinct),
all right?
24, would you like to carpool with me?
- Did you say karaoke automatically?
- [Will] Yeah,
because that's how it ends.
(Lucy laughing)
Didn't it?
- That's so random.
No, carpooling is like
sharing cars to work.
- [Will] Oh, I thought
it was carpool karaoke.
Whatever!
(Lucy laughing)
Once you're sharing your
(laughter drowns out Will).
- Would you like to carpool with me?
- [Will] Why should we hire you?
- Why should you hire me?
Creating a business, business. (laughs)
(Will laughs)
Creating a business that
help people to speak.
(laughter drowns out Will)