There's a saying in English
that one of the only things
that remains the same in life,
one of the only things
that is constant is change.
Things change.
It's fall here in Ontario, Canada,
and as you can see, the
leaves are changing color.
Everything around me is changing.
So I thought this would be a good time
to do an English lesson about change.
So stick around for this English lesson,
I'll help you learn about
10 different English phrases
that we use to talk about all kinds
of different changes that happen in life.
(cheerful music)
The first phrase I wanted to
teach you to talk about change
is the phrase like night and day.
We use this phrase to talk about something
that's changed quite a bit.
The best example I can give you is this.
Sometimes my kids have messy rooms.
They leave everything on the
floor and it's a real mess.
And then I tell them on a Saturday,
"You need to clean your room
or you can't play computer
games later today."
And then they clean their room.
And then the difference between
when their room was messy
and when their room is
clean is like night and day.
The difference is so great
that I would walk in the room and say,
"Wow, the difference,
it's like night and day.
It's so much nicer when
your room is clean."
So when you say that something
is like night and day,
you mean that it's changed so much
that it looks completely different now.
The next phrase I wanted
to teach you is a phrase
that we use to describe when
someone's appearance changes,
and it's the phrase to
barely recognize someone.
Now, this phrase, I
actually saw in the comments
in a video a number of months ago.
Because I shaved off my
beard and my mustache,
and then when I made a video
with no beard or mustache,
in the comments, a few people said,
"I barely recognized you."
What they were saying is that
because my appearance had changed so much,
it was hard for them to tell
that I was Bob, the Canadian.
They thought maybe I was another person,
or maybe I was Bob's brother or something,
but it was actually me.
Now, be careful when you use this phrase,
because you don't want to use it
in a way that sounds negative.
You might wanna add a positive phrase
before you use this phrase
because it can be misinterpreted.
So you could say something like this.
"Oh, I can tell you've been exercising.
You look amazing. I
barely recognized you."
Or, "Wow, your new haircut looks great.
I barely recognized you."
So when you use this phrase,
you're simply talking
about how someone's
appearance has changed.
Hi, Bob, the Canadian here,
just jumping into the
middle of this lesson
to ask you to do one thing, actually two.
If you are not a subscriber,
please consider clicking
that red subscribe button over there.
And if this video is helping you learn
a little bit of English,
please give me a thumbs up.
Now, back to the lesson.
I don't know if you've noticed this,
but sometimes kids go
through a growth spurt,
and we use the phrase to grow like a weed
to describe this change.
A weed is a plant that grows
in a garden or a field,
and it's a plant you don't want there,
and they usually grow
really, really quickly.
So we use this comparison to
talk about how fast kids grow.
Maybe you have a nephew
or a niece who you haven't
seen for a year or two
and the next time you
see them, you could say,
"Wow, you're growing like a weed.
You're so much taller now."
In fact, at some point they
might even be taller than you.
That's happened to me with a
few of my nephews and nieces
in the last year or two.
I'm starting to feel a little bit short.
So when you're describing a
child who is growing quickly
or a child who you
haven't seen for a while
and they're much taller
now, you could say to them,
"Wow, you're growing like a weed."
The English phrase to
change your tune means
to change your behavior,
usually in a positive direction.
Sometimes people do bad things.
Sometimes people do things
that they're not supposed to do
and you wish that they
would change their tune.
I have this sometimes in my classroom.
Sometimes I have students who don't listen
and they misbehave,
and just day after day,
their behavior is not very good.
Their behavior is bad.
So I wish that they
would change their tune.
I might even say to them, "You know what?
You need to change your tune
if you want to do well in this class.
If you want to succeed, you
need to change your tune."
So the English phrase to
change your tune means
to change your behavior in a way
that you are now doing things
in a more positive way.
Instead of doing bad things,
you're doing good things.
The next two English phrases about change
have the same meaning.
They are the phrases to do a 180
and to have a change of heart.
The best example I can
give for these two phrases
is if you think about
a professional athlete
who announced their retirement,
an athlete who decided not to play anymore
because they thought they
were getting too old,
and then after being
retired for a little while,
they decide to come back,
they decide to play again.
In that situation,
we would say that the player did a 180.
They've reversed their decision.
Or we would say that the
player had a change of heart;
they reversed their decision.
So instead of doing what
they were going to do,
instead of doing what they decided to do,
they've decided to reverse their decision
and come back and play again.
It's always cool when your
favorite athlete retires
and then does a 180 or
has a change of heart
and decides to play again.
This next English phrase
is a phrase we use
to talk about the change
in someone's appearance,
and it's a phrase that we use maybe
to bug someone a little
bit or in a humorous way,
and it's the phrase to clean up nicely.
Sometimes Jen and I
have to go to a wedding,
and so I get a haircut
and I shave my beard or trim my beard,
and I put on a suit and
tie, and Jen will then say,
"Wow, you clean up nicely."
And what she's talking about is the change
from how I normally look
to how I look after I get a haircut,
and trim my beard, and
put on a suit and tie
makes me look really, really good.
So, remember, this is a phrase you use
with someone you know well.
It's a phrase you use
to kinda jokingly give
someone a compliment,
I hope that makes sense,
but you would say,
"Wow, you clean up nicely."
Hi, I thought I should pop into the lesson
with my suit and tie on just to show you
that I do actually clean up nicely.
The English phrase out with
the old, in with the new
is a phrase we use to talk about change
in almost any situation when
we think change is important.
I don't know if you noticed,
but the intro to my English lessons
on YouTube changed about
a month and a half ago
because it was time
to make it look a little
more fresh and new.
It was time for me to get rid of the old
and bring in something new.
The way I would describe
that is I would say,
"You know, out with the
old, in with the new.
It was time to make a change
so that things would look
just a little bit better."
So when you say out with
the old, in with the new,
it's used any time you want
to talk about the reason
why you're changing something.
If someone at work was saying,
"Why are we doing it this way now?"
You could say, "You
know, out with the old,
in with the new.
We have to keep up with the times."
Sometimes you need to make
changes to stay current.
So, out with the old, in with the new.
Have you ever had a job
that you didn't like?
Or maybe there's a room in your house
and you just don't like how it looks?
You might use this English phrase
to describe either of those situations.
You might say it's time for a change.
In English when you say
it's time for a change,
it means that you want
to change your situation
or you want to change
something to look more pleasing
or just to be more pleasing.
So the best example would
probably be the job.
Sometimes people work at a
certain job for a long time
and then they start to not enjoy it.
And then the best phrase to
describe that would be to say,
"It's time for a change."
In fact, you might have a
friend in that situation
and you might say to them,
"Hey, I know you've been complaining
about your job a lot lately,
maybe it's time for a change.
Maybe it's time for you to
look for a different job.
That might make you happy."
The English phrase to
shake things up means
to do something differently
than how you have been doing it.
Here's a good example.
My sister and brother-in-law
go to the same campground every year,
but this year when they went camping,
they decided to shake things up.
They decided to go to a
completely different campground.
We use this phrase when we decide
to do something differently
than how we've been doing it.
Maybe you've become bored with
doing something the same way.
Maybe you've become bored with the place
where you've been going.
Maybe you've become bored
with the kind of food you've been eating,
and then you decide to shake things up.
You decide to change how you do something
so it's a little more exciting.
A long time ago,
if you wanted to communicate
with someone far away,
you would make a long distance phone call.
But times have changed.
Now you would probably
send them a text message
or just send them an email.
The English phrase times
have changed is used
to describe big changes
that we have all experienced as humans
over the course of time.
Probably the smartphone
is the biggest change
that I can think of
when I use this phrase.
Many years ago, no one had a
smartphone in their pocket,
but times have changed.
Now, almost everyone has
a smartphone with them
on a daily basis and uses it
for all kinds of things.
Wow, times have changed.
Well, hey, thank you so much
for watching this English
lesson about change.
I hope you were able
to learn just a few more
English phrases that you can use
to talk about the things
in life that change.
Remember, if this is your first time here,
don't forget to click that red
subscribe button over there,
and give me a thumbs up
if this video helped you learn
just a little bit more English.
And if you have the time,
why don't you stick around
and watch another English lesson?
(cheerful music)