And I'm back with the torture of phrasal verbs.
I know everyone hates phrasal verbs; I hate
them, too, because there're so many of them.
They're confusing, but cool; I'm going to
teach them to you.
My name's Ronnie, and I am going to make you
check out this lesson.
So, today's lesson is phrasal verbs of "check".
So, we have, first of all, the construction
of a phrasal verb.
A phrasal verb is a verb with a preposition,
or two prepositions just to make it fancy.
A preposition you think of as placement; up,
out, in, for, off, into, blah, blah, blah.
So, these are what make English very confusing,
and people look at the sky, like: "Check up.
Why am I up?
No.
Down.
No."
So, if you...
For example, if you "check up on someone",
this means that you want to make sure that
they are okay or that they're not doing something
bad.
So, you will hear this a lot in movies where
the teenager will say: "Mom, are you checking
up on me"?
"Mom, are you checking up on me?" this means
someone is concerned about what you are doing.
Like I said, maybe you're doing something
bad or maybe you're sick, so someone will
come check up on you to make sure you are
okay.
So, we have two meanings; one's good, one's
bad.
If you "check out"...
You maybe have heard this in a hotel; you
might see: "Check-out time".
But, as a phrasal verb, "check out" means
you physically leave the hotel.
Also, if you go shopping and you're ready
to pay for something, you can check out, which
means you pay at a store.
In a supermarket, there's a check-out...
Check-out, girl.
There's a sort of check-out area; that's a
noun.
So: "I'm going to check out" we can also use.
The opposite for "check out" is "check in".
So, when you enter the hotel, you're going
to confirm a reservation.
Also, if you're going on an airplane-I want
to go on an airplane-you go to the counter
and you check in, so you confirm your reservation
on an airplane, or you confirm or you get
a hotel room.
If you "check for something", you're going
to search or you're going to examine something
for...
To make sure it's there or not there.
A common problem we have with children around
the world...
I remember when I was in elementary school,
we all had to get checked for lice.
Lice are little bugs that live in people's
hair.
So, we had to get checked, so: "We checked
for lice."
So, the nurse came in and looked at everyone's
head, made sure you had no bugs roaming around.
I didn't have lice.
Yes.
Cool.
Have you ever had lice?
It's cool; you just get some shampoo; everything's
good.
Don't tell anyone.
It's kind of...
Maybe you won't have any friends if you have
lice.
So, we checked for lice.
"Check off" is, like, a checkmark.
So, a checkmark is this, and you check something
off a list.
So, you can make...
For example: "I checked off another point
on my list."
Maybe you have a bucket list.
A bucket list are...
Is a list of things you would like to do,
like: "I want to skydive."
So, you skydive, you come back, and you...
You check off skydiving on your list.
Have you gone skydiving before?
I haven't.
I'd like to.
We can also "check into"-which is different
from "check in"-a hospital.
Now, I know what you're thinking.
You're thinking: "Ronnie, why do we check
in on an airplane, but we check into a hospital?"
I don't know.
Okay?
I didn't make these stupid phrasal verbs;
I'm just teaching them to you, so I don't
know.
Maybe get in your time machine, go back in
time and change it, or ask someone in your
magical time machine, because I don't know.
But you check into a hotel.
As an example, if you use the future: "We
will check him into the hospital."
Not hotel.
It's certainly not a hotel.
If you check your luggage through, this sometimes
can be a little bit troublesome because this
is how luggage gets lost most of the time.
So, imagine you are flying from destination
A, then you have a stopover in destination
B, and your final destination is C. So, the
airline company says: "Guess what?
We will check your luggage through to your
final destination of C." Yay.
So, you go on your merry way, you go to your
transfer point in B, and by the time you get
to your final destination at point C, you're
waiting for your luggage.
Oh, no, you're the last person.
There's no luggage.
Where's your luggage?
So, you go to the counter and you say: "Hey.
My luggage was checked through to San Francisco."
And the airline company goes: "Well, it's
not here."
Oh, yeah.
Bye-bye; it's lost.
So, losing luggage is not a good thing, but
they can tell you: "We will check it through."
So, this means they pretend they will send
your luggage to your final destination.
Good luck, luggage.
It's a big tour.
We can also say "check with".
So, maybe you ask someone: "Hey, hey.
I have this great idea.
Let's do it."
And the person says: -"Nah, I got to check
with Bob."
-"Who's Bob?
Let's do it."
-"No."
So, if you "check with someone", you're going
to confirm something.
You're going to confirm information or you're
going to confirm that something is okay to
do.
I don't like this.
It's important, though.
You're going to check with someone.
We have another phrase that we use in slang
all the time.
People will say: -"Hey, check it out!"
-"Check...
Check...
Check what out?
What?
What are you talking about: Check?
I can't check anything."
-"Check it out".
"Check it out" means: "Hey, go look at something
over there."
Or...
Bless me.
"Go examine it."
If you say: "Hey.
Check out my new video."
That means: "Hey.
Look at my new video."
We have another expression: "check him/her
out".
This basically just means: Look at her.
You will see some people, maybe at the mall,
and they're watching people, and they go:
"Hey, check her out."
Or: "Hey, check him out."
This can be positive or negative.
Maybe someone is very strange looking or it's
me, and people go: "Hey, check her out.
What's she doing?
That's weird."
So that can be a good thing or a bad thing.
Another good thing or a bad thing, depending
on who's doing it: If someone is checking
you out.
Okay, you're not shopping at the mall.
If he's checking you out or she's checking
you out, he or she is looking at your body.
Excuse me?
Or they're...
They're checking you out to see if they like
you.
So, maybe you go to a bar or you go to a restaurant,
or you go somewhere, and you see someone looking
at you.
"Huh?
Huh?
Huh?"
And they wink.
"Do you have something in your eye?
No, okay."
This person is checking you out; they're looking
at you to see if they like you.
I'm checking you out right now.
Oh, that was creepy, Ronnie; don't do that.
So, you have to check out more lessons on
www.engvid.com.
Check out and subscribe to my YouTube channel.
And I'm checking out of this crazy hotel called
this lesson.
Bye-bye.