Hello and welcome to this video.
Today you're going to learn 15 advanced words
to sound fluent in English.
So are you ready for a challenge to expand
your vocabulary?
Of course, I'm Jennifer from JForrestEnglish.com.
And this channel is dedicated to helping you
feel confident speaking English in public
so you can take your career and your life
to the next level.
Now, before we go any further, make sure you
subscribe and hit that bell icon so you're
notified every time I post a new lesson.
Now let's dive in with this lesson.
Are you ready to learn 15 advanced words to
help you sound fluent in English?
Let's get started with number one.
Number one, To Urge.
The sentence structure is to urge someone
to do something.
Urge is a verb and it means to strongly advise
or persuade someone to do something.
For example, the lawyer urged him to take
the deal.
So the lawyer strongly advised him the lawyer
tried to persuade him to take the deal.
The lawyer urged him to take the deal.
Number two, Amid.
Amid.
This is a preposition.
There's an alternative spelling which is amidst,
amidst.
So you're adding "st" on the end.
They mean exactly the same thing.
Amid is more popular and common in American
English.
So that's the one I urge you to use.
Now as a preposition, this means in the middle
of or surrounded by.
So let me give you an example sentence.
Tesla launched its new car amid a lot of publicity.
So we have the launch of the new car.
Now remember, amid means in the middle of
or surrounded by so you can almost imagine
here's their launch of the new car and then
surrounded around that launch is all this
publicity.
Publicity is just media attention.
So that's when we use amid.
Tesla launch their new car amid a lot of publicity.
Number three, To Roam.
To Roam.
This is a great one.
You can add this to your daily vocabulary.
Because to roam, this means to move about
or travel without a clear direction of where
you're going.
But you do that on purpose.
You can think of it as an activity.
So when would you want to move around or move
about without a clear direction of where you're
going?
Well, probably when you're on vacation or
when you're exploring a new area, even of
your own city.
So you might find a new area and then you
just roam around.
You go on this street and then you see something
interesting and you go there and then you
see a store and then you go there.
You don't have a clear direction of where
you're going.
Number four, To Encompass.
This means that you include a lot of different
types of things for this one think of when
you go to a conference.
There are many different types of things,
right?
There are different speakers, there are different
topics.
There are different people in the audience.
There's different entertainment.
So all of these are different things.
Now the verb to encompass just means to include,
so we could say the conference encompasses
many different speakers, entertainment, audience
members, presentations, topics, and you can
go on and list the different categories of
things.
The conference encompassed many different
Number five, Mired.
Mired.
Look at the spelling.
Now listen to my pronunciation, My-erd.
My-erd.
That's the pronunciation.
We use this when someone or something like
a company is involved in a difficult situation.
It must be a difficult situation.
For example, the new company was mired in
controversy, was mired in controversy.
They were involved in that situation.
And notice I use the word controversy, which
is negative.
Number six, meticulously.
Ooh, that's a fun word to say.
Isn't it?
A little bit of a challenge for you.
Number six, meticulously, meticulously.
This is an adjective and as an adjective it
means in a way that shows great attention
to detail.
For example, the entire project was meticulously
planned.
Remember, adjectives are always optional.
So I could say the entire conference was planned.
But now I want to give more information about
how it was planned.
And I want to say with a lot of attention
to detail the entire conference was meticulously
planned.
So this is a positive adjective is somebody
used it on you?
You would take that as a compliment.
Number seven, exacerbate.
Ooh another tricky one for pronunciation.
Exacerbate.
This is when you make something that's already
bad, even worse.
We could say this attack will exacerbate the
already tense relationship between the two
communities.
So remember, it's a bad situation.
That's why I used already tense relationship
that is not a positive relationship.
So it's already bad, but then when you exacerbate
it means you make it even worse.
This attack will exacerbate their relationship.
Number eight, to call for.
This is a phrasal verb and you call for something
to happen.
And this is simply when you demand that something
happened.
For example, the union called for his resignation.
The union called for.
The union demanded.
The union called for his resignation.
Number nine, swift, swift.
This is an adjective.
It's a fun adjective because it simply means
quickly.
For example, the police took swift action
against the rioters.
Swift action, so they acted very quickly.
Swift action.
Number 10, to erode, erode.
This is when you slowly reduce or destroy
something.
You probably know this from a scientific perspective,
because of erosion or when rocks erode is
when rocks naturally become smaller, smaller
and smaller and smaller, because they gradually
reduce.
Well, the meaning is the exact same but instead
of a rock I want you to imagine trust.
Trust between two people in a business relationship
or a personal relationship as well.
And I could say these budget cuts could erode
the public's trust.
So we have the public's trust.
Just like a rock, and it's eroding, it's getting
smaller and smaller and smaller and smaller.
The trust is gradually decreasing.
And the reason why is because of the actions
of the person, the budget cuts.
The budget cuts could erode the public's trust.
Number 11, to highlight.
This is when you want to attract attention
to something specific or you want to emphasize
something specific.
For example, the report highlighted the need
for increased safety measures.
So the report was written in a way that it
took your attention to something specific
it emphasized specific information and that
specific information is we need more safety
measures the report highlighted the need for
increased safety measures.
Number 12, to expose.
This is when you make public something bad
or something wrong.
So there's something wrong and most of the
time people don't want that information public
right.
So when you take that wrongdoing, that someone
wants to keep secret, and you make it public,
you expose, you expose that person or you
expose that action, the bad action that that
person took.
For example, the report exposed government
corruption.
So there's government corruption.
Of course the government does not want the
public to know about it, right.
So when that information is made public, it's
exposed.
The report exposed government corruption.
Number 13, fundamental.
This is when something is more important than
anything else.
Fundamental, for example, it's one of the
fundamental differences between men and women.
So there are many differences between men
and women, obviously.
Remember, fundamental is more important than
anything else.
Now notice how I didn't reveal that fundamental
difference.
I just used "it's".
So you can decide what is the fundamental
difference between men and women?
If you want, you can try to put that in the
comments below.
It's the fundamental difference between men
and women, what could it be?
Number 14, to deploy.
And you deploy resources, resources could
be people in the form of their efforts and
the work their contribution, or it could be
money, it could be supplies, things like that.
And you deploy resources.
What does this mean?
When you deploy resources, it means you simply
use the resources but you use them in any
efficient way, or at least that a plan.
For example, the government is meeting to
discuss how to deploy the funds.
So they don't know how they're going to use
those resources in the best way.
And that's why they're meeting.
They're meeting to discuss how to deploy the
fund.
And finally, number 15, to pitch.
You pitch an idea or a plan.
And this simply means you share an idea or
a plan in a way that's meant to persuade,
persuade someone to do something specific
or to buy something.
For example, we pitched them our strategy
for how to deploy the resources.
So we have a plan, an idea, and we shared
it with you.
But we did it in a way that we want you to
say yes, we want you to accept our plan, that
is to pitch.
So now you have 15 advanced words to sound
fluent in English.
Which one was your favorite?
Which one are you going to add to your vocabulary?
Put it in the comments below.
And then practice.
Practice an example sentence using your new
favorite vocabulary.
And of course, you can practice more than
one, two or three would be awesome.
And if you found this video helpful, hit the
like button share it with your friends and
of course subscribe.
And before you go, make sure you head on over
to my website, JForrestEnglish.com and download
your free speaking guide.
In this guide, I share six tips on how to
speak English fluently and confidently.
And until next time, Happy Studying!