(upbeat music)
- Welcome back to English with Lucy.
Today I am going to teach you
15 beautiful English words
that I think you should use more often.
I think we should all use them more often.
I've selected these words
because I find that they
roll off the tongue,
well, at least some of them do,
and others just have
really beautiful meanings.
To help you with your English
learning journey even more,
I have created a free PDF that
goes along with this lesson
and I have created a quiz.
I know you all love quizzes.
You always request quizzes.
If you would like to download
the free PDF and the quiz,
all you have to do is click on the link
in the description box.
You enter your name
and your email address.
You sign up to my mailing list
and I send the PDF directly to your inbox.
Before we get started,
I would just like to thank
the sponsor of today's video.
It is Lingoda, Europe's number
one trusted language school
with their language sprint.
With the sprint, you can learn
to speak English confidently
in just three months, gain
100% of your money back,
and gain free access to the
Cambridge online speaking test.
You just need to take
one of the 24/7 classes
every day for three months
and get your course fees
completely refunded.
Click on the link in the
description box to check the dates
for this sprint.
But be quick because if
the deadline has passed
or the spaces are filled,
you will miss out.
The super sprint offers a 100% refund
but there is also a lighter
regular sprint option
which offers a 50% refund.
You can join the sprint in
English, business English,
French, German and Spanish from
beginner to advanced level.
I'm really excited to share
this opportunity with you
because I have firsthand
experience of how amazing
and effective these
Lingoda challenges can be.
They've transformed so
many of my students' lives.
They love Lingoda
because they can interact
in intimate small group classes
with amazing qualified teachers
any time, any day, anywhere.
Over 40,000 people have participated
in the previous Lingoda
language challenges
with many of them becoming able
to overcome their fear of
speaking and get new jobs.
I actually joined one of
Lingoda student Facebook groups
and I was blown away by how many students
were celebrating their refunds
and their fluency transformations.
So how can you participate?
Sign up before the deadline
and pay the deposit to secure your spot.
You can use my code
CHANGE50 for 10 euros off.
Lingoda will refund
your tuition fee in full
together with the deposit
if you attend the agreed number of classes
within each sprint month by
following the contest rules.
Remember, spaces in
the sprint are limited.
This is a language school
and places fill up.
So you have the link
in the description box.
You have my code CHANGE50
for 10 euros off.
What are you waiting for?
Let's get started with the lesson.
The first beautiful English word
that I think you should
use more frequently
is number one, appealing.
Appealing.
I love the long E sound.
This means attractive or interesting.
An example, his rich vocabulary
made him sound so appealing.
This is a word that my
mother uses quite a lot.
If she sees something delicious
or smells some nice food,
she'll always say, oh,
that looks so appealing.
It appeals to me.
It's appealing.
Number two is ineffable.
Ineffable.
This means too great or
beautiful to describe in words.
Something so wonderful
that you can't express
how wonderful it is.
It's ineffable.
An example.
When I heard of their pregnancy,
I was filled with ineffable joy.
Number three is nefarious.
Nefarious.
I know a lot of learners
of English struggle
with the /eə/ sound.
Now we are always taught
to pronounce it as /e/ /a/,
together, /eə/.
However, lots of my
students find it easier
to think of it as an
extension of an /e/ sound.
/a/ /a/.
Nefarious.
It might not be what you
find in a pronunciation book
but if it helps you,
then that's fine by me.
Now this might be a beautiful
word in my opinion, nefarious,
but it doesn't have a
very beautiful meaning.
It means criminal or extremely bad.
I like this word because
I find it very expressive.
An example.
They hacked into my bank account
and used the funds for nefarious purposes.
Criminal, extremely bad, extremely bad.
Number four is ethereal.
Ethereal.
This means extremely light and beautiful;
seeming to belong to another
more spiritual world.
I think the word sounds beautiful
but I think the meaning is amazing.
An example.
At sunrise, the London
skyline almost looks ethereal.
Number five, if you know me well,
then you might understand
why I love this word so much.
It is epiphany.
Epiphany.
Can you guess why I like it?
It means a sudden and surprising
moment of realisation.
I chose to name my pronunciation
course after this word,
Epiphany Language Studios.
This is because I want my
students to have an epiphany,
a moment of realisation and understanding
when it comes to their language skills
and their pronunciation.
An example.
When she took the course,
she had an epiphany and
everything became clear.
Number six, short, but sweet, angst.
Angst.
It's a feeling of great worry or concern
about your situation or your life.
You often hear teenage angst.
I wrote emotional poetry when
I was full of teenage angst.
Number seven is euphoria.
Euphoria.
This means an extremely
strong feeling of excitement
or happiness that usually
only lasts a short while.
An example.
After receiving the letter of acceptance,
I was in a state of euphoria.
Number eight is cherish.
Cherish.
This is a verb meaning to
love someone or something
very much and wanting
to protect them or it.
An example.
I will always cherish
the letter he wrote to me
before he moved away.
Number nine is eternity.
Eternity.
This simply means time without end.
For example, a mother's
love lasts for eternity.
Number 10 is quintessence.
Quintessence.
You may have heard it's
adjective form before,
quintessential, which
is also very beautiful,
but I think this one
is used less frequently
and I simply believe it should
be used more frequently.
It's a very good word, quintessence.
It means the perfect example of something.
An example.
It was the quintessence of
an English country cottage.
If you see a perfect country cottage
with beautiful light
stone and roses up it,
you can say that is the quintessence
of an English country cottage.
English country cottage.
That's a hard thing to say.
Try repeating that three times.
Number 11 is plethora.
Plethora.
This one does roll off
the tongue, plethora.
It means an amount that
is greater than is needed
or can be used.
For example.
The article contained a
plethora of information.
We're implying that there's
slightly too much information,
maybe in a good way,
just so much information
more than I could ever take
in, a plethora of information.
That might be one of my all
time favourites, actually,
or this next one.
Number 12, pristine.
Pristine, oh, I love this word.
It's so expressive.
It means fresh and clean, as if new.
Her house was pristine.
It's another that my mother uses a lot.
Her house is always pristine,
and that is true of my mother.
You could eat off her floors.
Number 13 is surreptitiously.
Surreptitiously.
It means in a quick or secret way
so that people don't notice.
An example.
She surreptitiously slid
the check under his napkin.
Napkin is another word for serviette.
Number 14 is dulcet.
Dulcet.
This means sounding sweet or pleasant
and it's often paired with tones.
If you're talking about
somebody's dulcet tones,
it means their sweet voice.
An example, I can always
recognise her dulcet tones.
I can always recognise her lovely voice.
And number 15, the last one is docile.
Docile.
This means quiet and easy to control.
We often use it to talk about animals
that are very sweet natured.
An example.
The puppy is calm and incredibly docile,
said no puppy owner ever.
(laughs)
My puppy was docile for the first week
and then it was chaos for nearly a year
and now he's completely
docile again, not completely.
Right, that's it for today's lesson.
I hope you enjoyed it and I
hope you learned something.
Don't forget to take the quiz.
The link is in the description box.
You sign up to my mailing list
and I send it directly to your inbox.
You can share your scores
in the comment section.
Also, I've still got a
few things to figure out
but quite a few of you mentioned
that my white background
makes your eyes feel tired.
So, I had a brainwave, black background.
Do you like it?
What's your feedback?
Step by step I am trying
to make these lessons better for you.
New microphone, black background,
PDFs with every lesson.
I hope it works for you.
I always listen to your feedback.
This is due to your feedback.
So let me know.
Another thank you to the sponsor
of today's video, Lingoda.
If you would like to join their sprint,
click on the link in the description box
and use my code CHANGE50
for 10 euro discount
on your deposit.
Remember that if you'd like
to practise your listening
and pick up some real vocabulary in use,
then you can have a look
at my vlogging channel
where I've logged my life here
in the English countryside on a farm.
And every vlog is fully
subtitled for your understanding.
Don't forget to connect
with me on my social media.
I've got my Instagram
and I've got my fantastic
website, englishwithlucy.co.uk,
where I have a really
cool pronunciation tool
that you can use for free.
I will see you soon for another lesson.
(blows kisses)
(upbeat music)