With English, idioms, you can
precisely express your feelings.
You can even add finesse or nuance,
no matter whether you're feeling
joyful, calm, or frustrated. Now,
of course you can use
the words, joy, calm,
and frustration to describe
how you're feeling. However,
in this lesson today,
I'm going to share with you 21
English idioms to help bring
sharp accuracy to how you express
the way you're feeling in English.
Moreover,
it will allow you to increase the level
of sophistication in your vocabulary.
If you don't already know, I'm
Annemarie with Speak Confident English,
everything I do here is designed to help
you to get the confidence you want for
your life and work in English.
One way I do that is with my
weekly Confident English lessons,
which you can find at my Speak
Confident English, YouTube channel,
and at the Speak Confident
English website. In these lessons,
I provide my top fluency and
confidence, building strategies,
targeted grammar lessons and
advanced level vocabulary.
Just like in this one
today. So while you're here,
make sure that you
subscribe to this channel.
So you never miss one of my
Confident English lessons.
Now let's get back to those 21 English
idioms to help you express your feelings
in English.
What makes idiom so exciting
is that they allow us to
describe something in a precise
and creative way. Not only that,
but idioms also help
us to be concise in our
communication.
The right idiom can help us describe
an extremely complicated emotion
in just a few words. For example,
if I say that I'm feeling
frustrated that word doesn't fully
express whether something is
simply under my skin or whether
I'm nearly ready to flip my
lid. These are two idioms.
You're going to learn more about today.
Recently members in my Confident Women
Community explored more than 30 idioms
that help us to express feelings
of joy, calm, frustration,
and even anger. And for
you in this lesson today,
I've refined that list to
21 English idioms together.
We're going to explore how these English
idioms can be useful to you as you
describe your feelings and we'll
discover their subtlies as well as we go
through this lesson together.
If you begin to wonder how you can
remember all of these idioms and
use them effectively in
English conversations,
be sure to stick with me because I'll
share my top strategies to learn.
And remember at the end of this lesson,
let's start today with four idioms that
are used to describe a general state
of positivity. The
first one to feel sunny,
if you're feeling sunny, it means to
be outwardly cheerful and optimistic.
This typically happens when things
in our life line up in a way
that make us feel pleased
and hopeful. For example,
you might be the kind of
person who loves to brainstorm.
You love sharing ideas and exploring
possibilities. If that sounds like you,
then this sentence might be
a great example to follow.
Hannah felt sunny as
she brainstormed ideas,
similar to feeling sunny.
You might describe yourself as
feeling upbeat when you're feeling
upbeat. It means that you're feeling
full of hope, optimism, and joy.
Now, as I said, this is very
similar to the idiom to feel sunny,
but there is just a slight difference.
A person can feel sunny,
feel generally optimistic and not
draw a lot of attention to themselves.
It might be a general feeling of
joy that they have internally.
However, when we describe
ourselves as feeling upbeat,
it typically means that we are
exhibiting our hope, our joy,
our optimism in a lively
expressive way. For example,
if you hear your favorite song, come
on the radio while you're driving,
you might turn it up and say, oh,
this song always makes me feel upbeat.
And when you do that,
it's likely that there's going to be
some outward sign of that upbeat feeling.
Our third idiom for general
positivity is to be in good spirits
when you're in good spirits,
it means to feel lighthearted
or cheerful while maintaining
balance. For example,
you may be working on a difficult
project at work and with any project,
there are bound to be moments of
stress or missed deadlines. However,
despite those potential obstacles,
you still feel that overall
sense of cheerfulness.
So a great example sentence you could
use might be the team was in good
spirits as they approached
the project deadline.
And number four for general
positivity is to be in good humor.
Once again,
this means to have a general
sense of cheerfulness or to be
amicable, to be agreeable.
You'll often hear this idiom used
when someone is feeling particularly
cheerful after a difficult
or stressful situation.
For example, if someone, you know,
recently had a major operation,
if they come through that operation
and go through their recovery process,
feeling cheerful and
optimistic, you might say,
my mother seemed to be in good humor.
As we stroll through the
garden after her surgery.
Now let's continue to our next section
where we'll focus on five idioms that we
typically use to describe feelings of joy.
When you feel so happy that
you nearly jump into the air,
or maybe you actually
do jump into the air,
you can use the idiom to leap
or jump for joy. For example,
she couldn't help, but leap for
joy when they offered her the job.
Can you think of the last time you felt
so happy that you were ready to jump
into the air? How would you use
that idiom to describe that moment,
write down an example
sentence. And if you want,
you can share it with me
in the comments as well.
Our second idiom for describing
feelings of joy is to
burst with joy. Let's talk about that.
Verb burst for a moment.
Imagine a balloon that is full of air.
What's going to happen to that balloon.
If you take a small pin or
needle and you poke the balloon,
it's going to burst, right?
This idiom figuratively describes
that feeling of having so
much happiness, so much joy that
you feel that you're about to burst.
For example,
my niece was bursting with joy as
she got ready for her first day of
school, the next one to weep for joy.
This means to cry out of
pure happiness. For example,
if you haven't seen a family member
for a particularly long time,
that first moment, when
you see your family member,
when you're able to give them a hug,
you might be overwhelmed with joy
to the point that you start crying
to cry for joy. For example,
it was hard not to weep for joy.
When I saw my brother for the
first time, after four years,
our fourth idiom to describe feelings
of joy is to be over the moon.
Simply put this means
to be extremely pleased.
For example, we were over the moon. When
we found out we were moving to France,
similar to feeling over the
moon is to be on cloud nine.
When you're on cloud nine,
it means to be overwhelmed
with feelings of happiness,
satisfaction and excitement. For example,
Rachel felt like she was on cloud nine.
When she finally bought her dream house.
Our next three idioms are focused
specifically on feelings of
calm or tranquility.
And the first one is to be
even keeled when you're even
keeled, you're balanced
well adjusted and calm.
Think for a moment about a coworker
or maybe a boss that you've had,
who always stays calm and logical,
no matter how stressful a
situation might be at work.
You could always describe that
person as having an even keeled
manner or an even keeled characteristic.
And if you want an example
sentence, you might say my coworker,
Susan is always even keeled,
no matter how stressful the
situation might be in our office.
The second idiom that we can use to
describe feelings of calm is to be as
cool as a cucumber.
Have you ever gone to a spa and
had slices of cool cucumbers
placed over your eyes?
Why do they do that?
It brings an immediate
sense of coolness and calm.
And this is a wonderful idiom to use.
When you want to describe
someone as being perfectly calm,
perfectly composed.
Despite the circumstances,
for example, as she got ready to
go on stage for her presentation,
Carrie was as cool as a cucumber
and our third idiom for describing
those moments of staying
calm is to keep one's cool.
I love this idiom to keep
one's cool means to stay calm
in a difficult situation.
This is particularly important for anyone
in the customer service industry and
a great example sentence. You
could use what this idiom might be.
I felt frustrated by the
constant questioning,
but I kept my cool all the same. Okay.
So far we've had idioms to
describe general feelings of
positivity,
idioms to describe feeling
joyful and idioms for feeling
calm.
Now we're going to transition into idioms
that we might use to describe moments
of frustration or even anger.
Let's start with three English idioms
we can use to describe those moments
of irritation, annoyance,
or frustration when things get difficult
or don't go the way we expected.
The first one is to get under one's skin.
This is one that I use at the very
beginning of this lesson today.
If something gets under your skin,
it means that you are annoyed
by someone's behavior or
their communication.
Here's an example sentence,
despite trying to stay calm,
her teenage daughter's behavior
got under Elaine's skin.
Think for a moment
about behaviors at work.
Is there anything that someone
does that irritates you that
annoys you? If so,
try using this idiom to describe it,
describe what happens and how
you feel using the idiom to
get under your skin after you do that,
share it with me in the comments below.
And now let's go onto the second
idiom to describe frustration
to push one's buttons. If
someone pushes your buttons,
it means that they do something or
say something in a way that aims
to get some kind of a strong
reaction or an emotional response.
Typically negative. For
example, when I was younger,
my brother knew exactly how to push
my buttons and get me in trouble
with our parents. And number three,
to be on edge earlier,
I used an example of someone
remaining as cool as a cucumber just
before they go on stage
to give a presentation.
The opposite of that
might be to be on edge.
When you're feeling on edge, it
means that you're feeling nervous,
anxious, irritated, or frustrated.
And usually this is exhibited
in some kind of behavior like
pacing back and forth.
So just like I use the idiom cool as
a cucumber to describe how someone
appeared just before
giving a presentation,
I could use this one as well
as she prepared to go on stage
and give her presentation.
Carrie appeared to be on edge
as she paced back and forth.
Now that you have idioms to describe
feelings of frustration in English,
let's move on to what you might say.
When those feelings of
frustration, transition into anger,
we have three idioms. We're going
to learn focused on feeling anger.
And then we're going to move further
with three idioms that we use to describe
uncontrollable anger. So when
things really reach their limit,
our first English idiom to
describe feeling angry is to
lose one's temper or simply to lose it.
If you lose your temper,
it means you lose your
composure and you visibly show
anger. You're no longer able
to keep it inside. For example,
my mom lost it. When she
found out I failed my test.
Can you think of a moment when
you lost it? In other words,
you lost your composure.
You are no longer able to
keep your cool and instead
you showed your anger. If
you've had a moment like that,
try using that idiom in an
example, sentence of your own.
Our second idiom for describing
feelings of anger doesn't necessarily
mean that you exhibit anger.
You don't necessarily show it,
but you do take some kind of
action to help you stop those
feelings of anger.
The idiom is to be triggered
and we use this to describe our
emotional response to
something disturbing.
It might be something disturbing that
we see on media or at a social event.
It could also be something that
brings back a negative memory
or experience.
So the moment that disturbing
image comes on the computer screen,
or the moment that we
hear something disturbing,
we have this immediate angry
response. And as a result,
we might walk away from the situation
or turn off the TV or stop watching a
movie. For example,
watching the movie triggered me
and I couldn't finish the rest.
I had to turn it off English idiom.
Number three for describing
feelings of anger is to lash out.
This means to suddenly attack someone,
either physically or verbally
out of anger. For example,
she lashed out when she
found out she lost her job.
Before we get into a few final tips,
I'd like to share with you on how you
can learn and remember these English
idioms so that you're able
to easily use them in English
conversations.
I want to finish with three more
idioms and here we're going to the very
extreme of strong anger.
And the first idiom we'll
use here is to blow a fuse.
This simply means to
become extremely angry.
For example,
Jamie's aunt blew a fuse when she
found out the family wasn't coming
over for Thanksgiving this year. Now,
before I share my final two idioms,
I want to pause here for a moment
and reflect again on why idioms
are so helpful at the beginning of
this lesson. I highlighted that, yes,
we can use the words joyful, angry,
or frustrated to describe
our feelings. However, again,
if I use the word frustration,
I felt frustrated at work today.
It doesn't really tell you
the extent of my frustration
was I mildly frustrated and mildly angry,
maybe something got under my skin a bit,
or was I frustrated enough
that I became so angry
to blow a fuse.
This is where idioms become
particularly helpful.
Adding that sophistication
and nuance to our speech.
Now let's finish up with our last two
idioms and some tips on how to remember
these easily. So you can use them
in your English conversations.
The next idiom is to go ballistic.
This one is quite strong and
even has this violent feeling to
it.
It means to become extremely angry and
to show signs of rage. For example,
fans went ballistic when they found
out their favorite player was cut
from the team. And finally,
our last idiom for today is to flip a lid.
I love the imagery of this idiom,
even though it's quite negative.
I want you to imagine a pot of
boiling water with a lid on it,
and then imagine that
pot becoming so hot that
the steam and the boiling water result
in flipping the lid off that pot.
Now think about that in terms of the
kind of anger we might feel inside
to flip one's lid means to
become angry in an uncontrolled
way. For example,
my supervisor flipped his lid
when we didn't meet our sales
target.
Now that you have 21 English
idioms to describe feelings of joy,
calm, and frustration,
let's quickly talk about how you can
remember these and use them naturally
in your English conversations.
If you've been following me for a while
and you've watched some of my other
lessons on learning vocabulary in English,
these steps will be familiar to you.
The first thing I want you to do is
to choose two or three new idioms
from this list today, I recommend
choosing only two or three,
it's important to limit how many
idioms or expressions you try
to learn at any given time in time
select the two or three that are most
interesting or helpful to you.
And then I want you to immediately think
about how you would use those in your
own example, sentences apply
those idioms to your real life.
Doing this will help you to remember
how to use them in a practical way.
Now, the next step is I want you
to do the same thing with the
same two or three idioms
for an entire week.
I know that seems like
a long period of time,
but the key to learning something
and remembering it is repetition.
And this is the biggest
mistake I see students make.
They learn something one time,
they practice it one time and then
they move on giving yourself the
opportunity to repeat using
the same key vocabulary.
Over a short period of time will help
you lock it into your active vocabulary.
So I want you to have your two or
three idioms from today's list.
Give yourself time to make
an example sentence today,
and then tomorrow do the same
thing. Create an example sentence,
or maybe even try to use that idiom in a
conversation that you have with someone
else over the next week.
I want you to go back to the same
two or three idioms again and again,
using them as often as you can,
this will help you to remember
them so that in two months or
six months or a year from now,
you're able to use that idiom accurately.
You haven't forgotten it as always.
If you have example sentences,
you can share them with me.
I would love for you to do that in the
comment section below while you're there.
Take time to review examples
from other students as well.
This will give you ideas of how to
use these idioms in your own life.
If you found today's lesson helpful
to you, I would love to know,
make sure that you give this lesson a
thumbs up here on YouTube and don't forget
to subscribe. So you never
miss one of these lessons.
Thank you so much for joining me. And
I look forward to seeing you next time.