Recently,
one of my students told me that I haven't
done a lesson on English idioms in
ages and she's right.
I haven't done a lesson dedicated
to English idioms for quite a while.
Like my students,
you might love incorporating English
idioms into your conversation,
sprinkling idioms into your speech here
and there (the way that you sprinkle
salt on food) is a wonderful way to
bring interest in creativity to your
speech. It makes our
language more dynamic.
And that's exactly what I want to
help you do with this lesson today.
If you're joining me for the very first
time I'm Annemarie with Speak Confident
English,
everything I do here is designed to help
you with the confidence you want for
your life and work in English in
this Confident English lesson today,
I hope that you'll join me to
learn and add 24 new English
idioms to your active vocabulary.
All of these idioms are
focused on the concept of time,
whether you want to express that
something happened right on time,
that you don't have enough
time, or you have too much time.
Be sure to stick with me
all the way to the end,
because I do have a practice
opportunity for you.
I want to make sure that you absolutely
understand what these idioms mean
and how to naturally use them
in your English conversations.
[Inaudible].
Let's start with our first four idioms,
all of which help us express that
something happened at just the right time.
It wasn't too early
and it wasn't too late.
The first one is in the
nick of time. For example,
we were stuck in traffic,
but we arrived at the airport
just in the nick of time.
We use this idiom to express that
something happened just at the last
possible moment before it was too late.
If we had arrived any
later at the airport,
we may have missed our flight. So
we arrived in the nick of time.
Similar to that,
we can also describe something
as happening at the 11th hour.
Again,
this idiom tells us that something
happened just at the last possible
moment before it was
too late. For example,
just when we thought we were
going to miss the deadline.
Carol finished her editing and we
submitted the proposal at the 11th hour.
Our third idiom in this
category is it's high time.
For example,
it's high time that we consider moving
out of our apartment and into a house.
This idiomatic phrase expresses
that it's about time that we finally
do something.
Maybe someone has been waiting for a
very long period of time and they are
finally ready. It is about
time now is the right time.
It's high time.
And our final idiom in this
category is in good time
and good time expresses that
something will happen when it's
supposed to happen. For example,
when I was worried about whether I
would ever find a job, I really wanted,
my mom said all things
happen in good time.
And now let's move on to our
second category of idioms.
All of which are focused on
different points of time.
For example, eons ago or ages ago,
English speakers love this phrase to
express that something happened a while
ago. In fact,
it emphasizes that something
occurred a long time ago.
Just like the example I
shared at the beginning,
when my students said you haven't
done a lesson on idioms for
ages, in other words, for a
really, really, really long time.
Another example, I finished that
book eons ago. In other words,
months ago or years ago,
an idiomatic expression.
That means the opposite. That means
that something will occur in the future,
but not for quite a while is a ways out.
For example,
let's say that it's January and you've
already started to plan your summer
vacation. You have everything ready to
go in a conversation. You might say,
I know that summer is a ways out,
but you can never start
planning your vacation too soon.
Another great idiomatic expression to
use with a future focus is in the long
run. When we use this in a sentence,
we're expressing that something
will more fully develop over time.
For example,
we should start saving money now so
that we don't have to worry about our
financial security in the long run.
The next idiom on our list
is one of my favorites.
When I get up particularly early
for a flight or to work out
at the crack of dawn, for example,
I was so excited about my new job that
I woke up at the crack of dawn today.
This phrase refers to that moment when
we first start to see the sunlight on the
horizon,
and we use this expression to talk
about things that happen super early
in the morning.
And now our final idiom for talking
about different points of time is a
moment of truth.
And we love to use this idiom to talk
about a present moment when something
will be revealed.
Maybe we've been waiting and
waiting and waiting to find out some
information.
And when it is time for that
information to be revealed,
we can say, it's the moment
of truth. For example,
if you have a child
applying to universities,
you might be waiting and waiting and
waiting to get news in the mail on whether
or not your child was
accepted into that university.
So when that letter finally arrives
and your son or daughter starts to
open that envelope,
it is most certainly that moment of truth.
When you will find out whether or not
your daughter or son was accepted into
that university. And now it's
time for our next six idioms,
all of which are focused on
expressing a lack of time
in the past,
I've done lessons on time management
and trying to create better
life work balance.
So some of these idiomatic
expressions may be familiar to you.
The first one on our list in this
category is to be pressed for
time.
And we use this to let others know
that we don't have very much time.
For example,
we were pressed for time and had to
finish dinner early so we could make it to
the theater. The second one in
this category is running late.
You've probably heard this one before,
because it's extremely common when
we know we are going to be late,
or we already are late for something,
a very common way to use this is
to let others know that you are
running late. So you may not
be at the meeting on time.
You might call your coworker and
say, go ahead and start the meeting.
I'm running five minutes late when
you are unable to complete something
because you no longer have time.
You can use the expression
to run out of time.
For example, before I knew it, the test
was over and I had run out of time.
When we use that expression,
we're indicating that we were
not able to finish the task
time, ran out the deadline passed,
and we were unable to succeed in
our task. We didn't finish it fully.
We ran out of time. And of
course in those moments,
when you know the clock is ticking,
you see time going forward.
And you know that you're going to have
a really hard time completing the task.
We can say that you're in a race
against the clock or in a race
against time. For example,
during the holiday season,
everyone raises against the clock to get
their shopping done before the stores
close. And sometimes when
we're racing against the clock,
we might try to do something that's kind
of cheating or trying to get ahead in a
way to beat the clock. In other words,
you want to make sure that you finish
your task before you run out of time.
For example,
Sam tried to beat the clock as he scarfed
down his breakfast and ran out the
door. Let's pause here for a
moment. What do you think? I mean,
by scarfed down his breakfast,
if someone is trying to beat the clock,
they're trying to do something before
it's too late and they're running for the
door to get to work on time.
How do you think they ate their breakfast?
Where are they eating in a calm,
super polite, formal manner?
Definitely not to scarf
something down means to eat it
extremely quickly. And
during that process,
you've probably lost all
your table manners as well.
And now our last idiom for expressing
a lack of time is certainly one
that, you know, I hear my students
use it often. Time is money,
as I'm sure you know,
this idiom is used to express that time
is precious and we certainly should not
waste it. For example,
my husband never sits down for a moment
to relax because he believes time is
money.
Every moment he is working on
something or trying to work toward a
specific goal or to complete
a project. All right,
so far we've had a variety of idioms that
can be used to express that something
happened right on time,
that we had a lack of time and to
express different points in time.
So now let's move on to our
fourth category with idioms,
we use to talk about having
excess time or too much time.
When you go on vacation,
you probably would love to
say that you have all the time
in the world. When we have all the time
in the world, there's plenty of time.
There's no rush. There's no panic.
We don't have to worry about
any upcoming deadlines.
That is definitely something we all
want when we're going away on vacation.
Another example might be, we have all
the time in the world to binge watch.
Netflix shows this weekend,
similar to all the time in the world
is to have a lot of time on your
hands. Again,
this is used to express that
you have plenty of time.
For example, Sandra has a
lot of time on her hands.
Now that our kids are at school
with this particular idiom,
we can also use it in the negative
sense to indicate that we don't have
time, that we have a lack
of time. For example,
now that I'm going back to work
and at the office full time,
I don't have a lot of time on my
hands to watch Netflix when you have
too much time on your hands.
And you're not really sure
how to fill up all that time,
you might start looking
for different things to do,
to occupy yourself or to
kill time. For example,
if you're traveling, you might have
a six hour layover in an airport.
So you might say that you want to find
a really good book to read while you're
at the airport to kill time.
And if that book is particularly good,
you might lose track of time.
When we lose track of time,
we don't even notice that time has
passed. Maybe before your flight,
you were really dreading
that six hour layover,
but then you found that fantastic
book you started reading.
And before you knew it, it
was time for your next flight.
You lost track of time
while you were reading.
Now let's say that maybe
you've lost track of time,
or you've missed out on opportunities
because you were way too busy
as a way to apologize to someone
else and to show that you
value their time. You might
want to make up for lost time.
For example,
both of Julian's parents
have been particularly busy
with work and approaching
deadlines. So to make up for lost time,
they dedicated their entire weekend
to spending time together as a family.
And now our last idiom in
this category is to live on
borrowed time.
We use this to express that someone
is living or surviving beyond
their expected amount
of time. For example,
after surviving cancer,
Karen felt that she was
living on borrowed time.
And now we have our final
three time focus, idioms,
all of which can be used to
express a lack of frequency.
For example, if you want to say
that something rarely happens,
you can say that it happens once
in a blue moon. For example,
we see our extended family
once in a blue moon,
and usually only at family reunions,
similar to once in a blue
moon is every now and then if
something happens every now
and then it's a little more
often than once in a blue
moon, rather than the adverb.
Rarely we might think of the
adverbs sometimes, for example,
every now and then Hollywood produces
a movie that impacts an entire
generation.
And now our final idiom on the
list for today is every so often.
For example, I don't
really have a sweet tooth,
but every so often I crave
a piece of chocolate.
And with that, you have
24 new English, idioms,
all of which are focused on time
to add to your active vocabulary.
Now, when I say active vocabulary,
I mean idioms that you can think of
and use instantly in a conversation
to make sure that these idioms are
part of your active vocabulary.
You need to of course learn
them and then practice them.
You need consistent repetitive practice.
So I've got a couple of
questions for you. Number one,
which idiom on the list today
was your absolute favorite.
Which one did you hear and think,
oh my gosh, I love that idiom.
If there was one, you
really enjoyed learning.
I want you to practice using it
in your own example sentence,
and you can share your example with me
in the comments below my second question.
You is a little more in depth. I want
you to think about your last week,
everything that you've done, the
things that happened right on time,
the things that you didn't have enough
time for moments when you felt like you
had too much time, think
about your past week,
choose three idioms from
this lesson today and use
those idioms to describe your week. Again,
you can share in the
comments with me below.
If you found this lesson useful
to you, I would love to know.
And you can tell me in
one very simple way,
give this lesson at thumbs up here
on YouTube. And while you're at it,
subscribe to the Speak
Confident English channel.
So you never miss one of my weekly
lessons. Thank you so much for joining me.
And I look forward to
seeing you next time.