How do you strategically and effectively
learn phrasal verbs in English?
Like many of my students, you
might struggle with that question.
You may even feel overwhelmed by the
sheer number of phrasal verbs we have
in English, because there
are thousands of them.
So where do you start and
how do you learn them in
a way that allows you to also remember
them easily so that you can use them
in conversations when you want,
If you don't already know, I'm
Annemarie with Speak Confident English,
everything I do here is designed to help
you to get the confidence you want for
your life and work in English.
One way I do that is with these weekly
Confident English lessons that I share at
my Speak Confident English website
and at the Speak Confident English,
YouTube channel in these lessons, I
share my top fluency and confidence,
building strategies,
targeted grammar practice,
and advanced level vocabulary
lessons, just like in this one today.
So while you're here,
make sure that you subscribe to my
Speak Confident English channel.
So you never miss one of these lessons.
And now let's get back to that question
of how do you strategically learn
phrasal verbs verbs in my
Confident English lesson today,
I'm going to answer that question
and help you get started.
The answer to strategic effective
practice is simple themes.
Learn new vocabulary, including
phrasal verbs in themes.
There are two reasons why
themes are so effective.
Number one, when you
choose a theme to focus on,
you're likely to choose something that
you are either extremely interested in,
or it's an area of need.
It's a topic that you need to speak
to for work or in your daily life.
As a result,
what you learn will be practical
and useful to your life.
The second reason themes are so
effective is that you are going to
encounter the same vocabulary
again and again and again,
as you study that theme.
And let me give you a clear example of
how that works with our focus today in
this lesson,
you're going to learn 26 must
have phrasal verbs in English
for travel. And let's talk
about this idea of repetition.
In this lesson,
I'm going to introduce you to several
new phrasal verbs or maybe some
phrasal verbs you've learned before.
So you'll have the
opportunity to hear them.
You can even go to my website to
see this lesson online and read
them as well.
So you're getting that learning process
in conversations with coworkers or
neighbors about their past vacations
or their upcoming summer plans,
you'll have the opportunity to hear
those same phrasal verbs. Again,
in those conversations, you might spend
a little bit of time online this week,
reviewing some articles
about travel. For example,
how to plan your dream vacation,
or maybe the top 12 cities to
visit this year. In those articles,
you're likely to see some of the same
phrasal verbs that you're going to hear in
this lesson today. And then finally,
when you practice speaking with others,
and when you get to share
your travel experiences,
you have the opportunity to
use these same phrasal verbs.
This is the key to not just
learning phrasal verbs effectively,
but remembering them so that when
you hear them in conversations,
you immediately understand the
meaning and you can use them in your
communication as well.
Now, with this theme today,
I've divided it into four subtopics.
So it's easier to stay focused.
We're going to look at phrasal verbs that
we typically use when we're booking or
planning a trip than a series
of phrasal verbs we use for
transportation.
Part three will be phrasal verbs that
we typically use at the airport and a
hotel.
And finally phrasal verbs that you're
likely to use or hear when you arrive at
your destination, before
we get into part one,
I want to spend a little bit of time
reviewing what exactly is a phrasal verb.
Now,
if you're crystal clear on this and you
have no questions about what phrasal
verbs are, I recommend that you
skip ahead to the next part,
where we begin with phrasal verbs
used in booking and planning a trip
I've made that easy to do by
splitting this video up into chapter.
So you can go on ahead
to the next section.
For those of you who want a quick review,
let's talk about what
exactly is a phrasal verb.
A phrasal verb is a standard
English verb combined
with an adverb or a
proposition, for example,
the phrasal verbs to get
away and to look forward
these two combine a standard
verb with an adverb.
Two more examples include to get
into and to dream of where we have
standard verbs combined with prepositions.
What makes phrasal verbs really
tricky is the fact that when we
combine the standard verb
with an adverb or preposition,
there's a whole new meaning to learn.
You are learning an entirely new verb.
You might be familiar with the verb,
look or familiar with the verb dream,
but the meaning of those
verbs when they are alone is
different from the meaning when they're
combined with an adverb or preposition.
And with that, let's
dive right into part one,
our first series of phrasal verbs when
you're booking or planning a trip.
One of the first phrasal verbs that
you're likely to hear is to get away,
to get away, means to leave
and go somewhere for a break
of vacation or holiday.
For example, in a conversation
with a friend, I might say,
you really need to get away
and recharge your batteries.
You've been working way too much lately.
And in response to that statement,
my friend might say,
I know I've been dreaming of going
to the beach to dream of something
means to think about or wish for
something that you really want.
Now, if you've been
dreaming of a long vacation,
you might need to sock away
for a while to sock away means
to put money into a bank account or to
invest it in some way so that you are
saving. For example,
in the past year alone,
he had socked away enough for
a two week trip to Portugal.
In addition to saving a bit of money,
you might also aim to rack
up points for free airfare.
This is something that
hotel chains, air airlines,
and credit card companies do quite a bit.
As you spend money on airline
travel or hotel stays,
you earn points over time,
or you can rack up points as you do that.
You'll be able to exchange them
for a few free nights of stay or
some cost savings on airfare. And
when you have enough of those points,
you might say I've racked up
enough points for a free trip,
socking away and racking up points
will certainly be important.
If you see prices hike up
to hike up means to increase
or raise the cost of
something. For example,
due to fuel and staff shortages
airlines have hiked up the cost
of airfare.
Before we continue with a few more
phrasal verbs we use when planning a trip,
I want to pause here and take a second.
Look at what we've learned so far.
We've had the phrasal verbs to
get away. I need to get away.
I'm dreaming of he had socked up airlines
have hiked up.
Do you notice that the way we
use phrasal verbs is exactly the
same as standard verbs. There are two
important things that we're doing.
Number one, to ensure accuracy,
we are changing the phrasal
verb according to its tense.
So you might see the phrasal verb in
the present past future. And so on.
The second thing to pay attention
to is that the phrasal verb
agrees with the subject. For example,
I can say I dream of going
to the beach and my husband
dreams of going to the mountains
as we continue to practice
today, keep these two things in mind.
And now let's continue with these phrasal
verbs. We need to plan for our trip.
Number six is to figure out
in those first moments of
planning where you're going next,
you might need to figure out where
you want to go to figure out means to
solve a problem, or to discover
the answer to a question.
If you're talking about
a past travel experience,
you could also use it in a sentence.
Like we figured out how to
explore Europe on a tight budget.
After you figured out
where you want to go,
you might need a little bit of help
deciding what to do when you're there.
And someone, you know,
or perhaps even a travel agent
might hook you up to hook someone
up with someone or to hook someone up with
something means to successfully
put someone into contact
with another person or to
successfully get someone,
something that they need.
Let me give you two examples.
Our travel agent hooked us up with
first class tickets home to the United
States. In this example,
the travel agent is helping us get
something we need or really want.
And the second example,
a friend of ours hooked us up
with an amazing travel guide.
We were able to explore the city,
learn its history and appreciate
its architecture. In this example,
a friend connected us with someone else.
Once you have a few of
those things in place,
I'm sure that you'll be
looking forward to your trip.
This means to positively anticipate
an event and for our final
phrasal verb in this category,
it's the one phrasal verb that
we never want to hear to fall
through. If something falls
through, it means that it fails,
or it comes to nothing. For example,
our travel plans fall through
due to a family emergency.
Okay? Now it's time to move on to topic.
Number two, under the theme of travel,
we're going to look at a series of
phrasal verbs that we typically use when
using transportation.
The first one is to get into
what this means is to enter a
car. For example, we got into
the car and drove to the beach.
Now, if you're using public
transportation, for example,
a bus train or plane,
rather than get into you would
use the phrasal verb to get on.
For example, once the gates are closed,
you are no longer able
to get on the plane.
Now you might be wondering why
do we use get in for the car and
get on for public
transportation. Recently,
I did a lesson on
prepositions of place in,
on and at you'll discover the answer
to that question in that lesson.
So I'll share a link to it in
the notes below this video.
Now the opposite of getting on a
plane train or bus is to get off.
It means to exit. For example,
if you're flying to see some friends in
another city, you might say, oh my gosh,
we got off the plane hours ago, but we
were held up waiting for our luggage.
Do you notice in that example,
I used another phrasal
verb to hold up to hold up
means to be delayed.
So perhaps there was some mix up
with the luggage. And as a result,
you were delayed. You were held
up waiting for your luggage.
You could also use this
one talking about traffic.
If you are late getting to the airport,
you might have gotten held up in traffic.
And this leads me to
our next phrasal verb.
The reason that you may have been
delayed or held up in traffic
is because traffic was backed up.
This phrasal verb actually has two
possible meanings when we're talking about
using transportation. So when
you're on your way to the airport,
you may be late because
traffic was backed up.
The second meaning of to back up when
we're talking about transportation means
to go in reverse. For example,
let's say that you're on vacation with
your family and you decide to rent a
large van, which you're not
really comfortable driving.
So you might ask someone,
could you give me some help?
I'm trying to back up the van.
And now we have just three more phrasal
verbs that we typically use with
transportation. The
first one is to pick up,
this is a fantastic phrasal verb to know,
and it has so much
meaning to pick someone up
means to go somewhere,
to get someone and provide transportation.
For example,
you might be waiting for an
Uber to pick you up and take
you to the airport,
or you might drive to the airport to
pick up a friend who's coming to visit
you. If you go to the airport
to pick up your friend,
you're likely to pull up to
the passenger, pick up area,
to pull up to a specific area
means to stop your vehicle
in a certain place. So once again,
let's imagine you have a
friend coming to visit you.
You are driving to the airport to pick
her up and you know that she has already
arrived. She sent you a text message
to say, I've landed. I have my bags.
I'm waiting for you in
the passenger pickup area.
And you might call her to say,
I'll be there in just a few
moments I'm pulling up soon,
or I'll pull up to the passenger
pickup area in just one or two minutes,
the opposite of picking
someone up. So again,
going somewhere to get
someone is to drop someone
off.
This means to take someone
somewhere and leave them there.
So at the end of your
friend's trip, you might say,
I can drive you to the airport
to drop you off this afternoon.
Or if you're in a taxi on
the way to the airport,
you might tell your driver where
to drop you off. For example,
you can drop me off at the United
gate. Now, one more phrasal verb.
I want to share here. Doesn't
connect to transportation,
but it is part of this process of dropping
someone off or it's related to it.
We also have a phrasal verb to see off.
This means to be present in
a departure area and to say
goodbye to someone,
remember to drop someone off means to
take them to a location and leave them
there.
So you drop your friend off at the
airport and you drive away to see
someone off means that you take them
to the airport. You park the car,
you go inside the airport with them.
You wait in the departure area.
And at that last moment you say goodbye.
So you could tell your friend, I would
love to see you off at the airport.
I'll take you this afternoon.
And when you say that,
it's clear that you'll be going into
the airport with your friend and you'll
wait with her until her flight is ready.
Okay. We have two more sections to go.
I hope that you're writing down a few new
phrasal verbs and getting some example
sentences written down as well.
Our next section is quite short with
just four phrasal verbs that we typically
hear at the airport and at the hotel.
Number one to check in this means
to officially let someone know that
you've arrived for a reservation.
The first thing that you'll do at the
airport is to check in for your flight.
And after you arrive at your destination,
you might check into the hotel before
you go out to explore the city.
The perfect opposite to that is
when it's time to leave the hotel,
you check out this means to
leave a place for example, hotel,
and in the process of leaving you
return any keys and pay outstanding
fees.
The third phrase LA verb in this category
is to take off and we only use it with
an airplane.
It's not used in a hotel to take
off means to leave the ground.
For example, the plane takes off.
After all passengers have boarded
and the doors have been closed.
And the opposite of that is to touch
down the next time you're on a flight,
listen carefully to the pilot. If
the pilot is speaking in English,
you'll likely hear this phrasal verbs.
It means to descend the wheels on
a plane and land on the ground.
So in the last 20 or
30 minutes of a flight,
you might hear a flight attendant or a
pilot say we're going to touch down in
about 20 minutes. Okay?
It's time for our final
section of 26 must have
phrasal verbs for travel in English.
Section four includes four phrasal
verbs you're likely to hear or use
when you get to your destination.
The first one is to look around
and this means to explore what
is near you in an area. For
example, that first day in the city,
you might not have a lot of
plans. And you might ask someone,
do you wanna look around
for a place to eat,
or do you wanna spend the afternoon just
looking around as you look around the
city, you might also get around.
This means to go or travel
to different places.
When you tell someone
else about your vacation,
you might say we were able to get
around the city easily on foot,
or despite the gloomy rainy weather,
we were still able to get
around and explore the city.
The third phrasal verb in this section
is to head for, or head toward,
and this means to begin moving in
the direction of a certain place.
So let's say that on your
second day of your vacation,
you have plans to go to a museum
after breakfast in the morning,
you might say to your partner, are
you ready to head toward the museum?
Or you might even say, let's
head toward the museum,
but on the way there there's a coffee
shop. I'd love to try. And finally,
our last phrasal verb for today
is to head back after a day
of getting around the city,
exploring everything there is to see
you might be tired and feel ready to
head back to your hotel.
This means to begin
returning to a place you
started your morning at a hotel,
you went out and explored the city,
and now it's time to return back
to that place. And with that,
you have 26 must have phrasal
verbs in English for talking about
travel. Now,
if you practiced along with me and you
wrote down a few of your own example
sentences, I would love
to know what they are.
You can share with me in the comment
section below while you do that,
make sure that you also review the
example sentences that others have shared.
It's part of that process of repetition.
And it might give you a few ideas of
how you can use the phrasal verbs you've
learned today. If you found
today's lesson helpful to you,
I would love to know you can give this
lesson a thumbs up and don't forget to
subscribe. So you don't miss my next
lesson. Thank you so much for joining me.
And I look forward to
seeing you next time.