Hey everyone, this is Alex from
EngVid. And today I want to share with
you three common idioms that you can use
to talk about appearance. Now, these
idioms can all be found in my book, this
book right here. It's called "200
Practical English Idioms". And what I
did with this book was try to think of
200 of the most common idioms that
English speakers use to help you, give
you language you will actually use. So
what's great about this book is I give
you a lot of examples. And I only
include high frequency idioms. So you
won't hear idioms that are no longer in
use in this book. If you want to check
it out, check out the link attached to
this video. And while you're on my
website on EnglishAlex.com, make sure to
subscribe to my newsletter. So on the
homepage, go all the way down. Just put
your email in. And I will send you an
email at least once a week to let you
know the latest things that I'm doing on
EngVid, on my own website, and you won't
miss any details.
Now, let's talk about the idioms that I
want to talk about from this book today.
So appearance: "You look like a million
bucks." So if someone looks like a
million bucks, this means they look
great, as well as they can look. So if
someone got a new haircut, for example,
you can say, "Wow, you look like a
million bucks". And remember, "bucks" is
slang for dollars. So if someone looks
like a million bucks, they look
fantastic. They look great. So a new
haircut or maybe they're wearing really
nice clothes, and they just look
fantastic. This idiom can also be used
to talk about the performance of someone
in a sport, for example. So you can say,
"oh, man, did you watch the game last
night, Ronaldo looked like a million
bucks", or "Messi looked like a million
bucks". "LeBron James looked like a
million bucks". So if someone plays
really well, to a high standard, you can
say they look like a million bucks as
well.
Another idiom that I want to share with
you guys today is "to catch someone's
eye". So if you catch someone's eye, it
means that you attract their attention
because of a particular characteristic
about yourself. Now I know this idiom
exists in many languages, like in
Polish, for example, you can say,
[Polish], like she caught my eye. So if
someone catches your eye, they attract
your attention. So to give you some
examples, his smile really caught my
eye, I was looking at new cars, and the
price of this one really caught my eye.
So a price can catch your eye if it's a
good price for something, for example.
So whether it's a particular feature of
a person, a particular feature of a
thing, anything that attracts your
attention, you can say, wow, that really
caught my eye. So "caught" is the past
of "catch", right? And also important to
remember, you can use idioms and the
past, the present, or the future -- just
make sure that you are using the correct
word order. Okay, so caught my eye,
okay, not caught eye my or something
like this.  make sure you try to use
the correct word order.
And the third idiom I want to share with
you today is "to cry your eyes out". So
if you cry your eyes out, this means
that you cry strongly, forcefully with a
lot of power, like you weep, basically.
So for example, if you watch a movie
that is incredibly sad, and if you are
someone who cries during movies that are
emotional, you can say, "Oh, I cried my
eyes out". So it's like imagine that
your eyes are just full of tears, and
everything is coming out of your eyes.
So I cried my eyes out. This is another
way to talk about how someone looks when
they're crying, for example.
So once again, you can look like a
million bucks, which means you look
great or you performed really well. What
was the second one? To catch your eye.
Right? So I hope this book is catching
your eye in this video. It looks pretty
good, right? I'm very proud of this. My
sister designed this actually. So I love
her today. Because she did a great job
with us -- today, you know -- and to cry
your eyes out, right? This means to cry
forcefully to cry strongly. So I will
cry my eyes out if you don't buy this
book, guys. I'm very hungry. Alex needs
food, Alex needs needs you to buy this
book. Is it.  am I coming across too
desperate? I hope not. But no,
seriously. I really strongly recommend
this book to you guys. If you enjoyed
the idioms that you heard in this video
and you want more example sentences,
more language, you will actually use,
check out "200 Practical English Idioms"
in the link that is attached to this
video. And if you did enjoy this video,
don't forget to subscribe to my channel.
Give this video a thumbs up, turn on
notifications. And leave me a comment
down below. Try to use the idioms that
you heard in this video in your
comments. What is the movie that made
you cry your eyes out? Do you look like
a million bucks today? Or do you know
someone who looks like a million bucks
for example? And what is something that
caught your eye about this video or
another video or something in your life?
So until next time, I hope you found
this useful. Thank you very much for
clicking, and I wish you success in your
studies. You look like a million bucks.