Hey today, you are going to.
Five English, idioms that you must know
English, idioms, that native English
speakers use on a regular basis.
Now, these idioms are right here.
We have a foot in the door, a shot in the
dark, allow the dust to settle barking up
the wrong tree and back against the wall.
Now, what do these idioms mean?
And how can you use them
naturally in real life?
Like a native English speaker.
I am going to teach you all of this.
Today.
So are you excited now?
I do want to let you know that all
of the idioms I'm going to teach you
today are found in my 100 English
idioms ebook, and there are a ton more.
So if you want to keep learning and
sounding like a native English speaker,
click the link in the description
and get your copy of 100 English.
Idioms.
Trust me, you won't regret it.
All right.
Now, let me ask you this.
Are you ready to get started.
Well, then I'm teacher
tiffani let's jump right in.
All right.
So let's get started with
our first idiom idiom.
Number one is a foot in the door after me.
A foot in the door.
Excellent job.
Now, a foot in the door just means
gives people an opportunity to start
doing something new, usually in an
area that is difficult to succeed.
So, for example, let's say there
was an individual that wanted to
get a great job at a very high
paying bank in New York city.
Well, if that individual went to the
number one finance university in America,
He, or she would have a foot in the
door for that job because they went to
an amazing school and that gives them
a better opportunity to get a good job.
Kind of makes sense.
We say a foot in the door.
Now, let me show you some other
examples that will help you
understand how to use this idiom.
My internship allowed me to get
my foot in the door for my career.
Now, this is a true statement.
And at the end, during story time,
I'll tell you the full story.
Now don't go anywhere at the end.
I'll tell you a story about this.
So having an internship helped this
individual, me, get a better job.
All right, we say, get a foot in the door.
Here we go.
Example, number two, this isn't
the job you hoped for, but it will
help you get a foot in the door,
meaning, Hey, the job you have right
now, I know it's not what you want.
But it's a stepping stone to
the next job, the next level.
So we say a foot in the door.
Now what about sentence?
Number three?
I worked as a movie extra just
to get my foot in the door.
It gave this individual more
opportunities to get better jobs,
better acting jobs, make sense.
Right.
Okay.
So one more time after me, we have.
A foot in the door.
Excellent.
All right, now let's go to idiom.
Number two, here we go.
A shot in the dark.
Excellent.
One more time after me a shot in the dark.
Good job.
Now, a shot in the dark just
means an attempt that has very
little chance for success.
Now, let me tell you a quick story
that will help you understand this.
So, you know, I am a woman.
I look very young though.
I'm a woman that looks very
young, but I actually I'm a
little older than you think.
So one day I was hanging out with some
friends and there was a young man who was
very handsome, but he was in his twenties.
Now, he assumed I was in my twenties.
So he approached me and
kind of made a pass at me.
He was trying to say,
Hey, I'm interested now.
Here's the thing.
I was not in my twenties.
I was well in my thirties.
So his attempt was a shot in the dark.
There was no way he would succeed in
dating me because he was too young.
Makes sense.
Right.
Again, it was a shot in the dark.
There's very little chance.
Honey.
You're too young for me.
That's the main idea you get it.
All right.
So we say a shot in the dark.
So let me tell you some example sentences.
Here we go.
You can look for your key on the
beach, but that's a shot in the dark.
Very hard to find your keys in the midst
of all that sand, a shot in the dark.
It's starting to make sense, right?
Okay.
Let's go to sentence.
Number two.
The figure he came up with
was really a shot in the dark.
Like, come on that that's not
realistic, a shot in the dark.
And finally sentence number
three, it was a shot in the dark.
I can't believe I was right.
So this person thought that
there were little chances of
them being correct or succeeding.
Oh, my goodness.
They were right.
So in English we say a shot in the dark.
So one more time after
me a shot in the dark.
Excellent.
Now a quiz is coming, so
keep paying attention.
I want you to ACE the quiz.
Here we go.
Let's go to idiom number three,
allow the dust to settle.
Allow the dust to settle.
Excellent.
Now you're probably wondering
teacher, what is this about dust?
Let me explain.
So allow the dust to settle means to
allow a situation to become normal again.
So this is what I want
you to imagine right now.
Close your eyes.
Just listen to my voice.
Imagine that there was
a rug on the ground.
And that rug was full of dust and dirt.
So you go and you walk up to the
rug and you pick it up and you
shake it to get the dust out of
the rug right now, what happens?
The dust gets all in the air and now it's
hard to see and you have to pause and
wait a minute for the dust to settle.
You have to wait for the
situation to become normal again.
It makes sense, right?
You kind of visualize now.
Oh yes.
The dust in the air.
You need to wait for it to leave the air.
So the same idea goes for this
idiom, allow the dust to settle.
So let's look at some examples
sentences that will help you
understand this a little bit more.
First one, I'm going to
allow the dust to settle.
Before I try talking to her again,
that means something happened.
There was a challenge or an issue,
and now things are a little bit
strange, like that dust in the air.
And you want things to go back to normal.
Hey, I'm going to let the dust settle
before I tried talking to her again.
Makes sense, right?.
You're seeing it now, even visually.
Right.
. All right, so let's check
out sentence number two here.
My mom said I needed to
allow the dust to settle.
Before I ask my dad to adopt a dog.
Makes sense.
Ooh, wait a second.
Let things go back to normal.
Before you ask your dad for a dog.
All right, here we go.
Sentence.
Number three, she waited
for the dust to settle.
Then began to express her feelings to her.
Fiance.
Makes sense again, waiting
until things go back to normal.
Before you do something in English,
the idiom is allow the dust to settle.
Make sense?
You're smart.
Here we go.
Let's keep going to idiom number four.
So again, we had idiom number three.
Let's move on to idiom.
Number four, here we go.
Back against the wall.
Wait a minute, teacher, what does that
mean to have your back against the wall?
Now this means to be in a very
bad situation or position,
a very bad situation.
So let me tell you really quickly when
I had my back against the wall, you see
I've been teaching for a long time, but
at the very beginning of my business,
when I started, I didn't have any.
My credit card was maxed out.
So my back was against the wall.
I had to figure out how
to bring in more money.
Again, I had my back against the wall.
I was in a bad situation.
Makes sense, right?
Maybe you've been in a bad situation.
You had your back against the wall.
Make sense?
All right.
Let's check out some example sentences.
Here we go.
The lawsuit had him with
his back against the wall.
Makes sense.
All right.
Sentence, number two, we had
our backs against the wall, but
somehow we managed to win the game.
Makes sense.
Right?
All right, here we go.
Now again, all of these
examples you can find.
If you go to my website,
SpeakEnglishWithTiffani.com and go to
the section that has the YouTube lesson.
So don't worry.
You can see all of these
examples sentences.
Here we go.
I was in a foreign country without a
phone and my back was against the wall.
It makes sense, right?
That's a horrible situation
to be in overseas in a foreign
country without a phone.
Your back will be against the wall.
Makes sense.
You're smart.
All right, now let's go to our next idiom.
Here we go.
Let's go to idiom.
Number five.
Remember your quiz is coming up.
So I hope you are paying attention.
Here we go.
Idiom.
Number five, barking up the wrong tree.
Good one more time after me
barking up the wrong tree.
Excellent.
Now this just means to pursue, to
move forward on a mistaken line
of thought or course of action.
It's like, Ooh, I don't think that's the
way you want to go or I don't think that's
the direction we're trying to go in.
You are barking up the wrong tree.
All right.
Now again, these idioms.
Oh my goodness.
We use them all the time.
So I get excited because I want you to
sound more like a native English speaker.
So here we go.
Let's look at some example,
sentences, sentence.
Number one.
If he thinks I'm paying for him,
he's barking up the wrong tree.
Now this is something that a
woman can say on the first date.
You know, they'd go out to dinner.
Candle light, beautiful restaurant.
The meal comes, oh, it looks delicious.
And when the meal is over, the bill
comes and the guy looks at her and
she looks at the guy and she says,
oh, he thinks I'm paying for him.
No, no.
He's barking up the wrong tree.
Makes sense.
Right?
Oh, that's the wrong train of thought.
That's the wrong idea.
We say barking up the wrong tree.
I think some ladies understood that one.
Here we go.
Sentence.
Number two, she's barking
up the wrong tree.
If she thinks that will solve the
problem, she has the wrong idea.
That's not going to solve anything.
She's barking up the wrong tree.
Makes sense.
Right?
I know you're taking notes
and I'm so proud of you.
Here we go.
Last example, sentence.
The investors kept
barking up the wrong tree.
Hey guys, come on.
This is not the right direction.
You guys are barking up.
The wrong tree.
Makes sense, right.
Again, barking up the wrong tree.
All right now real quick.
Before we have our quiz, I want
to go over them real quick.
Before our quiz.
I want you to ACE the quiz foot in
the door, giving an opportunity.
Number two shot in the dark and attempt
that has little chance of success.
Number three, allow the dust to settle.
Remember that one, let
things go back to normal.
Number four, back against the wall to
be in a very bad situation and number
five, barking up the wrong tree.
Hey, that's a mistake.
That's not the right way to think.
Are you ready?
It's time for your quiz.
Now you are going to have five
seconds for each question.
I hope you're ready.
I'm going to give you the
question you need to fill in the
blank with the correct idiom.
Remember you've learned them,
you know them, you can sound
like a native English speaker.
Here we go.
Question number one,
you have five seconds.
Here we go.
She doesn't like guys with long hair,
so I think you may be time starts now.
Time.
All right.
What's the answer.
Come on.
You know it what's the answer.
Yes.
Barking up the wrong tree.
Excellent job.
Very good.
All right, now let's go
to question number two.
Again, you have five seconds.
Here we go.
Question number two.
Her "blank" after she
lost her biggest client.
Woo.
Her blank.
She lost her biggest client.
This one is tricky.
You ready?
Here we go.
Five seconds.
All right.
What's the answer?
This one was tricky.
Her yes.
Back was against the wall after
she lost her biggest client.
Excellent.
All right, here we go.
Number three.
Now remember you have five seconds.
My mother was furious.
So I decided to, before I asked
for a new phone, what idiom goes
here, which idiom did we learn?
That matches this one, five seconds.
Here we go.
All right.
What's the answer?
Come on.
I know you know it.
What's the answer?
Yes.
Allow the dust to settle.
Excellent job.
Here we go.
Question number four, the project
was hopeless, so his suggestion
was really five seconds.
Here we go.
Time.
All right.
What's the answer.
Come on.
I know, you know it a shot in the dark.
Excellent.
Very good man.
You learned these idioms so fast.
All right, here we go.
And number five, last one who I
think this conference will really
help you get your five seconds.
Here we go.
Five seconds
Time!
What's the answer?
Yes!
Your foot in the door, man.
You are awesome.
Excellent job.
You did such an amazing job.
So again, today you learned five
new English, idioms that will
help you sound more like a native
English speaker, a foot in the door.
A shot in the dark, allow the dust
to settle barking up the wrong
tree and back against the wall.
Now, remember if you want to learn
even more English, idioms, and
sound like a native English speaker.
Remember to get this book right here.
I created this ebook just for you.
100 English idioms.
Download your copy.
Get your copy now by going to
the link in the description,
trust me, you are going to.
All right.
I hope you enjoyed today's lesson.
I hope you learn these
idioms and use them.
I love being your teacher and I can't
wait to see you next time, but as
always remember to speak English,
you still.
You know what time it is.
Here we go.
It's story time.
Hey, I said it's story time.
All right.
Now I promised you guys that I
would tell you the story about how
my internship helped me get a foot
in the door for my job at NASA.
All right.
Now.
So what happened was when I
was in university again, I was
a very hardworking student.
I actually paid my way through school.
I had three jobs when I was in
university because I didn't want my
parents to have to pay for anything.
So one of the jobs that I had when
I was in university was actually an
internship and it was connected to.
That's right.
My internship was with NASA and one of
their contractors, great internship.
I learned a lot.
Gained a  lot of experience.
So I, again, thought to myself, Hey, this
internship is going to help me get my foot
in the door so that I can get a great job.
So fast forward my senior year,
last year of university, and
we're moving closer to graduation.
But I hadn't gotten a job offer yet.
So I was getting a little nervous again.
I had worked so hard.
I thought I had done well
in my internship, but I
wasn't getting any emails.
I wasn't getting any messages
related to job offers.
So graduation day came, I graduated still.
No offers packed my things.
My parents came down to my university.
It was an Alabama.
Hacked my stuff, put it in the cars and
we drove back up to Maryland weeks, went
by about, well, two weeks went by still,
no offers, no emails, no phone calls.
And I was starting to get a little
bit nervous because I had worked
so hard at the internship, but
they weren't offering me a job.
So I said, okay, Lord, you know,
as you guys know, I'm a Christian.
I started praying a lot.
I said, maybe I have to look
for a job somewhere else.
So I started looking for other jobs and
I remember this, like it was yesterday.
I was walking in my house and the
phone rang; our house phone rang.
I walked into my parents room where the
house phone was and I sat on their bed.
I said, hello?
I said, hi, can we speak
to Tiffani Claiborne?
I said, okay, sure.
You know, it's me.
And they said, how are you?
I'm fine.
They said, you know, how did
you enjoy your internship?
And that's when I realized it
was connected to the internship.
So I got a little bit nervous again.
I still remember this, even though this
was literally 17 years ago, I was sitting
on the bed and my heart started to race.
I said, I really enjoyed the internship.
They said, yes, you
actually did pretty well.
I said, oh, thank you so much.
And I waited and I waited.
They said, well, Tiffani, um, did
you enjoy your time there a lot?
I said, yeah, I really did.
I enjoyed my coworkers and
what I learned and what I did.
I said, okay, would you like
to keep working with us now?
I didn't want to scream on
the phone, but I was excited.
I said yes, that that would be amazing.
I would appreciate that opportunity.
You know, when you're on the
phone for a professional call,
you know, you have to change.
That would be awesome.
I would really appreciate if you
all gave me that opportunity.
Meanwhile, inside my heart, I
was like, Jesus, come on now,
but I didn't want to do all that.
So I said, yes, that would be amazing.
Thank you so much.
So the phone call continued.
They said, okay.
So what we're going to do is we're going
to send you an offer via email and you
please let us know if that offer is okay.
They're talking about the month,
you know, the money amount of money.
My, uh, my I'm salary.
So I got off the phone.
Of course I immediately called my parents.
So of course I got a job offer again
with your family, you can be honest,
you know, the way you want to speak.
Right.
So I talked to my parents and then I
got the email and the offer amount.
I said, yes, Lord, the salary was good.
It was comparable for my experience.
It matched where I was going to be living.
It was amazing.
And then that moment I realized,
man, That internship really
did give me a foot in the door.
I now had a job with NASA
because of the internship I
had while I was in university.
I will never forget
the day the offer came.
I will never forget that day because
there were so many weeks and months
prior to that, that I just didn't
think I was going to get a job offer.
Maybe you've experienced
something similar.
You're waiting for a call.
Or maybe you did something that
you thought would get your foot
in the door for a specific job.
Then there was this period of waiting.
Now.
I appreciated everything that
happened during my time at NASA.
I loved the job, but as you all know, I
left and I became an English teacher, but
yes, hopefully you understood the story.
Hopefully you liked it.
And hopefully now you even
mastered get your foot in the door.
All right, guys, I will see you next week.
Don't forget to get your copy of
100 English idioms right here.
The link is in the description.
All right.
Love you all.
And I'll see you next week.