Hello, everyone, and welcome back to English
with Lucy. Today, I am going to talk to you
about my five tips for achieving fluency in
English. I know this is a topic that lots
of you are interested in. It does depend on
what fluency means to you. Different people
will feel fluent at different stages. So you've
got to define that for yourself, but I'm going
to offer you my advice today and, hopefully,
it will be a learning experience in itself.
I've created a free PDF that goes along with
this lesson. It's got the full transcript
plus key vocabulary that I have used throughout
the lesson. If you'd like to download that,
click on the link in the description box,
you enter your name and your email address,
you sign up to my email list, I send the PDF
directly to your inbox, and then from this
week onwards, you automatically will receive
my lesson PDFs for free. It's a free service
along with all of my information, offers and
course updates. Let's get started with the
lesson.
My first tip is possibly the most important
one. It is do not expect miracles. There are
a lot of products out there at the moment
that promote becoming fluent in 30 days. I
even saw a video the other day promising fluency
in a week. You've got to be realistic. Before
you do anything else, before you progress
with your fluency journey, get that idea out
of your head. Fluency is a marathon, not a
sprint. It's absolutely fine to sprint towards
certain goals, but make sure they are achievable
goals. Otherwise, you're just setting yourself
up for failure. Having learned two foreign
languages myself, I can understand completely
how frustrating it is and how much pressure
there is to get to a certain level quickly
or to pass a certain exam before a certain
date. Not everyone out there is a language
genius. Try and understand your own abilities
and your own pace of learning and set realistic
goals around that.
I ended up learning Spanish really quickly
because I had the golden opportunity of going
over there and living with a Spanish family
and having a Spanish partner. When I went
to learn Italian afterwards I was disappointed
because I learnt it much more slowly and I
didn't find it easy to get to a high level.
I had to realise it's not me. It's my situation.
So I set realistic goals around it and I ended
up doing really well in my Italian modules
at university.
Tip number two is learn efficiently and this
tip comes as thanks to the sponsor of today's
video, Lingoda. Now, whenever I speak to somebody
who is picking up a new language, I always
hear them say, "Yeah, I've downloaded loads
of language apps. It's going really well,"
but they never seem to carry it on that far.
I think that language apps are a great way
of passing your time and picking up certain
things and making a small amount of progress.
But I do not think that they are anywhere
near the most efficient way of achieving fluency
in a language.
This is where Lingoda comes in. They are an
online language school and they teach English,
business English, French, German, and Spanish.
They provide live online classes with amazing
qualified teachers in intimate little groups
so you get lots of attention and lots of feedback
and prices start at just €8 per 60-minute
small group class. The lessons are available
24/7 so you can always fit them around your
busy work schedule or your personal life.
Fairly often, I check into the Lingoda platform
and attend some classes just to keep up to
date with the school and see how everything's
going and I always have so much fun. Their
class booking tool is so simple to use and
the learning materials are amazing and you
have access to them all. You can use all of
them at any time and that is an insane resource.
If you want to boost your fluency with regular
structured classes then Lingoda for yourself.
Check out their monthly subscription because
they've got some amazing package deals. You
can sign up for a seven-day free trial by
clicking on the link below and using my code
LUCY30 to get 30% off your first paid month.
Let's move on to tip number three. Now it's
often said that in order to achieve fluency,
you have to focus on immersion. You have to
immerse yourself in the language. That's not
always an option for many people in the world.
Instead, I like to think of it as make fluency
a lifestyle choice. Do as much as you can
to immerse yourself in the language, but also
accept that it's not always possible especially
in a pandemic to travel over to a country,
give up your work, leave your family and spend
two months there to get fluent.
It's easy to compare yourself with other people.
For example, I always tell the story about
how I learned Spanish and it's frustrating
for other people to hear, "Oh, you got fluent
because you lived in Spain. So, of course,
you did, but what am I going to do?" The reality
is that before going to Spain I completely
immersed myself in Spanish whilst living in
England. It was my lifestyle change. I was
so passionate about learning the language
that I thought about it a lot of the time.
Spanish music, I listened to music, I watched
TV shows, films, I tried to speak with other
speakers of Spanish, I tried to meet as many
Spanish people as I possibly could, and I
spoke to them via WhatsApp, via Voice Notes.
I did everything I could to immerse myself
remotely.
One thing that I really like to get my students
to focus on is trying to think in English.
Take some time each day to really talk to
yourself out loud or in your head in that
language, no translating. Stop translating
in your head. Think in English or at least
try. For me, that was really the key to becoming
fluent. You may even find yourself developing
an additional personality in that second language.
This happened to me in Spanish. I've got English
Lucy in my head and I've got Spanish Lucy
in my head. We have different sense of humour,
we play with words and language in different
ways, and I am so happy with that. It's really
cool to discover that new part of yourself,
but you can only do that by really trying
to make it part of your lifestyle.
Tip number four is examine unique characteristics
of the language you're learning, English.
It's fairly easy to learn the basics especially
if you can translate to and from your mother
tongue. However, what really makes the difference
when it comes to achieving fluency is learning
things like phrasal verbs, idioms, humour,
really try and focus on those parts of the
language. Admittedly, they're the most difficult
parts to learn and that's why many people
don't achieve fluency.
Phrasal verbs and idioms are particularly
difficult because there are no real rules.
You have to learn them as you go. The best
technique I can think of is learning them
in context. If you are interested in improving
your phrasal verbs in English, I could always
look into developing something to help you
so let me know if you'd be interested in that.
In the meantime, I have got lots and lots
of videos on phrasal verbs and on idioms as
well. I have a place in my heart for idioms.
I absolutely love them in both English and
other languages.
My last tip is focus on pronunciation and,
in particular, I would say, focus on pronunciation
over grammar. I'm a pronunciation nerd. I've
never had too much time for grammar. This
is my personal view. I'm sure lots of teachers
may not agree with this but I think one of
the most important things is being able to
be understood. It's not about losing your
accent. It's about pronouncing each sound
correctly so that it's clear. That's why in
all of my vocabulary videos, I always add
the phonetic transcription. If you do not
know how to use the phonetic transcription,
I really recommend that you familiarise yourself
with it. I have created a tool on my website.
It's free to use, englishwithlucy.co.uk. I've
created the phonemic chart. It's got all of
the sounds that we use in modern RP and you
can click on each phoneme and hear me pronounce
it, and I've also got some words containing
each phoneme and you can click on those too
and hear me say them.
i:. No. eə.
Learn how to use these IPA transcriptions
because they will transform the way you learn
pronunciation. Once you have mastered each
sound in English, you'll be able to put them
together and pronounce things in a much clearer
way. If you're really interested in learning
how to produce each sound, then I also have
my pronunciation course, all the information
for that is in the description box, but it's
very thorough.
Right. That's it for this lesson. I hope you
enjoyed it. I hope it motivated you slightly.
If you'd like to download the free PDF that
goes with this lesson, it's got the full transcript
and I've picked out the key vocab as well.
All you've got to do is click on the link
in the description box, enter your name and
your email address, you then sign up to my
mailing list and every week you will then
receive my PDFs automatically for free plus
all of my news updates and offers.
Don't forget to check out Lingoda to claim
the seven-day free trial plus 30% off your
first paid month. Click on the link in the
description box and enter my code LUCY30.
If you'd like to improve your listening skills
and your vocabulary even further, then you
can try watching some of the videos on my
vlogging channel where I vlog my life here
on a farm in the English countryside. All
of the vlogs are made with you in mind. They
are all fully subtitled so you can pick out
that vocabulary. Don't forget to connect with
me on all of my social media. I've got my
Instagram, my Facebook, and my website, englishwithlucy.co.uk.
I will see you soon for another lesson.
It's nearly nine. I'm dying. It's just too
hot to film in the day. Is this on? Yeah.
Oh it's about to go out of battery at some
point. Let's get on with it. I pronounce things
in a much more clear way. In a much clearer
way. Hello, everyone, and welcome back. Oh,
I need to slow down.