Pull off, put off, go off, drop off, pay off! What
do all these phrasal verbs mean? Let's find out!
Hello my dear friends and welcome to English
mania! My name is Antonia Romaker and today
I'll teach you five popular phrasal verbs
with the preposition off. The
first phrasal verb is to pull off.
To pull off means to succeed in doing
something quite difficult or unexpected.
You want to run a marathon tomorrow!
Are you sure you can pull it off?
How long have you been training? You haven't! Wow!
I don't think you will pull it off. Who knows?
So running a marathon is a challenge and
succeeding in doing it would be quite
impressive. So a person would pull it off, succeed
in doing something difficult or unexpected.
My friend pulled off an incredible surgery!
So it was quite difficult, challenging
and he pulled it off, he pulled
off an incredible surgery.
I was so worried about my exam yesterday but I
think that I pulled it off. Reducing prices at
today's climate will be a difficult trick to pull
off. It will be difficult to succeed in doing it.
Reducing prices at today's climate
will be a difficult trick to pull off.
Pull off can also mean to start moving in a
car. Put the car into first and pull off slowly.
My driving instructor would say that to me
like a thousand times: and pull off slowly.
So you start moving in a car.
You can also pull off the road
and then the meaning is the opposite. It means
to stop driving, pull off the road for a coffee.
To put off can mean to delay an event
or an activity for a later time or date,
you put it off, you decide to do it later.
Never put off till tomorrow what you can do
today! Don't delay doing it, do it now. Never
put off till tomorrow what you can do today.
You shouldn't put off learning English any
longer, it should be your top priority!
The second meaning of put off is make somebody
dislike something or decide against it.
He's always smoking and this nasty habit of
his put her off, so now she dislikes him.
The next phrasal verb for today is to drop off.
It has two main meanings and the first one is
to start to sleep, you drop off.
The lecture was so boring that i started
to drop off. People can be really boring,
so you can drop off in the middle of the
conversation. There is one more meaning,
which is not that popular, to become less. So you
can talk about numbers or amounts of something.
Tourism has dropped off sharply in the last couple
of years. And the last meaning of the phrasal verb
to drop off is to drive somebody or something,
especially in a car, to a particular place. So
you take somebody or something and drive him
or her or it to a particular place. You are
driving me crazy! Drop me off at the nearest bus
station! So take me to the nearest bus station
and drop me off there. He dropped me off
in the middle of nowhere and drove away!
Pay off, it also has two main meanings, the first
one is to result in success, usually after a
period of time. Oh! I'm exhausted! I hope that all
this work will pay off! It will result in success.
I hope that all this work will pay off. If you
keep learning English, your efforts will pay off.
The next meaning of the phrasal verb to pay off is
to give somebody money that you owe them or that
they are asking in return for a favor, so give
somebody money and that person helps you somehow
in return. Do you think you should pay the
criminals off? I think you'll be sending
the wrong message. I would not like to be in
your shoes. It's your call, to your decision. So
make up your mind and do something! Do you
think you should pay the criminals off?
And the third meaning, which is not that popular,
is to take revenge on somebody for something.
I'll pay him off for treating me like crap!
And the last phrasal verb for today
is to go off. To go off can mean
to explode, if we are talking about
a bomb, or to fire about a gun.
The bomb went off at midday. Don't touch
the gun! Be careful! It can go off!
Speaking about an alarm, it can also go
off and it means to ring loudly to start
ringing loudly. Didn't you hear your alarm clock
going off this morning? Are you deaf or something?
And finally, the phrasal verb to go
off can also mean to stop working,
when we talk about a machine or a light.
The lights went out because of the storm.
Phew! Okay that's it today! We've mastered a
lot of phrasal verbs. To remember them better
you need to create your own examples, don't be
a couch potato! I hope that you enjoyed watching
this class and it was useful for you. If it's
actually true, don't forget to give me thumbs up,
it will mean the world to me! So please, like,
share, and subscribe, if you want to continue
studying English with me! And I hope to see you
soon! Happy English and Russian practice! Bye!