Hi. I'm Rebecca from engVid. In this lesson,
you'll have a chance to review eight common
English errors. So,
let's see how you do.
The first one: "Today morning I woke up late."
So, what's wrong with that? There is actually
something wrong with each and every one of
these. I'll tell you that in advance; there's
no... There are no tricks here. Okay?
So, what's wrong with that sentence?
"Today morning I woke up
late." Well, it should be:
"This morning". Okay? We
don't say: "Today morning".
We say: "This morning".
Number two: "What's the different?" What's the
different? Well, that's wrong too, because
"different" is an adjective. What
you want to use here is the noun.
So, what's the
noun of this word?
"Difference". "What's the difference?" Okay?
This is a really common error, so make
sure you don't make this one.
Next one: "I met John two years before." Okay?
What's wrong with that? Well, over here,
we can't say: "I met John two years before."
We can say: "I met two... I met John two years
ago." All right? If you use the word "before",
then you have to say before something. "Before
I graduated". Okay? "Before I got married",
or whatever. But you can't use "before" by
itself. So the proper word there is "ago".
"I met John two years ago."
Next one: "This is a six-months course." That
sounds almost okay, but it's not okay. So
the mistake here is
with the "s". When we use this
expression, it becomes... The entire
expression becomes an adjective for
the noun "course". So we should say:
"This is a six-month course.",
"This is a million dollar contract." And
so on. Okay? That's another... Each of
these is a different element of grammar,
different aspect of grammar, and so on.
Next, number five: "Thank you. I really enjoyed."
What's wrong with that? Well, the problem
is here. "Enjoyed" is a reflexive verb, so you
would need to say: "I really enjoyed myself.",
"I really enjoyed myself.", "He enjoyed himself.",
"She enjoyed herself.", "We enjoyed ourselves.",
"They enjoyed themselves." Okay? So there
are certain reflexive verbs in English, and
we need to use them correctly.
That's one of them. Very common one.
Okay, number six: "Did you loose your cellphone?"
What's wrong with that? I helped you a little
bit by actually showing you where the error
is. So, many people make this error. This
is actually a spelling mistake. You
should be spelling the word this way.
"Did you lose your cellphone?" "Loose"
is an adjective which means not tight,
and "lose" is the opposite
of "find". Okay? "Did you lose your cellphone?"
Also, the pronunciation is "lose" and not
"loose".
Next one: "This is an academic course.", "This
is an academic course." So, what was wrong
with what I said there? Okay?
So, what was wrong was my
pronunciation of that.
So many people mispronounce this word.
It is not "academic". It is "academic".
The stress is on the middle.
Academic. "This is an academic course.", "This
is an academic program." Okay? So, if... In
case you make that mistake. I'm not
saying you do. In case you do,
make sure you correct it.
Last one: "Yes, I
have a free time."
Is that...? What's wrong there?
What's going on? Okay,
here. We don't need to say: "A free time".
We need to say: "Free time", because this
is a... Time is an
uncountable noun.
Now, each one of these examples represents
a different aspect of grammar. So, how can
you possibly learn all of them? Well, I'll
give you two easy ways to help you out. One
is to go to our website: www.engvid.com, because
there, we have currently I think more than
700 lessons on different aspects of English
grammar and of English in general for exams,
for writing, speaking, all kinds of things. And
by watching them, you can find the lessons
that you actually need. And the other thing
is that we also have... I've written actually
a resource which might help you, which shows
50 such common errors that people make in
English, and that might
help you out as well. Okay?
So, I hope you did well, and I hope you
continue to do better and better in English.
All the best with your English.
Bye for now.