Good morning. Can I have
your mark sheets, please?
I'm Jane Allemano, and this is Radha
Roychowdhury. What's your
-name?
-My name is Rashid.
And what's your name?
My name is Gonca.
Gonca, do you work or are you a student?
I work.
Where do you come from?
I'm from Turkey.
Thank you. Rashid, do you work
or are you a student?
Yes, I work.
Where do you come from?
From Qatar.
Thank you. Now, let's talk about friends.
Rashid, how often do you see your friends?
Between five or six every week.
And what do you like doing
with your friends?
I like
my friendly, my friend
like to quite and
- I don't know what.
- And Gonca, where do your friends live?
In my country or the USA
and here. When do you see your friends?
Every day.
Now, Rashid, please tell me something
about one of your friends.
One, my friend
named
Ali Jabber. This is manager of insurance
company, yes? I know him
20 years ago. Yeah.
Where did you meet your friend?
In my company.
Now, let's talk about home. Gonca,
who do you live with?
In my parents, with my parents.
How many bedrooms are there in your home?
Bedroom? Four. Four bedroom, I have, we have.
Rashid, where do you watch TV at home?
Where? In living room.
What's your favourite room
at home?
You know, my country, you know, majlis,
meeting
all my friends and my father and my.
This is beautiful
beautiful room.
Now, Gonca, please tell me something about
the things you like doing at home at
the weekends.
I like have a breakfast with my family
and we have a big garden.
We grow some plants, and
that's all.
Do you like cooking at the weekends?
Yes, I like.
Now, in this part of the test,
you're going to talk together.
Here are some pictures that show
different places to eat.
Do you like these different places to eat?
Say why or why not. I'll say that again.
Do you like these different places
to eat? Say why or why not.
All right? Talk together.
Actually, I like this place to
eat because I adore eating.
with my family. And my son. Yes, yes. Yes.
And then
this picture is good.
- And this?
- Yes. I can see
- this family.
- a happy family, yeah
eat some food outside.
- In the park.
-Yeah.
- What do you think about this picture?
- This is desert
- I think, cook with grill
- Yes.
to put meat on.
These families, small family.
This is a restaurant, I think.
Maybe. I don't like
this same place because
- very noisy
- Yeah.
- for me.
- deafened me three times because
the high
noise. Noisy. Yes.
Do you think eating in restaurants
is expensive?
- Yes.
- Here, yes. Cambridge can be expensive.
Do you think eating
on the beach is fun, Rashid?
Yes, I think. Why? Because
I can cook anything in beach
and see them. Yes.
And do you think eating in the park is nice?
- Yes, nice.
- Why?
Because a park has different
plants and many tree and
sometimes quite place.
So, Rashid, which of these places
to eat do you like best?
This is best, I think. Because I can
talk with my family.
Thank you. And Gonca, which of these
places do you like best?
This is best, for me.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Now, do you prefer eating with
friends or family, Gonca?
Both. Why? Different things, I think.
Sometimes I want to spend time
with my  family, sometimes with my friends.
And what about you, Rashid? Do you prefer
eating with friends or family?
With family. Why? Sometime
I go with my friend
but every time with my family because I
went see my wife and daughters.
Do you prefer eating at home or in
a restaurant, Rashid? At home.
Why? This is, I think, healthy.
And what about you, Gonca? Do you prefer
eating at home or in a restaurant? Home.
Why? Because healthy and cheaper.
Thank you. That's the end of the test.
You're welcome. Thank you, too.