-Good morning.
Can I have your mark sheets, please?
I'm Claire and this is Sandra.
What's your name?
My name is Asia.
And what's your name?
My name is Vittoria.
Vittoria, how old are you?
I'm 12 years old.
Where do you live?
I live in Buccinasco,
a little town near Milan.
Thank you. Asia
how old are you? I have 12 years old.
Where do you live?
I live in Buccinasco near the Milano.
Thank you. Now, let's talk about food.
Asia, what did you have
for lunch yesterday?
Yesterday, I had meat.
What time do you usually have breakfast?
I had breakfast at today seven o'clock.
Vittoria, what do you usually
eat after school?
After school, I usually eat pasta or meat.
Who cooks your meals at home?
At home, cooks my sisters or my mother.
Now, Asia, please tell me something
about what you like to eat with friends?
With my friends, I like eat
the pasta and the fish.
Do you eat sweets with friends?
Yes, I eat sweet with my friends
because is funny and
I eat the sweet once a week.
Now, let's talk about clothes.
Vittoria, what clothes do you wear to school?
To school, I wear jeans and a t-shirt.
What's your favourite colour for clothes?
My favourite colour is black for clothes.
Asia, what clothes do you wear
when you go to a party?
I wear a dress and
jacket.
Who helps you to buy your clothes?
My mother.
Vittoria, please tell me something about
the clothes you like to buy.
I like to buy jeans and a t-shirt
and usually, I really like to buy a jumper.
Now, in this part of the test, you're
going to talk together.
Here are some pictures that show
different outdoor activities.
Do you like these different outdoor
activities? Say why or why not.
I'll say that again. Do you like these
different outdoor activities?
Say why or why not. All right? Yes.
Now talk together.
Do you like these different outdoor
activities? Yes, I really like it.
What's your
activities?
My favourite activities
of this is going to bicycle.
Do you like
ride the bike? Yes, I really
like it and I'm quite good.
Do you like
swimming in the swimming pool?
No, I don't
like it very much. For me, is bored.
Do you like going to concerts?
No, I don't like going to the concert
because it's very boring.
Do you like going to
the park for a picnic?
Yes, I like
going to the park with
my friends for a picnic
because is very funny.
What's your
favourite outdoor activities?
My favourite is swimming.
Thank you. Asia, do you think
skateboarding is difficult?
Yes, for me it's difficult
because is funny and dangerous.
And do you think swimming in
the lake is dangerous?
Yes, it's dangerous.
Vittoria, do you think going
for a bike ride is fun?
Yes, for me is
very funny with my friends.
Do you think having a picnic is boring?
No, for me is funny.
I usually go make
picnic with my friends or my family.
So, Asia, which of these outdoor
activities do you like best?
My best activity is swimming.
And you, Vittoria, which of these outdoor
activities do you like best?
My favourite outdoor activities of
this is going to the bicycle.
Can I have the booklet, please? Thank you.
Now, do you prefer being by the sea
or in the mountains, Vittoria?
In the mountain. I go to the
mountain every summer.
What about you, Asia? Do you prefer being
by the sea or in the mountains?
I prefer go in the sea
because it's funny.
Is it better to do sports alone
or with other people, Asia?
With to the people because
is interesting and funny.
And you, Vittoria, is it better to do
sports alone or with other people?
For me, with other people,
because it's too funny.
Thank you. That is the end of the test.
Thank you.