Articles
Learning article in short
Hello
And welcome to the next video
Today I'm going to teach you about
a very difficult
confusing
fun
maybe
grammar point
called articles
*wink*
Oh, really ? Yeah
Articles are confusing
there are many many rules
in english about articles
I do not have the time
the energy
to teach you all of them
but I'll do my best
Okay?
And
What are articles first of all ?
Articles are
A
AN
and THE
Articles come before a noun
A noun is : a person
a place
or a thing
So
I'm going to generalise here
and say that
before most nouns in english
you have to use an article
Of course there are millions of exceptions
to what I've just said
Sometimes we do not use an article with a noun
That's a whole other lesson
Hold the time warp for your brain
we're gonna stick to these ones
When to use A
AN
and THE
before a noun in a proper english sentence
We use these
when we speak
when we write
and they're very important in grammar
So
There's no way to avoid these
I'll help you don't worry
The first one is AN
AN's easy
It's the easiest we'll do this one first
AN
is a singular noun
huh
is used in the singular nouns
it's in article
and
we use it before
the noun that starts with a vowel
now
the pronunciation of this word
sounds like
va-will
the vowels in english we have five vowels in english
they are
A
E
I
O
and U
now
Everyone who speaks spanish
portuguese
italian
any of our latin american friends
or latin language speakers
you're gonna mix up these two vowels E and I
Let me teach you one thing that will help you
If you can remember
that you have to dot your I
you're gonna get the pronunciation of this word
so this word
or this letter sorry
When you write this letter
You always have to put a *ping* a dot
in the middle of the word
so you're going to remember that
this I
you can make a nice little EYE here
to help you
So, I
When you write this word
by itself you have to use a capital
so this would only be in the middle of a word
but the pronunciation is the same
I
So
If you have a vowel
A, E, I, O, U
that begins
the noun
you have to use AN
for example
"eye"
yey
We have to say
"an eye"
because the word eye begins with a vowel
If the word begins with
this word
with this letter I
for example "ice cream" yey
We have to say "I'd like AN ice cream"
Do you like ice cream ?
Or
If the word begins with a vowel sound
How can, what is a vowel sound Ronnie ?
A vowel sound is usually always
the letter H
for example
the word
"hour"
We do not even say the H word
it sounds like we're saying "our"
So
Because this word "hour"
sounds like a vowel because the H
is silent
We have to say
"an hour"
Ok, you got it? You with me?
"an hour" so
AN
We use before
a vowel
or
before a vowel sound
usually
a noun that begins with an H
The next one is A
The very first letter of our alphabet
A
is a vowel
Don't let that confuse you
A
We use
for again a singular noun
All of these are going to be used with singular nouns
If the noun is plural
if the noun has an S
Do not use an article
So
A
We use for a singular noun
in a general form
You can think of this
easier as
using, replacing it with the word "any"
So
If you go
to
a coffee shop
and they have
five muffins
and they're all the same muffin
You're going to say to the person that works at the coffee shop
"Hello"
"I'd like A muffin"
You do not get to choose
or pick
what muffin you get
You can choose the flavor
but you cannot specifically choose
which muffin you would like
It's the same
as saying "any"
It's like saying
"I'd like any muffin"
"Just get me a muffin"
"I want a muffin"
"I'd like anything"
"Just give me something"
Okay ?
It's used for when you don't care which one it is
You just want one of something
A
If my nose was stuffy and I had to blow my nose
I would ask someone
"Do you have A Kleenex ?"
I don't
have to go through the box
of Kleenexes
"No, I don't want that one"
"No, yes, this, no"
You're just gonna get A Kleenex and you're gonna blow your nose
Okay ?
So
A and AN
the only difference is
AN you use before a vowel
as an example
You can say
"I'd like
a
cookie"
I was going to write coffee maybe I want a coffee right now
but I would definitely rather have
a cookie
I don't care which cookie you give me
Just give me a cookie
I'm the cookie monster
Okay ?
So
"I'd like a cookie"
I'd like any cookie
The next
is
THE
THE next is THE
is opposite to A
THE
means something very very very specific
general and specific are opposite
this means
you actually choose
which one
you are going to get
Think about this when you go shopping
You do not walk into a store and go
"Hi, could I have a shirt ?"
"I don't care what it looks like I don't care how much it is
"Just gimme a shirt"
This never happens
Ladies
When you go shopping for shoes
You just don't go into the shoe store and say
"Just a pair of shoes please"
"Just a pair of shoes"
"Don't care"
"Size 8, fine, anything"
No
We want to go though all of the shoes
We want to try them all on
We want to get a handbag and match them
with our shoes
and choose
the shoes of our dreams
So you're not going to say "A pair of shoes"
You're gonna say "THE"
shoes
Another very confusing thing
about THE
is
the second time
you talk
about the same noun
in a phrase
you have to put
the second noun with THE
for example
This is a little more difficult
"I bought
some fruit"
Okay ?
"Fruit"
is an uncountable noun
If the noun is uncountable
we do not use an article
"I bought some fruit"
"THE fruit
was bad"
But Ronnie you just said
if it's an uncountable noun
we don't use an article
What are you doing ?
Have you lost your mind ?
No
This is a grammar rule
The first time I talk about the fruit
I use no article
because it's uncountable
but
the second time I'm talking about the same noun
I have to
I don't know why I just have to it's a rule
So I have to say "THE fruit"
"THE fruit was bad"
The third point
when we use the article THE
the article THE
I'm using articles all the time
is
when the speaker
and the listener
or the reader
whatever, if you're reading or listening
know
they both know
which
noun you are talking about
for example
If you and your friends
go to the same school
you have to say "THE school"
If I were talking to my friend on the phone and I said
"Hey, yeah, hum
Oh, I left my book at the school"
My friend and I both know
what school I am talking about
In my city there are 2,5 million schools
There's a lot of schools in Toronto
There are 2,5 million people
and a lot of people go to different schools
but because my friend and I go to the same school
I have to say "THE school"
"I'm going to go
to THE school tomorrow"
You and I both know we're talking about the same one
Okay ?
The next one is
we use with countries
but only 1% of the countries of the world
So I ask you
What country are you from ?
I am from Canada
We have listeners from all over the world
I would guarantee that 99% of you
would not use an article with your country name
I come from Canada
Below Canada there's a country
it's a big country called
anyone know?
Below Canada ? Geography time
The United States of America
or, shorter
the USA
A lot of people, their ancestors
in Canada came from a country
a group of countries called the United Kingdom
THE United Kingdom
hum
There's a country in the middle east called
the United Arab Emirates
If anyone from there ?
I went there once in an airplane
It's cool
The United States
The United Kingdom
The United Arab Emirates
All of these three countries
we have to use THE
because
there is the word "united" in the title
of the country
I do not say "the" Canada
I do not say "the" Japan
If the word has "united" in it I say "the"
The second one is
if the country has more than two words
in the name
you're gonna say "the"
for example "New Zealand"
New Zealand only has two words
I do not say 'the' New Zealand
If it has more than two words
I have to put "the"
in front of the country
The last one is the most difficult
If you are like me and did not do well in geography class
this one's hard
we have to use THE
if the country is comprised of
tiny or small islands
I do not expect everyone in the world to know
which countries are made of small islands
but to help you out
off the top of my head
the Philippines
if you look at a map
The Philippines has many tiny little islands
that make one country
another example would be The West Indies
The Canary Islands
these are all places
that have small islands that
form one country
So
If you look at Japan for example
Japan has
maybe five or more islands
but there are quite large
so we cannot use this as "the Japan"
They have to be very small islands
I hope you understand this
If you have a question please leave me a comment
if you need more help with this
please ask me
bye