♪ (AFRICAN HIP HOP
MUSIC PLAYS) ♪
Welcome to Black Table Talk,
the only place
on Tariq Nasheed's internet
where we can have
an honest conversation.
Today's topic,
"Women in the Workplace: Why?"
I'm your host, Dr. Haddassah
Olayinka Ali-Youngman, Pre-Ph.D,
and I'm about to take you
on the overground railroad to--
GABRIELLE UNION:
How long is this intro?
I'm sorry, I do not mean
to rush you, Queen Haddassah,
but Kaavia has me on a curfew.
See, see, see, no, no, no,
Gabrielle Union.
Black women babies are
not allowed to issue curfews.
Only our original kings
can do that.
You know, Supreme Rahmeek
told me to be home by three.
Ooh, is he here?
Can he sign a headwrap for me?
Unfortunately, no. He does not
fraternize with married women
except for me and all eight
of his wives.
Oh, that's very Doug Christie
of you guys.
Anyway, welcome to the show.
It says here now
that you're an actress,
an author, a television host,
a fashion designer,
-and a spokeswoman.
-Thank you.
Why so many jobs and how does
your husband deal
with this betrayal?
Betrayal? Uh.
I think my husband appreciates
a woman--
-Oh.
-I'm sorry.
- Female.
-Thank you.
. that makes her own money,
is incredibly flexible
and still is able to raise
a family.
I'm glad you said that.
Now, as everybody knows,
there are many factors
working towards the destruction
of the Black family.
Number one: wedge sneakers.
Number two: working women.
Aren't you at work right now?
(STAMMERS)
I don't get paid for this!
I have made no money
doing anything.
Now Miss Gabrielle,
let's talk
about your professional goals.
-Sure!
-. with your king, Dwyane Wade.
Oh shit! Okay. Uh.
How do you feel about your wife
out here working
like a free-range chicken?
I'm sure my, uh, cardboard king,
uh, would love for me to be home
a little bit more--
(SHUSHES)
Earth, let your god speak.
You know, my husband.
nay, god,
you know, he just retired
from the universe of the NBA.
Why would he do that?
Such a lucrative job.
You know, he's a little old
and he's--
How dare you speak about him
in that way?
I'm so sorry,
Cardboard Dwyane Wade.
Please continue.
But you know, I-- I have worked
my whole career.
That's the problem.
I'm actually fine being one of
the breadwinners in my family
Breadwinners?! Oh no!
White people got you thinking
bread is a prize!
Sister, may I call you Oshun?
As long as I can have
my hand back.
Oshun, this is not your fault.
Like Lauryn Hill, you've been
miseducated and you're late
to the true knowledge.
But we can get you back.
Oh, yes, All you have to do
is enroll in my learning center.
Is that-- is that like a school?
'cause you need to leave
every child behind!
-(PHONE PINGS)
-Oh, I'm sorry.
Did you just send me a Venmo
request for 58,000 dollars?
And that's just
the first installment.
For another 700,000,
you can become
a Founding Pharaoh
of the Dr. Haddassah Institute
for Elevation,
Conspiratization,
Melanization and Vitamins.
Vitamins? So you want me
to be a Founding Pharaoh
of your pyramid scheme?
No thanks.
But, but, but, see, see, see,
no, no, no,
with your tuition,
you will also receive
the singular, sacred text
that will help build your mind
to the ultimate level.
The Earth is Flat: And Other
Reasons You Shouldn't Vote.
But people should vote.
Why? Cast a ballot?
Think about it:
"ballot" is just two letters
away from "bullet."
They want us
to kill our community.
Ma'am, this is a takeout menu.
-But if you want to talk
empowering Black literature.
-Yes! Yes!
-Literature!
-Literature! Let's do it!
My New York Times
bestselling book,
A Woman Who Actually Farts:
The Freedom of Flatulence.
-Chapter one--
-Get it out of here!
You have disgusted me.
You never told me you
were literate.
This is a total abomination.
Until next time. This has been
Black Table Talk.
You didn't think I could read?
I had hoped not.
Explain yourself.
How much can you read?
The whole alphabet? That's why
you only have one husband.
I've had a couple.
You know what?
Let's talk about that.
(SOBS) I shouldn't have read
in that first marriage.
-Thank you.
-It was a book club,
-Queen Haddassah.
-Oh!
How many books did you get
through?
-Dozens.
-(GASPS)