Hi guys welcome back to Emma´s Easy
English, the Youtube channel where
you can learn English in a fast, fun and
free way! Please remember to like, subscribe,
comment and share my videos, I really appreciate
it. And be sure to check out my Instagram page,
okay, where you can get lots of tips,
tricks and help with your English learning.
Now, today is an easy lesson, okay, maybe this is
for your more beginner learners of English. But
even if you are intermediate or advanced, this is
still a great catch-up lesson to remind you to use
adverbs of frequency in the correct way. So today
our video is about adverbs of frequency. Now,
maybe this sounds a bit complicated, adverbs of
frequency, but it is very, very easy. Okay today I
am teaching you six key words so that you can talk
about adverbs of frequency. So what does this mean
adverbs of frequency? Well it means how often we
do something, how many times do we do something.
Okay so the first word we are
going to learn is always. Always.
Now this is the highest frequency that
you can do something. For example,
I always drink coffee in the morning. This means
every single day. Every morning I drink my coffee.
Always. Okay and be careful with the position
of your adverb in your sentence. Listen to me.
I always drink coffee. So the adverb goes between
the subject and the verb. I always drink. Okay,
but be careful when you use the verb
to be. As I'm sure you already know
the verb to be is a bit special, it doesn't
follow all the rules like the other verbs
so when you want to use the verb to be,
your position of your adverb changes.
For example I am always happy. I am always
happy. So this time we have subject, verb,
adverb. Okay we have switched the adverb and
the verb around. Okay so I always drink. I
am always happy. Okay so far so good?
Let's learn the next verb of frequency.
So the next level down is when you almost always
do something but not always. And this word is
usually. Usually. So this is almost
always but not every single time.
For example, I usually go to the gym. I usually
go to the gym. This means I go to the gym
almost every day, but maybe there are one
or two days that I don't go to the gym.
I usually go. And remember with the verb to
be it changes, okay, I am usually on time. I
am usually on time. Not always, maybe one or two
times I am late, but usually I am on time, okay?
Okay, next adverb of frequency, next level
down, this is when you do something a lot
but it's just not as much as always or
usually, okay, and this word is often.
Often. I often walk in the park. I often walk in
the park. Okay, this means, I don't know, maybe
three times a week, four times a week, sort
of in the middle. I often go. Not always,
not usually, but often, many times. And again
remember with the verb to be. I am often tired.
I am often tired. The next adverb of frequency is
sometimes. Sometimes. So this is sometimes I do
sometimes I don't, it's completely in the middle.
Sometimes. For example, she sometimes studies. She
sometimes studies. She doesn't always study,
she doesn't even study most days, sometimes,
maybe two or three times a week, sometimes, when
she wants to, we don't know when. Sometimes, okay.
And again with the verb to be, the same as
all of them, she is sometimes lazy. Okay,
she sometimes studies. She is sometimes lazy.
Okay, be careful with the position of the adverb,
okay. All right, next adverb
of frequency is hardly ever.
Hardly ever. So this is almost never, but maybe
one time a month. One time a month. For example,
I hardly ever go to the cinema.
I hardly ever go to the cinema,
maybe I go to the cinema once a month or once a
year even, I hardly ever, once every now and then.
And again with the verb to be the same as all of
the others, it's super easy to follow the rule.
I am hardly ever late. I am hardly ever late.
Maybe one time I am late, but usually no,
I am hardly ever late. Okay, it's super easy
right? With every single adverb frequency
it's the same pattern and the same rule for the
verb to be. Okay, super easy, you still with me?
We have one more adverb of frequency and it is
the adverb never. Never. So this is the opposite
of always. Always is every single time and never
is no times. Never. For example, he never goes
swimming. He never goes swimming. Not once
a week, not once a month, not once a year.
Never. He never goes swimming, not once. Okay and
again with the verb to be, the same as all of the
others. He is never sad. He is never sad. Not
sometimes, not often, never. He is never sad,
which is the same as saying the opposite. He
is always happy, okay. He is always happy.
He is never sad. Okay so adverbs of frequency are
super simple and easy to put into your sentences,
but they lift up your english level, okay, to
make it even more complex, complete and like
a native English speaker. Okay so now it's your
turn. In the comments below you have to put some
sentences using adverbs of frequency.You
tell me what do you always do? What do you
sometimes? Do what do you never do? Okay, make
some sentences and put them in the comments below.
Okay, so I hope you liked this video, please
give it a thumbs up and subscribe to my channel.
Remember to check out my Instagram
for more English tips and tricks
and please check out my website which i shall put
here where you can book private classes with me,
private classes or group classes, whatever
you decide, okay. I have conversation classes
and exam preparation classes, okay,
so be sure to check out my website and
contact me if you want any classes with me.
Okay, and very soon my website will also have
some English challenges for you to take part in
okay, so stay tuned and take a look at my website
okay. Thanks so much for watching, I hope
you liked it and see you again next time
for another English lesson with Emma's
Easy English. See you next time, bye!
you