What would I do without your smart mouth?
Drawing me in, and you kicking me out.
You got my head spinning, no kidding.
I can't pin you down.
What's going on in that beautiful mind?
I'm on your magical, mystery ride.
And I'm so dizzy,
Don't know what hit me,
But I'll be alright.
My head's under water, but I'm breathin' fine.
You're crazy, and I'm out of my mind.
'Cause all of me, loves all of you.
Love your curves and all your edges,
All your perfect imperfections.
Give your all to me,
I give my all to you.
You're my end and my beginning,
Even when I lose I'm winning.
Cause I give you all of me,
And you give me all of you.
(Oh)
How many times do I have to tell you -
Even when you're crying, you're beautiful too.
The world is beating you down, I'm around through every move.
You're my downfall,  you're my muse.
My worst distraction, my rhythm and blues.
I can't stop singing, it's ringing in my head for you.
My head's under water, but I'm breathin' fine.
You're crazy and I'm out of my mind.
'Cause all of me, loves all of you -
Love your curves and all your edges,
All your perfect imperfections.
Give your all to me, I'll give my all to you.
You're my end and my beginning,
Even when I lose I'm winning.
'Cause I give you all of me,
And you give me all of you.
(Oh)
You give me all of you. (Oh)
Cards on the table, we're both showing hearts.
Risking it all, though it's hard.
'Cause all of me, loves all of you.
Love your curves and all your edges,
All your perfect imperfections.
Give your all to me, I'll give my all to you.
You're my end and my beginning,
Even when I lose, I'm winning.
'Cause I give you all of me, and you give me all of you.
I give you all of me,
And you give me all of you, oh.
...
Hey guys! Thanks for watching.
And that was the amazing John Legend that you just saw.
And he just released his new album,
So go check out his album -
You can find the link in the description below for that!
And also, I just re-released
A deluxe edition of my album, and it's got cool new bonus tracks on it.
So you can get that on iTunes, Amazon, and in-store!
So - I'm really excited about that,
See description for more details.
And you guys know I love you -
So keep spreading the Lindsey love, and more will come soon :) *Clicks tounge*