Two magical words to express
you’re grateful because someone has
given you something or done
something for you, thank you.
Hello, hello guys, have you
ever wondered if there are
more alternatives to thank you?
Well, there are.
Today we’ll be checking
some expressions to show
gratitude and different ways
to respond to the words thank you.
First thoughts on how
to show gratitude will
naturally be thank you,
thanks a lot, thanks a ton,
thank you very much.
But you can also say
will you do that for me,
I really appreciate it.
I can’t believe you found them you rock.
Hey, guess what, I got in,
I couldn’t have done it without you.
Hey, this is for you, oh you shouldn’t have.
Hey Maria, I was printing my work
and I thought about you, here’s yours.
Hey, that’s so kind of you.
Oh my gosh, this painting looks great,
how can I show you how grateful I
am?
I bet the traditional way to
respond to thank you was one of
the first expressions
you learned in English,
but have you thought about
these alternatives before?
Okay guys, for this part of
the video I need your help,
the characters will
say the orange sentences,
which are the expressions to thank.
And you will be in charge
of reading the pink ones,
which are the expressions
to respond to thank you.
Will you do that for me?
I’d really appreciate it.
No problem. Will you do that for me?
I’d really appreciate that.
No worries. Hey guess what? I got in.
I couldn’t have done it without you.
Oh, don’t mention it, congratulations.
Hey, that’s so kind of you.
Any time. Hey man, thank you.
Sure.
Guys, do you know any other expressions
to thank or respond to thank you?
Share them in the comments below
and also let me know which other
kind of expressions you would
like to learn in future videos.
Bye.