You're learning English,
everyone else who's watching
this video is learning English,
so it might be cool
if we could find out what
everyone is listening to,
what everyone is reading,
what everyone is watching
in order to improve their
grasp of the English language.
So in this video, I'm
going to do two things.
I'm going to share with you the song
that I'm currently listening to,
the book that I'm currently reading,
the TV show that I'm currently watching,
and the most recent movie that I've seen,
and then I would like you to do the same.
I would like you,
there'll be a link, by the way,
in the description, to a Google form,
I would love it if you could share with us
the English song that you
are currently listening to
to help you understand English.
What's the English book that
you are currently reading?
What's the English TV show that
you are currently watching?
And what movie did you watch in English
just a few days ago or a week ago?
I will take all that information
and I will put it together in
some nice charts and graphs
and I'll make another video in a week
where I'll show you the results
and then you'll know
what all the other English
learners are doing,
or at least you'll know what
the most popular song is,
the most popular book,
the most popular TV show,
and the most popular movie.
So stick around, I'll share
with you what I'm doing,
and then I'll ask you what you're doing.
(upbeat music)
Let's start by talking about songs.
Songs are one of the best
ways to learn a language
because it's so easy to listen to a song
over and over again.
If a song is really good,
you never get bored of it.
You just enjoy listening to it 10 times
or 50 times or 100 times.
The song that I'm currently listening to
is "Save Your Tears" by The Weeknd.
In particular, I really like the version
where Ariana Grande sings along with him.
It's a really cool song.
I think it's actually a good
song for English learners
because it's very easy
to understand The Weeknd
when he sings.
So that's currently my favorite song.
It's great, it has a nice
melody, I just really enjoy it.
So what song are you
currently listening to?
Remember, I wanna collect
information in this video,
so please let us know.
There's a form linked in
the description below.
You can tell me in the
comments if you want
but it will be better for everybody
if you click that link,
fill out that form,
and tell us what song are
you currently listening to
to help improve your English?
I'm curious and I think
everyone else is as well.
Let's talk a little bit about books.
Books are an amazing
way to learn a language,
I think for two reasons,
in my humble opinion.
The first reason I think books are amazing
is because you can read
a book at your own speed.
You can read it quickly or slowly
and you can even reread
parts of it if you want to.
That makes books kind of unique.
The second thing I really like about books
when learning a language
is I think it's the best
way, for me at least,
to learn new vocabulary.
It's really cool, when you read a book,
to learn one or two
new words on every page
or in every paragraph.
So those are the two reasons
I think books are a cool
way to learn a language.
But what am I reading?
I am currently reading a book
called "The Humans" by Matt Haig.
It is a science fiction book.
It is about an alien who
comes to the planet Earth
and kind of takes over
the life of a human being
and starts to live as a human.
He changes so he looks like a human
and then he lives as a human being.
I don't wanna give away too many spoilers
but it's an interesting book
because you get to see
what humans are like
from a nonhuman perspective,
so I'm quite entertained by it.
So that's the book I'm reading.
It's called "The Humans" by Matt Haig,
but I'm curious to know,
and I think everyone else is
as well, what you're reading.
So please let us know
what book you're reading.
And I'm curious to see which
book is the most popular.
It should be interesting.
Let's talk a little bit about TV shows.
TV shows are a great way to learn English
because you can get to
know the characters.
Maybe the show you are
watching has multiple seasons.
There's season one and
season two and season three
and maybe each season
has a number of episodes,
maybe there's 10 episodes in every season.
This really gives you a chance
to listen to the same person speak English
over and over again.
You can really start to
understand each individual actor
and the way they speak English.
So TV shows are really cool
in that sense that you get hours of time
listening to the same
people speak English.
But what TV show am I watching?
I'm actually watching
a British crime drama
right now called "Vera."
It's in season 11, there
are 11 seasons of it,
and it's a story about a police detective
and she's very, very smart
and she figures things
out, not always quickly,
but she has a unique way
of investigating the crimes
and a unique way of solving them.
So the show I'm watching
right now is called "Vera."
It's in season 11.
If you are learning English,
if you're learning British English
and you want to watch a crime
drama, I highly recommend it.
Eleven seasons of listening
to the same people talk,
that would be really, really good.
Anyways, once again, I'm curious
and everyone else is curious
to know what you're watching
so please follow the
link in the description
and let us know.
Let's talk a little bit about movies.
One of the coolest things about movies
is that they are very immersive.
Movies are an escape from life.
When you watch a movie for an
hour and a half or two hours,
you can forget about all the things
that you're worrying about,
if it's a good movie.
Hopefully you're watching a good movie
and it's very immersive
and it allows you to just
forget about all of the worries
you have in life for a little bit.
So that's the cool thing about movies.
Awesome for you as an English learner
if you can watch something
that is very, very immersive
and helps you kind of forget
about the other language you speak.
But what movie did I just recently watch?
The movie I most recently watched
is a movie called "Free
Guy," starring Ryan Reynolds.
By the way, he's Canadian.
I'm not sure if you knew that.
A lot of the, little bit
of Canadian pride here,
a lot of really good actors
and entertainers in
the world are Canadian.
I'm not sure why.
I think it's because the
winter's so long and cold,
we have to think of ways
to entertain each other.
Anyways, back to the subject at hand.
I watched "Free Guy." I loved it.
It was very entertaining.
It is a great movie.
It's about a guy who actually lives
inside of a computer game
and I'm not gonna say too much more
because I don't wanna
spoil the movie for you.
But anyways, once again,
what are you watching?
Let us know, follow the
link, fill out the form.
I will put a nice list together in a week
and you'll find out what
everyone's favorite movie,
favorite TV show, favorite book,
and what their favorite song is right now.
Well, hey, thank you so much
for watching this little English lesson.
I hope it helps you to think
about how important it is
to read and listen to
music and watch TV shows
and watch movies in English
and I hope that you find
a way to do a lot of that.
Remember, if this is your first time here,
don't forget to click that red
subscribe button over there
and give me a thumbs up
if this video helped you learn
a little bit more English.
And if you have the time,
why don't you stick around and
watch another English lesson?
(upbeat music)