Work your ass off there is no magic pill. It drives me crazy to go to the gym. If you read one hour a day
I went and worked out five hours a day, and I was working on construction
We have 24 hours a day, organize your day, work hard
I'm here to talk about success
I went to college
I went and worked out five hours a day and I was working on construction
Because in those days in bodybuilding, there was no money
I didn't have the money for food supplements or anything. So I had to go to work. So I worked in construction
I went to college I worked out in the gym and at night from 8 o'clock at night to 12 midnight
I went to acting class
four times a week
I did all that
There was not one single minute that I wasted
And this is why I'm standing here today
At the age of 20 I went to London and I won the Mr Universe contest as the youngest Mr Universe ever
and it was because I had a goal
If you don't have a vision of where you go
And if you don't have a goal where you go, you drift around and you never end up anywhere
74% of the people hate their job in America
The majority of people don't like what they're doing
Because they are really not doing it because they didn't have a goal and followed this goal
They're just aimlessly drift around and then there's a job opening so they get their job because you have to work
But then when you work it's a chore
It's work
It's not fun
So if you think about only a quarter of the people really enjoy what they're doing in life
So people always ask me
When they saw me in the gym in the pumping iron days, they say why is it that you're working out so hard?
Five hours a day six hours a day and you have always a smile on your face
The others are working out just as hard as you do and they look sour in the face
Why is that?
And I told people all the time because to me I am shooting for a goal
In front of me is the Mr Universe title
So every rep that I do gets me closer to accomplishing the goal to make this goal, this vision turn into reality
Every single set that I do
Every repetition every weight that i lift will get me a step closer to turning this goal into reality
So I couldn't wait to do another 500 pound squat. I couldn't wait to do another 500 pound benchpress
I couldn't wait to do another 2,000 reps of sit-ups. I couldn't wait for the next exercise
So let me tell you something visualizing your goal and going after it makes it fun
You got to have a purpose no matter what you do in life. You got to have the purpose
Mohammed Ali
Worked his butt off
And I saw it firsthand
Now remember that there was a sports writer
That was there in the gym, and he was working out he was doing situps
And asked him how many sit-ups do you do?
And he said I don't start counting until it hurts
Now think about that, he doesn't start counting his situps and he feels pain
That's when he starts counting
That is working hard
And so you can't get around the hard work, it doesn't matter who it is
Work your ass off. There is no magic pill
There is no magic out there
You cannot get around you have to work and work and work
You have this make sure of that in order stuff. So it's work
And it drives me crazy when people say that I don't have enough time
To go to the gym
For 45 minutes a day and work out
Or to do something for 45 minutes to an hour a day to improve if it is physically improve or if it is mentally to improve
Imagine you read one hour a day
About history
How much you will learn after 365 hours.  in one year
Think about if you study about the history of musicians of composers how much you would know?
Imagine if you would work on the business and some business that you want to develop every day for an hour
imagine how further along you will go and get
So it drives me nuts because when people say they don't have the time. We have 24 hours a day
We sleep six hours a day. So that gives you still 18 hours
There's someone shaking the head out here in front to say probably I don't sleep 6 hours. I sleep eight hours, right?
Or just sleep faster. So we have 18 hours a day. The average person works around 8 to 10 hours
So, let's assume it's 10 hours so we have 8 hours left then you travel around an hour a day
Maybe two hours a day. So now you have still six hours left. So what are you doing with this six hours?
Maybe eat a little bit. Maybe schmooze a little bit
Talk a little bit to people and all that stuff, but you can see how much time is available if you organize your day
So you got the work hard
I hate Plan B
I tell you why
Because we have so many doubters as I've said earlier the no sayers
We have so many of those people who say no, you can't do it, that's impossible
That is okay because we just turn off as I said earlier and bees
Listen and be hear that no being a yes. You can't do it do it. You can do it and all that
So that that is possible to do that
amongst all the negative people around you but when you start doubting yourself
That's very dangerous because now what you're basically saying is is that if my plan doesn't work
I have a fallback plan. I have a plan B
And that means that you start thinking about Plan B and every thought that you put into Plan B
you're taking away now that thought and that energy from plan a
And it's very important
To understand that we function better
If there is no safety net because Plan B becomes a safety net. It says that if I fail
Then a fall and I get picked up and I have something else there that means they will protect me
And that's not good because people perform better when there's no safety net
People perform better in sports and everything else if you don't have a plan B
I'm telling you I've never ever
had a plan B I
I made a full commitment that I'm gonna be a bodybuilding champion. I made a full commitment that I'm gonna be in America
I made a full commitment that I'm gonna get in the show business
And I'm going to be a leading man. No matter what it takes. I will do the work.
I will do the work over and over and over, until I get it
The same as in politics and everything like that. So to me, it is very dangerous
to have a plan B because you're cutting yourself off from
the chance of really succeeding and the reason one of the main reasons why people want to have a plan B is
Because they are worried about failing
What is if I fail then I don't have anything else
Well, let me tell you something. Don't be afraid of failing
Because there's nothing wrong with failing
You have to fail in order to climb that ladder
There's no one that doesn't fail Michael Jordan said in one of his interviews
When they said "you're unbelievable the greatest basketball player of all times"
I mean tell me about that. And then he said "Well, you just mentioned the successes"
But he says "for me to become the greatest basketball player I missed"
"nine thousand shots"
"When I was playing basketball in the NBA games"
So during this games that he was so successful he missed nine thousand shots
Does it make him a failure? No, he is one of the greatest basketball players are four times, but he failed
9,000 times. Do you get it?
We all fail. It's okay.
What is not ok is when you fail you stay down
Whoever stays down is a loser
And winners will fail and get up fail and get up, fail and get up, you always get up that is
a winner
That is a winner
I failed in bodybuilding. I lost bodybuilding competitions
I lost powerlifting competitions and lost weightlifting competitions
I had movies that went in the toilet that were terrible. It got the worst reviews
And in politics, I remember I had many of the initiatives and the ballot
And we lost
My approval rating in California went down to 28% and
Then it went back up again and I won again the governorship
Hey, we all lose
If you all have lost as this is okay, and this is why I say don't
Be worried about losing because when you're afraid of losing then you get frozen
You get stiff you're not relaxed. You got to be in order to perform
Well in anything if it's in boxing or if it is on your job or with your thinking
Is only happening when you relax
So relax, it's okay to fail
Let's just go all out and give it everything that you got. That's what it is all about. So don't be afraid to fail