Good afternoon. Good afternoon.
Can I have your mark sheets, please?
Here you are.
I'm Susan Watson, and this is
Radha Roychowdhury. What's your name?
My name is Kenza.
Where do you come from?
I'm from Algeria.
Thank you. And what's your
name? My name is Mohammed.
Where do you come from?
From Saudi Arabia.
Thank you. Mohammed, do you
work, or are you a student?
I work in a Ministry of Foreign Affairs.
Thank you. And Kenza, do you
work, or are you a student?
I was a student, but I have
finished at university.
What do you do? Now
I have my own salon beauty.
Thank you. Do you think that English will
be useful for you in the future?
Yes, I think that English is the most
useful language in all of the world
because its permit us to achieve our
objectives
and to go further than we think.
Tell us about the people you live with.
I live with my family in my country,
and we are neighbours
and they are some of them
are cousin of us, of me.
Kenza, how do you get to work every day?
I generally get to work by car.
What did you do yesterday evening,
Mohammed?
I've been rather gathering with my friends
and we go into one Middle East
restaurant here in Cambridge.
Thank you. Thank you.
Now, I'd like each of you to talk
on your own about something.
I'm going to give each of you a photograph
and I'd like you to talk about it.
Kenza, here is your photograph.
It shows someone
getting information about something.
Mohammed, you just listen.
Kenza, please tell
us what you can see in the photograph.
I can see a lady which is maybe connecting
of a laptop
and reading on a book. He is
normally in a library or
I don't think she is at home.
Maybe she is preparing for an exam,
for getting more information.
Maybe she is revising.
That's it.
Talk about the place.
I can see that she is in a library
there are a lot of books,
and she is sitting alone.
As I said before, she's maybe revising or
preparing for an exam or presentation or
Thank you.
Mohammed, here is your photograph.
It shows someone relaxing at home.
Kenza, you just listen.
Mohammed, please tell us
what you can see in the photograph.
Yeah, I see one man, he's relaxing in his
sofa, and he left his mobile on the floor
because he didn't want to
distract by his mobile.
And maybe he's a musican
because there is one guitar
just next to him and
maybe he just come from outside and
he didn't take out his clothes.
He just start to eat and having one cup
of tea and relaxing in his home. And
maybe he's live alone because there's
no-one with him and his home is very tidy.
There's no toys for his
children or something.
That's mean that really maybe live
alone in his flat.
And I think that the weather outside
is cold because he didn't-- Thank you.
Now, in this part of the test
you're going to talk about something
together for about two minutes.
I'm going to describe a situation to you.
A local football club is celebrating
its fiftieth anniversary
and wants to give its fans a gift. Here
are some gifts the club could give.
Talk together about the different things
it could give, and decide which
the fans would like best. All right?
Now, talk together.
I think the calendar is perfect or
a t-shirt, because for me, the calendar
I can see my club every day when
I just checking the date.
I can see my club, and they are enjoying
by the fifth anniversary for the fourth
or fifth established for their club.
I think the t-shirt is the best idea. So
if he had the t-shirt with him, he
can always remember the team.
But sometime you can't wear
the same t-shirt every day.
But at least you have it at home and you
can see it even if you don't wear it.
And for this football, I think no, because
I can't play football every day.
If there is some students
or from their friends
they can't play and keep it away from
their studying or something.
I think it would be a good idea
for the balloon football.
Yeah. And for this, there, no, because
all, they have a lot of children
and from their fans, they can give it to
their children. Yes. For a book or album.
I think it's album for pictures.
For pictures. Yes.
Yes. It would be nice.
So that he can put all her pictures in
this album and he can watch pictures
whatever he wants.
And you keep remembering
your team by my, like, cover.
It's amazing. Yes. What about this bag?
What do you think about this bag?
I don't think that it's a good idea.
But it's useful nowadays.
You can use it for going to school
or for going to the gym.
You can put your toes.
Thank you.
Which sports do you like?
I prefer football. I love football.
My admire is football.
I watch it. I play it. I
am very interested about football. I
watch it from when I was child.
I rise with football. Yeah.
For me, is swimming. I love swimming.
I really enjoy swimming.
It doesn't matter if it will be
on summer or on springs.
I love swimming in the swimming pool,
but specially on the beach.
It's my favourite activity to do.
Yeah, swimming help me some time to relax.
Yeah. If I swim that I lose my weight
and like flying and, yeah, like
floating in the water.
Swimming permits us to be relaxed.
Yeah.
Why do so many people like football?
Because everyone can watch it.
And if you have one team in your, like,
hometown or your country, he won
a lot of competitions, that make
a lot of supporters, we can
if they have the same admires and the
same ambition about their teams.
And for me, it's the best sport. Yeah.
Do you agree?
Yes, I agree. I think that football is
an international sport in every country.
We can see that there is a lot of teams
which playing footballs. Yes, I agree.
Do you have a favourite sports team?
Yes, for me, it's the Algerian team.
Do you agree?
Yeah, for me, I have one football team.
It's from England. Manchester United.
I love this team.
I go to Old Trafford two times.
It was amazing.
Is it a good idea to join a fan club?
Yeah. To take in ideas and to keep discuss
about our team with what we miss in
on some positions, or if we need to have
a new players, we discuss about
the gomers, if they have, like,
one player that they decide to
have a contract with him. If he good
for this position or no, yeah.
What do you think?
I'm not for this fan club. Why?
Because I think it's a waste of time
and I don't have enough time to study.
So, I can't go to this kind of activities.
Thank you. That is the end
of the test. Thank you.