Good afternoon. Hello. My name is Jenny Cooke
and this is my colleague, Jill Budgie.
Hello.
And your names are?
My name is Victoria.
My name is Edward.
Can I have your mark sheets, please?
Of course.
Thank you.
Where are you from, Victoria?
I'm from Germany. I'm from the
north coast of Germany.
And it's very nice there because
I live close to the sea.
And Edward, where are you from?
I'm from Peru. I live in the capital,
Lima. It's near the coast.
First, we'd like to know something
about you. Victoria
how do you like to spend your evenings?
In Germany, I like to go to my horse
and now I go
to the gym or do something else
or spend time with my friends.
And, Edward, tell us about a festival
or celebration in Peru.
Well, in Peru, there is a lot of
festival. There is one called Mistura.
It's about food because in Peru, we have
a lot of very different kind of foods.
So, all that chefs
and plates goes there.
And there is a big festival in Lima.
I love it.
Victoria, do you use the Internet much?
At home, not really, but now I'm
in England, so I used to Skype very often
and to go, yeah
and look films at the Internet
or listen to music
more because I have more free time now.
Edward, tell us about a film
you really like. A film?
Well, I really like cars and action
so maybe Fast Furious was quite
interesting for me, the last one. Six.
I find it really good
because there is a quite expensive cars,
there are things I like. Thank you.
In this part of the test, I'm going to
give each of you two photographs.
I'd like you to talk about your
photographs on your own for about a minute
and also to answer a short question
about your partner's photographs.
Victoria, it's your turn first.
Here are your photographs.
They show people who are helping other
people in different situations.
I'd like you to compare the photographs
and say how important it is to help people
in these situations. OK. All right? Yeah.
In the first picture, I see a sportsman
a footballer, and somebody, I think he
has a cramp or something like this
and somebody helps him. In the second
picture, there's a policeman. The lady
I think she asks for the direction because
she's confusing in the city.
She's new or a tourist. I think
both are very important persons
because one has, in the first picture,
he has pain.
In the second picture,
she needs help as well.
So, I think that are both very important
persons for the people in each situation.
I think I would prefer to help
people who make some sports
because I'm like sports.
And it's really interesting to
see other people. And I-- Thank
you. Edward, do you find it easy to ask
for help when you have a problem?
Yes, I have an experience in London.
I was looking for a hostel, and I ask
ambulance for some special place
for a cheaper hostel, and they helped me.
Thank you. Can I have the booklet, please?
Now, Edward, here are your photographs.
They show people spending time
in different gardens.
I'd like you to compare the
photographs and say
what you think the people are enjoying
about spending time in these gardens?
OK. All right? Yes.
Well, in the first picture, I see a girl,
a young girl in a garden with
I think, a special plants there,
have a special care about them.
In the second, I think a big gardens where
people can go and have a picnic
or spend some time with family,
a time to relax.
I think, both cases, they are all enjoy
the things. In the first one
I think that girl like to
make these plants in maybe his garden.
Maybe she's going to eat them. In
the second one, they like
to spend time in the air, free air
or maybe free things
is good. Both are enjoying each.
Thank you. Victoria, which garden would
you prefer to spend time in?
I think I would prefer to enjoy in my own
garden, so in the first picture
because it is really enjoyable
to see the plants grow up
and which colour they have.
And so, I think it is nice
when you sit on the terrace
and have a look in your own garden.
Thank you. Can I have the booklet, please?
Thank you.
Now, I'd like you to talk about something
together for about two minutes.
I'd like you to imagine that a town
wants more tourists to visit.
Here are some ideas they're thinking about
and a question for you to discuss.
First, you have some time
to look at the task.
Now, talk to each other
about why these ideas
would attract more tourists to the town.
OK. Maybe we can choose one.
Yeah, OK. Won't we like to talk
about a building nightclubs?
What we think about it? Yes, maybe.
Nightclubs, I think are focus for young
people. I think that not young
people like to visit towns for
a nightclub. What about having more shops?
I think that shopping is a special thing.
Shops is, I think, as well, a good idea
because they can go with the whole family
or sometimes parents can go on their own
and the childrens are for their own.
But I think it would be nice when it is a
shopping area and not shops on the street
because when the children want to go
alone, maybe it is a little bit dangerous.
So, maybe we can be providing new parks.
Parks, parks. I don't really like parks.
So, because I don't want to have a picnic
in the park, but maybe it is nice.
What do you think about it?
I'm sorry, I can't agree with you.
I like park
because most people like
to spend time with their family
doing a picnic on the free air if it's
a good weather. So, maybe more tourists
can go to the parks.
Yeah. Well, but maybe we can--
what do you think about
building Holly's flats?
I think it is a good idea, but I'm not
really sure if everybody wants to live in
a holiday flat, but I think it can be
very interesting when it's nice
yeah, it's a nice flat.
What's your opinion?
I think that is not good
for tourists or for
the interests of them and putting
up security cameras also.
I think they are more for
people who live there.
Yeah, I think when I went to holiday and I
know there are still cameras around me--
Thank you.
Now, you have about a minute to decide
which idea would be best for the town.
OK. OK.
I think the shopping areas
is really nice because
the whole family has something of it.
I also think providing parks.
So, we have to discuss
which is the best one.
OK. Yes. I like parks because also
help for the weather and good for
the environment.
When you go to a new place
you also visit the parks,
that kind of things.
OK, maybe I would change my opinion
when I see a nice park. It's possible.
Yes? So, if we can find a new parks?
Maybe. I have to try it, yeah.
Yes. It was the best option. I think so.
But not about discussing the nightclub
or putting security cameras because they
are more for determinate kinds of people.
Thank you. Can I
have the booklet, please?
Thank you.
Victoria, do you think you have to spend
a lot of money to have a good holiday?
Not really. I think when you're well
organised and you look early enough
for something, it might be possible
to make it less expensive
to go on a good holiday.
So, it depends what I want
to do, but I try to.
What do you think, Edward?
Well, I think that is not good to have
a lot of money and spend on holidays.
I think the most important is the person
who you enjoy who you go with
on holiday so you can enjoy
more that place.
Edward, some people say
we travel too much these days
and shouldn't go on so many holidays.
What do you think?
Well, yes, it can be if you have
enough money to travel
well, it's great to go to
new places and visit new cities
and learn more about the culture, also.
What do you think, Victoria?
I think it's nice to travel a lot because
you can see more of the whole world
and from the culture and how
the people live. So, I think it's nice.
Do you think people have enough
time for holidays these days?
Well, it depends of the person.
Because a businessman is always
busy and have to travel a lot
but not for that kind of issues. He
have to make busy for other people.
Yeah, I totally agree with you.
I think sometimes it's difficult to travel
because you haven't got enough time
because you have to work hard
to earn money.  So, it is difficult.
Why do you think people like
to go away on holiday?
I think it's nice because you can, when
you're far away from your home
you have not any thinks about
your work and at your firm.
So, you are far away and you don't
care what's in your home.
Yes, I agree with you.
I have the same idea.
I think that when you go out of your
home and you can't relax because
you do a new things, maybe you can
try other things. So, it's interesting.
What can people do to have a
good holiday in Germany?
I don't know exactly, because I don't want
to make holidays in Germany because
the weather is all the time
cloudy and bad, but I like it.
It is nearly the same as
in England, I think. So.
And we have the sea, and so, they can go
surfing and you can visit small islands
and it's nice.
I think so. And in Peru?
In Peru, there are a lot of places you
can visit. There is Machu Picchu
very famous place of Nazca lines.
Also, Peru have a lot of beaches, pretty
beaches, where you can choose if you want
like the jungle or the coast. There is
a lot of places where you can visit.
Thank you. That is the
end of the test. Thank you.