- Ho-oh, oh!
Did you hear that?
Hold on I'm going back.
- That was amazing.
[laughing]
- I'm like in shock.
- She is my idol.
- Thank you so very much.
- This is the best day ever.
- Hi, I'm Billie Eilish
and You Sang My Song.
["Lovely" by Billie Eilish]
♪ Thought I found a way ♪
♪ Thought I found a way yeah found ♪
- Oh-ho, oh!
Whoa, that shit's crazy,
did you hear that?
Hold on, I'm going back.
♪ Thought I found a way ♪
♪ Thought I found a way yeah found ♪
- Whoa, God, that is so clean, what?
♪ So I guess I gotta stay now ♪
♪ Oh I hope some day I'll make it ♪
♪ Out of here even if ♪
- I have goosebumps.
Oh, my god, whoa!
♪ Or a hundred years ♪
- Something about the runs she did,
I feel like I've never
heard runs like that.
- Xae, come over, [laughs]
come over, let's write a song.
["Lovely" Cover by Xae]
- Holy crap.
- Whoa, God, that is so clean, what?
- Whoo!
- Something about the runs she did,
I feel like I've never
heard runs like that.
- Did she really, is this real?
- Xae, come over,[laughs]
come over, let's write a song.
- I will come over, I'm on my way!
Oh my gosh, this is crazy!
It doesn't feel real.
When I posted this I didn't
have the intention of,
oh I hope Billie sees this.
People were commenting under my videos
have so many negative things to say,
so coming from her, like it means so much.
'Cause I love her so much,
like it makes me feel better about myself,
she really like boosted my self esteem.
Don't care what anyone else says,
I'm just going to listen
to what Billie says.
Thank you so much for watching my video
and for saying all the things you said,
it meant the world to me.
I love you, I love the person
that you are, you inspire me.
I'm not gunna cry [laughing].
I had make-up on and now I'm ruining it.
["Lovely" Harp Cover by Arianna Worthen]
- I really have to say,
like harp is one of
the most beautiful instruments
I think in the world.
It like hits you in a different place
than I think anything else does.
Um, I almost cried did you see me?
Arianna, you have a talent and a gift,
that shit is rare as hell bro.
And you're killing it.
["Lovely" Harp Cover by Arianna Worthen]
- Wait, she saw my song, wait,
Billie Eilish watched my cover?
- I really have to say,
like harp is one of the most
beautiful instruments
I think in the world.
- This is so cool!
- God,
- No way.
- that's so impressive bro.
- She is so sweet, oh my gosh.
- I really hope Arianna knows,
how fire she is, that's beautiful.
- Is this real, oh my gosh!
That's incredible to have the
artist say such nice things.
I never thought she
would ever see my cover,
that just means the world to me,
so this is the best day ever.
It doesn't feel real
but it will eventually.
Billie, thank you so much
for watching my cover,
you are so amazing and
so incredibly talented,
and so kind, what you had
to say about my cover.
I never thought you would
see it, so thank you so much
for taking the time and
being who you are, thank you.
♪ Thought I found a way ♪
- Oh!
♪ Thought I found a way out ♪
♪ But you never go away ♪
- Bro, her vibrato is crazy.
♪ Oh, I hope some day ♪
♪ I'll make it out of here ♪
- Okay, these covers
and especially this one
is like making me think that
the song is actually pretty.
Because since it's my song,
like I'm so used to singing it
that I don't really hear
it like it is anymore.
But these are like reminding me of
like how beautiful it actually is.
Hearing these kids sing it, like
it's beautiful, but
they make it beautiful.
♪ Outside, I can fight my fears ♪
- She has really good pitch,
that is fucking crazy.
I mean, come on, Lynnea,
what I don't even have words.
["Lovely" Cover by Lynnea]
Oh!
- What the heck?
Oh my god, that's insane.
- That's so much better
than I could do it.
Dude, and she did the first
note, super low, like perfectly.
And then goes and does the most beautiful
thing I've ever heard, what the fuck.
- That's insane.
Yeah, I don't even know where
to go with that, that's insane.
- That's Lynnea,
I mean,
- Oh my god!
- come on, Lynnea, what?
- She said my name!
Holy crap, that was literally
the best moment of my life.
Just the fact that she
even said my name, wow.
I'm like in shock, this
is insane, I'm sorry.
'Cause I've loved Billie Eilish
ever since I first heard her voice.
To think like someone, like an A-lister,
has heard my cover and has
said good things about it,
I'm so happy right now.
I'm filled with so much joy.
Thank you so much.
I love your music, keep
doing what you're doing,
cause you're fricken sick.
♪ When you give me those Ocean Eyes ♪
♪ I'm scared ♪
♪ I've never fallen from quite this high ♪
♪ Falling into your ocean eyes ♪
- First of all, they both
beautiful as hell, what the fuck.
Look at, look are you kidding me?
♪ I've been walking
through a world gone by ♪
- They both have so much control,
that's a kind of a rare thing to find,
in like a good singer.
Is just like control.
♪ No fair ♪
- Man, that's also like, a
really hard song to sing.
When me and my brother
first like, made that song.
I could not get the timing right
and I pronounced all the words wrong.
I kept pronouncing napalm and naah-palm.
I was like naah-palm skies.
In my bedroom, I was sitting
on my bed and I was like,
not doing anything right.
I was getting all the timing off.
There's still, there's
like a recording of me
singing it for the first time, I believe.
♪ Those ocean eyes ♪
- Keara and Alyssa, both of
you have incredible eyebrows,
first off and your
voices are unbelievable.
That was beautiful.
["Ocean Eyes" Cover by Keara
Graves and Alyssa Baker]
- Stop.
Okay, wait.
- Oh, my gosh
I actually can't believe
that she watched it.
That's the first thing
I'm gunna say, what?
- First of all, they both
beautiful as hell, what the fuck?
- This is crazy, that's awesome,
she's so sweet, that's amazing.
- They both have so much
control, that's a kind of a rare
thing to find in like a good singer.
- It's kind of crazy to
watch her, watching me sing,
that's so surreal to me, ah.
- She seems to be really liking
it that's crazy, holy crap.
- Keara and Alyssa,
- Oh my god.
- both of you have incredible eyebrows,
first off, and your
voices are unbelievable.
- Wow, I wasn't expecting that.
- My hearts beating so fast right now.
- It's making me very happy.
- She's so down to earth,
that's what I like about her.
She's not putting on anything
she's just being herself.
Which is amazing and
that's what I try to do to.
- Also, I wasn't expecting
her to ever see it.
Like, when we posted it,
we just loved the song,
we were having fun, to know that it
got into her hands, and
not only that she saw it.
She thought that it did her song justice
and that she actually
thought that we were good.
I'm very touched, it feels really good.
- Damn, that's so cool.
["Ocean Eyes" Piano cover by The Theorist]
- Piano is like the first
instrument I learned.
I think piano and ukulele.
Honestly, piano is a difficult fucking
instrument bro, for real.
The Theorist, it's impressive man.
Talented as hell, what the fuck.
Damn, he was just playing the
piano like nobodies business.
["Ocean Eyes" Piano cover by The Theorist]
- Wow.
You're kidding.
- Piano is a difficult fucking
instrument bro, for real.
- Yo, that's so sick.
- The Theorist, it's impressive man.
Damn, he was just playing the
piano like nobodies business.
- Oh my God, this made
my morning, made my week.
Shout out to Billie, the fact
that she's watched my video,
I feel really, really grateful.
It just feels so refreshing
and inspiring to see that
she watched and listened to my cover.
It's so dope, thank you so much.
Holy shit, can't believe
she watched my cover.
That's amazing!
["Bellyache" by Billie Eilish]
♪ Where's my mind? ♪
- The way she hits that
last note, like, aw,
it's like you're like
reaching for something
and then you just like
pull away right then.
There's a taco bell burrito right there
and I'm like and that
bitch just floats away.
That's how it sounds but
in like the best way.
♪ My V is for vendetta ♪
♪ I thought that I'd feel better ♪
♪ And now I got a bellyache ♪
- Daisy, I'm just gunna
go home and take a bath,
listen to Daisy, sing me to sleep Daisy,
with that beautiful ass voice of yours.
["Bellyache" Cover by Daisy Clark]
- No.
- The way she hits that
last note, like aw,
it's like you're like
reaching for something
and then you just like
pull away right then.
- I'm like shaking.
- She has the kind of voice that you
just want to listen to.
- Oh my.
- That sounds stupid because
obviously that's what you
do when people sing, listen,
but the kind of voice you
just are like, I need to hear that.
- Oh I love her.
- You, Daisy,
Daisy has the kind of
- Wow.
- voice that I'm just
trying to go and listen to,
Daisy, don't stop.
- That was amazing.
I'm kinda speechless at the moment.
I was like shaking
through that whole thing,
I was like oh my god, what,
she's seen my face that's so strange.
To have someone that inspires me so much
and I listen to their voice so much.
To be the other way round,
just seems very strange
but incredible and I'm blown away.
What?
Thank you, thank you so much,
you've honestly just made my day.
["When the party's over" by Billie Eilish]
♪ Call me friend but keep me closer ♪
- I can see the way, like,
the emotion is just like,
pouring out of her,
like I can just see it.
Oh god.
She sounds like she's
hurting, like beautiful pain.
♪ Oh, I could lie, say
I like it like that, ♪
♪ like it like that ♪
- God, the rasp is so, oh.
And it's like so much more
than just singing a song.
'Cause you can have a beautiful voice
and there's no emotion in it
and she really just like.
Beautiful.
♪ Once we've both said our goodbyes ♪
- Abbey, dude the emotion
you have, oh my god.
I feel like I could like feel it
from wherever you were taking that video
I can like feel it, like
it's like, right here.
That's how it feels and that's like,
to have that element,
when you have any sort of
form of art, is like beautiful.
["When the party's over"
Cover By Abbey Glover]
- Feels weird that she's watching me.
- God, the rasp is so, oh, what the fuck?
And it's like so much more
than just singing a song
'cause you can have a beautiful voice
and not show any poise.
- That's kinda why I went into--
I sing more with emotion than I do with
making it sound perfect.
- Abbey, dude, the emotion you
have, oh my god, beautiful.
- Oh, this is lovely, I'm all. [laughs]
It's just really hard
to put it into words.
I put it up because that's
how I was feeling at the time.
The person that I was with,
pretending that I'm okay
with things just so that
someone stays but they don't.
I just wanted to get it out.
It's nice to know you're
not alone, feeling that way.
I never would have expected Billie to
watch that cover when I put it up.
Seeing that she has shows that
anyone could see what I do.
I feel lucky and special.
Thank you for giving me hope.
And making me want to keep going,
it's easy to feel discouraged making music
and I just feel so special that someone
like Billie has noticed it.
["idontwannabeyouanymore"
by Billie Eilish]
Violin cover by Wei Nin]
- Bro, violin is impossible to play.
I cannot play that shit if there was
a fuckin' gun to my head.
If you have to play the violin or die.
I'd be like, see you, I'm dipping now.
Wei Nin in Taiwan, that is impressive,
that is mad impressive.
I really don't know how you could do that.
["idontwannabeyouanymore"
Violin cover by Wei Nin]
- I'm always so impressed when
people can play violin man.
And also, it's sitting under your chin,
how uncomfortable, guh.
That's crazy, that is impressive,
that is mad impressive.
- I am very surprised.
She is my idol, I really
like her, so I'm very happy.
Thank you Billie Eilish,
you touched my heart.
Thank you so much.
["you should see me in a
crown" by Billie Eilish]
♪ Visions I vandalize ♪
♪ Cold in the kingdom size ♪
♪ Fell for these ocean eyes ♪
- Okay, already the fact
that she can play guitar.
Like, she's wearing a
Minnie Mouse shirt, right,
and she's playing the
guitar, that is hardcore.
♪ One by one by, one ♪
♪ One by one by ♪
♪ You should see me in a crown ♪
- That is badass dude.
Come here and give me a
hug man, you hardcore.
["you should see me in a
crown" Cover by Sophie Pecora]
- Oh my Gosh.
- Okay, already the fact
that she can play guitar.
Like, she's wearing a
Minnie Mouse shirt, right,
and she's playing the
guitar, that is hardcore.
- This is so cool.
- That is badass dude.
- I've watched these before,
where the singers react
to people covering their songs.
I was just like, oh that would be so cool
if I was in that one day
and I can't believe she actually reacted.
I'm such a fan of Billie like, I've done
so many of her songs.
I even wrote a song, like with her lyrics.
I used to do them on piano,
this is the only one with guitar.
I was a little more
nervous to share that one
'cause I never do it on guitar
but I'm glad she liked it.
Thank you for the compliments you gave me,
when you watched it.
Also, just thank you for your music.
It's just amazing.
♪ Bite my tongue, bide my time ♪
- Say what?
♪ Wearing a warning sign ♪
♪ Wait till the world is mine ♪
- I'm here, honestly,
I fuck with the vision.
He got a good head on his shoulders.
♪ Fell for these ocean eyes ♪
♪ You should see me in a crown ♪
- That is crazy, cause
like, that's eccentric,
like the good type of eccentric.
I'm sure people are like, that's weird.
That shit is dope.
♪ One, one by, one by ♪
♪ You should see me in a crown ♪
- Who's doing that,
Richie, bro, so many people
don't realize that art is not like,
how can I look the best.
That's so not what it's
about, like it's art.
You know I've always had
this thing, since like,
the beginning of when
I started making music
where I don't care if I look pretty,
I just want it to be artistically perfect.
You can already tell that
that requires so much talent
to be able to like sit there
and do every single part yourself,
that is impressive as hell.
["you should see me in a
crown" Cover by Social Repose]
- Aw did she react to it? [laughs]
- I fuck with the vision.
- Aw, this is really cool.
- Humans are so used to what we know
that when we see something
that we haven't seen before
we automatically feel uncomfortable
with it, which is stupid.
Richie, bro, that is impressive as hell.
- I'm happy that she liked it,
I think she is one of the few
that kind of fiercely is herself.
It's really good to promote
that kind of artistry.
Thank you so very much
for watching my video,
I really appreciate your authenticity,
your uniqueness, and just your willingness
to do things that people
may not understand
but we need you in this scene.
It's like it's all about
the art and the music.
Which is really cool.
- If there's a song that for you is like,
you hear it and you're
like, ah, this is my song.
That's your song then, I
don't wanna say it's my song.
Yeah, I made it, I wrote it, I sang it,
but it's your song, from here on out.
It's such a beautiful
thing that you can just
take art that was created out of love
from that person and love
it for your own reasons.
I love you guys.
[blows kiss]
[Piano instrumentals -
"Ocean Eyes" - Billie Eilish]