People in the North Kivu province in the Democratic
Republic of Congo have been returning to their
homes after Saturday's eruption of Mount Nyiragongo.
At least 15 people are reported to have died,
most of them scrambling to flee their homes,
following official warnings that many believe
came too late. Provincial authorities say
the death toll is likely to rise, as the situation
on the ground is still too chaotic for a thorough
assessment.
Aerial pictures show a trail of destruction
- a community overrun by lava from Saturday's
fatal volcanic eruption.
Hundreds of homes were destroyed in eastern
Congo.
People told of how they'd been forced to leave
behind their loved ones as the lava approached.
"I was with my husband, who's old and couldn't
leave the house because he was sick and couldn't
walk. I said to myself, I can't go alone.
I went back to at least try to get him out
but couldn't. I ran away and he got burned
inside."
"I was sweating, trying to lift an old man
who died in the end. I lost my strength when
I saw that the lava was coming."
Many more people are missing since the eruption.
The survivors left filled with uncertainty
about the fate of their loved ones and their
own futures.
There's been criticism of the authorities
for failing to alert residents.
"It's incomprehensible how with a respectable
and funded institution like the Goma Volcano
Observatory can fail to warn of an imminent
eruption, not even an hour before. It's incomprehensible."
And while the city of Goma may have been spared
- there's no question these villagers to the
east have paid a heavy price.