When was the last time you heard
someone describe something as the bee's
knees or when you heard someone
brushed off a topic as passe?
You're probably looking at me
right now thinking, uh, Annemarie,
what are you talking about? And
you would be right to wonder.
When my students talk about the
latest podcast or the coolest
Netflix series happening right now,
I typically hear the words
it's so popular and that phrase
certainly works. But when
we're talking about trends,
there's a whole world of fun
idiomatic language and slang we
can use.
Plus just like fashion or culture
or the latest Netflix series,
language also goes through trends.
A phrase that was popular in the
past to describe something that was
particularly cool or a trend that
was popular may be outdated now.
For example, to use the
expression, the bee's knees,
no one really uses that anymore.
If you don't already know I'm Annemarie
with Speak Confident, English.
Everything I do here is designed to
help you get the confidence you want for
your life and work in
English. In this lesson today,
we're going to have a lot of fun with
language we use for describing trends.
What's cool right now and
what isn't cool anymore.
By the end of this lesson today,
you'll be able to confidently
express what's trending right now.
And what's out of date using the
same expressions English speakers
use in conversations on podcasts
and on TV shows as well.
For today's lesson, I've divided up the
phrases into four different categories,
hot like fire, cool like
water, a trend, like a trend.
And eye-roll worthy.
[Inaudible].
First on our list is hot like fire.
English speakers seem to love
expressions that are rooted in nature.
And quite often,
popularity is associated with the
characteristics of fire. For example,
imagine you're at a restaurant and
you hear a popular song come on.
You might say to your friend, oh, I
love this song. It's so hot right now.
When we describe something as being so
hot right now we're expressing that it's
particularly trendy or it's something
that everyone loves right now.
Here's another example. Learning to
bake bread at home is so hot right now.
In other words, everyone's doing it.
In sticking with this idea of fire,
currently English speakers
may also describe someone or
something as fire, using it as
an adjective rather than a noun.
Now,
this is very much in the slang
category of language and is best
used in casual situations.
I also have to admit that
as individuals get older,
they're less likely to use slang that
is common among teenagers and young
adults. In full disclosure,
this is not a word that I use.
And I actually asked my 15
year old niece about it,
but you might hear it. So I want
you to know why you're hearing it,
why people use it. And if
you're comfortable with it,
you could use it as well.
So, as I said,
you might hear individuals
describe someone or something as
fire. For example,
your outfit is fire or the
new Mac book pro is fire.
This is an alternative way to say
that something is so hot right now,
or it's really cool. And while
we're on the topic of fire,
let's go over one more
great expression to know,
to spread like wildfire.
When a trend experiences,
rapid growth and popularity.
We say that it's spreading
like wildfire. For example,
imagine one of your coworkers is talking
about an app that everyone's using
right now. And in the conversation
your coworker might say,
I can't believe how popular this app
is. It's spreading like wildfire.
And with that,
let's move on to our second
set of expressions under
the category of cool like
water. Sometimes we catch trends right,
as they start. And when talking about it,
we may want to express that a particular
new trend is creating a lot of buzz or
excitement, which means that
everyone's talking about it.
But it's just at the beginning
phase when something is generating a
lot of excitement and growing rapidly,
we can say that it's making
waves. Here's an example.
Think back to a book series that you
love and you were waiting, waiting,
waiting for the author to release
the next book in the series.
You knew that it was coming out and
there were already some reviews about it.
In a conversation,
you might say the author
hasn't even released the book
yet, but it's already making waves.
We can also use this expression
of making waves when we're talking
about the ongoing ripple
effects of a trend.
A ripple effect is the ongoing
result of an action. For example,
if a company like Facebook
makes a new policy,
it's going to have additional consequences
or results for other industries and
companies as well.
There are ripple effects in a
conversation on that topic. Again,
you might hear the word making
waves. Let me give you an example.
The updates to Google's privacy
policy is making waves across
Silicon valley.
We have one more water themed
expression we can use when a trend makes
a particularly large impact.
We can say that it's made a splash.
When something makes a splash,
not only does mean that
it had a large impact,
but it also has the feeling
that that impact was unexpected.
For example,
the newest and youngest player
is making a splash in this year's
NBA tournaments.
Typically we don't expect the youngest
newest player of a professional
basketball team to have
the biggest impact.
So making a splash is a
great expression to use here.
It expresses that this
individual is trending.
Everyone's talking about this
individual and the impact they've
had was significant and unexpected.
And now category number three,
a trend like a trend. Of course,
when we want to say that
something is popular,
we can be explicit and simple
by simply saying that it's
trending right now or that
it's on trend. For example,
Olivia Rodrigo's song
is trending worldwide,
or it's on trend right now to
paint your home in earthy colors.
I'm curious if there's something where
you live that is particularly on trend at
the moment. It might be
someone's comments on Twitter.
It might be how you style your home or
something happening in the workplace.
I want you to take a moment and think
about what is on trend or what's
trending where you live right now.
Try using it in a sentence and share
it with me in an example, below.
And now let's finish with our
final category. Eye-roll worthy.
This last set of expressions
is perfect when something is no
longer on trend,
it has become outdated when
something is no longer cool.
We might say that it specifically
belongs to a bygone era and we
start that with: That's
so.  That's so 2020.
That's so early two
thousands. That's so 1980s.
For example,
I remember when I was a kid
in the 1980s and faded wash
jeans were so popular. Everyone had them.
And now when I see them,
I think, oh my gosh,
I would never wear those
it's so 1980s,.similarly,
if we've moved on from a trend,
everybody knows it's popular.
Everybody knows that people have been
talking about it and maybe you're
starting to feel a bit tired of it.
You could say that's so old news that's.
So yesterday or even that's ancient news,
everybody already knows about it.
That's ancient news. Here's an example.
The 2016 election is yesterday's news.
We've got to move on and talk about
the current events. And finally,
if we really want to express
our exasperations and the fact
that we are completely tired
of talking about something,
that was a,
then we can say I'm so over
that or I'm so over it,
I'm so done with that, for example,
I'm so over reading about
feuds among the Royal family,
or I'm so done with hearing
about zoom fatigue on every
podcast right now, and with that,
you have a plethora of ways to talk
about what's trending and what's
not in English.
And all of these are wonderful
alternatives to saying
that's so popular right
now to finish. I want to challenge
you with a couple of questions.
I've already asked you to
share with me an example,
sentence of something that is
trending, where you live right now.
And now I've got two more
questions for you. Number one,
what are you so over right now? Or
what are you so done with right now?
What are you tired of talking
about? And number two,
is there something that is making
a splash where you live right now?
Maybe it's something happening at work,
something on Twitter or in the news.
Again, I want you to tell me
about it in an example, sentence,
using the expression to make
a splash or making a splash
as always, if you found this lesson
helpful to you, I would love to know.
And you can tell me in
one very simple way,
give this lesson a thumbs up here on
YouTube and subscribe to the Speak
Confident English channel.
So you never miss one of my
Confident English lessons.
Thank you so much for joining me. And
I look forward to seeing you next time.