(upbeat music)
- Hello, everyone, and welcome
back to English With Lucy.
Today, I am going to be teaching you
all of the ways that you
can respond to thank you.
Now you're welcome or you are welcome
is a perfectly valid way
to respond to a thank you.
But I think it's a little bit overused,
especially by learners of English.
It's completely natural.
You find one way you like to say things
and then you say it again,
and again, and again.
The purpose of this video is
to expand your vocabulary bank,
so that you have many more
options when somebody thanks you.
So this video is going to be perfect
for improving your vocabulary.
But if you want to improve your listening
and your pronunciation even further,
than I highly recommend
listening to audio books.
It's something I mention
in a lot of my videos,
but I mention it a lot
because I know it works.
I advise you to take a
book that you already have,
a book that you've maybe already read
and download the audio version
and listen to it whilst you are reading.
Just reading alone will not
help you with your pronunciation
because English is not
a phonetic language.
If you are hearing the
word as you read it,
your brain will make the connection,
and next time you see that word,
you will know how to pronounce it.
And next time you hear that word,
you will know how it's spelt.
You can get a free audiobook,
that's a 30 day free trial
of audible by clicking on the
link in the description box.
I've got loads of recommendations
for great audio books,
and also the physical book
counterpart on Amazon.
I really encourage you
to try out this method
because it could transform
your pronunciation,
your spelling, your vocabulary
and you're listening.
Right, let's get started with the lesson.
Let's begin with informal
or casual phrases
that you can use with
your friends and family.
The first one is, you're welcome.
But let's expand on that a little bit.
If you really want to emphasise
that their thanks has been
taken into consideration,
you can say, you're very welcome.
This is quite a British one, I think,
for example, thank you so much
for packing my shopping for me.
Oh, you're very welcome.
Number two, this one is
slightly more American.
It's, no problem,
no problem.
Bear in mind that the older generation
seem to dislike this one.
So keep that in your head
if a slightly older
person is thanking you.
An example, thanks for the help today.
No problem, I enjoyed helping you.
Number three, the third
way to respond to thank you
is, thank you. (laughs)
But this one is all about the emphasis.
If somebody thanks you but you think
that they should be thanked,
you can say, no, thank you.
Or just, thank you.
For example, thanks for
accepting the invitation.
Thank you.
I'm emphasising that really,
I should be thanking them
because they invited me somewhere.
Number four, this one is much more formal.
If we say it in its entire form
it's, the pleasure is mine.
The pleasure is mine.
You can also shorten it
to make it less formal
by saying, my pleasure,
or simply, pleasure,
that's very casual.
For example, thanks for
taking the parcel in for me.
Pleasure.
That's a short way of
saying it was my pleasure,
or the pleasure is mine, or was mine.
Number five is a very friendly one.
Only use this with people you know well.
It's, I know you'd do the same for me.
For example, I'd like to thank you
for looking after my cat so well.
The response, I know
you'd do the same for me.
I know you'd look after my
cat, so I looked after yours.
Even Stevens.
Number six is much more casual.
And it's slightly less heartfelt.
You might say this if
you don't really care,
or if somebody is thanking
you for doing something
that you might not have wanted to do.
But depending on the intonation
and the tone of voice,
it can also be quite warm.
It's, that's all right.
So I could say, thank
you for picking me up
from the station.
I could say either, that's all right.
Or, that's all right.
My tone of voice is telling you
everything you need to know there.
Number seven is a very casual one.
It's, no worries, no worries.
In use, thanks for letting me know
that my car alarm was going off.
No worries, I thought I'd better tell you.
The next one is very British.
It's quite self-deprecating.
It's, don't mention it.
For example, thank you so
much for bringing the desert.
Oh, don't mention it.
It was a lot of effort to
bring dessert probably.
And they probably do
want you to mention it,
but we just say, don't mention it
because, oh, it was nothing.
Number nine is very heartfelt.
It is, it was the least I could do.
For example, thank you for
visiting me in hospital.
Oh, it was the least I could do.
Again, very British,
very self-deprecating.
Number 10 is quite casual.
It's, anytime.
Thank you for stopping by, oh, anytime.
It's quite a generous
response, I like this one.
Number 11 is a really American one.
I hardly ever hear it used in the UK.
But I thought I should teach it to you
because British English
is not the only English,
it's good to know about all of
the different slang phrases.
And yes, this is a very
casual one, it is, sure.
A one word answer to say you're welcome.
Thank you for thinking of me, sure.
It often goes hand in
hand with no problem.
Sure, no problem.
Number 12 is, oh, it was nothing.
Again, another self-deprecating one.
It's a way of saying that
what they are thanking you for
was no extra effort.
Thank you for picking
my kids up from school.
Oh, it was nothing, my kids
already needed picking up.
No extra effort here.
Now I want to talk to you about four
more formal ways of
responding to thank you.
And these are more likely to
be used in business situations,
or maybe in a shop or restaurant.
Number one is very British,
it's quite old fashioned,
and it is, much obliged.
The full formal way of saying it is,
I'm very much obliged to you.
For example, thank you so much doctor,
This is shortened down to, I
actually experienced this one
in use the other day at a shoe shop.
I said, thank you so much after paying
and he said, "Much obliged."
And I thought, oh, I haven't
heard that phrase in a while,
I'm gonna put it in a video.
The guy had an amazing
Cockney accent as well,
he was really nice, really helpful.
Great shoes, they had a gel bottom.
Number two is a more formal
way of saying you're welcome
it is, you're most welcome.
Now, this does sound very posh.
So I wouldn't use it willy-nilly,
willy-nilly means without
careful thought, or planning.
I wouldn't use it willy-nilly.
But if you're in a formal situation,
for example, I thanked my solicitor
on the phone the other day
for sending me some forms.
And she replied with, you're most welcome
because she's quite a formal person,
and it was a formal legal situation.
Number three is, we
appreciate your business
or we appreciate your custom.
Custom if you're talking to a customer
and business if you're
talking to a business client.
For example, thank you for
sending the sample so promptly.
We appreciate your business.
And the last one,
definitely a business one,
it's, I'm happy to help.
For example, thank you for
helping me carry the coffees
to the office.
Oh, I'm happy to help.
Right, that's it for today's lesson.
I hope you enjoyed it and I
hope you learned something.
Again, really consider starting
to listen to audiobooks,
you can claim your free audio book
by clicking on the link
in the description box.
Don't forget to connect with
me on all of my social media.
I've got my Facebook,
I've got my Instagram
and I've got my twitter.
And I shall see you
soon for another lesson.
Muah!
(upbeat music)