Do you hate your voice?
Or do you have a lot of opinions
about how your voice sounds?
Or maybe you think that you need
to change your voice to sound
more American, or British, or
Australian when speaking English?
If that's the case for you, and you
feel that you are not happy with how
you sound in English or in your native
language, then this video is for you.
Because today we are going
to talk about the voice.
We're going to talk about
how it is formed and created.
And then we're going to talk about
placement and answer the question whether
or not English has a specific placement.
And then finally, I'm going to give
you a few tips on how to find your
optimal voice, where your voice is most
comfortable at and most expressive.
And you don't need to
work hard to be heard.
And maybe, maybe you'll start liking
your voice and even loving your voice.
Are you ready for that?
I mean, are you ready ready for that?
Okay.
I hope so.
So let's get started.
By the way, if you're new
to my channel, then hi.
My name is Hadar.
I'm a non-native speaker of English,
and I am here to help you feel amazing
when speaking English in your own
voice, speaking authentic English.
And authenticity is definitely
something that we talk about when we
talk about communicating in English.
And definitely, when we
talk about the voice.
And if you want to find out more
about me, then you can find me at
hadarshemesh.com, that's my website.
And I have a lot of free resources to
help you get to where you want to be
when it comes to your English journey.
Oh, and you can also follow me on
Instagram at @hadar.accentsway.
So let's talk about the voice.
Why is it so important?
The voice is such a fundamental
element when it comes to communication.
And not just in English, in
your native language as well.
The voice is the first
thing that people hear.
And a lot of times, people form
an opinion about someone based on
the sound of their voice before
even hearing what they have to say.
And we all do that, by the way.
Whether or not we like this person, or
we feel like we can't trust them, we are
engaged or bored when listening to them.
And even beyond this idea of,
you know, how you are being
perceived when you speak.
Because it's definitely not about that.
It's more about you feeling comfortable
and confident with your voice.
Because a lot of times I hear my students
saying that they don't like their voice.
And even that they hate their voice,
which is a horrible experience.
Because your voice is how you speak.
It's like you hear it all the time.
And if you don't like it, and if you even
hate it, then you probably don't like
anything that comes out of your mouth.
Or you constantly feel that
other people feel the same thing.
And they don't like your voice,
and they have the same opinions
about your voice as you do.
Which is not the case by the way, but
it doesn't help our self-esteem, and
it doesn't help our confidence, and it
doesn't help our communication abilities.
Also, when you know how to use your
voice, you feel a lot more expressive.
You feel like you're able to
express an idea in a compelling way.
You can express your feelings,
and when you think about things
without using words - right?
- by using your tone or your intonation.
And all of that is a
skill - using your voice.
You just need to understand how it works.
And unfortunately, no one teaches that.
I mean, you're born learning
how to speak, so that's it.
But then with time, we learned
to manipulate the voice.
Maybe we have opinions about
being too loud or being too
quiet, or speaking a certain way.
Or if I want to sound American, I
need to be higher in pitch, or lower
in pitch, or louder, or softer.
So all of these ideas that we have about
how we should sound causes to manipulate
our voice, sometimes not to our advantage.
No, I'm not saying that you
can't use your voice in a better
way, in a more optimal way.
But you want to understand what is right
for you and what is healthy for you.
And also learn that the way you
sound is probably how you need to
sound, and be comfortable with that.
Even if it's not this idea or ideal
that you have about the voice.
So let's begin by understanding
how the voice works.
So, the voice needs
three elements to exist.
One is the power source or the
energy, and that is the breath.
Without breath, there is no voice.
Then we need the vibrator where the
voice is actually created, and that is
the vocal folds or vocal chords that are
right here, I'll talk about that in a sec.
And then we need the resonators - the
space for the voice to enhance,
and become stronger and louder.
So, we start with a
breath, we need to inhale.
And the more breath you have
and the deeper the breath is,
the stronger the voice is.
Think about it, that's the energy source.
So, if you tend to take shallow breaths,
let's say, just to your chest, or very
short breaths, then you're not going to
have enough power to support your voice.
So breath is such an important element
when it comes to using your optimal voice.
I recommend practicing belly breathing.
Now, I'm going to link to a few
videos that teach you how to do that.
But if you've ever done yoga or
meditation, you should know what belly
breathing is, where you breathe into
your belly and not into your chest.
In fact, I have a full interview that
I've conducted with a friend of mine about
breath, and I'm going to link to it below.
So, to make a long story short, you want
to practice belly breathing and to breathe
into your belly, so you have more breath
in your body every time you take a breath.
Okay.
So you take a breath, you expand, and
then you exhale it or you release it.
And the breath goes
through the vocal cords.
Now, the vocal chords are
right here inside the vocal
box, also called the larynx.
And the vocal box is right here.
You can feel that little bump here.
For men it's more noticeable..
And you can put your fingers here
and even hum, you can feel it moving.
A lot of vibrations.
And the breath passes between the
vocal cords, that are muscles that
open and close the vocal cords.
And the vocal chords vibrate
and create this sound.
The sound is not very loud when
it's created in the larynx.
And the vocal chords vibrate.
And when the frequency is really
high, when they vibrate really
fast, the pitch is higher.
And when they vibrate a little
slower, then the pitch is lower.
Now, the voice then moves
up the vocal tract and start
resonating in different spaces.
So, for the voice to enhance and
to become louder, it needs to
bounce around in an empty space.
Now let's think, what are the empty
spaces that we have in our mouth or face?
We have the throat right
behind the vocal box.
It's called the
pharynx - the throat itself.
The back of the throat.
The mouth itself, that's a big space.
So this is why when you open your
mouth for the open vowel sounds,
for example: 'ah' and 'aa', you
create more space inside your mouth
for the voice to vibrate, which
changes the quality of the sound.
Right?
So when you drop your jaw and you
create more space in your mouth,
your voice is usually a little louder
because it has more room to vibrate.
More places for the voice to
vibrate: we said the mouth, right?
Nose.
Nasal passages.
Now the sound waves are created here,
but then they move around the body,
and they bounce against hard elements.
In our case, the bones, right?
We have the cheekbones, and the skull,
and the chest - chest bones, the ribs.
So these are bones that
also vibrate with the voice.
Now, lower notes, lower frequencies,
tend to vibrate with the chest bone.
So the chest tends to vibrate with
lower notes, while the head and the
cheekbones and all the parts here
tend to vibrate with higher notes.
Where your voice is at, whether it's
your chest, or your mouth, or your
nose, or your head, that's your vocal
placement - where you place your voice.
And when it resonates and enhanced.
Okay?
So it resonates in the spaces,
but it's enhanced by adding higher
notes, right, like that high pitch.
And then it's more head
voice and mask resonance.
Or if you add lower notes, and then
it's more chest voice, and that's
a deeper quality of the voice.
Now, a lot of times people talk about
English as if it has a certain placement.
A language doesn't have a
placement, people have placement.
And here's the thing, I might use my
placement differently, based on what I'm
saying or the context of the situation.
For example, If I'm speaking to my friend
on the phone and I want to be funny or
sarcastic, I might just go lower in pitch.
If I want to be flirting with them,
I'm going to go to my lower notes.
And then if I need to call my friend from
across the street, I might move to my
mask resonance so they hear me better.
"Hey, how are you doing?"
Or sometimes I might use my head voice.
"What?
What are you talking about?
No way!"
Right?
And I use that to express
an emotion and my tone.
So we constantly shift between
placements based on the situation,
based on our tone of voice, and
based on what we want to say.
Also, every person has their own
natural placement, where their
voice is most comfortable at.
For some people it's a little lower,
for some people it's a little higher.
Because this is also the structure of
your vocal chords and how thick they
are, and the shape of your mouth.
So, you definitely don't want to
compare yourself to someone else
when you're exploring the voice, but
you might want to take some elements
about how they use their voice
maybe, or how expressive they are.
And not try to imitate someone
else's voice, because it might not
be aligned with your own voice.
People have different voices.
So you want to understand what
feels right for you, what feels
right when you are using your voice.
And how can you use your voice so that
you are effortless and expressive.
That is the most important thing.
Even if it's a little higher than
what you had intended it to be or
what you had thought that your voice
should sound like, or even when it's
lower than what you had planned.
Right?
So, the most important thing
is to be connected with your
voice and with your sound.
Now, how do you find that optimal voice?
Here's the thing.
Let's begin with the fact that if your
voice is too high or too low, you're
going to be a little less expressive
because you'll have less play.
English is a very varied language.
You use your pitch continuously,
whether it's about going up or going
down when trying to say something, or
up when you want to stress something.
And you always hear this
melody going up and down.
And if you stuck down here, there's
very little room for you to be
expressive with your voice, and to
express your feelings and emotions; and
even to deliver your message clearly.
Same thing if you're stuck up here and
you're not using your voice a lot, and
you're not playing with your pitch.
That's also preventing you from a very
essential element of communication.
So ideally, you want to
use your middle voice.
And your middle voice, by the
way, is usually the place where
your voice is most comfortable at.
And it's called the optimum pitch level.
I've already discussed it on another
video where I talk about changing
your voice in English, and I'm going
to link to that video below if you'd
like to learn more about the voice.
And I have also a video about fun
exercises that you can do to feel
more powerful with your voice.
But back to our story.
What is the optimum voice,
the optimum pitch level?
Your optimum pitch level is, like I
said, the place where your voice is
most comfortable at and most effortless.
And that is the place where you hum.
'Mmmmm'.
Your hum is usually your
optimum pitch level.
'Hmmmm'.
'How are you doing?' 'How are you doing?'
Now, if you hum and your voice that
comes out is very different than the
voice that you usually use when speaking,
this is something to explore, right?
Because maybe, just maybe, you're speaking
lower than your optimum pitch level, or
higher than your optimum pitch level.
And again, there's nothing wrong with
that, if you feel 100% comfortable.
But if you feel that you're not
expressive, that you're straining
your voice when speaking and you
feel exhausted at the end of the day,
I would definitely look into that.
Because sometimes when our voice
is too high or too low, and we feel
that we are not heard and we want
to increase the volume, we might
strain our voice while doing it.
Instead of just placing it in the
right placement, where the mouth
already does all the work, because
you have all the resonators.
So why not use whatever is naturally there
already, without straining your voice?
So, another way to find your optimum
pitch level is by going really low.
And then you want to push your belly,
your diaphragm actually, a few times.
Let's do it again.
Go really low.
You hear that the voice
goes up really quickly.
That's the optimum pitch level.
So you can try that too, and you can
try the hum and see what feels right.
Now, I'm not saying this
should be your voice.
I'm saying that understanding that this
is your middle voice, and this is where
your voice is most comfortable at.
You can start with that and
you can start exploring that.
And then, remember, that you can
definitely go a little lower and a little
higher, and use all your resonators.
And when you speak a little lower - not
too low, but a little lower - you
add all the resonants of the chest,
which usually has this deeper,
darker, richer quality to your voice.
But sometimes, you might want
to use more of your head voice.
So ideas about, "Oh, my voice is too high.
My voice is too nasal".
I mean, yes, sometimes we use
more nasality in our voice.
And that's especially the case
if you have a lot of nasal
vowels in your native language.
And yes, you don't have to use
them, if we don't have nasal vowels.
And understanding how to
use your mouth or your chest
resonance instead can serve you.
But it doesn't mean that there is
something wrong with your voice.
The idea is to understand how
to use everything entirely.
Now, to understand how to use your
resonators, like I said, I have a video
with a bunch of fun exercises to help you
explore the versatility of your voice.
And I'm going to link to
it in the description.
Okay, that's it.
Now I want to hear from you.
Do you find yourself having
negative thoughts about your voice?
If so, what are they?
You can share them in the comments and
see that, first of all, you're not alone.
But also I would be more than happy
to support you, and see if there's
anything else I can help you with.
Also, I have a task for you to
find someone that you really love
their voice and how they use it.
And start asking yourself
question why you like it so much.
What is it about their quality of voice?
Is it because you feel
that they're expressive?
Because you understand their feelings?
Because you feel that they're connected.
So, I want you to ask yourself
all of these questions.
And then if you have any insights, share
them in the comments with us below.
Or come on over to Instagram at
@hadar.accentsway and send me a DM.
All right.
That's it for today.
Thank you so, so much for being here.
Remember, loving your voice
is so incredibly important.
Because if you don't love your
voice, you will believe that no
one is going to love your voice.
And that is not healthy, my friend, for
anything related to life or communication.
And also, when you start loving your
voice, you start enjoying recording
yourself and hearing yourself on video.
And that is also something that
you want to incorporate more into
your life, especially when it
comes to practicing your English.
All right.
Have a beautiful,
beautiful rest of the day.
And I'll see you next
week in the next video.
Bye.