I'm a forensic artist, worked for the San José Police Department from 1995 to 2011.
I showed up to a place I've never been and there was a guy with a drafting board.
We couldn't see them, they couldn't see us.
Tell me about your hair
I didn't know what he was doing, but then I could tell after several questions that he was drawing me.
Tell me about your chin.
It kind that protrudes a little bit. Especially when I smile.
Your jaw?
My mom told me I had a big jaw.
What would be your most prominent feature.
Kinda have fat, rounded face.
The older I've gotten the most freckles I've gotten.
I would say I have a pretty big forehead.
Once I get a sketch, I say "thank you very much" and then they leave. I don't see them.
All I have been told before the sketch was to get friendly with this other woman: Chloe.
Today I'm gonna ask you some questions about the person you met earlier and I'm gonna ask you some general questions about their face.
She was thin, so you can see her cheek bones. And her chin was a nice, thin chin.
She had nice eyes. They lit up when she spoke.
Cute nose.
She had blue eyes. Very nice blue eyes.
Ok...
So here we are. This is the sketch you helped me create. And that's a sketch that somebody described of you.
Yeah, that's.
She looks closed off and fatter. Sadder too. The second one looks more open. Friendly and happy.
I should be more grateful of my natural beauty. It impacts the choices in friends that we make, the jobs we apply for, how we treat our children
It impacts everything. It couldn't be more critical to your happiness.
Do you think you're more beautiful then you say?
Yeah. yeah.
We spend a lot of time as woman analyzing and trying to fix the things that aren't quite right
and should spend more time appreciating the things we do like.
YOU ARE MORE BEAUTIFUL THAN YOU THINK.
Watch the whole experience at dove.com/realbeautysketches