You're so hypnotizing
Could you be the devil
could you be an angel
Your touch magnetizing
Feels like I'm floating, leaves my body glowing
They say be afraid
You're not like the others, futuristic lovers
Different DNA, they don't understand you
You're from a whole other world
A different dimension
You open my eyes
And I'm ready to go, lead me into the light
Kiss me, k-k-kiss me
Infect me with your love and fill me with your poison
Take me, t-t-take me
Wanna be a victim, ready for abduction
Boy, you're an alien, your touch so foreign
Its supernatural, extraterrestrial
You're so supersonic
Wanna feel your powers, stun me with your lasers
Your kiss is cosmic, every move is magic
You're from a whole other world
A different dimension
You open my eyes
And I'm ready to go, lead me into the light
Kiss me, k-k-kiss me
Infect me with your love, and fill me with your poison
Take me, t-t-take me
Wanna be your victim, ready for abduction
Boy, you're an alien, your touch so foreign
Its supernatural, extraterrestrial
There is this transcendental, on another level
Boy, you're my lucky star
I wanna walk on your wave length
And be there when you vibrate
For you I risk it all, all
Kiss me, k-k-kiss me
Infect me with your love and fill me with your poison
Take me, t-t-take me
Wanna be your victim, ready for abduction
Boy, you're an alien, your touch so foreign
It's supernatural, extraterrestrial
Extraterrestrial, extraterrestrial
Boy, you're an alien, your touch so foreign
Its supernatural, extraterrestrial