Our next guest is sitting
in the audience right now.
And it could be you.
Everybody stand up.
All right.
And you have to be honest here.
Stay standing if you
watch my show every day.
Every day.
You should be ashamed
of yourselves.
Stay standing if you have
written me over 30 letters.
Stay standing if
you're originally
from the Dominican Republic.
Stay standing if you've learned
English by watching my show.
Diana, come on down.
Hi.
Diana Aquino, right?
Yes.
Hello.
Hi.
I love you.
I love you, too.
You're very sweet.
So, first of all,
it was a great way
to find out who watches
my show everyday.
So when did you move here
from the Dominican Republic?
I moved here on May of 2011.
OK.
And you didn't speak
any English at all?
No.
I literally speak two words.
It was hello and goodbye.
The most important words here.
Really.
Of course.
All right.
And so you learned English
from watching my show.
And how did you do that?
Oh.
OK.
That's a funny story.
I was just flipping
through the channels,
just flipping through it.
And I just came to your face.
You were there I asked
my mom, "Who is that?"
And my mom was
like, "She's Ellen.
She's really funny.
Just watch the show.
You will love her.
I was like, "But I don't
understand what she's saying.
She was like, "Me either.
But just watch it.
She's hilarious.
And then I was like, "OK.
I watch it."
I didn't understand anything
you were saying, literally.
I'm sorry, but I didn't.
And then, at the end of
the show, it was like,
there was just this
word that you say.
You say, "Be kind."
And then that word
stuck with me.
You know when you get
this word that you really
want to see what it is.
I got my dictionary.
I looked it up.
And I kept looking
at the wrong word,
with the C instead
of the K. Oh, my God.
But I got it.
And I saw how the word
kind, and it means kindness,
to be good to other people.
And that stuck with me
forever, because I'm loud.
I'm affectionate.
I like to be kind to everyone.
So that just stuck with me
to be who I am, with myself.
So yeah.
That's so sweet.
I love that.
So you said that you're
very affectionate.
I know that our
culture is not as
affectionate as your culture.
Right?
Yes.
Y'all are very affectionate,
and Americans are very uptight.
Over there in Dominican,
we are so loud.
And we know everybody.
We know every neighbor by name.
We hug.
We kiss in the cheek.
And we hug you no matter what.
If we meet you for the first
time, we will still hug you.
We still crazy.
So I just keep doing that.
Yeah.
You keep doing it.
You keep hugging them.
You kiss them in the cheek.
Of course.
I do it.
All right.
And so you're putting
yourself through college.
You're a math tutor,
And what else do you Do
I'm a math tutor right now and
I'm a cashier, sixth floor,
in a retail store.
In a retail store.
So all right.
So I have a gift
for you, because you
said you learned
English watching me.
So I have the Ellen
DeGeneres Dictionary.
All right.
Thank you.
So Let's see.
All right.
The first word of course,
it starts with an Andy.
And it's a noun.
And the definition
is an average human.
OK.
I love Andy.
He's so cool.
I love him, too.
And then we have a Bachelor.
And that's a noun, a television
show Ellen tries not to watch
but inevitably gets sucked
back into every season.
It's OK.
Me too.
I know.
They pull you in.
And then we have glitter.
It's a noun.
Tiny pieces of sparkly material
that make me an absolute mess
and should be illegal.
Oh, my God.
Right.
Then we go further back in the
dictionary we have Shutterfly.
It's a noun.
It's an incredible company
that loves sharing life's joy
and wants to help you
with your education
by giving you a
check for $10,000.
Oh, my God.
Thank you so much!
You're welcome.
Hi.
I'm Andy.
Ellen asked me to remind you
to subscribe to her channel
so you can see more
awesome videos, like videos
of me getting scared or
saying embarrassing things,
like ball peen hammer.
And also some videos of
Ellen and other celebrities,
if you're into
that sort of thing.
God!