Hey, Tyler. You going to that all day meeting tomorrow?
I'll be on vacation from Tuesday, June 27th until 2 days ago.
Um, your auto-response is still on.
[intro]
Okay, everyone, I need you to send me your reports ASAP, before lunch if possible.
Will do, Tripp.
- Will do, Tripp.
Why are you including me in this?
Be there around 7 tonight, if that's okay?
Yeah, sounds good.
Kind regards, Tripp Crosby, Regional Sales Manager. Work -404-555-6112 ext. 405. Mobile -404-555-
3767. Email tripp@biz.dot "Success is always an option." ~John Maxwell, Author.
Here's that report you needed.
I don't see anything.
Oh, dang it. I forgot to attach it.
Hey, Beth, did you see all of the submissions we got today?
OMG, I KNOW!
Easy on the all caps.
Sorry.
It's okay. Semi-colon. Closed parentheses.
Hey, son. You have to watch this video of this cat sleeping on a horse. It is so cute!
Mom, I'm at work!
Dear friend, I am Johnson Emmanuel. This might come to you as a surprise. I am the next heir to the throne in
Nigeria and I want to offer you a large sum of money.
Please stop coming here.
Hi, Tripp. Are you satisfied with-
Hi. I'm the administrator. I cannot deliver this document. It was too big. On Monday at 10:37am, Paul
wrote, "Hi, Tripp. This is the latest version of the document you were looking for. Hope it's not too late.
Paul."
Yeah, I know what I wrote.
Hey, really looking forward to seeing you guys tonight. Oh yeah, circular disclosure: this information
transmitted just now is intended only for the person or entity to which it is addressed. It may contain
confidential and/or privileged material. Any review, retransmission-
I don't know what that means.
Inbox full.
Hey, what's this poker game I hear about this weekend?
Who's that guy?
You need me to bring anything, or-
I meant to invite a different David. Raincheck?
Email can be frustrating, but that's probably because you're trying to use it for the wrong things, like
status reporting or approval tracking. If you're looking for a smarter way to manage work, consider using
WorkFront, a much better than email approach to work management.
For more information, just click the link or go to workfront.com/trippandtyler
Hey, and, thanks for watching our intakes. If you want to watch our outtakes, click right here.
Still watching? We also want to tell you about our new weekly web show coming up- a great reason to
subscribe to our channel. It's going to be great.
Great sell!
Thank you.