Hello. I'm Gill at engVid. And,
today, we have a lesson on some
vocabulary, and it's all
connected with climate change.
So, if you.   you probably know
a lot about this subject
already, but if English isn't
your first language, then this
might be useful for you to teach
you some of the main terms which
are used in English to do with
climate change, which is also
called "global warming", because
the problem is that the
temperature is rising gradually,
but.   but definitely. So,
"climate change" is to do with
global warming; the temperature
rising. Okay. And one of the
main reasons for it is that for
many years now, we've been using
what are called "fossil fuels",
which are things like oil and
gas, and coal. And I think
caught.   coal goes back a very
long time, more than 100 years,
and causes a lot of air
pollution. Okay. So, the "fossil
fuels" are the things we.   we
need to try to stop using, and
to stop.   especially mining for
coal; no more digging coal out
of the ground, and burning it
for.   for power. Okay? Because
all of those produce CO2, which
is the chemical formula for
carbon dioxide, which goes into
the atmosphere, and it just
makes things warm up even more,
what are called "greenhouse
gases". If you think of a
greenhouse, which is a sort of
glasshouse that you grow things
in — things like tomatoes,
fruit, other plants that like a
warm atmosphere — so in a
greenhouse, which is made of
glass, that.   the glass, and
the light, and the sunlight
coming through the glass helps
to keep it warm inside. So,
that's why we have this kind of
metaphor: "greenhouse" to
describe the kind of gases, such
as CO2, which contribute to
global warming. Okay?
So, all of this is described as
a "threat to human life",
meaning human life is in danger
because of all this climate
change which is going on. And
not just to human life, but also
the last of species, which can
either be plants, or animals, or
things like the coral reefs
under the sea. A lot of those
different species are becoming
extinct; coral reefs are sort of
disappearing. So, all these
things that we're losing — it's
not a good thing for the
environment. Okay. So, and one
term that's used — a result of
climate change — is "extreme
weather", which can be all sorts
of extremes. It can either be
too wet or too dry.   so.   too
hot. I think too cold — I don't
think that's one of the extremes
so much, but definitely things
getting too hot. "Heatwaves" —
when you have a very high
temperature, more than 40
degrees temperature. Some
countries are going into 50
degrees, so that's called a
"heatwave" when it's so hot, you
can hardly go outside; you can't
walk, you might feel faint, you
might collapse because it's so
hot. So, "heatwaves". This word
is pronounced: "drought". It's a
strange spelling, but a
"drought" is when there is no
water; there's no rainfall., so
everything dries up, and you
can't grow crops, things like
that. So "drought", but then the
opposite: "storms" where you
have heavy rainfall. So, those
are the extremes — very dry or
very wet. Storms, "hurricanes",
when you have a very strong wind
coming. And then because.   if
it's very dry and hot, it.
you're more likely to get
"wildfires", which are fires
that might just start for no
reason. Or it may be somebody
has thrown a match on the ground
and the grass has started to
burn, and the fire spreads. But
sometimes a fire can just start
almost on its own, and then they
spread in an area with a lot of
trees. The trees are very dry.
In places like Australia,
California — there are very
often wildfires, and the fires
just spread and spread. If the
trees are there, the fires will
just spread. And people with
houses in those areas, they
often lose their homes; their
homes burn down as well. Okay,
so that's "wildfires". If it
does rain very heavily, you get
"floods". So, people go out and
they.   they.   they're
having.   they've got water
coming up to their knees or even
higher, or they can't go out at
all because the water is so
high. So, "floods".
And scientists think that even
"volcanic eruptions".   if you
think there are a lot more
"volcanic eruptions" nowadays;
if you think: "Oh, there seems
to be another volcanic eruption
every.   every few months. Is it
more than usual?" Scientists
think that even volcanic
eruptions could be a result of
global warming. It's a theory, I
think at the moment, but it's
partly to do with the.   if
there were glaciers on the
mountain, the.   the ice, the
glazier — a big sheet of ice —
if that melts, and they do melt,
the weight of the glacier
pressing on the volcanoes
possibly helps to stop the
volcano erupting. But if the
weight of the glacier has gone,
there is less weight pressing
down, and that may be part of
the, you know.   likelihood of
an eruption. So, that's another
thing. So, "rising sea levels" —
the sea rising, partly with ice
melt.   melting. And then, if
you have smaller islands, in
places like the Pacific Ocean,
there are a lot of little, small
islands — they could disappear
completely if the sea level
comes up high enough; islands
will be just lost. So, the
melting ice is.   a lot of it is
in the North Pole, the Arctic,
and the South Pole, the
Antarctic. And it's the melting
ice, and very big pieces of ice
break off and float around in
the sea, and gradually melt. And
they're helping to raise the
level of the sea, which is
another danger. Okay. And then
the other way is, again.   so,
if.   if there's.   if it's very
dry, what used to be farmland
where people grow crops for
food, the farmland could go very
dry and turn into a desert. So,
it.   it may have looked very
green at one time, and then you
see it looks sort of yellow or
brown, and you can't grow
anything there unless you have
water to water it with
regularly. So, farmland becoming
desert, then you can't grow
crops, so that will then lead to
food shortage; not enough food
for everybody. Okay.
So, you may wonder: "Well, what
can we do about it? What.  ?
What are the contributing
factors?" Well, two of them are
to do with transport and things
that we do at home. So,
transport, traveling by plane,
by car adds a lot to the global
warming because of the fuel
that's being used. If, you
know.   the planes have fossil
fuels to.   to power them. And
cars have either diesel or
petrol, which is fossil fuel
again. And there's a trend now
to make a lot more electric
cars, where that will be less
harmful to the environment.
Okay. But then if.   if you
avoid planes and cars, and go
use public transport instead, or
walk, if you don't have too far
to go, then that's one thing
that.   that can be done. Okay.
And then at home, household
appliances, electrical
equipment, heating, the heating
in your house. If it's.   if
it's gas, then it's.   it's a
fossil fuel. And then, if your
house doesn't have.   or your
home doesn't have insulation, if
the.   if the heat that you have
in the house can escape through
cracks in the window, or in the
door — if it's drafty, so you
have to turn the heating up to
keep warm — then that's a bad
thing. So, another good thing
that we can do is insulation,
for example, double glazing for
windows; two sheets of glass in
the window, rather than one,
and.   and things like that.
Okay, so.   so that's just a
very short summary, really, of
climate change, global warming,
and some of the vocabulary
connected with it. So, I hope
that's been helpful for you. And
there will be a quiz on this, so
please go to www.engvid.com and
try the quiz. And see you again
soon. Okay. Bye for now.