hello i'm gonna i'm gonna cook something
my name is ronnie
um but i need my tongs and
oh gotta make sure they work why do we
do that
when when you grab the tongs out of the
drawer which is
the thing that you store them in why do
we always test them
what's that like oh i think they broke
in the drawer overnight but
these are tongs and this lesson is about
doing some really
crazy strange things as humans i think
that you're human
are you a robot
no okay i'm a human and i do some really
weird things so for example
i wear mascara and every time i put on
mascara
i do this
okay let me demonstrate i'm going to put
on mascara and i
always have to open my mouth i could do
it like this but i have to do this
why do we do that are we eating
something are we expecting food to fly
in our mouths
i got a biscuit oh great no
no we're just really kind of strange
humans aren't we
um so ask yourself
why do i do these things
why do you open your mouth
to put on mascara now if you actually
look at this sentence
put on is a phrasal verb you're going to
learn some phrasal verbs
so a phrasal verb means that there's a
verb
and a preposition so we
put on some kind of makeup put on
mascara
put on blush eyeshadow i don't know what
you ladies apply but
whatever you're putting on it looks
great
so put on means apply
do you drive a car or have you been in a
car
yes we have why
you're driving along got the tunes
cranked
which means up really high you have to
find an address
even google map says you have arrived at
your destination
but you got to turn down the music you
will never
be able to find the address unless you
turn the music down
no no your eyes are like no i'm just
don't i can't see anything until you
turn the music down
it has to work with our delicious brains
and
it's about distraction i'm telling you
the answer why okay
if we have too many sounds or too much
confusion in our heads we can't focus on
one thing enough so
that's the answer that's why we turned
down the radio
to find an address why we open our mouth
when we put on mascara
uh kind of opens our eyes more
yeah we're just really strange humans
alright let's go to the next one
turn down is a phrasal verb so turn down
something means you
decrease so we turn down the radio we're
actually turning down the volume
of the radio but we just say the radio
it's like
take the radio turn it no it's not
working so turn down the volume
um i do this so turn off the lights
when we leave the room now this is a
good habit
okay so i'm i'm proud that i do this
ronnie's saving energy
but sometimes there's other people in
the room
so i leave the room total darkness to
the other people oh my god
ronnie why did you turn off the lights
oh because
i left the room it doesn't work like
that
um so be careful it's a good habit to
get into
when you leave the room turn off the
lights just make sure there's no other
people
enjoying something what are you enjoying
um this happens to me
every day because i live
in a place that has an elevator and
elevators are quite fascinating actually
there's lots of stuff you can do in them
brano
keep it up um but
you're waiting for the elevator
and the elevator finally comes you stand
right in front of the elevator door
the door opens oh my god and there's
people
what there's other people
in the elevator already and they they
scare you like
how are there people in the elevator the
door opens you look up
people sometimes other people scream
kind of like doing this i have a dog and
sometimes a dog comes out first and
scares the people and
he's just a small guy but people are
weird so
we never never we never fathom which
means
think that there is another person
already in the elevator we think
the elevator is always empty it's always
for us i called it ding
it's here oh there there's another
person in the elevator get them out of
there
here's another phrasal verb to throw
something out or throw out something
this means you put it in the garbage so
a lot of the times you're making a
packet of something maybe you're making
craft dinner because you're in canada or
you're cooking something that has
instructions
so you rip open the box or the bag or
the package
put the crap in your pot
throw out the box
oh my god i have no idea how to cook
this what am i going to do
how long do i cook it for what's the
next step you have just thrown out all
of the magical answers
to the world right in the garbage
but why do they put the instructions on
the box
why not put it inside that would help us
so throwing out cooking instructions
it's kind of a stupid thing that we do
i do this i really honestly do this to
you
pack extra gitch
now let's just find out what these words
mean pack
so this means i'm going to go someplace
on vacation
or a night trip or to some place and i
need a change of clothes
pack means you put the things into your
bag okay
extra means more than you need and gitch
apparently is a slur slang term for
underwear
i've said it my whole life and it's kind
of a cool thing to say now
nice gitch so we always
i always pack extra git and i think to
myself
i'm going to put these in just in case i
ship myself because
i'm prepared to do that because it's
going to be a crazy time when i go
on a road trip but we always do this
we're like we need extra underwear
it's like we think or we prepare
yourself for the worst
oh i'm gonna get diarrhea if i go to
mcdonald's
and i definitely gonna need that extra
underwear for this job interview
so let's put that in my job interview
bag
and then if you do actually have
diarrhea you're gonna have to go to a
public washroom
and most of them have locks
which is fantastic to have a lock on a
public bathroom
and you can say bathroom or washroom
doesn't matter um
restroom's always weird why are you
taking a rest in there what are you
do i know what you're doing okay so
in the public washrooms you knock on the
door
and what do you say when you're in there
um hello
i'll be a second um so usually you just
go
or make a noise or flush the toilet or
something
but then the people check the door and
they check it again
and again it's like maybe it's locked
maybe it's not locked maybe maybe it's
just broken maybe
no there's somebody in here and it's
always uncomfortable when you're going
to the bathroom like
i have to go faster because somebody's
waiting yeah it's just weird
just we should have like an alarm or
something someone
is in the bathroom please step away from
the door until i'm ready to come out
i don't know how we're gonna get around
this one but knocking
hello occupied somebody's in here i
don't know what's going to go there
um do you have
problems understanding people when they
talk to you
i do and i'm
a native english speaker and sometimes
people speak to me in my native language
and i just don't understand them
and i do this yeah yeah
i have no idea what they're saying to me
i'm sure that happens to you
if you're learning english but we just
kind of nod and say yes
and smile and they could be telling us
anything really oh my
my ten children just died in avalanche
yeah
and then what if they ask you questions
and so what do you think about that
yeah if you don't understand the person
just say to them
ah you know sorry i didn't get that or i
don't understand that don't just nod
you get yourself into a lot of trouble
yeah be careful
if you don't understand something ask
the person did you just say
10 kids oh no okay good
um this is fun
so maybe you're waiting
at an elevator or at the stoplight
and there's a big button that you get to
press okay
you know if you press the button one
time it's gonna do its job it's gonna do
its function so
press the elevator button once the
elevator is like i'm coming to get you
but be careful there's other people in
here
or you're at the stop light and people
press the button many many many times so
yeah do you know what if you press a
button it does actually make the light
change faster
and it does make the elevator come
faster so please press it
as many times as you want and the faster
you press it and the more times you
press it
it's going to work faster i promise try
it
oh it's here oh there's people in there
wow what happened there
surprise sometimes i do this
um you get into the elevator there's
another person
how awkward now in our crazy world of
coronavirus we're only allowed to have
one other person
in the elevator with us yes so it's not
as
awkward but you're still like what do i
say
where do i look where do i put my eyes
oh damn i can look at the little lights
as they light up now my building's quite
modern
and we don't have the little lights
across the top we have a number plate
digital two three
four it doesn't talk but we always look
at this
we just stare at that we could look at
our shoes that would be better
but we always stare at the numbers you
could look at the person well
don't look at the people they'll think
that you're weird if this is your mask
then you try and talk to them get on the
phone just shut up
and stare at the numbers it'll work
great
and then oh the other person's off the
elevator then we can look anywhere we
want we can
ah yeah how's my hair huh where's my
shoes we can do that
um one time i was doing something
and i had no idea where my glasses were
okay and i was oh my god
i know i had my sunglasses i know that i
put them someplace
and i looked in my car i got out
looked around
they're on my head
so
i know i put lots of things on my head
it's my new storage compartment
but why do you always forget this you
know they're there you look in the
mirror like no
not there um this one is a
terrible habit that we have okay when we
click on ads
so this means with your mouse which is
weird it's a mouse
not a dog or a rat or a cat it's a mouse
and we're looking
at something
and we don't want this ad there but they
do this on purpose
there's a little tiny x you can't see
the x
but it's tiny ah
pollock's actually clapped on it and
that
adds an extras like three seconds before
you actually get to watch my next
youtube video
and you have to wait that three seconds
or one minute even oh after the ads
don't click on the ads
you go oh i clicked on the ads again
it's it's human habit so
here's another phrasal verb i can click
on something
now this means that i
press my mouse button if you have a
mouse
i can click on something and i press it
um
do we have any other phrasal verbs we
can find what about look for
okay if i look for something it means i
search
ah oh i just have no idea of my glass oh
glasses are
so search is too formal um we're not
going to say
i am searching for my sunglasses we
search in a more public
thing for missing children or things
that are missing but
in a public realm we can search for
those
um we can stare at
something yep that was long enough you
stare
at something press the button many times
it's not a phrasal verb
say yes or no pack that's in through oh
that's it
those are all the phrasal verbs for
today ladies and gentlemen so
the next time you take an elevator press
the button
many many many many many many times
you'll get to your destination faster
if you're at the stoplights press that
button if you do it a hundred times
it changes right away i promise try it
and uh
enjoy the crazy things that we do being
humans till next time
i'm gonna go wrangle up some cowboys