How you guys doing? Good, good good good good.
Well guys, I was born this way, and there’s
no medical reason why that happened. My brother
and my sister were born with arms and legs.
And sometimes in life, things happen that
don’t make sense. My doctors never thought
that I’d be able to walk, and today, I’m
walking. I’m from Australia, anybody want
to one day go to Australia? It’s such a
cool place. And I now live in LA; I’m a
Southern California boy. So I only live about
four hours from here.
And today I’m going to tell you, man — I
love freaking people out. One day I’m in
a car, I’m in the front seat — I’m not
driving of course. Can you imagine if I’m
driving a car? They reckon they can put a
joystick — that thing that controlls my
wheelchair — we can put that in a car. Like
how fully sick is that? Imagine if I get pulled
over by the cops? Can I have your driver’s
license please? Yeah, but, it’s over there;
you’re going to have to get it.
Imagine if I’m in big trouble! Put your
hands up! Uhhhh.. Get out of your car! Uhhhhh…
So I’m in the front passenger’s seat,
we’re at the traffic lights, and this car
comes up next to us and this girl’s looking
at me. And I’m looking at her, she’s looking
at me, I’m looking at her, she’s looking
at me, I’m looking at her. All she sees
is my head, right? She has no idea that I
have no arms and no legs. So I’m thinking,
cool. I’m going to freak you out.
So I get the seatbelt in my mouth, and I loosen
it like this, so that I can freely move. And
she’s looking at me like “why are you
eating your seatbelt?’ So I pull it, the
belt is loose, I can move.
Now she’s looking at me, full 100% attention
and focus. And just imagine all you see is
my head, all right? You might want to put
up your hand to your face to cut off the rest
of my body. So you can really see the effect,
so…That’s it, exactly.
Here we go, ready? I just did this. And her
face, man. She was like — she nearly ran
the red light, man. It was so good.
My parents always said, Nick, you don’t
know what you can achieve until you try it.
And the doctors looked at me and said, he’s
not going to walk, he’s not going to go
to school, he’s not going to do anything
in his life.
And then my parents; they just loved me like
crazy, and said you’ve got to try. Try this,
try that, try this, try that, and I’m thinking
sometimes, like, Mom and Dad, you’re crazy,
I have no arms and no legs. How would I ever
be able to do this or do that?
But they encouraged me, and they loved me.
And as human beings, we’re waiting for stuff
like that, we all want love. Everybody say
it — loooooove. Very good.
We all want love. I went to school, and I
wanted to be cool, you know. You go to school
and you want to be accepted. So, you see these
guys, and you’re like, oh man, you know?
Everyone swears, like every third sentence.
F this, and F that, and F’n this, and F
F, like, what, they think they’re cool,
you know. And so I’m thinking, maybe I need
to be like them to be cool.
And then you compare each other with how we
look and I wish I was smarter, I wish I was
taller, I wish I was shorter, I wish I was
more popular, I wish I did this, I wish I
didn’t have that. I wish my life was different.
That was me when I was about 8 years old;
I looked at myself, and I looked at everybody
else, and everyone else had more than me.
And I’m asking, why? Why me? Have you ever
asked the why me questions, but get nowhere?
If I had no answers from the doctors, and
if I had no answers from my parents, I still
have a choice, every day in my life, to keep
going or give up. You see this book up here?
This is my favorite book in the whole wide
world. This is my favorite book, the bible.
And here I am – and here I am, and for me,
that’s my full potential in all that I can
be here on earth. And so encouragement takes
me closer to all that I can be, and discouragement
takes me away.
You see, it only takes three seconds for someone
to tease me when I was at school, and just
say ewwwww, you’re ugly. Ewww, you can’t
do this and you can’t do that. Some of you
are thinking, like, man, seriously? You had
kids picking on you? How heartless are those
kids? Picking on me with no limbs? You would
probably say, well, I’m not that bad. I
wouldn’t pick on a kid with no limbs. But
why would you pick on anyone? Well, because
it’s fun, it’s just culture. OK, we’ll
get to that.
But for me, facing all that stuff? I’m getting
these seeds, everyone say seeds, S-E-E-D-S,
seeds. Have you seen the pictures of the sequoia
reds up here in California? These huge trees.
Like some of the trunks could be nearly as
big as this room. I’ve seen those photos
where they’ve actually dug out a tunnel
in a trunk of a tree — you can drive a full-size
SUV right through it. That all started with
a little seed.
If you leave a seed of lies in your heart
and in your mind, and you don’t know the
truth? If you don’t know the truth, you
will die with the lie. I started dying, because
I started believing what I was told.
I want you to know the three things that I
needed to come to in my life is the truth
of my values, the truth of my purpose, and
the truth of my destiny. I want you to know
something. In our mind, we put ourselves down
all the time. I want to ask you today, do
you think I’m cool enough to be your friend?
But I don’t swear, I don’t use the F-bomb,
am I still cool enough to be your friend?
But I don’t tease people, am I still cool
enough to be your friend? But I have no arms
and no legs. Seriously.
You would be my friend, even though I have
no arms, no legs. So you’re telling me it
actually doesn’t matter, right? If it actually
doesn’t matter, for how we look, then why
do we tease one another for how we look if
it actually doesn’t matter? Why is it that
we look ourselves in the mirror, and we say,
well, we’re having fun! Oh yeah, man it’s
just part of culture, man.
There were twelve people one day teased me.
Taking me away from my hope. 12, 11, 10, 9,
8, 7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1. Don’t worry, I won’t
fall off, because if I did, I’d break my
arm.
But twelve people teased me one day. And I
can put a pretty brave face on but cry on
the inside. For real. Oh, it doesn’t hurt!
Yeah, it hurts. There was this one bully,
I became his target for three weeks. And every
time I’d go by him — I was 13, he was
17. I was in my chair. I’m only 4’9″
in my other chair, my old chair. He’s like
6′ something, so he’s huge, right? So
I’m looking up at him, and every time I’d
go by him, he’s like, “Hey, there’s
Nick! He has no…” And you can imagine
what he said. And I’m like, what’s his
problem, man?
So I would try to avoid him, and I was so
embarrassed, because he would say it really
loud and everybody would be looking and some
would be laughing. I’m like, what is this
guy’s problem, man? So one day, after three
weeks, I went up to him and I said, “Hey”.
He’s like, “Hey”.
And I said, “Can you please stop it?”
He said, “Stop what?”
I said “Stop teasing me”.
He said, “What are you talking about?”
I said, “Every time I walk by you say that
stuff”.
He’s like, “What stuff?” He didn’t
know how to take me on.
So I’m looking up at him and said, “No
man. Every time I walk by, you say exactly
this, and I want you to stop. I forgive you,
but stop it”.
He’s like, “Oh, it’s not hurting you”.
Now, I could have said, “No,” or I could
have said yeah. It takes a level of humility
to actually say, um, actually, I don’t like
that. It’s killing me. And I said, “Ah,
yeah, it’s hurting me”.
He said, “All right, I’m sorry man. I
was just, you know, playing around”.
I said, “Give me a hug”.
He said, “What?”
He’s like, “All right”. So I gave him
a hug. I’m a hugging machine. We made the
Guinness Book of World Records: 1,749 hugs
in one year. We did it last year — my arms
fell off, all right? The scary thing about
hugging so many people is that anyone can
just pick me up and take me home. Like, what
am I going to do, like, –hit them or something?
Pretty mean head-butt, right?
I want you to know that you might be playing
around. I can pretty much say that 98% of
you have teased someone in your life. I tried
to commit suicide because of people who thought
they were having fun, not knowing the hell
that I was going through. The people you’re
teasing — what if the person you’re teasing
is the person who’s thinking of committing
suicide.
What if the person you’re teasing is the
one who’s trying to commit suicide, who
hates their life because of you? You don’t
know if the person you are teasing is the
son or daughter of a drunk at home getting
abused. And all they need is someone like
you to keep on pushing them this way.
We need hope, so find something else to do.
Find positive things in your own life; I don’t
care about how you look, I will never ever
ever tease you. I will never tease you! I
could tease you, I could be tough. People
thinking that bullying is tough? It ain’t
tough! My wheelchair? This is tough. This
thing, man, I’ll tell you something — you
ready?
This wheelchair. This thing’s so tough.
When my friend built this for me, he said,
you’re going to love it. I said what, does
it go fast? He said no, but it’s tough.
And I said, well, what do you mean? He said,
you’ll find out.
The torque in these motors, at the bottom
at the back. This thing. If someone’s holding
it. I’m telling you, it can go 90 degrees.
I went 80 degrees up, alright? Someone’s
holding me to make sure I don’t tip back.
My wife, she loves shopping with me, because
she just jumps on the back, and we go shopping.
She just shops and shops, because she doesn’t
drop, right? We just go and do it; it’s
fun.
Now what I tried one day to do — you’ll
never believe me, maybe you will, just know
that every word that comes out of my mouth
is not an exaggeration.
One day, I needed to move a car. So I got
my wife to put my car, my ’66 Chevelle,
in neutral. It’s a two and a half ton car,
and I backed it back with this thing. Two
and a half — just this. Just like this,
like nothing. This thing is tough. Guess what?
The definition of tough means it’s strong.
To show your strength, you need to do something
that’s difficult. I would sound so stupid
if I said hey guys, I got a matchbox car one
day, and I got some fishing line, and I towed
that matchbox car all around all day. How
tough is my BMW? That’s stupid.
That’s the same thing with bullying. You
think you’re tough? You’re trying to show
your strength? That’s not your strength.
Let me come back in ten years and let me get
your three — anyone have a three year old
nephew? Anyone have a three year old nephew?
Cool. Put your hands down.
I will get any one of your three year old
nephews, bring them tomorrow night at where
I’m speaking, and we’re going to put them
up on stage, and let me show you how tough
I am. We’ll get your three year old nephew,
and we’ll put him up here, on the table,
and let me tease him. Let me show you how
tough I am. That’s what you are! I could
pick on you, you biggest bullies. I could
pick on anything you like. Any singer, any
music that you like. I could tease you, I
could tease your family, I could tease your
friends, I could tease about the movies you
think are really cool, I could tease anything
about you. I could tease you about your nose,
your eyes, your teeth, your chin, your hair,
your ears, your elbows, your knees, your whatever,
man! I can tease you about anything. It ain’t
hard, just like you can tease me.
You want to know what tough is? Go to the
people you tease, and say sorry. You want
to know what tough is, go up to the people
who still tease you, and say, hey. Stop it,
I forgive you, but please stop it. That’s
tough.
I want you to know something, the truth of
who you are. I don’t care what job you get.
I don’t care. I don’t care how smart you
are, everyone. I don’t care. I don’t care,
I love you and I believe in you. I don’t
care if you end up being a janitor in this
school, I’ll tell you why – because the
janitor in my high school inspired me to be
a speaker. He changed my life. He said, you
should be a speaker, you know, and I said,
you’re crazy! He said no really, you need
to be a speaker. I said, stop it man. Four
months later, he twisted my arm, and I said
yes. I spoke in front of ten people, then
another ten, then another ten, then I found
myself in front of 300 sophomore students.
And three minutes into my speech, half the
girls were crying, and one girl in the middle
of the room started weeping. She put up her
hand and said “I’m so sorry, can I come
up there and give you a hug.” And in front
of everybody, she came up and she hugged me,
and she cried on my shoulder, and she whispered
in this ear. Thank you, thank you, thank you,
no one’s ever told me that they love me.
No one’s ever told me that I’m beautiful
the way that I am.
It was because my parents told me that I was
beautiful that I am still here. Some of you
don’t have those parents, and that’s why
I’m here. I love you and you’re beautiful
just the way you are. Never, ever give up.
How many schools do you think that I spoke
to actually stopped bullying altogether? OK.
Whoever said one, you are correct. One school
out of 600, I got a letter from the headmaster,
and he said Nick, you forever changed our
school, blah blah blah. We haven’t seen
any bullies pick on anybody for eight months
straight. We don’t know what happened, but
in the best words that I can describe, there’s
just a new thought in the air that it just
ain’t cool anymore. It just ain’t cool.
I want to ask you: What are you going to do?
Are you going to continue on? At the risk
of knowing that in each section, this section,
right here, five people already tried to commit
suicide. That section there? Five people.
When you extrapolate it out? What if the person
you’re teasing is one of those and you have
no idea. Would you find something else to
do?
So, the change is up to you. If you want to
see more love in your school, be love. If
50% of the school come together and say you
know what, it just ain’t cool anymore the
people who think it’s still cool, every
time they look down upon you, I want you to
look up. I want you to imagine my face looking
at you. Because I’m telling you, everyone
you’re teasing is my brother and my sister.
And you’re my brother, and you’re my sister.
And I’m asking you to stop.
Love yourself a bit more, love each other
a lot more.