a pop of cap in your ass
you want to learn some slang yeah you do
the slang we're going to learn today is
pop so
maybe you know a kind of music called
pop music
do you know that pop actually means
popular
so when you think oh i really like pop
music
that actually means that you like
popular music
maybe you know this one i'm thirsty
i wish i had a soda
but sometimes we call it pop
do you have a favorite pop cola
mmm maybe a little fruity drink for you
in some parts of america they say soda
and some other parts they say pop
what are you gonna say soda pop
i just i'm gonna pop in an egg here so
when we're cooking something
it's it just means to put in so i'm just
gonna
pop in or i'm just gonna put in
the definition i'm just gonna pop it
right in there you won't even know it's
there
it needs to put something in fast oh but
not like that
oh dirty mind
she just popped another one out
what did she do this means
she had a baby
do you have a baby
so to pop another one out needs to have
another baby
they are only five bucks
or five dollars a pop this means they're
only
five dollars each so you might go to the
store and someone's like
how much are those they say five bucks a
pop you want one
it means they're only five dollars each
pop-up shop pop-pop shop
a pop-up shop is a store that is not
normally there
but it appears out of nowhere oh my god
it's a store
so to pop up means to come by surprise
are you surprised so a pop-up shop means
a store
that's only there for a short amount of
time
do you hate when you're watching
something
on your computer and all of a sudden an
ad comes on
they're evil evil ads so you what you
want to do
is you want to install a pop-up blocker
so this blocks the pop-up now
a pop-up means an advertising
advertisement and we just say
add i like to add a pop-up blocker
ah do you know what i want to tell you
guys something
my pops is the best he is
so handsome like me and really cool and
amazing he's getting my hair
i have his hair and that means my father
so my pops actually refers to
my father do you have a father
bad subject isn't it
his head popped off this means that i
took my knife
and his head just popped right up so if
somebody's head pops off
it really doesn't just pop off means
that
somebody has to cut it off or slay it
off if
somebody's head pops off it just means
it it came off very easily
if you'd like that arranged call me
his eye popped out
do you know what that means it means
that somebody's
eyeball actually
came right out of his eye oh glorious
eyeballs
all over so if your eye pops out it
comes out suddenly
did you get what i said at the beginning
i said i pop a cap in your ass
this means i'm going to shoot you and
notice i said didn't say you're i said
yo
so this means you're
so if someone offers to pop a cap and
you ass
you should maybe maybe disagree and say
nah
you know what nah i'm good thank you
thanks no don't need it
he just popped him one
right in the eye right now right there
he's popping right in the eye
this mean that he punched him
it's very violent this english lesson
isn't it
it's very violent oh this isn't violent
what about my new hair color do you
think it pops with my skin tone
so we can say that color really pops
we talk about design you talk about
something that stands out from the crowd
i don't stand up from the crowd i don't
know why you'd say that
i just pop up in fun places
and i wear colors that pop
if you are scared that's the purpose
learning english is very scary
especially slang okay