My name's Ronnie and I'm going
to teach you some grammar.
It's kind of a... difficult grammar, but once
you learn this overview of-dunh, dunh, dunh,
dunh-"Auxiliary Verbs", English grammar is
going to become easier for you, I hope.
So, if you're just beginning to learn English
grammar, oh, stay in there, you can do it.
Yuri, this goes out to
you in Salvador, Brazil.
Let's keep going, man.
We have three auxiliary verbs that we
use in English: "be", "do", and "have".
But the thing about the auxiliary verbs is
that each auxiliary verb will tell us what
kind of grammar we're
going to use with it.
So, let's look at the
first one: "be".
So, "be" in its form in the present tense
is "am", "is", "are"; negative: "am not",
"isn't", and "aren't".
These are present.
The past tense would
be present...
Or, no.
The past tense in the positive is "was" and
"were"; negative: "wasn't" and "weren't".
So, how do we actually
use this auxiliary verb?
And the answer is: We use it in
two forms of English grammar.
The first one is progressive.
So, if you have a progressive sentence, we
have present progressive, past progressive,
and future progressive.
Every time we have a sentence in English with
progressive, we know we're going to use the
verb "to be".
So, if our sentence is present progressive,
we're going to use the present tense of the
verb "to be", "is am are"
with a verb with "ing".
So, in English grammar, anything that's progressive
or continuous is another word for the same
grammar, it's always going
to be an "ing" on the verb.
The thing that changes and tells us
the grammar is the verb "to be".
Present is: "is", "am", "are", plus verb "ing",
but the past, we're going to use the past
tense: "was" and "were"
plus verb "ing".
So, progressive will
always have a verb "ing".
The thing that changes the tense
of it is the verb "to be".
We have future progressive
or future continuous.
In this one we're simply going to use the
verb "will", so in this one we have "will
be" plus verb "ing".
For example: "I will
be eating pizza."
This tells us what's going
to happen in the future.
"I was eating pizza" was the past, and "I am
eating pizza", something's happening now,
that's present progressive.
So, the progressive will always have the verb
"to be", either past, present, or future,
and it will always have
an "ing" on the verb.
Okay, cool.
Let's get more
complicated, okay?
We have another structure in
English grammar called passive.
Now, passive voice basically you're taking
the action from the person or the focus on
the person, and we're putting
it towards the activity.
So, in a normal English sentence we would say:
"I eat lunch", but in a passive sentence,
we're taking away the subject and
we're focusing on the action.
So, with the passive voice we have future
passive, present passive, and past passive.
It goes along the same idea, is that the verb
"to be" is going to tell us: Is it present?
Or if it's past.
When we use a passive sentence, we can only
ever use the past participle of the verb,
or the third step of the verb.
So, passive will always be the verb
"to be" plus the past participle.
If it's present, it's: "is", "am",
"are", plus PP, past participle.
If it's past, it's "was" and
"were" plus past participle.
It's hard to say the past
participle, so I'm going to say PP.
I have to go PP.
So, as an example, we say:
"Lunch is eaten", present tense.
"Lunch was eaten".
I'm going to step away and
let you check that out.
Let your brain absorb it.
Make some sentences using
this and the verb "to be".
If we used the future passive, I could say:
"Lunch will be eaten", so again, when we're
using the future, we use "will be", but
we're going to use the past participle.
Have you made some sentences?
Do it now.
Come on.
Make some sentences.
Go.
Okay.
So we've done the verb "to be".
And hopefully it's beginning to make sense,
because English grammar rarely makes sense.
I'm going to make it make
it make sense for you.
So, the next one is the
auxiliary verb "do".
Now, this one's interesting because we only
use it in the negative form in the simple
present, or we use it in
the negative simple past.
So we don't have to worry about the positive,
but we do use it for the negative in the simple
present and the negative in
the past, and for questions.
So, let's check out first the
simple present, or present simple.
We only use this auxiliary verb for
the negative and the question form.
So, in the negative we're going to use subject,
plus "don't" or "doesn't", plus the base verb.
Now, this is where English gets tricky and you
have to remember that if it is "I", "you",
"we" and "they", we use "don't".
But if it's "he", "she", or
"it", we have to use "doesn't".
So this is...
You always have to be careful with
your subject and your verb agreement.
They have to agree.
So, as an example: "I
don't like pizza."
If I used "he", I would say:
"He doesn't like pizza."
And we have to be careful
and use the base verb.
Okay?
The question would be:
"Does he like pizza?"
Ar?
Like a dog.
If it's a question form, we put the auxiliary
verb first: "do", "doesn't", subject, plus
the base verb.
Not the base verb,
We also use this in the past simple, again,
only with negative and only with a question.
So, the way that
we change "did"...
Sorry, "does" into the negative is "didn't"
in the past, but this is where we always make
a mistake.
I've told you English grammar
is crazy, I'm not joking.
When we use "didn't", we always
have to use the base verb.
So, this is where we get confused, because
we think: "Ronnie, this is past tense."
So, if it's past tense, we have to use the
past of the verb-mm-mm-because our auxiliary
verb "didn't" makes
the sentence past.
So, if it's an auxiliary verb it's going to
tell us if it's past or present, and we have
to use the base verb.
So, we have to say:
"He didn't go home."
You cannot say: "He
didn't went home."
That's grammatically wrong.
This verb tells us it's past, and
this verb tells us it's present.
Oh, that's kind of cool
when you learn it.
If you're doing the question form, it's very
similar to this, past tense: "Did", subject,
plus your base.
Again, you always
have to be careful.
Even though it is past, we actually have to
use the base verb because the "did" or the
auxiliary verb tells us: "Hey, this
is a past tense, not a present tense.
Please use the base verb."
So: "Did", "didn't".
Ah.
"Didn't" in the negative
and "did" in the question.
Another tip when you are speaking English and
you're asking someone a question, always
ask them a positive question.
It's more difficult for the listener, and
for the speaker, and for everyone involved
if you use a negative question.
So, just for now, you're just learning
this, always ask a positive question.
"Did I go home?",
"Didn't I go home?"
The negative question is always much more
confusing, and we need to make English grammar
simpler.
Ah.
We're almost done here.
I'm going to step away and
let your absorb this.
Please make one, two, three, four
sentences using the auxiliary verb "do".
And we're back with the last one, the last
one, the most exciting one maybe ever.
Yeah.
This is the most exciting one.
We are going to use "have has", negative "haven't",
and "hasn't", and then we have the past: "had"
and "hadn't".
So, when we use the verb as an auxiliary "have",
we use it for perfect tenses in English.
They're so perfect.
So, when we use the perfect tense, our verb
is always going to be the past participle,
just like in the passive.
So the passive and the perfects in English,
we always use the past participle.
And again, we can have the future perfect,
we can have present perfect, and we can have
past perfect.
So, the way we form the future perfect is
we're going to use subject with "will", so
future we use "will" all the time,
"have", and then the past participle.
Okay?
Or we can also use "has".
So, the future we use "will" plus "have",
plus the past participle or the PP.
If we're using present perfect, we're going
to use the subject: "have" or "has", plus
the past participle.
So, if you can think about this: "have" in
the present tense is "have" and "has", so
in the past tense we're going to use
"had" plus the past participle.
So, if we're using past perfect,
we're using "had", plus PP.
If we're talking about present
perfect, we're using "has" plus PP.
People get confused and a lot of people think
that the present perfect is the present tense,
but it's not.
The present perfect
talks about the past.
The thing that makes the verb present or past
is our wonderful auxiliary verb: "have".
If the verb "have" is present perfect,
we use the present tense of the verb.
If we use the past tense, if we use past perfect,
we're going to use the past tense of "have".
So: "I haven't eaten lunch.
Oh, I'm hungry."
Future: "I will have played seven games", so
we're using "will", "have", plus the past
participle.
If we use present perfect, we use: "he", "she",
"it has eaten", "you already have eaten".
You have to be careful again on your
subject and your verb agreement.
There're so many
things to remember.
And then the past participle...
Or, sorry, the past perfect, all we're doing
is changing "has" or "have" to "had".
And this one's cool, because we don't have
to worry about "he", "she", and "it"; they
all use "had".
Thank you for being
easy, past perfect.
If you have questions about these specific
grammar points, if you don't know what these
grammar points are, if you want to know more detail
about them, you know the website: www.engvid.com,
you can search in the search area and you
can find exactly the grammar points and how
we use them.
But the thing that I need you to understand
is the auxiliary verbs are going to help you
understand grammar
easier I hope.
If you have questions, throw it to me
in the comment box and I can help you.
Until next time,
I'm out of here.