Hello everyone. And welcome back to English
with Lucy. Today I have a very special guest.
This is my fiance, William.
Hello everyone.
Will has never been on this channel before.
No.
So it's an honour.
It's been long overdue.
It has. So I've seen that many of you have
requested a video on daily routines. So I
thought it would be a good idea for us to
have a conversation and tell you about our
daily routines. And then I'll pick out some
vocabulary to show you. So this is a fantastic
listening lesson, pronunciation lesson, because
you can see how we pronounce specific words.
Don't forget to switch on subtitles if you
need them. And to make this even better, I've
created a PDF sheet for you, which contains
all of the key vocabulary. All you have to
do to download that is click on the link in
the description box and sign up to my mailing
list. It will be sent directly to your inbox.
Also, don't forget to share your own daily
routine in the comment section down below.
I'd love to know what time you wake up, what
you eat for breakfast, what you have for lunch,
what you have for dinner, and also what time
you go to bed. So first I think we should
introduce ourselves because although we are
getting married, we live quite different lives,
don't we?
Couldn't be more different really.
Yeah. So we live in the same house, but we
have very different jobs. I am an English
teacher, but I work on YouTube.
And I am a farmer and I work mainly outdoors
on the farm.
Yes. So quite the unique pair I think. My
first question for you is what time do you
usually wake up?
Usually I would wake up at 5:30 to 6:00.
Yes, but what time do you get up?
But I get up at 6:00.
Yeah. So there's an important difference between
wake up and get up. When your eyes open in
the morning, you wake up. But when you leave
your bed in the morning, you get up and Will
has a big problem. This gap between waking
up and getting up is getting bigger and bigger.
Isn't it?
I've gone from setting one alarm to three
alarms.
Three alarms, and I have to lay next to him
hearing each alarm. So I have a very different
job. I, well, I wake up at 5:30, at 5:45 at
6:00 with Will. But I keep on sleeping and
I get up at 7:30. But something very important
happens between that time frame I think.
I feed the pets and I bring up a couple of
coffees.
Yes. So very important. In the morning when
Will gets up before he goes to work, he brings
me a coffee in bed and we try to have a coffee
together. It's a nice routine to have, I think.
Yeah. It's a good start to the day.
Yeah. But it's interesting because Will's
job isn't the same all year round. In summer
you're really, really busy. I mean, what time
do you wake up in the summer?
4:30 normally.
Really, really early. So in the UK, we have
very long days in the summer and very short
days in the winter. If you're from Norway,
Sweden, or anywhere more up North, you'll
think, "What are you complaining about?" But
I remember when I was teaching English in
Spain, people were surprised that the sun
would rise at 4:30 in the morning in summer
and then set at 10:00 at night. But then in
the winter, the sun doesn't come up till 9:00
and then it can set at 3:30. So it's a big
difference. So your days in summer are so
much longer.
Yeah.
So let's move on to having breakfast. I normally
have breakfast at around 8:00. When do you
have yours?
Either 7:30, before I go out to work again
or at 10:00.
Oh yes. Because you go out and come back in
for a break.
Yeas.
Yeah. And what do you usually have?
Normally I would eat a bowl of cereal or I'd
have a plate of toast.
Toast. Yes. Or on a special occasion, bacon
sandwiches.
Very special.
Bacon sandwiches on special occasions, or
what about a full English breakfast?
Only on weekends.
Yes. So this is a really famous breakfast
in the UK. The full English where you have
eggs, sausages, bacon.
Black pudding.
Black pudding. What's black pudding? I don't
think some of my students will like it.
You don't need to know then.
It's sausage made out of blood. Black pudding,
hash brown.
Hash browns.
It's like fried potato. Baked beans.
French toast.
Yeah. Toast fried in oil. And we often have
a cooked tomato and cooked mushrooms as well.
So it's a huge breakfast, very high fat. And
we normally have it if we have drunk alcohol
the night before.
Yes.
So it's something you'd have if you are hung
over. You can have a hangover or you can be
hung over. This is important. They need to
know it. Because I think they see the English
breakfast sometimes and think that, that's
what we eat every morning. And that's not
true.
No.
You have to be really hungry for an English
breakfast.
We don't.
No. We don't eat every morning. I would say
maybe five times a year.
Yeah. Not a lot.
Five times a year. If we go to a hotel full
English. Sometimes we compress it down to
a flinglish. Can I have a flinglish. So for
my breakfast, I nearly always have it at around
8:00 and I normally have porridge. So that's
oats and milk cooked with some fruit like
banana, nectarines, or plums at the moment.
And in summer I use blueberries and bananas.
Delicious.
So the next thing that I do after breakfast
is I do some exercise. In American English,
it's more common to say I work out. And we
do say this, but it's not as commonly used
in British English. I do a workout. Yes. But
I work out. I mean, would you think it's more
American?
Yes, definitely.
Yeah. So I either go to the gym and do an
exercise class or I stay on the farm and I
go for a run. I go for a run. If you do exercise,
what do you do?
I do a lot of walking all day. So 80% of my
day will be walking. And we have a Fitbit
that tracks every step we take, every move
we make. And that tracks our steps every day.
Yeah. And we have a competition. So you can
see all the steps that our friends and family
have done. And if Will remembers to wear his
Fitbit, he always wins. It's so annoying.
I run 10 kilometres and I still don't beat
Will because you just spend all day walking.
So all day, nearly every day I will be lifting
bags, shovelling grain, just a lot of physical
work really.
Yeah. So you said shovelling.
Yes. Shovelling.
So that's to use a shovel or a spade. It's
the verb of using that. I think that was a
good one. And grain. Grain is basically seeds
like wheat, barley, oats, and a thing like
that. That's what Will grows on his farm.
So Will also does some work in a little gym
that we have set up. We have put in place
downstairs and I see you do lots of-
Bicep curls.
Bicep curls. Squats.
Squats.
I do some squats at the gym sometimes.
Yes.
And bench presses as well.
Yes. Bench press.
Those are the three that I really see you
do.
Yep.
Yeah. Anything else?
What else? Press ups.
Press ups. When you're down going like that.
And some chin ups.
Oh yes. When you pull your body up like that.
Yeah.
I hope you enjoyed my demonstration of that.
I won't be starting a fitness channel. One
thing that takes a lot of time for me is doing
my makeup and doing my hair. It's a long process.
I'm exactly the same. Exactly the same. Why
else do you think I get up at 4:30 in the
morning?
You got to look good for those fields. I also
spend a long time writing scripts and doing
a lot of researching because I'm always learning
as well. So I have an idea for an English
lesson in my head, and then I'll spend a full
day researching and writing the scripts for
the next day's filming. So on a Monday, I'll
do the research and the writing. On a Tuesday,
I'll do the filming. On a Wednesday, we'll
get all the editing done. And then on the
Thursdays and Fridays, I'll do more admin
work. So looking at my accounts, the finances,
replying to emails, sending emails. It's a
full time job.
Yeah.
It's a full time job.
It is.
Will has a very specific lunchtime. What time
is it?
1:00.
1:00 is lunch time. It has to be lunch time
because that's when Will's dad has lunch as
well. And you work with your dad.
Yeah.
Yeah. So at 1:00 every day we come in and
we have lunch and we both have different lunches,
don't we?
Yes.
Yeah. We hardly ever eat the same thing.
Yes. I normally have a sandwich.
In the winter I always have soup. I love having
something warm for lunch because I'm quite
a cold person. I get cold very easily. And
in the summer I nearly always have salad,
but not boring salad. I like to make interesting
salads with different seeds. I like to use
butternut squash.
Yep.
Yep. So that's similar to pumpkin. Some cheese
like feta cheese or mozzarella. And I try
to include a bit of protein like chicken or
fish as well. In the UK we to have a light
lunch and a heavy dinner. I know this is different
in some countries and cultures. I remember
when I lived in Spain, we would have a big
lunch and then a lighter dinner. And this
was really hard for me especially as the dinner
time was so late. Whereas in England we eat
dinner quite early.
But before we talk about dinner, what do we
do in the afternoons? When I know one thing
that I often do is I walk the dog. I love
taking our dog Diego on a long walk across
all the fields. And I think he loves that
too.
Yes he does.
He loves it. Okay. Let's talk about dinner
time. Here we normally have dinner at around
6:00. Although sometimes in the summer we'll
have it later. Maximum 8:00, right?
Yeah, latest.
Yeah, latest 8:00. And what do we typically
have for dinner?
Our meals are quite varied. We normally eat
fish twice a week.
Yes. So one of my favourite dishes is to cook
salmon with lemon, asparagus and potatoes.
We have that every single week. Don't we?
Yes, we do.
And then we have other fish like tuna, sea
bass.
Sea bream.
Sea bream. Haddock?
Sometimes yes.
Basa as well. I love Basa. We do eat a lot
of fish, two or three times a week. One of
Will's favourites is steak. So I do that every
now and again. We do it on the barbecue.
Yap.
And we also like doing chicken and salads
inspired by the Italians. We do a lot of prawn
linguini with lemon and sun dried tomatoes.
That's delicious. And then on a Sunday we
often have a very traditional British meal.
The Sunday roast. Sometimes I make it myself
and sometimes we go.  Well more often we
go to the pub.
I think more often we go to the pub.
Definitely. Definitely. I love going out on
a Sunday afternoon for a Sunday roast.
A Sunday roast is made up of one meat.
Yeah. So typically turkey, chicken, lamb,
pork, or beef.
Yes. One side of potatoes.
Roast potatoes. So roast potatoes are very
special. You peel them, you boil them. Then
you cover them in fat, like an oil or sometimes
duck fat or goose fat. And then you put them
in the oven and cook them until they're golden
and crispy. They are so good.
They are delicious.
They're amazing. And every British person
thinks that their parents, their moms or their
grandma's Sunday roast potatoes are the best.
And then vegetables, you'll have two to three
or more.
Could be more. Your mom does four different
vegetables.
She loves it.
She does such a good roast.
Okay. Let's say for different types of vegetables
will be on your plate as well. That would
be broccoli, cabbage, peas, beans, carrots.
Carrots, parsnips.
Parsnips. Yes.
That's the one vegetable that I.  I will
eat it. There's nothing I won't eat, but parsnips,
I would not choose to have them. They're too
sweet for me. But often with chicken or with
turkey, because they're birds, they have stuffing,
which is.  What is stuffing?
Stuffing is made up of chopped nuts.
Onion.
Flour.
And some herbs and they're all blended together
and made into a bowl.
Yeah.
Really.
And it's quite doughy. He's quite heavy. And
then we also have Yorkshire puddings, which
is like a big.  It's like a big fluffy pancake
almost. The mixture is the same as pancake
mixture, but it's very light and airy. It
starts off with this size and it grows and
grows. And if I have one, I always give it
to Will because it's just too much food for
me.
And Will accepts.
He does. And then the best bit is the gravy,
which is a meat sauce made from the juices
of the meat and you pour that all over and
it's absolutely delicious. Let's move on to
the end of the day. What about baths or showers?
Because I prefer a bath, but if I have to
wash my hair, then I'll have a shower. And
I normally have it in the morning so that
my hair can be clean for the rest of the day.
When do you have yours?
So every night before I go to bed, about 9:30
to 10:00. I have a shower.
Yeah, just before bed.
I never have a bath. I can't fit in baths.
So Will is six foot six or 1.98 metres tall,
nearly two metres. So baths are often not
an option. What time do you normally go to
bed?
I normally go to bed between 10:00 and 10:30.
Yes. So we go to bed quite early, but obviously
it's because we wake up quite early as well.
Will wakes up very early. But after Will wakes
up in the morning, I find it hard to go back
to sleep. So I also go to bed between 10:00
and 10:30. We would like to know what time
you wake up and what time you go to bed and
any other information of what you do and at
what time in your own daily routine. Please
write it down below in the comments section.
Right. So that's it for today's lesson. I
hope you enjoyed it. And I hope you learned
something and don't forget to download that
PDF with all of the vocabulary from today's
video. It's really, really useful. Just click
on the link in the description box. If you
want to see more of us, you could check out
the vlogging channel. It's called Lucy Bella.
Again, there is the link down below. We show
our life on a farm in the English countryside
and don't forget to connect with us on all
of our social media. My Facebook, my Instagram,
my mailing list. And you can actually find
Will on Instagram if you want to. We'll put
that down there. Right. We will see you soon
for another lesson.