Krista Smith:
Over 70 performances you've had, of characters
that you've played to me when I look at some
of this stuff, and obviously, this year you
have two films, Boy Erased and Destroyer,
which you guys are lucky enough to be going
to see after we finish chatting.
But it seems like your work is only getting
better and more interesting as you go along
in your career.
Do you look at things differently now than
you did, let's say when you were just starting
out and we first met you when you came, it
was dead calm, I think.
And then you went into Days of Thunder and
you kind of started your path here in America
with that?
Nicole Kidman:
I started actually at 14 in a film called
Bush Christmas.
And I got to get out of school for six weeks.
And, but I think my whole journey has always
been trying to find characters.
And as an actor, you're very much, you're
not in the driver's seat.
I mean, you need a director to choose you.
You audition a lot, particularly when you're
young, it's like, that's what you do.
And sometimes you get the role and sometimes
you don't.
And I think you just have to have a passion
and sort of view it as a long term because
for me it was always the journey.
I wanted to go and explore the world.
I wanted to explore the human psyche.
I wanted to live a well-examined life.
And by doing what I do and being given the
chance to be able to act, it's taken me on
this extraordinary road and I've worked with
the greatest directors in the world, I've
been around the greatest minds.
I've been the recipient of some of the greatest
writers and their words.
So, it's an amazing place to be, but I never
would've thought that it was going to be like
this.
I dreamed big, but not like this.
Krista Smith:
And how do you sustain that passion and curiosity
and energy to take on what you do because
you do give a hundred percent at every single
performance, whether it is a supporting or
the lead?
Nicole Kidman:
I mean, it ebbs and flows and that's the truth
of it.
There's times when you go, I just don't have
anything left to give.
And there's been times when I've gone, okay,
I'm now drained.
I don't know where I'm at in my life.
I've got to go and find, and I always say,
you know, you have to have the life to then
be able to go and put it into your art.
And I've had a crazy life.
I just have, and I've also had, I'm a highly
sensitive person and I also attach very strongly
to people.
And so, with that comes all of the emotions
that are attached to that.
And that then gives me the well to draw from.
But I'm also just, I'm still very curious.
I'm still, I still have this passion for the
work and for being on the set, and that time
between action and cut, it is still extraordinary
to me.
And sometimes it falls and you just go, I'm
never, ever going to be any good ever again.
And then something happens and it ignites
and you're off.
And I love it and I still love it to this
day.
Krista Smith:
Now you've said before that Moulin Rouge is
the film that if you see it on TV, you have
to watch it.
Perhaps, I don't want to say one of your favourite
films, but how important was that moment and
that character, what you did in Moulin Rouge
with Baz and playing Satine?
Nicole Kidman:
I mean, I grew up in a family where musicals
were considered the best that, that was what
you wanted to do.
My family, we would stand around the piano.
We would sing.
That was, but I don't have a great voice.
I have a medium voice, but I don't have a
voice that could sustain a Broadway show,
eight shows a week for, you know, years.
But suddenly Moulin Rouge came along and it
was like, oh my gosh, I get to sing and dance
and act, which is what they used to do.
I mean, the great actresses all could do all
of those things.
So, it was kind of like being given this opportunity.
Then of course I freaked out and went I can't
do it, and Baz kind of had to push me into
it.
And he's such a showman, Baz.
I mean, he just, so he almost willed that
performance and that out of me.
And I'd always said, I wanted to make a love
story as much as I make so many dark films.
And I explore all the territories that are,
you know, I like going into places that are
considered uncomfortable and dangerous.
I also love, love.
And I just had never been in a great love
story.
And I see Moulin Rouge is a love story and
I love being a part of that and putting that
in the world.
Krista Smith:
That was one of the great love stories.
It was so great to see the little bits of
it here.
And speaking of those dark characters, obviously,
Destroyer is, what struck me about this film
was first off, you're unrecognizable in it
from when you see it on the poster.
The just physical transformation that you
did, obviously in makeup and hair and that.
But it was your whole walk and your body and
your voice.
You almost changed from the inside out.
Nicole Kidman:
I mean, that's what you do as an actor.
I don't like focusing on the hair and the
makeup and all of those things, because I
still believe in the mystery of the performance.
And there's such a desire now for people to
tell you everything and dissect everything
and give you.
But there's magic involved.
And I love keeping that magic too so that
then people just watch the film.
I mean, I have to say this year, I got given,
well, it was last year, but they've seemed
to have come out within a couple of months
of each other.
But Boy Erased and Destroyer, to have both
those characters in the same year is amazing
at this time of my life.
And they're both really extreme and you're
not seeing Boy Erased tonight, but by talking
about the two, one of them is they're both
mothers, they're both on a path trying to
heal what they've done to their children.
And I find that really powerful and emotional.
And I love that they're so different, but
strangely enough, they're on the same path.
And that was really, really interesting to
me.
And I actually did Boy Erased, I had four
weeks off, and then I went straight into Destroyer.
And then I collapsed.
Krista Smith:
Yeah.
I was going to say because it's a very physical
performance and it's also very masculine,
but yet so deeply feminine.
Nicole Kidman:
Well, I would say it's deeply female.
Krista Smith:
Yeah, it is.
Nicole Kidman:
Which is a weird thing to say, but I do see
it as deeply female because her motivations
are female.
I mean, you haven't seen the movie yet, but
there's a moment when, and only a woman gets
to experience this when she finds out she's
pregnant and it's a flash.
She's high, she's doing cocaine and that is
devastating for her.
That's the beginning of her relationship with
her child.
So, that's a female situation for her.
That is, and it's so complicated and devastating.
It leads her on this very, very destructive
path.
But she's maternal and she's operating from
a maternal force.
It may have been a maternal force that has
made massive mistakes, has not been there,
and has not been what we call a good mother.
But she's a mother and the basis for so much
of her motivations and her drive is from that.
And her shame and her pain.
Thank you for having us.
Krista Smith:
Thank you.
Enjoy the film.