Hello. Welcome to my bedroom. It's not my bedroom.
It's a whiteboard with words on it,
but I'm going to teach you about bedroom -- vocabulary that is.
Stay tuned. Maybe I'll teach you
some other bedroom vocabulary if you know what I mean.
We're going to go on the innocent
side today, and I'm going to teach you about
basic things in bedrooms. I know. I know.
Okay. This is a bed. Do
you sleep on a bed, or do
you sleep on a futon? Did I speak Japanese?
Hi, Japanese people in the house. Konnichiwa.
O-genki desu ka? When you sleep, you usually
sleep on a "futon". We have stolen your word.
We're so nice. And we use it for our own.
"Futon" -- if you know or don't know -- is,
basically, a mattress that you put on the floor.
It sounds kind of uncomfortable, but
it's really, really good if you're really
drunk, and there's never a fear of falling
out of the bed. You just kind of roll over and,
boom, you're awake. It has some advantages
and some disadvantages. So this is a picture of a bed.
I am an artist. Remember this as
we go through this. The first
very common thing that you will
find in a bedroom is a pillow. "Pillow". A
lot of people -- I don't know why -- have
never learned this word in English. I know
it's not in a lot of textbooks. You don't
open your textbook and go, "Wow, this is a
pillow." You're more like, "This is a pen."
Thanks. I know that. So the first one is a pillow.
A "pillow" is a soft or hard, squishy
thing that you put your head on -- not that head; this head.
And to keep your pillow clean,
you're going to put a pillow case on it. A
"pillow case" is like a cover for the pillow.
You can take the pillow case off, and please wash it.
You can have different kinds of pillows.
There're feather pillows. So what we do is
we take a duck or a goose; we kill it; we
take all its feathers off; and we stick them in a pillow.
Yeah. I don't think that's really
cool. Or you can just have a fluffy cotton
pillow or another microfibre pillow. You have
a pillow case. The next thing
that is essential for a bed
-- please -- are sheets. Now be careful with
your pronunciation. You don't want to say
"shits". That's the stuff that comes out of your bum.
You want to say "sheets". When you
say this, the "e's" are very long. So you're
going to say "sheets". Usually, we have a
top sheet and a fitted sheet. The fitted sheet
just means it's the bottom sheet. They like
to use fancy words like fitted sheet, top
sheet -- just two sheets. And you know what?
You can use just two of these. Don't worry about it.
The top sheet -- it goes on top.
And the fitted sheet goes on the bottom. It
covers -- the main part of your bed here is
a mattress. The "mattress" is, like, a big
fluffy thing that you get to relax on. And
the black part of my picture would be a bed frame.
Let's write that down. It's important.
So a "bed frame" is the support of the mattress.
Pillow, pillow case, sheets, top and bottom
or fitted sheets. Next: In Canada,
or maybe in your country,
in the winter, it's cold. You want something to cover you.
Sheets are very thin. They're
usually made of cotton. A "cover" or a "blanket",
a "duvet" -- du-what? This word is a French
word. So the way that we say it looks very
different from the spelling. It looks like
"duvette". I think that maybe some people --
especially people in America -- would say,
"I got a new duvette cover. It's got some
'dubyas' on it." It's actually very important
that you say this properly and you say "duvet".
So it's like "du-vay".
The next one is a comforter. "Comforter",
"duvet", "blanket", "cover", and the last
one, a "quilt" -- they're all the same. Don't
tell people who like to design beds and fabrics
that it's just something that keeps you warm.
There are slight differences between a quilt,
a comforter, and a duvet, but you can discover
that for yourself. You've got homework. Go
to a store. Ask the people that work there
to show you a quilt, a comforter, a duvet,
a blanket, and a cover. You're
practicing your English.
The next thing that you would have in your bedroom
is furniture. "Furniture" is an uncountable
noun. "Furniture" includes a bed, a nightstand --
"Ronnie, what's a 'nightstand'?" Oh, "standing
up", "nighttime" -- what? No. A nightstand or
-- maybe this makes more sense -- a bedside
table. Look at my picture. This thing right
here is a "bedside table". It's beside your
bed, and it's a table. I know. Sometimes English makes sense.
"Nightstand" or "bedside table"
-- these are the same. Some people say "nightstand";
some people say "bedside table". Some people
just say "that thing beside the bed". But it
is definitely a bedside table or nightstand.
Also, we have "dresser" or -- long way to say
it -- "dresser drawers", or you can just
say "drawers". It's your choice. I naturally
would say "dresser". I would say, "I'm going
to put my clothes into the dresser." A "dresser"
is a piece of furniture that you put your
clothes into -- clean clothes, people. Don't
put your dirty socks in my dresser. So you're
going to put your beautifully folded up underwear
and socks into a dresser. Maybe above your
dresser you have a mirror. A "mirror" is something
that you look at and you can see yourself
-- your reflection. You see yourself in the mirror.
It's most common to have a mirror
in a bath -- bathroom. What? In the bedroom
and the bathroom as well. People like to look
at themselves, make sure
everything is in the right places.
This -- this contraption made by Satan is
called an "alarm clock". You might just know
the word "alarm". That's okay. You can just
say "alarm", but please, please, please, when
you say this word, do not say this word by mistake.
"Alarm clock". You have to -- right
there. If you say "alarm cock" -- "cock" means penis.
Don't say "alarm cock". You want to
say "alarm clock". Alarm clock goes off when
it's time for you to get out of bed, go to
work, go to school. We have a magic button on the alarm clock.
And this is call a "snooze button"
or "snooze bar". A "snooze button" is magic.
It gives you ten long, luscious
minutes of extra sleeping time. So if your alarm
clock is set for 7:02, you hit the snooze,
and it will give you ten minutes more sleep.
You might hear people saying to their boss
-- the boss might say, "Why are you late?"
"I hit the snooze. I -- I -- I -- I just hit
the snooze five times. That's an hour, so I'm
late." Good excuse. If you're late, just
say, "I hit the snooze." And they're, like,
"Oh, yeah!" Okay? Danger button. Ten minutes
of lovely sleep. If you watch
a very popular TV show called
"Sex in the City" or any, I guess, TV show,
women -- mostly, ladies in the house -- are
going to go on about a "walk-in closet". Normally,
in houses, you're going to have a closet.
A "closet" -- it's like a little room. There's a door.
You open it, and inside is where we
hang our clothes. These are clothes. If you're
lucky enough to have a walk-in closet, it's
like a whole other entity or a whole other room.
A "walk-in closet" is, basically, a
room. And it is really, really big, and there're
lots of places to hang all of your clothes
that you never wear. So a "walk-in closet"
just means a "very big closet". In my house,
I have a closet. Don't open it, though. You
never know what's going to come flying out.
Another word for "closet" is "cupboard", which
is very strange. The pronunciation of this
word is very strange. We say "kub burd", "cupboard".
It looks like "cup board". A long, long time
ago, we would definitely have a cupboard in our kitchen.
Now we have a cupboard in our
bedroom. So a "closet" and a "cupboard" are the same.
It's a place to put your clothes.
I hope you enjoyed the lesson. If you have
questions about your bedroom, ask me. Bye.