Score!
You just found this lesson, and this lesson
is on "score".
And you're probably confused: Why did I just
say: "Score"?
Because I say it all the time.
I use this when I find something that's cool
or good.
So, for example, if I am walking down the
street and I see-dunh-dunh-dunh-dunh-20 dollars,
I go: "Score!" because I found something.
"Score" is a word that has many meanings,
and I'm going to teach you what they mean
in slang-yes-and also what they mean in regular,
everyday language.
But slang is more fun, so let's start with
the regular, everyday language first of "score".
There's a really famous guy; he had a big
beard, a big hat.
Why do you wear such a big hat?
I don't know.
And his name was Abraham Lincoln or Abe Lincoln.
He was a famous guy in America.
He was a president and stuff.
To shorten his name, we say: "Abe".
And we don't say the name like: "Linc-lon";
we say: "Lincoln", which I'm still trying
to work out.
So, Abe Lincoln said this famous quote; he
said: "Four score and seven years ago."
And maybe you know "score" means to get a
point or get a goal, and you're wondering
why there's four goals and then seven years.
But actually, "score" meaning number one,
means 20.
So, yes, I have to do math again, but this
time I can do it.
So, if you say: "Four score", that means 20
times four, which is-dunh-dunh-dunh-dunh-80.
So-haha-four times 20 is 80.
So, basically, "score" means 20 of something.
You can get a score of apples, which means
20 apples.
"Four score and seven years ago"-a very famous
quote-actually means 87 years ago.
I didn't do the math, obviously.
Thanks to Josh for doing that.
Unh-huh.
You might know "score" if you watch sports.
So, if you watch hockey, or baseball, or any
sports, they score a goal; and this means:
When you score a goal, you get a point.
So, as a sentence, you can say: "The team
scored 10 points."
So they got 10 points.
Score!
Sometimes when people watch hockey, they'll
all of a sudden go: "Score!"
Right now, if you're hearing a little bit
of noise, it's because there's a hockey game
going on and people are going to yell.
Or maybe they're just crazy people.
Another way that we use the word "score" as
a noun is a piece of music.
There is a really fantastic movie, I think,
called Pee-wee's Big Adventure, and the soundtrack...
"This movie's score was written by Danny Elfman."
So, Danny Elfman is a very famous composer,
and he wrote the music or the score for Pee-wee's
Big Adventure.
Do you know that movie?
If you've never seen the movie, go; it's so
funny.
Don't go; Google it, look at it on your computer.
If you go to the movies, there's no movies
anymore of Pee-wee's Big Adventure; I'm sorry.
So it's something you're going to have to
do by yourself.
So, the movie's score (the movie's music)
was written by Danny Elfman.
Now that song is in my head.
Ding-ding-ding-ding.
Another thing you can do is you can score
music.
This means that you arrange or change the
As an example, as a composer, I would take...
I have written music for only a violin, and
a viola, and a cello, which would be three
people playing it; but I want to make it a
quartet which has four people, so I'm going
to score the music to include a flute.
So: "The quartet"-which means four-"was scored
for the flute, violin, viola, and piano."
This means the music was changed or rearranged
to include another instrument.
Do you play an instrument?
Do you play the flute?
Oh.
Another way we use this is in cooking or not
in cooking, but most commonly in cooking,
is you make a cut or a mark on something.
So, you will hear maybe on cooking shows:
"She scored the roast."
So, a lot of the times you cut the fat of
the meat so it doesn't explode and it's delicious.
So, you can cut or mark the surface of something.
So, your roast looks like this, you've got
a layer of fat, and you score it.
The next one is also a verb, and... to draw
a line through writing.
So, maybe you have a teacher and your teacher
doesn't like what you've written, so they
get out their red pen (or in this case, a
blue pen) and they do this.
This is called "score".
So, they score out the words.
Now we're getting into the slang; this is
where the fun happens.
I told you that I say this a lot, and "score"
means you find something that's good.
Okay?
So if I'm walking down the street and I see
dog poo, I'm not going to yell: "Score!"
I'm going to say: "Ew.
Somebody didn't clean up their dog poo, and
this is disgusting".
"Score" is only if you find something that
you are excited about or that you like.
If you like dog poo, that's cool; just I wouldn't
really say...
Whatever.
Please use this word to your discretion.
So, you can find money, you can find an earring,
you can find something that you've lost, you
can help someone find something; you say:
"Score!
I got it!
Woo-hoo!"
"Score" also means to have sex.
What?
There is a really famous American cartoon
called Beavis and Butt-Head.
Ha-ha.
I don't know if you've seen this, but they
are silly.
I think they're kind of stupid, actually,
but that's my personal opinion.
But they always say: "Ha-ha, you're going
to score tonight.
I scored last night."
So, when they say that and they say it like
this: "You are gonna", which means "going
to"...
"You're gonna score tonight!"
This means one of them is going to-woo-hoo-have
sex.
Also, you can use this in the past tense.
Maybe your friend says: "Yeah!
I scored last night!" and you think: "You
weren't playing baseball or hockey.
You weren't...
I...
I saw you yesterday, and you were hanging
out with a lovely la-...
Oh.
Ah, you scored.
Okay."
You're not playing hockey.
The last meaning in the slang era is when
you get drugs.
So, normally if you get a prescription, you
go to the pharmacy, and you're not going to
say: "Score!"
This is for illegal street drugs.
So, you will hear people in movies: "Where
can I score some crack?"
Or...
They're saying: "Where can I get some drugs?"
You'll hear people, like: "Yeah, we scored
last night.
We scored weed last night."
Or: "We scored"...
I don't know; whatever you guys...
Whatever drugs people do.
You'll hear people say: "I scored some dope,
yo".
"Dope" has two meanings.
One, it means marijuana; it also means heroin.
So, I don't know where that went.
That...
Well, it's crazy.
So, if your buddy says: "Oh, I scored last
night", you've got three options.
Did they get drugs?
Did they have sex?
Did they find something?
Or were they actually playing a game?
Video game; they scored a goal.
If you want to score more points on your next
IELTS test, keep on watching this.
Go to www.engvid.com; subscribe to this YouTube
channel, and you can score with the ladies.