Hi, guys.
This is F@nny.
Welcome to this English pronunciation video.
In this video we will focus on two English
vowel sounds:
/I/ and /i:/
Now I know they sound very similar, but they
are different.
And they are two very important vowel sounds
in English.
So let's start with our two example words:
sit
Now listen to how I pronounce this word.
Can you hear the /i/ sound?
sit
Now listen to another word:
seat
Can you hear the pronunciation?
/i:/ sound.
seat
sit
I know it can be difficult at first.
But with a little bit of practice, I'm sure
you will hear them differently.
Although they are similar, they are two different
vowel sounds.
I promise you by the end of this video
you will hear and pronounce them differently.
So keep watching.
Get ready students.
I'm gonna help you make these vowel sounds
/I/ and /i:/.
I really want you to be able to hear the difference
and to pronounce them correctly.
It is very important for you to know the IPA
spelling.
Watch how I move my mouth.
And always repeat after me in this video.
I know that you can master these vowel sounds.
Let's get started.
First, let's try to make the sound /I/.
So when you pronounce it,
your tongue is a little higher in your mouth,
closer to the front.
/I/
Stretch out your lips a little.
And it's a short sound.
/I/
Repeat after me.
Let’s now practice with the word, sit.
sit
Good guys.
Let's now practice the second sound, /i:/.
So the tongue has the same position.
It's a little bit higher, closer to the front.
But, when you say /i:/, you stretch out your lips a little more.
And it's a long sound.
/i:/
Your lips should feel a little tighter, too.
Repeat after me.
/i:/
Let's practice with the word, seat.
Repeat after me.
seat
Good guys.
So we're going to use minimal pairs.
They’re words with very similar sounds,
but the actual vowel sounds are different.
And they're a very good way to practice these
vowel sounds.
So let's now practice together.
First, just the sounds.
Watch my mouth.
And repeat after me.
/I/
/i:/
Can you see my mouth?
Okay let's now practice with the words.
sit
seat
Good job guys.
Okay guys let's now move on to minimal pairs.
I have a few for you.
I'm gonna read them to you.
I want you to be very careful.
Look at my mouth - how it moves.
And repeat after me.
Let's get started.
Let's practice further.
I'm now going to show you some words
and I want you to read them with the proper English vowel sound.
/I/ or /i:/
Let's get started.
Let's start with the first word.
Which one is it?
Is it sit or is it seat?
Of course it is sit.
Next word.
Is it chick or is it cheek?
It's chick.
Next word.
fill or feel?
fill
Next word.
his or he's?
Of course his.
chin or cheat?
Its cheat.
Is it pip or is it peep?
Of course people it’s pip.
Next word.
bitch or beach?
It's beach.
Then we have sit or seat.
Which one is it?
It's seat.
his oh he's?
It's he's.
And finally, is it hill or heel?
It's heel.
Great guys.
Let's continue on.
Okay guys, let's now move on to sentences.
I have a few sentences for you with different
/I/ and /i:/ sounds.
So pay attention and repeat after me.
The first sentence is:
Pick a seat and sit without making a peep.
The second sentence:
Don't peel a peach or eat its pit.
And finally.
I feel sick and ill after eating the big meal.
Excellent guys.
Let's move on.
Great job guys.
I know you now have a better understanding
of the difference between the English vowel sounds
/I/ and /i:/.
It's difficult.
It takes time and practice to master,
but you can do it.
So keep practicing and make sure to watch
my other pronunciation videos
very important if you want to improve your
English skills.
See you next time.
Thank you so much guys for watching my video.
If you’ve liked it and if you want to see other videos,
please show me your support.
Click like.
Subscribe to the channel.
Put your comments below and share the video.
Bye
Hello guys and welcome to this English pronunciation video.
In this video, I'm going to focus on two very
important vowel sounds in English.
/e/ and /ɪ/
Let's take two example words.
The first word is 'bed'.
Can you hear /e/ the sound?
'bed'
Now the second word is, bid.
Can you hear the /ɪ/ sound?
bid
bed
I know they sound similar, but they are different.
And with a little bit of practice, you will
start hearing them differently.
I promise you that.
So keep watching.
Get ready guys.
I am going to help you make these sounds
/e/ and /ɪ/.
I want you to be able to hear the difference
and to pronounce them correctly.
It's very important, also for you to know the IPA spelling.
Watch how I move my mouth.
And as usual, repeat after me.
I know that you can master these vowel sounds,
So let's get to it.
So let's first practice how to make the sound
/e/.
So your tongue is in a middle part of your mouth.
/e/
Watch my mouth.
How it moves.
/e/
Can you watch my mouth and repeat after me now?
Okay let's now practice with a word, ‘bed’.
Can you repeat after me?
bed
Good job.
Moving on to the sound /ɪ/.
Now your tongue - it's a little higher than
for the /e/ sound.
And you should stretch out your lips a little.
And it's a short sound.
/ɪ/
So let's practice.
Repeat after me.
/ɪ/
Let's practice with a word, ‘bid’.
Watch how my mouth moves and repeat after me.
bid
Okay guys, let's now use minimal pairs -
same words only the vowel sounds change.
They're a good way to practice these sounds.
But first just the sounds,
so just watch how my mouth moves
and repeat after me.
/e/
/ɪ/
Let's now take the words ‘bed’ and ‘bid’.
Repeat after me.
bed
bid
Good, guys.
Okay guys, let's now read minimal pairs together.
Repeat after me.
And watch how my mouth moves.
Let's go.
Okay let's continue practicing.
I'm now going to show you some words
and I want you to read them with the proper English vowel sound
/e/ and /ɪ/.
Let's get started.
Let's start with the first word.
Which one is it?
‘beg’ or ‘big’?
It's beg.
Next word.
Which one is it?
‘bet’ or ‘bit’?
It's ‘bit’.
Next word.
Which one is it?
‘mess’ or ‘miss’?
It’s ‘mess’.
The following word.
Which one is it?
‘set’ or ‘sit’?
It's ‘set’ of course.
Next word.
Which one is it?
‘left’ or ‘lift’?
lift
Next word.
‘hell’ or ‘hill’?
‘hill’ obviously.
Next word.
‘beg’ or ‘big’?
It's ‘big’ this time.
Next word.
‘dead’ or ‘did’?
It's ‘dead’ of course.
Then we have ‘mess’ or ‘miss’?
It is ‘miss’.
And finally, ‘dead’ or ‘did’?
‘did’
Great guys!
Let's continue on.
Okay guys.
Moving on to sentences now.
I have sentences for you
and they're filled with /e/ and /ɪ/ sounds.
So pay attention and repeat after me.
The first sentence is,
‘Ken did not sit on the hill.’
The second sentence,
‘My pet pig fell off the cliff.’
And finally,
‘Set the big desk in the middle.’
Good job, guys.
Let's carry on.
Great guys.
Well now you have a better understanding of
the difference between the English vowel sounds
/e/ and /ɪ/.
Keep practicing.
Practice makes perfect.
I know you can do it.
And make sure to watch the rest of my pronunciation
videos.
They're very important if you want to improve
your English skills.
See you next time.
Thank you so much guys for watching my video.
If you liked it, please show me your support.
Click ‘like’.
Subscribe to the channel.
Put your comments below.
Share the video.
Thank you.
Hello, students.
This is F@nny.
Welcome to this English pronunciation video.
In this video we are going to focus on two
English vowel sounds.
/e/ and /eɪ/
These are two very important vowel sounds in English.
And they sound different even though very similar.
Let's start with two example words.
The first word is ‘let’.
Can you hear the sound /e/?
‘let’
The second word is ‘late’.
/eɪ/
‘late’
So ‘let’ and ‘late’
I know to some of you they sound exactly the same.
But with a little bit of practice you will hear the difference,
and if you keep practising with me,
by the end of this video,
I promise you will hear and pronounce them correctly.
So keep watching.
Get ready guys.
I'm gonna help you make these sounds /e/
and /eɪ/ in English.
I want you to hear the difference and to be
able to pronounce them correctly.
Also, it's very important to know the IPA spelling,
watch how I move my mouth,
and as usual repeat after me.
I know that you can master these sounds,
so let's get to it.
First, let's learn how to make the sound /e/.
So your tongue is in the middle part of your mouth.
Okay, and your mouth and doesn't move.
/e/
Can you repeat after me?
Let's now practice with a word please.
Repeat after me.
let
For the sound /eɪ/.
It's a little bit trickier.
It's what we call a diphthong.
So it's actually two vowel sounds combined.
/eɪ/
So as you can see, your mouth moves,
and your tongue goes up a little
as you produce the sound /eɪ/.
Can you repeat after me?
/eɪ/
Let's practise with the word ‘late’.
Repeat after me.
late
Great job!
Let's now use minimal pairs.
So words that are extremely similar but the vowel
sounds change.
They're a very good way to practice your vowel sounds.
First let's just practice the sounds.
So watch how my mouth moves and repeat after me.
/e/
/eɪ/
Let's now use our words ‘let’ and ‘late’.
Repeat after me.
let
late
Excellent job, guys.
Let's now find out about other minimal pairs.
I'm gonna read them to you.
I want you to repeat after me
and pay attention to my mouth and how it moves.
Let's go.
Excellent guys.
Let's move on.
Ok let's continue practicing.
Now I'm going to show you some words
and I want you to read them with the proper English vowel sound
/e/ or /eɪ/
Let's get started.
Let's start with the first word.
Is it ‘bed’ or ‘bade’?
It's ‘bed’ of course.
Next word.
‘fell’ or ‘fail’?
Which one is it?
It's ‘fail’.
Next word.
‘test’?
‘taste’?
It’s ‘taste’.
‘men’?
‘main’?
‘main’
Next word.
‘ren’?
‘rain’?
It's ‘rain’.
Next ‘sell’ or ‘sale’?
It's ‘sell’.
Next word.
‘test’? ‘taste’?
Which one is it?
In this case, it's ‘test’.
Next word.
‘men’?
‘main’?
It's ‘men’.
Next word.
‘sell’ or ‘sale’?
‘sale’ of course.
And finally,
‘when’ or ‘wane’?
It's ‘when’.
Very good.
Great job guys.
Let's carry on.
Okay guys let's now practice with sentences.
I have sentences containing /e/ and /eɪ/sounds.
So pay attention and repeat after me.
The first sentence is:
‘Ken made cakes well.’
The second sentence:
‘Tell him to send red paint.’
And finally:
‘Men fed a whale in the rain.’
Great guys.
Let's continue on.
Great job guys.
You now have a better understanding of the
difference between the English vowel sounds
/e/ and /eɪ/.
But keep practicing.
It takes time and practice of listening and
speaking to master the vowel sounds.
But you can do it.
Also make sure you watch the rest of my pronunciation
videos.
Very important if you want to master the English
language.
See you next time.
Thank you so much guys for watching my video.
if you've liked it, show me your support.
Click ‘like’.
Subscribe to the channel.
Put your comments below and share the video.
See you.
Hello, students.
This is F@nny.
Welcome to this English pronunciation video.
In this video, I'm going to focus on two English
vowel sounds:
/æ/ and /ʌ/
They sound similar, but they are different
so you need to pronounce them differently.
Let's start with two example words.
My first example word is ‘ran’.
Can you hear the /æ/ sound?
‘ran’
My second word is, ‘run’.
/ʌ/
run
ran
Can you hear the difference?
I  know they sound very similar.
But if you practise with me,
I promise by the end of this video,
you will hear and pronounce them correctly.
So keep watching.
Get ready guys.
I am going to help you make these sounds.
/æ/ and /ʌ/ in English.
I want you to hear the difference very clearly
and to be able to pronounce them correctly.
Also you should know the IPA spelling,
watch how I move my mouth,
and please try to always repeat after me.
I know you can do it so let's get started.
First, let's try to make the sound /æ/.
So your tongue is very low in your mouth.
/æ/
Can you repeat after me?
Let's now use the word, ‘ran’.
Repeat after me.
ran
And now let's produce the sound /ʌ/.
Your tongue is in the middle part of your mouth.
/ʌ/
Please repeat after me.
Let's now practice with the word ‘run’.
Repeat after me.
run
Good guys.
Let's now use minimal pairs.
Words that are very similar, but the vowel
sounds change.
A very good way to practice the vowel sounds.
First, just the sounds.
Repeat after me.
And watch how my mouth moves.
/æ/
/ʌ/
Let's now use the words ‘ran’ and ‘run’.
Please repeat after me.
ran
run
Great guys.
Ok, guys.
Let's see other minimal pairs together.
Repeat after me
and pay attention to my mouth
how it moves.
Let's get started.
Excellent job guys.
Let's carry on.
Okay, guys.
Let's practice further.
I'm going to show you some words.
I want you to read them, but with the proper
vowel sound.
/æ/ or /ʌ/.
Let's get started.
Let's start with word number one.
Which one is it?
‘hang’ or ‘hung’?
‘hung’
Very good.
Next word.
dad or dud?
dud
Next word.
rag or rug?
rag
Next word.
F@nny or funny?
funny
Next word.
stab or stub?
It's ‘stab’.
Next word.
hang or hung?
It's ‘hang’.
Next word.
dad or dud?
It’s ‘dad’.
Next word.
rag or rug?
rug
Next word.
stab or stub?
It’s ‘stub’.
And finally,
F@nny or funny?
It's ‘F@nny’.
Very good guys.
Awesome guys.
Let's move on.
Okay, guys.
Let's move on to sentences now.
I have sentences for you and they all contain
/æ/ and /ʌ/ sounds.
so pay attention and repeat after me.
The first sentence is:
‘My funny uncle must come’.
The second sentence:
‘The bad crab stunk’.
And finally:
‘F@nny must teach funny slang’.
Excellent, guys.
Let's move on.
Great job, guys.
I know it's hard but you now have a better
understanding of the
difference between the English vowel sounds
/æ/ and /ʌ/.
Keep practicing.
It takes time and practice of listening and
speaking to master the English vowel sounds.
But you can do it.
And also make sure to watch the rest of my pronunciation
videos.
They're very important if you want to improve
your English skills.
See you next time.
Thank you so much guys for watching my video.
If you've liked it show me your support.
Click ‘like’.
Subscribe to the channel.
Put your comments below.
Share the video.
Bye.
Hi guys.
This is F@nny.
Welcome to this English pronunciation video.
In this video, I'm gonna focus on two tricky sounds:
/əʊ/ and /ɔ:/
Sounds similar,
but they are very different
and you need to hear the difference and to pronounce them differently.
Let's take two example words
shall we.
The first word is 'so'.
/əʊ/ is the sound.
Can you hear it?
'so'
The second word is 'saw'.
The sound is /ɔ:/.
Can you hear it?
so /səʊ/
saw /sɔː/
Now I know they sound very similar to most of you.
But they are different
and with a little bit of practice, you will improve your skills.
I promise you by the end of this video,
you will hear and pronounce them differently.
So keep watching.
Let's go guys!
I'm gonna help you make these sounds
/əʊ/ and /ɔ:/ in English.
I want you to hear the difference and to be
able to pronounce them correctly.
Also you should know the IPA spelling.
Watch how I move my mouth.
And please try to repeat after me.
I know you can do this so let's get to it.
First, let's make the sound /əʊ/.
/əʊ/ is actually a diphthong.
So it's two vowel sounds /əʊ/.
So as you pronounce it, as you can see,
my mouth is quite round.
It moves and it becomes smaller.
/əʊ/
Let's practice.
Repeat after me.
/əʊ/
Let's practice now with the word 'so'.
Repeat after me.
so
And now for the sound /ɔ:/.
As you can see my mouth is round as well
but it's doesn't move.
And the sound is a tiny bit longer.
/ɔ:/
Let's practice.
Repeat after me.
/ɔ:/
Let's take the word 'saw'.
Please repeat after me.
saw
Good.
Let's now use minimal pairs.
Words that are very similar but the vowel
sounds change.
They're a very good way to practice these
vowel sounds.
First, let's just practice the sounds.
Watch how my mouth moves and repeat after me.
/əʊ/
/ɔ:/
Let's now take our words 'so' and 'saw'.
Repeat after me.
so
saw
Excellent guys.
Okay students let's now move on to
minimal pairs together.
I'm gonna read them to you.
You should repeat after me.
And watch my mouth - how it moves.
Let's get started.
Good guys.
Let's carry on.
Okay guys.
Let's practice further.
I'm going to show you a couple of words.
I want you to read them with the proper English vowel sound:
/əʊ/ or /ɔ:/
Let's get to.
Let's start with the first word.
Is it stoke or stalk?
Which one is it?
It's stoke.
Next word.
moaning or morning?
It's 'morning' of course.
Next word.
code or cord?
code
Next word.
stoke or stork?
stork.
Very nice.
Next word.
poke or pork?
It's 'poke'.
Very good.
Next word.
boat or bought?
Its 'bought'.
Next word.
poke or pork?
It's 'pork', guys.
Next word.
hone or horn?
horn
Then we have 'code' or 'cord'?
It's 'cord'.
And finally.
boat or bought?
'boat'
Very nice.
That was excellent guys.
Let's move on.
Ok, guys. Moving on to sentences containing
/əʊ/ and /ɔ:/ sounds.
So pay attention and repeat after me.
The first sentence,
I saw four crows fly low.
Second sentence.
Joe chose pork and corn.
And finally.
There's more snow on the low shore.
Great guys.
Let's move on.
Great job guys.
You now have a better understanding of the
difference between the English vowel sounds
/əʊ/ and /ɔ:/
But keep practicing.
It takes time and practice
speaking and listening to master these vowel sounds.
But you can do!
Also, make sure you watch the rest of my pronunciation videos.
Very important if you want to master the English language.
So see you next time.
Thank you so much for watching guys.
If you've liked it, show me your support.
Click 'like', subscribe to the channel, put
your comments below
and share this video.
See you.