Tripp the Dominator: Hey, I was on this date the other night, and we were at this
restaurant,
Tyler the Leader: Alright guys. Are you guys ready to get started?
Tripp the Dominator: Hang on a second.
Tyler the Leader: Tripp, are you ready to get started, buddy?
Tripp the Dominator: Ok you guys. We're all here, we should start.
[Music Intro: 00:10 to 00:13]
Tyler the Leader: Alright, thanks for coming guys. I just wanted to take a few minutes,
and talk about some ideas for the marketing strategy this year. So, if you got one, just
throw it out there. I'd love to hear them.
The Time Nazi: Yeah, how long is this meeting supposed to last? The schedule wasn't
exactly clear.
Tyler the Leader: We should be out of here in thirty.
The Time Nazi: Is that approximate? Or,
Get Here When You Can Guy: Hey guys. Sorry, I'm a couple of minutes late. I got
caught in traffic.
The Time Nazi: Seven minutes, actually. A couple is two.
Get Here When You Can Guy: Ok.
Tyler the Leader: So what we're doing is coming up with some ideas for our new
marketing strategy.
Get Here When You Can Guy: Sure.
Tyler the Leader: Anyone?
Nancy the Negator: I think we should implement Pinterest.
Carol the Underachieving Scribe: Oh, that's a fun idea.
Ol' Thin Skin: What about a publicity event in the park?
Nancy the Negator: Interesting, but how are you going to plan around the weather?
What if it rains?
Ol' Thin Skin: So, well party in the rain.
Tyler the Leader: Ok, I just want to emphasize, there's no bad ideas here. We're just
brainstorming.
Nancy the Negator: Yeah, I'm just really thinking that it'll be a huge waste of money to
try to plan around the weather.
Ol' Thin Skin: Yeah, ok, we get your concerns, Nancy. Thank you.
Tyler the Leader: Ok, does anyone else have an idea, Ephraim?
W. T. Ephraim: I've always wanted to see rain fall down all at once, in a big splash,
instead of small drops over time. I mean, think how it could impact the irrigation system.
Tyler the Leader: Ok, Terry?
Terry the Rambler: Well, I have an idea from my previous job, that I had last year, let
me take that back a little bit. I have this wonderful idea, but it doesn't really make sense
unless I just take it back a second, and bring it forward, together. It was like three weeks
ago, that I remember, he said something that I couldn't understand,
Tripp the Dominator: Hold on a second, Terry. Hold on. Thanks for pointing. Here's
what we need to do, ok? Lauren, you got this?
Lauren the Social Worker: [Ignoring the meeting while on multiple devices]
Tripp the Dominator: We do a video submission contest on YouTube.
Nancy the Negator: Oh, that's been done.
Tripp the Dominator: It'll be on Facebook, it'll be on Pinterest, it'll be on Twitter.
Nancy the Negator: If we do something with technology, we lose the senior
demographic.
Tripp the Dominator: So, you guys want to see an example?
The Time Nazi: Shouldn't we be moving on to the next topic? I mean, it's already a
quarter after.
W. T. Ephraim: Ha, a quarter after. That's funny.
Tripp the Dominator: Uh, who knows how to put this on the screen, up there, because I
want you to see all the details? Do we have cable? Does this cable work?
Tyler the Leader: I think that's power. In think this one.
Terry the Rambler: [Unknown]
Nancy the Negator: That cord's not going to be long enough.
Tyler the Leader: Does that remote go to the TV?
Tripp the Dominator: Plenty of time guys, no rush.
Nancy the Negator: [Unknown]
W. T. Ephraim: I got a green marker.
Tripp the Dominator: Call the IT guy.
Tyler the Leader: Wait, turn what off and back on? Hello?
Ol' Thin Skin: Ok, I've got it working.
Tripp the Dominator: Good Play. Ok, now imagine hundreds of those floating around
the web. Do you actually want to watch it one more time?
Terry the Rambler: No, please.
Tyler the Leader: Tripp, I think you're onto something with this idea. I really like it.
Carol, did you get that down?
Carol the Underachieving Scribe: Yeah, I got it.
Tyler the Leader: Sorry, what is c, test, up, sub, yt, prz?
Carol the Underachieving Scribe: Well, I'm abbreviating, to make room for all these
great ideas. Contest, uploading it to YouTube, funniest, and you can get a prize.
Tyler the Leader: Wait, where are the other ideas?
Carol the Underachieving Scribe: [Point to her own head]
The Time Nazi: And, time.
Tyler the Leader: Hey, where are you all going? We still have one hundred percent of
the things to accomplish.
Tyler: One of the biggest hassles in all of life is, when you're in a meeting, and you're
trying to get what's on the computer screen, to be on the big screen. Well, it's doesn't
have to be a hassle, thanks to our friends at AIRTAME. these guys have,
Tripp: Hold on a second. I don't know what you're doing here, but I just want to tell
you, real quick, about something called AIRTAME. It's a device that allows you to
wirelessly send something from your computer, to a bigger screen, in a meeting, making
life way easier. Go ahead.
Tyler: That's, that's what I was saying.
Tripp: Oh. Well, I probably did it better. Click here if you want to see more about
AIRTAME.
Captions by GetTranscribed.com