-Wow, that is really hard.
You really think you can
go all day long?
Well, you always left me
satisfied and smiling, so.
-[ Laughs ]
-Michael.
Michael!
-[ Laughing ] Come on!
-Michael, please.
-There he is.
-Mwah! [ Laughs ]
-Come on.
-Why did you get it so big
-"A" -- that's what she said
Jim?
-No, thanks. I'm good.
-That's what she said.
Pam?
-Uh, my mother's coming.
-That's what she sai--
[ Clears throat ]
-Does the skin look red
and swollen?
-That's what she said.
-That's my joke.
Damn it, Dwight.
That's what she said.
-Ha!
I don't get it.
-Grapes -- seductive.
How about the Phyllis-Angela
dispute?
-You already did me.
-That's what she said.
-I-I can't stay
on top of you 24/7.
-[ Laughs ]
And the best way to start
is to hit "Start."
And up comes the toolbar.
That's what she said.
Hey, can you make that
straighter?
That's what she said.
-Did you plan that?
-No.
-"Can you make that straighter
That job looks hard.
You should put
your mouth on that."
How can you even
use that one naturally?
-Blowing up balloons, I thought.
Eat it. Eat it, Phyllis.
Dip it in the water so it'll
slide down your gullet
more easily.
-That's what she said.
-Oh, no, no, no! Not --
That's -- Just --
Come on, you guys.
Let's do it.
I need two men on this.
That's what she said.
No time! But she did.
No time!
-I want to give you something.
-Oh. W--
[ Laughs ]
That's what she said.
[ Laughs breathlessly ]
Okay, you know what?
I want you to think about
your future at this company.
I want you to think
about it long and hard.
-That's what she said.
-Don't. Don't you dare.
I'll be your first customer!
-You're hardly my first!
-That's what she said!
-Go.
Force it in as deep as you can
-[ Muffled ]
That's what she said.
I'm glad if today
spurred social change.
That's part of my job
as regional manager.
But you know what?
Even if it didn't,
at least we put
this matter to bed.
That's what she said.
Or he said.
-They kept hiring
from the outside.
It was easy to get in
but impossible to rise up.
-That's what she.
A lot of places
are like that.
-One more bite of eclair each.
Hold it in your mouth
if you can't swallow.
-Really? Nothing.
-Hewo, you.
-Michael?
-Hey, buttercup.
-Hi.
-I am on my way.
Should be there in about 15 --
-Let's just blow
this party off.
-That's what she said.
-Why is this so hard?
That's what she said.
Oh, my God.
What am I saying?
-Dwight, get out of my nook.
-That's what she said.
That's what she said!
-Good one.
-Where's the band?
'Cause there's no way
you guys
are making this magic
with just your mouths.
-That's what she said.
-10 years, you'll figure it out.
-Well, I don't think
I'll be here in 10 years, but.
-That's what I said.
That's what she said.
-That's what who said?
-I never know.
-[ Chuckles ]
-I just say it.
I say stuff like that,
you know,
to lighten the tension
when things sort of get hard
-That's what she said.
-[ Laughs ] Hey.
Nice.
-This is huge!
-That's what she said.
-[ Laughs ]
-Sold for $300 to me!
[ Gavel squeaks ]
What the hell is that?
-It's the only gavel
I could find.
-It squeaks when you bang it
That's what she said.
Ahh.
Oscar, would you reach ove
and touch his thing.
That's what he said.
Right, guys? 'Cause of gay
-How long have you known
Ms. Levinson?
-Six years and two months.
-And you were directly
under her the entire time?
-That's what she said.
-Excuse me?
-Ms. Levinson told you that
she was your direct superior
-W-- Uh.
Why would she say that?
-Can we just move on
to another question?
-N-No, wait.
I don't -- I don't understand.
Who's on record as saying this
-With all due respect,
I'm in the middle
of a line of questioning.
Now, Mr. Scott, what did you say
Ms. Levinson said
regarding your employment status
with respect to
her corporate position?
-Come again?
That's what she said.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
-Okay, if I may, he --
he was just
telling a joke before,
so can we move on
to another question?
-Oh, are you sure?
-Uh, yes.
-Can you go back to
where this digression began?
-Mr. Schneider --
"And you were directly under her
the entire time?"
Mr. Scott --
"That's what she said."
-Well.
delivery's all wrong.
She's butchering it.
-You need to get back on top
-That's what she said.
-Yeah.
-Your office
is full of genitalia.
-[ Clears throat ]
Eso es lo que dice el.
-"That's what he says"?
-Damn it!
-I never recommended you because
I didn't want to lose you
and I didn't want to lose Pam.
And now I don't want to
lose the baby.
-So instead, you screwed me?
-[ Whispering ]
That's what she said.
-No.
-I would like you all
to go to the website
and watch my clip 11 times
-So, instead of working,
you want --
-Yes! Yes.
-Okay.
-Come on!
. because I'm a manager here.
Get it up!
That's what.
Let's do it.
Jim -- that guy is an ace.
Dwight is my king
up my sleeve.
Phyllis is my Old Maid.
Oscar is my queen --
that's easy.
Give me a hard one.
That's what Oscar said.
You are so far above them,
it is stupid.
-Michael, no, don't.
Don't make it harder
than it has to be.
-That's what she said.
-No, comedy is a place
where the mind goes
to tickle itself.
That's what she said.
[ Laughs ]
Oh, man.
-[ Groans ]
That's good!
-Ah!
-You are making this harder
than it has to be.
-That's what she said.
-I'm not saying
it won't be hard,
but we can make it work.
That's what she said.
-Mm.
Alright. Oh.
This is gonna feel so good
getting this thing off my chest.
[ Muffled ]
That's what she said.
-Michael.
I can't believe you came.
-That's what she said.
-[ Laughs ]
-Best prank ever.
-Yeah!