In 2021,
the topic of COVID vaccines has
become a hot topic of conversation.
And in some situations it's
even become a contentious
conversation.
What that means is that it causes
or is likely to cause an argument
it's controversial.
One of the greatest challenges my
students have is feeling comfortable and
confident in sharing their opinion,
especially when someone has a
differing or opposing opinion.
And you might have the same frustration.
How do you express your opinion
politely when others disagree or have a
different point of view without
getting into an argument? Of course,
one strategy is to simply
stay silent and say nothing,
but that's not a good long-term
solution. If you're here,
you're here to become confident
in your English language skills.
And that means the ability to express
yourself clearly to share your opinions
no matter who you're talking to
or what the situation might be.
The good news is there are strategies
you can use to help you effectively,
politely share your opinions
and handle differing
opinions using neutral language.
If you don't already know,
I'm Annemarie with
Speak Confident English,
this is where you want to be every week
to get the confidence you want for your
life and work in English. By
the end of this video today,
you will be able to clearly and
politely express disagreement or
share an opposing perspective
using neutral phrases with
three powerful strategies.
Plus at the end,
I'll share three quick tips
to help you stay clear-headed
when you're in a conversation that
is particularly controversial,
Let's get started. If you
don't already have them,
I'm going to ask you to get a pen piece
of paper or notebook ready for you to
use, because there will be a lot
of new phrases for you today.
And I want you to keep all of them
so that you can practice using them,
get comfortable and start using them
regularly in your English conversations.
And now let's get started
with strategy number one,
when you're working to
use neutral language.
Acknowledge the strengths
of the opposing argument or
point of view in a conversation.
You might know that you absolutely
disagree with what someone else has said
before you jump in to
share that disagreement,
take a moment to acknowledge the strengths
of the other person's perspective.
This doesn't mean that you
agree with what they've said,
but you did listen and you're
acknowledging that they've
made some good points.
After you acknowledged those strengths,
then you can go on to use some neutral
language to introduce your opposing
perspective. When we do that, we
tend to focus on functional phrases,
such as in my opinion,
based on my experience,
it seems to me or my
concerns or my thoughts are.
Let me put all of that
together in an example for you:
imagine that you and a team member
are talking about your budget at
work.
And there's a bit of disagreement when
you respond to what your coworker has
said,
you can start by acknowledging the
strengths and then get into your opposing
point of view. And here's how that
might sound. Your points are valid.
And I agree with what you've said about
the expenses. Based on my experience,
an increase in the price for more
profit can have a negative impact on
consumer demand. In that example, I'm
acknowledging the other strengths.
I've validated what they
said and I've introduced my
opposing idea, but in doing that, I
haven't used any negative language.
It's all very neutral. I didn't
use however, or I disagree.
I simply acknowledge the strengths
and then introduced my own
perspective.
We can use this same strategy in
casual or informal conversations as
well. Here's an example.
I understand your reasoning and you've
made some good points. In my opinion,
gradually reducing our expenses will
help us save money for a new house more
quickly. Again,
I'm acknowledging the strengths and
validating the other perspective.
And then introducing my own.
The second strategy for handling differing
opinions using neutral language is
to use I-statements.
Using I-statements helps to
reduce tension because it avoids
blaming others or pointing
the finger. In other words,
there's no accusation and we're
separating the person from
the topic or the problem that
we're discussing in this process.
We also can avoid negative
language such as, but,
however I disagree.
The goal is for you to share
your opinion on neutral
ground. So to do that, we use
things like, I think, I believe,
I understand, I'm convinced or I would.
In using these I statements instead
of focusing on my disagreement,
I'm shifting the focus to my
opinion and my reasons for
my opinion. Let me give you two
examples of what this looks like.
One for professional situations and the
second for more personal or informal
conversations, let's start with
the professional example. Well,
your proposed cuts will
help balance the budget.
I think we should be mindful about how
those cuts will affect our business
longterm and in a personal situation.
I understand that you have
certain goals in mind.
I believe we should focus on how
to minimize the costs of daycare.
Look at those two examples carefully.
You can definitely see examples of,
I think I believe,
and I understand I've also avoided
any negative language or direct
disagreement,
but I was still able to
introduce and state my opposing
perspective.
And now strategy number three
for handling differing opinions
using neutral language is to
use the power of suggestion.
The power of suggestion can
be used to share an opinion or
perspective without emotional language.
Emotional language tends
to get us into problems.
That's where we start to get frustrated
or angry and it starts to show,
but we want to avoid all of
that by using more neutral
suggestive language,
such as let's consider
or let's think about,
have you thought about
what if we, what about,
what are your thoughts on,
or what do you think about all of
this language helps us to introduce a
suggestion, an alternative idea,
opinion or perspective without
being confrontational or bringing
emotion into the conversation. For
example, in a professional conversation,
I might say something like,
I agree that customer
satisfaction comes first.
What do you think about training team
members by assigning them different roles
every month? In that example, I'm
introducing a different perspective,
maybe even an opinion that
I know others won't like.
And instead of doing it in
a direct, aggressive way,
I'm introducing it as a suggestion
in a personal conversation.
I could use an example like this. I agree
that we need a more affordable option.
What if we minimize a few other expenses
like going out on the weekends while we
look for a more affordable daycare option.
Now that you have three powerful
strategies using neutral language to
help you have successful, productive
conversations on differing opinions,
let's take a look at three tips that
you can use to help you stay calm.
And clear-headed when you're
discussing a topic that is
particularly controversial or
that you feel strongly about.
Tip number one is to clarify,
in order to avoid assumptions.
When you find yourself poles apart
from another person, in other words,
you're on two absolutely
opposite sides of an issue,
it can be easy to start making
assumptions about the other
person's perspectives
or their reasons why.
But in order to have a successful
conversation on a sensitive issue,
it's important to know exactly
what the real reasons are
behind someone's position,
not what you think they might be
the best way to do this is to ask
clarifying questions. Now,
if you're not sure what kinds of questions
are clarifying questions or what are
the best to use,
keep an eye out for a future lesson
because I've got a lesson coming on that
topic very soon. Tip number
two for staying clear,
headed is approach problems together,
include the other person in your
thought process and in your problem
solving approach that
isn't always easy to do,
but it leads to a much better
outcome and it helps to avoid things
getting tense or conversations
getting into something that
becomes an argument. Instead of focusing
on the two different perspectives,
you can bring the focus on how you can
work together toward a common goal or
solving a problem to do that.
It's always important to find
the places that you agree on.
For example, maybe both of you agree
that you need to reduce expenses.
So that becomes the common
goal and you work on finding
solutions that you're both okay with.
And tip number three for staying
clear and calm headed is to always be
aware of your tone and volume. Honestly,
this one is really tough when you're
communicating on a topic that you're
passionate about.
It's very common to start increasing
the volume of your voice or
change your tone to indicate
frustration, sarcasm,
or even passion for the topic,
but in order to disagree
successfully and move forward in the
conversation,
it's important to be careful
about the tone and volume.
I have to admit that I'm particularly
passionate about politics.
So I have to be careful when I talk to
others with an opposing point of view,
to help me stay calm and clear headed.
I will often step back from the
conversation and say something like
I need a moment to collect my thoughts.
And while I pause and
take time to reflect,
I'm also very careful about breathing
in a way that helps to reduce
anxiety or frustration.
And that is something I often
share with my students as well.
In addition to saying something like,
give me a moment to collect my thoughts.
You could also say I need
a moment and that's it.
Just take a pause in the conversation.
Step back from the frustration
so that you can have a productive
conversation now that you have these
three powerful strategies with examples of
neutral language,
and you have some tips to help
you stay calm and clear headed.
I have two challenge questions for you.
I know that giving opinions or
sharing your point of view in a
situation where someone has an opposing
point of view can be really difficult.
So let's practice.
I have two different scenarios
or topics for you. And in both,
I want you to think about how you would
respond using what you've learned today
in scenario. Number one,
I want you to imagine that one of your
friends strongly believes that children
should not go back to school
until September, 2022.
However you disagree with that opinion.
How could you express your
opinion without upsetting her,
try using some of the example language
that you've learned today to do that.
And now scenario number two,
your son's teacher recommends that
your son switch from an advanced
placement level class to a
regular class based on poor
performance.
You know that your son has had
a particularly tough month and
you also know that your son is
more than capable of doing well in
the advanced placement level.
How would you express this?
How would you disagree with
your son's teacher? Again,
go over the strategies
we've talked about today,
review all the examples of neutral
language and then share an example below.
The best place for you to share is always
in the comment section below the video
or in the online lesson.
Not only will others in the
community be able to learn from you,
but it's also where I go
to review and respond.
If you found this lesson useful to
you today, I would love to know.
You can tell me by giving it a thumbs
up here on YouTube and subscribe to my
Speak Confident English channel.
So you never miss one of my
Confident English lessons.
Thank you so much for joining me. And
I look forward to seeing you next time.