day one of feeding my pet seagull to
gain his trust
[Music]
so tasty give me more please
delicious oh that's nice
oh i'm falling divine see you
tomorrow buddy
i'm still hungry and i hate you day two
of feeding my pet seagull to gain his
trust
time for some protein we want a strong
seagull
chef hurry up
please gonna open the window a little
more this time
oh my god that's tasty i need more
coming right up oh god
my wings are tingling this is the best
day ever
divine i wonder if you can eat from here
of course i can i'm still hungry
and my feet are cold can i come in not a
chance
you will kill me try this leaf hmm what
the is that
gross are you trying to die maybe we can
trick him
that's more like a wait a minute
what was in that
i'll see you tomorrow buddy do that
again and i will kill you
day two of feeding my pet seagull to
gain his trust hey
i brought some friends this time feed me
or i'll kill you
this is starting to scare me let's try
some fruit
that's a sad banana what is that
feed me with your hand you oh no
slippery banana
gotcha divine i can feel the potassium
strengthening my knees more last
piece
oh my god i'm falling you need to open
the window more
nice try buddy i will get inside one day
delicious you better sleep with one eye
open tonight
i'll see you tomorrow buddy i will kill
you a three of feeding my pet seagull to
gain his trust
quick snack it better be tasty or i'll
kill you
don't you worry buddy somebody sent you
a special snack
they look so divine
chef chef hurry up please my feet are
starting to get shaky
you have to wait buddy i don't want you
to get sick i don't care
these look golden and tasty we are going
to have a strong seagull
better cool them down i don't want to
burn his seagull lips
they look sick chef opening the window
wider this time
bad idea so delicate and tasty
oh no i almost fell off the roof let me
in and this will be easier
i just don't trust you yet buddy you
almost bit me if i wanted to bite you
i already would have that's nice
we are also hungry feed them and it'll
be the last thing you do
i'll see you tomorrow buddy day four of
feeding my pet seagull to gain his trust
hey smokey fish very fancy
big protein my little guy is gonna be so
strong
hurry up and feed me chef chef
oh no this is bad he is in the living
room don't worry you won't be living for
long
he brought another friend this time i
want mac and cheese
i hope the rain doesn't make the roof
too slippy if he fell off i would be so
sad
oh this is slippery so delicious oh
my god please help
build me something to stand on i
will do anything for you
can you let me inside when you stop
trying to kill me never
be quiet don't you see i am trying to
bond with my seagull
divine feed me with your hand
can you stop inviting your friends no
chefs kiss bellissimo i feel so strong i
can run so fast faster than you
you can never outrun me
i'll see you tomorrow buddy did i say i
was finished eating i'm scared
day five of feeding my pet seagull to
gain his trust i've been waiting here
all night watching you sleep
today we have a special treat a scotch
egg delicious
are those balls for me yes but please
never say that again
sorry i'm just so excited for the balls
i understand
it do be like that sometimes don't rush
me this roof is scary
i can smell the balls brb just slicing
the balls
and getting the crumbs off we want a
healthy seagull it's ball time
let's start with the eggo eggo for my
seagull
incredible egg that's juicy
try them together divine oh no oh my god
that's a slippery egg
i am so sad tasty that stole my
egg
don't worry buddy there's more sick you
are growing so
strong and i am so proud of you buddy
proud enough to let me in the house
not yet i'm still scared of you day five
of feeding my pet seagull to gain his
trust
did you miss me so much let's try
some veggies
somewhat veggies no don't worry buddy
they are tender stem
tender my ass just try it get the heck
away from me with that
but it's good for you buddy no get me
something else or i'll jump off this
roof
i know just the snack for a sad seagull
big protein to strengthen his little
stick legs
my eyes are up here sorry about
that yum
that's a tasty treat let's see if you
can eat from the tray yet
drop it i thought i could trust
you that was just payback for the tender
stem
divine can i eat from your hand let's
see
wow you didn't bite me this time just as
long as you never tender stem me ever
again
i'm serious day six of feeding my
pet seagull to gain his trust
i am starving today is a special
day big protein time
i hate this roof so much don't worry
buddy i have a plan
that looks unsafe i think you can do it
oh no help me please i'm gonna die are
you trying to kill me
try it once more you almost had it no
build something better
i'm so sad he doesn't like it i guess
it's hard to teach an old seagull new
tricks
i may be old but i can kick your ass are
you gonna eat that
step aside oh you better
leave that alone
no be bang don't you dare god damn it
you can have it
sick i'll just eat her when she's done
worth it i'll need to get a better
platform for next time
see you tomorrow buddy bye day
seven of feeding my pet seagull to gain
his trust
hey we have so much food but none
of this is good enough for my little
buddy
chickpeas more like chickpeas did
someone say chicken
stop being such a cannibal buddy no
here's a quick snack
divine brb buddy please don't break the
window while i'm gone
you better be quick then bumblebee
tuna with skin and bones
yes please jackpot into the pink
he really loves getting into that pink
juicy salmon
i'll get him the deluxe it's more boogie
and these for dessert
this might be the most i've ever spent
on a seagull but right now he's the best
buddy i've got
what took you so long it's time
to eat it's into the pink let's go
eat gotcha so pink moonwalk
yes duh bye
that's all for today buddy you're
looking kinda thick what did you just
say
come here day number eight of
feeding my pet seagull to gain his trust
start cooking right away deluxe
salmon
big protein he's gonna be the strongest
seagull there ever was
that's some juicy meat looks sick
i never thought i would turn into a
personal chef for a wild seagull
but i wouldn't trade it for the world
chef chef beat that meat
he's waiting so patiently such a good
boy shut up
cook to perfection but we can't forget
the seagull herbs
bon appetit come hither seagull
feed me take a bite yes incredible
i feel so strong there's plenty more ooh
flaky and divine it's making my feathers
dance
yum slide tackle this is my roof
i feel so proud watching him fly he is
growing up so fast
so graceful so strong so powerful
bye bye buddy day number nine of
feeding my pet seagull to gain his trust
i will never trust you but i will
never stop trying buddy
wild bony pink skin this will fuel them
well
so pink looks like he brought his friend
again
feed me bacon never this food is only
for my buddy
yes so moist and sweet have another
oh no got them divine try some of the
bones
yes please oh my god i need more
sick bones they are stuck in my seagull
teeth are you gonna share with your
friend
don't be ridiculous i am so hungry i
wonder if he can catch
if you miss i'm gonna kill you sulky you
are so skilled
and your legs are looking stronger every
day
wait where did your friend go in my
stomach your next
day number 10 of feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
i missed you buddy dessert time gotta be
careful
i don't want to bruise it do i smell
divine rice rice cam pov
hurry up please oh my god
this can't be legal fluffy
that's fire i'm so glad you like it i
could eat this for every meal
divine all done now give me the rest
that's all buddy you're getting fat
say that again and i will cut you i just
worry about your little knees
maybe this will help
i'm so happy hey watch the fingers
i just wanted a taste yes looking strong
buddy
give me an arm wrestle maybe tomorrow
come on
open this window send help for the past
10 days
i've been feeding my pet seagull he
comes every day for a little treat
but i think he's getting a little chubby
fight me
kiwi it's healthy time
what the hell is this do i look vegan
that's kind of juicy want some more yes
please
gotcha tasteless long yellow grape
where did he go i was pooping on a
grandma well done
i like doing that too
this sucks oh no i don't even care
get me some real food right now more
kiwi
trash we'll have something nice tomorrow
buddy talk to my seagull ass
you are so cheeky day in the life let's
go shopping for my pet seagull
let's get some treats whole sea bass
it's a little beefy
i don't want him to gag that's what she
said shut up fish
king scallop for the king kipper kipper
kipper he'll love it
have you watched the office leave me
alone
[Music]
is that king scallop for me of course
buddy come get it
oh god you clumsy little bird chuck it
you're the boss divine just went from
six to midnight
can i keep the shell i don't know you
might use it against me one day it's a
seagull frisbee
no i'm gonna hide it somewhere he will
never look
i know it's in the bed it's not safe
here anymore day number 13
of feeding my pet seagull to gain his
trust sick
let's prepare a tasty treat hehe
i'm so excited my knees are getting
sweaty cheesy biscuits with sweet pink
fish
shut up and hand it over let me
break it up a little i don't want to
hurt your seagull lips
come to mama wings are happy
have another buddy
back off that's mine try some tiny meat
so tiny but so delicious more please big
boy
divine can you let me inside today my
legs are getting chilly
let's try fly on through buddy i didn't
think you'd say
yes i'm too shy did you just poop on my
roof
no this roof is mine don't hurt me day
number 14
of feeding my pet seagull to gain his
trust let's try some cat snacks
woof woof i'd rather just eat the cat
you're so cheeky break me off a slice
homeboy
just let me unbox it that's chewy
10 out of 10 would cat stick again does
it look like i'm smoking
i feel so cool divine
throw one for me sick you're getting so
talented and strong
i am so proud we make a good team see
you tomorrow buddy
bring me a cat next time or i'll kick
your ass day in the life with a pet
seagull
it's time to play catch batter up
today we have some kobe trout
i am vibrating get ready buddy
toss it oh come on
you call that a throw sorry about that
buddy throw better or you will never
throw again
please don't eat my hands i'm trying my
best
sick catch oh that's divine go see gulgo
that's chunky i can handle it yes
that hits my seagull spot last slice
it's got a little bone
it's just excited to be eaten tasty bone
all done bring me more bones or i'll
kill you
day 16 of feeding my pet seagull to gain
his trust
i did something bad what did you do
don't go outside
it's croc o'clock i just hope he didn't
get into the bins
croc parkour oh no why seagull why
i am sorry but tbh no rag rats i just
fed you this
it tasted better the second time i think
the secret ingredient
was the crime some of this isn't even
edible
edible it was divine i'm glad you
enjoyed it i guess
but you've made my crocs very sad let me
in the house
and maybe stuff like this won't happen
i'm still quite scared of you buddy
i've been feeding you so well you have
become stronger than me
unless you can promise to never hurt me
no even for tasty fish
i'll think about it wait till you try
this one
oh my god that makes my head spin and my
toenails tingle
please stay out the vents from now on
i'll just trash the neighbors instead
leave some for me i like trash too no
for the past two weeks i've been feeding
my pet seagull
and already we are celebrating half a
million followers let's cook something
special
chop chop
into the pink seagull pancakes yes
please ready in a jiffy
eggo for my seagull one hander six chef
in
little splash of white water i'm
starting to seek all sweat
wet and sticky just like my pits these
actually smell kinda sick
watch this trick shot stop playing with
my food
or i will gut you i will never flip
another pancake ever again
this is a special moment i'm so proud of
my little buddy
make a wish world domination oh no how
did he do that i didn't open the window
magnets you are so crafty
divine see you tomorrow little man not
if i eat your eyes
i need to find my goggles day number 18
of feeding my pet seagull to gain his
trust
i'm starving don't worry buddy we have
leftover seagull cakes
busting i told you not to invite your
friends they are my groupies
i guess you are pretty famous i'm the
next charles de melanomo
tasty hand it over eat sorry buddy
come on you're lucky i'm so
skilled so true
oh that's divine i get so proud when you
catch it shut up and feed me
tiny meat tiny but tasty
last piece kimmy oh the protein
i can feel it working my neck is growing
i am evolving
see you tomorrow buddy you're leaving
that makes my neck sad
so sad just go poop on some grandmas
that sounds so much fun
don't poop on the mall save some for me
day number 19
of feeding my pet seagull to gain his
trust feed me a baby
i'll check but i don't think we have any
jumbo jumbos
for my jumbos egos big protein
jumbo me please coming right up
i'm ready for the jumbo jumbo incoming
sick
tasty jumbo this might be a bad idea
that looks fun to poop on ye it's
raining jumbos
are they for me only if you can get to
them don't watch
i'm kind of shy don't worry windows do
be kind of scary
but i believe you can do it we so scary
don't give up we juicy
that's a salty jumbo more
divine i'm so proud you didn't poop on
the window
i'm saving it so i can poop in your
shoes please don't
that's where i poop day number one of
trying to pet my pet's seagull
i hope he doesn't bite my fingers
i'm so hungry stinky pink fish and
bumblebee tuna with a little spring
water
to hydrate those little kickers this is
a real seagull treat
better get these ready and make sure he
is well fed
tasty i wonder if he will let me back
off
i'll get some more fish oh my god
that's moist my tongue is tingly try
this
tender and divine bring me a philangie
never oh mama so slippy slip slip
be careful buddy you're scaring me shut
up
yes he fell off the roof and is too far
away
you missed your chance that makes
my hand very sad
i'm sad too fingers are so tasty
back off good job buddy we can try again
tomorrow
sick day number two of trying to pet my
pet seagull
hey i've been feeding him for
about a month i think it's about time we
made contact
i will eat your hands please don't i've
got some tasty pink fish
and a sick landing spot for you to eat
it tbh it does look kinda sick
taste the pink yes pink and sweet
tastes like a treat sick bars buddy
thanks homie
can you jump on the windowsill i'd
rather go up there
you look so cool king of the window
yes more please yes king
divine can i pet you yet no please
i said no your hand stinks and i just
had a seagull shower
i won't tell you again chill
please forgive me fine
gonna leave this open for a few hours
chuck some fish under the tree
just in case he decides to come inside
the house
promise not to poop on the tv no you
cheeky seagull
day number 23 of feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
he's been such a good boy so today we
are getting something special
seagull caviar from 1899 with some
salmon
i'm so excited
chef chef little black fishy balls
smells a bit sweaty but i think he'll
love it i can't wait to taste the fish
balls
tuck in young man
holy balls the taste is unlike any other
try another
my head is spinning with flavor flavor
of the balls this one has extra
come to mama you silly goose
you dropped some of the balls whoopsie
no balls left behind divine
you are getting stronger and stronger
every day i am such a proud father
we what would you like tomorrow bigger
balls
same day number 24 of feeding my pet
seagull
sit tight buddy i'll get you some snacks
hmm
i can't seem to find the seagull section
aisle seven
thanks doggo bingo wild birds i hope
it's okay for pets too
it's got big protein i hope he likes it
it better be tasty
we or i'll kill you deal
eat from my hand no your hands stink
and i hate you but these worms are
excellent
it tastes even better from the hand nice
try
my hand is so sad divine can i have some
more
only handworms from now on those fingers
look tasty
he broke the skin let me take a look i
have a phd
you've done enough go think about what
you've done does this mean i will get
seagull powers
no probably just rabies cool
day number 25 of feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
yesterday while feeding him he tried to
eat my phalanges
and infected me with the rabies last
night i slept for 21 hours
and my hands feel sweaty and my legs
they are so weak
ow but the show must go one my little
buddy needs me
sorry about the rabies i was just so
hungry your phalanges looked like
sausages
i'm gonna need some protection i hope
these are seagull proof
they are not hey
time to eat another finger gonna feed
him a little before
just so he isn't ravenous all done now
let me eat your hands
please be gentle no
oh my god such a good boy divine
i may still have rabies but at least my
seagull is starting to trust me
ow sorry i mistook it for a quizzy
i guess they do look kinda juicy and one
day they will be inside me
never say that again giving my pets
eagle a little morning snack
did you say snack a delicious wormy
breakfast
i'll give them a taste
oh my terrific worms
you're making a mess shut up
divine come back later for some lobster
i can't wait
my wings are getting sweaty day 27 of
feeding my pet seagull
today is a special day somebody sent my
little guy some lobster
bust in sit tight buddy i'll go get it
should i get him a salt lamp
acacia wood is his favorite let's just
focus on the long crab today
i can't tell if it's cold or if i'm just
shaking from the rabies
either way i'm just happy my seagull's
happy 69
so cheeky get back to the house we
just gotta figure out how to cook it
whoever wrote these instructions is
really bad at spelling
i'll just microwave it for 20 minutes i
hope it doesn't explode
what's taking so long lobster boy let me
go change into my lobster shirt
it broke the microwave but it's cooked
to perfection stop
touching me be quiet you are dead we
never do this in two parts
but we are running out of time go watch
part two if you want to see my little
buddy enjoy his snack
divine day 27 of feeding my pet seagull
part two i just bought him a lobster
tried to cook it and broke the microwave
but it was worth it i would do anything
for my little buddy
i need a grenade no please they are so
cool
no means no chef that looks juicy
go ahead it's so tasty i've went
completely blind
can you still catch i don't need my eyes
to see
maybe now's my chance to pet no i will
eat your eyes
we try claw more
i need more last slice divine
i hope you got enough meat your knees
are looking kinda slim
slim but deadly i could still kick your
ass day number 28
of feeding my pet seagull to gain his
trust it's been three days since he
infected me with rabies
my whole body is so weak and i slept
until 4 p.m
he's been watching me all day wake up
my sleep jeans are getting too heavy for
my rabies legs
but at least i've still got my crocs
crocs make the pain go away
hey very nice i really want to pet
him
go ahead see what happens
let's feed him from the hand such a good
boy
divine have some more no
no there are worms in my pockets but i
guess that's what happens when you live
with a seagull
one more try he ate my glove
watch yourself or next time it'll
be the whole hand
day 29 of feeding my pet seagull to gain
his trust
shut up and get the snacks right away
i'll go get you something tasty
maybe a yellow apple or a watermelon
cactus
no get the pink fish great choice oh my
god
they have seagull gloves for only 69 i
really hope they will protect me
i can't handle any more rabies 10 pairs
should do
what's taking so long i'm getting
ravenous i'm running as fast as i can
where did he go i was fighting a cat
like father like seagull it was practice
for fighting you
please have mercy then ice
catch this one ready freddy divine
let's test the new gloves they make you
look fat you're hardly one to talk
to shea tasty he didn't try to bite me
this time
i think he's almost ready to come inside
sick
day number 30 of feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
look at my feathers dance well done
today we are going to clean the window
it's getting so dirty i like it dirty
dirty and stinky
makes my little legs extra pinky if you
let me clean it i'll give you more
lobster
hmm fine thanks buddy please don't
attack me
no it smells so bad
hurry up please i'm getting restless all
done
it's so clean he is scared of his own
reflection who the hell is that
catch
big boy time
why seagull why yolo
divine let's try something new and back
good job you have made some serious
gains this month
i couldn't have done it without you
buddy i am so proud of you
and i can't wait to see what you'll
learn next archery
i'll try find you a bow day 31 of
feeding my pet seagull to gain his trust
hey my rabies are getting worse he
bit me six days ago
my body hasn't felt right since my legs
feel weak
but stronger at the same time and every
day they look
more pink i can feel some feathers under
my knees and the cut looks kinda
infected
wait that's just sriracha
at least i didn't fall over this time
owie i am so weak but i need to feed my
buddy
should i get him a whole salmon please
help me no
big tuna and a red cow for my rabies
legs hurry up
enjoy buddy exquisite
[Music]
tenderly pink just like your legs i hope
mine get like that
you couldn't pull it off you're right
gonna leave the windows open for a bit
drop some fish and see if he wants to
come inside
coming inside sounds divine
cheeky day number 32 of feeding my pet
seagull to gain his trust
hey we have ran out of food all we
have left is kiwi want to try
no just a taste get that thing away from
me
i need protein let's get him some treats
octopussy i really hope it's fresh cheap
salmon
yes please tuna baboona that hurt
i don't care my seagull is going to be
so happy i go for my seagull
don't forget to rub them bargain hey
buddy
i want to give it to him whole but
i'm scared he will gag
please no so fresh
thank god tasty puss it's making me all
moist
don't worry buddy it do be like that
sometimes
that's divine run along you're making
such a mess
fine gonna try find more see cheeky
day number 33 of feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
how's the rabies i feel tingly but
increasingly stronger every day
i can move my legs with my mind my
senses are so sharp
that means it's working what do you mean
working
the sequel venom the wound has
disappeared
what does this mean don't worry about it
get me a snack
right away buddy stinky pink he could
probably eat it out the tray
but he likes it from the bowl you know
me so well of course i do
we share the same dna and i know your
secrets
we're connected buddy for life that
sounds divine
so divine tiny meat chunky
sweet meat i wonder what powers i'll get
next
my legs are looking extra pink and i can
feel my feathers beginning to sprout
can you teach me how to fly only when
you're ready can't wait
giving my pet seagull a tasty breakfast
are those for me of course young man dig
in
wow beautiful
exquisite did you make these yourself
yes i have worms same
look at those pink kickers and i just
noticed he has little hairy shorts
i wonder where he bought them ebay you
are so thrifty
divine we see you later bud day number
of feeding my pet seagull to gain his
trust it's a rough day for steven i hope
the wind doesn't blow him off the roof
hurry up hang in there seagull
gonna get some yellow slugs and some
fish sticks
i love fish sticks same look at them go
i'm back buddy it's tick time on my way
touchdown we break me off a slice
just a sec god has left them to activate
the protein
and remove its sheath it's so jiggly
smells divine
be careful buddy help shut up
juicy fish dick i'm so glad you like
them
ow try the slug file
it's so cold today buddy i wish you
would come inside
you are always welcome thanks buddy but
the grandmas won't poop on themselves
you make me so proud see you buddy bye
day number 35 of feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
what we having today i'll check what's
in stock
tuna baboona or mackerel mackerel tuna
me
excellent choice sir i'll go chef it up
sick
it's so moist hurry up please
your manners are getting better shut up
so cheeky
juicy catch buddy mr slice
whoopsie delicious he waits so patiently
for the food
i will kill you
look at those pinkers such a healthy boy
water please
i wonder if he can be trusted with the
tub
oh no trash you are so silly
but at least you can clean your feet and
have a small sip
how's it taste divine day number 36
of feeding my pet seagull to gain his
trust hey
look at those chest feathers go let's go
buy some snackos
delicious muscles for his little pink
stick legs
and some salmonella he's gonna be so
happy
hurry up we touch down the smell is
intoxicating
and it tastes even better more
oh no my girlfriend is home early please
don't poop on her
that'll require another snack so tender
the muscles are working already your
legs are so thick
jealous yes let's try get him to land on
the couch
i'm so glad you're home you can be my
seagull shield
come on buddy i know you can do it i'm
scared
this is a big step for me and my legs
are so small
i understand don't beat yourself up
about it
we can try again tomorrow divine day
number 38
of feeding my pet seagull to gain his
trust want some mackerel buddy
do you even have to ask
the mackerel squirted on my phone i call
next
please no it already smells so bad calm
down steven
dig in yes so juicy
we sirens what did you do this time just
a little arson
he burned down our doghouse is this true
those dogs had it coming they made fun
of my feathers
he also pooped on a baby nice work buddy
thanks for having my back
forever and always that's what buddies
do
sick i got juice on my sleeve
stop doing that ooh
got a blast buddy the cops are looking
for me there's always time for another
snack
divine bye see you tomorrow buddy
day number 39 of feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
hey today we're going to introduce
my buddy
to my best buddy take a treat and throw
it to him gently
he better not miss
you are so good at catching i'm so proud
shut up cheeky divine
let's see if he will eat from a
stranger's hand that hand looks quite
tasty
but i'm not sure if i can trust it i can
tell you are in your defensive stance
i don't trust his hair neither do i why
is it so blue
but don't worry my hands are safe
safe for now but i will eat them
eventually
if hands are what you want hands are
what you will get a happy seagull is
priceless
we are such a good team you give my life
meaning bye buddy
for the past 40 days i've been feeding
my pet seagull to gain his trust
i gave him lobster and he gave me rabies
he is so cheeky yesterday we got a
comment that really warmed my heart
warm heart can i eat it no steven i'm
talking about yesterday
when you showed up with only one leg i
was so worried and sad
but it was only a prank you still have
both of your little pinkers
can you hurry up and get to the point
the comment said that birds only
stand on one leg to have a rest
so what they also said that birds only
do this when they feel comfortable
safe and at home you make me feel so
safe
and your friendship is the greatest gift
my life has ever given me
day number 40 of feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
our last idea to get him to eat inside
didn't really work
i think it was too low for him he was
too shy but today
we have another plan bigger shelf this
better work
i hope so buddy chef chef
we jump up little man i think this could
work
chuck me a slice oh yes
perfection a little closer this time
with a trail to help him out
i think you're the one who needs help no
come on buddy so tasty you're doing so
well sweetie
no don't worry bud more
you're almost there it's a big step my
legs are so small
strong but small i'll think of a new
plan maybe a seagull balcony
from window to window so he can just
walk right in
have a snack and watch some tv that
sounds divine
we can binge watch icarly day number 41
of feeding my pet seagull to gain his
trust hey
should we watch a movie only if it's ice
age i'll get the snackos
pink fish oh for my seagull start the
movie buddy
i'm so excited we've already watched it
11 times
because it's flawless i'm crying already
it's okay we'll get through it together
i'll try be strong
that diego is so cheeky just like you
stephen
i do try perfect movie snack
here comes the waterworks this bit gets
him every time
it's so beautiful i can't watch
he's never made it to the end of the
movie but once the credits roll
he comes back for the rest of his snacks
it breaks my little
secret heart say what you want about
seagulls
but they sure do have a love for fine
cinema i just can't stop crying
day number 42 of feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
i've been trying to get some work done
all day but he won't stop staring at me
hungry i'm busy right now steven fine
what's he looking at he found the toast
or maybe it's the crocs he wants
hungry he's not gonna leave until i get
him something
let's try some more fruits thank god
they made them vegan
i'll grab some salmonella and another
octopusey as well
so colorful i hope he likes it gonna try
the fork today
i just hope he doesn't steal it and use
it against me gimme
that's quite nice glad you like it
it's refreshing and oh so healthy what
are you trying to poison me i swear it's
good for you buddy
no please it'll make you very strong
it's trash
i would have ate that do i look like i
care not even a little
but at least you learned how to use
cutlery divine
day number 43 of feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
where is that little scamp i've not seen
him all day
i'm so worried for my little buddy he
has never missed a day since he started
coming
stephen is that you no i didn't realize
how much this silly little bird meant to
me
without him sitting in his spot i feel
so empty
there goes a grandma i bet he would poop
on her if he was here
i'm tempted to do it myself but i'm too
sad without my bird
hey you finally came not yet
what about now twice why were you so
late today
colonoscopy anything serious it was
recreational
i won't ask any more questions his name
was glenn
i'm so happy you're making some new
friends today is a very exciting day
steven's new merch just arrived
he looks so handsome i can't wait to try
it on sick
fitch like a glove and almost as soft as
steven's cheeks
which cheeks all of them so cheeky we
made sure to put steven's face right on
the chest
so he can always be close to your heart
these past two months have been divine
and we love sharing these episodes with
you all
anything you want to add steven thanks
day number 43 of feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
hey today has been quite a lazy
day i've just been practicing my foot
guitar
i wrote that myself but it's time to eat
somebody just sent him his favorite
is it into the pink you betcha buddy
only the pinkist pink for you
[Applause]
be careful with the pink it's so juicy
it's incredible i can tell you have your
pinky out
i was feeling fancy so much class from
such a little bird
more please only if you do the window
trick
dealio
so talented whoa there buddy i'm just
playing
be careful you are too strong to play
like we used to
don't be such a puss gimme
divine gotta go buddy my friends are
waiting
i thought i was your friend no you're my
little buddy and buddies get pink
see you tomorrow i'll miss you buddy day
number 44
of feeding my pet seagull to gain his
trust where is that little scamp
i've not seen him all day i'm starting
to get worried
he has never missed a day since he
started coming stephen is that you
no rats i didn't realize how much this
silly little bird meant to me
when he's not sitting in his spot i feel
so empty
there goes a grandma i bet he would poop
on her if he was here
i'm tempted to do it myself but without
my buddy
i am just too sad hey
you finally came not yet what about now
twice so cheeky divine why are you so
late today
colonoscopy anything serious it was
recreational
i won't ask any more questions his name
was glenn
i'm so happy you're making some new
friends day number 45
of feeding my pet seagull to gain his
trust today we're gonna try some fresh
fish
and see if he notices the difference
chef chef it up little man
look at that cheeky caboose freshly
waxed
like father like son
we before we eat let's wash your little
pinkers
and cleanse the palate ready for the
freshest fish of your life
cleansed and ready catch the freshness
is intense
i feel tingly this piece will blow your
mind
my taste buds have peaked wait till you
try the head
the eye was exquisite last slice gimme
so fresh so divine my life will never be
the same
did you paint your toenails black i was
feeling edgy
i'm edgy as well that's just sad
i was only trying to fit in day number
of feeding my pet seagull to gain his
trust people keep asking me about
my rabies
it's now been 21 days since the
infection the day my life changed
forever
my sleeps are restless and my dreams are
so frightening
but in those dreams i can fly and that's
pretty cool
also check this out if i lift up my
sleep jeans
my leggies have gone completely pink i'm
so happy
i've always admired his little pinkers
and i finally have a set of my own
dreams really do come true they make you
look that
just wait till i break them in but apart
from the pinkers
not much else has changed except my
beard has finally started to fill out
feed me sure thing buddy we
we this smells kind of tasty did you
wake up with a death wish
it was just a joke jokes are supposed to
be funny
let's hear a better one then come on
funny boy
your face nice one buddy
day number 47 of feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
open this goddamn window now go grab
mama some snackouts
let's try some hockey bassin chef chef
nice and squidgy very squidgy
but so divine it makes my tongue tingle
and my foot sees curl
cool your jets young man this is a
wholesome snack oh
i'm just warming up for glenn hello baby
we're just friends special friends back
off
i'm just happy to see you so happy he
makes me feel special
let's go baby i planned something
special on the roof
gotta go buddy have some extra protein
you're gonna need it
you kids have fun this roof's about to
get sweaty
please clean up when you're done day
number 48 of feeding my pet seagull to
gain his trust
hey let's make a tiny seagull
breakfast tomato eggies
with fishy pancakes
oh my god they are so small
can you speed up two minutes buddy
i'll get started on the cakeys
cakeys i'm so excited i'll make them
extra special
please bumblebee tuna with a little fish
lego
for dessert with some seagull h2o to
wash it down
looks incredible we cake me
veggies first you know the rule
tasteless
egg time nice egg i laid them myself
they taste so fresh try the cakey
divine more tomy no stinky
wash the taste out your little beak it's
time for dessert
catch basin clean plate so tasty
i'm so glad you liked it see you
tomorrow buddy
bye day number 49 of feeding my
pet seagull to gain his trust
something special just arrived in
the mail
i wonder what's inside it's steven's new
merch
oh my god bird into house fits like a
glove
so soft and moist we do you have one for
me
sorry buddy they only make them for
humans that's discrimination
i know and it makes me sick to my core
but don't worry little
man tuna baboona makes the pain go away
so true how's it taste
divine you've earned it buddy you've
been such a good boy
i can't wait to build your window
balcony and see your little pinkers walk
inside
we can watch your seventh favorite movie
13 going on 30.
fabulous oh i can't wait to have my bird
in the house
and i can't wait to be roomies see you
tomorrow buddy
bye roomie day number 50 of feeding my
pet seagull to gain his trust
hey this past week has been a
messy one and our house is starting to
smell
so i think it's about time we clean the
window just don't make it too clean
i like it dirty trust me buddy i know
don't think i didn't see you earlier
how earlier hanky panky o'clock you and
glenn on a stranger's roof
just going for it like little chickens i
was practicing my jujitsu
i've never heard it be so loud i bet you
haven't
cheeky scooch over buddy give mama some
room
kimmy yeah back off
whoa i think he smells the salmon chuck
it
divine now please let me clean hey
give me the rag it's old and stinky i
need it for jiu-jitsu you will never get
my rag
and you said we were buddies buddies
don't share jiu-jitsu rags
that's a tough one to swallow for the
past 50 days
i've been feeding my pet seagull to gain
his trust
i've spent hundreds of dollars on him
but sadly all i've gotten is rabies
and he's not once stepped a foot inside
the house but today
things are going to change what you
build in your ticket to the inside
wow
she's complete and built sturdy like a
chrysler
now we've just got to lure him inside we
not the window stephen please help we
you can do this buddy
i'm trying my best
we hey this is more of a challenge
than i thought
sorry i let you down come hither we
even in failure you will never let me
down we can try again tomorrow
that sounds divine day number 51
of feeding my pet seagull to gain his
trust
it breaks my heart to see him out in the
rain get me some snackos
sit tight little man i'll be back in a
jiffy
jesus chrysler the octo is on sale
just hope it doesn't slither out my
basket
gonna grab a magazine too for a big
surprise later
steven what you doing in the car park i
could smell the from a mile away
and i'm desperate for a slice i'll go
snip snip it up
we some fresh puss just for you buddy
better be fresh that was gorgeous
glad you like it love it
divine tuna time this is the best day
ever
and it's about to get a whole lot better
what can be better than tuna
you just got featured in cosmo what
we made it buddy die why did you do that
just a little playful vandalism die
you are so cheeky for the past 52 days
i've been feeding my pet seagull to gain
his trust
but sadly so far all of our
attempts to get him inside
have been unsuccessful even with a
custom seagull balcony
he was still too shy and i cried but
today we have a new plan
we what's the plan come hither
bigger balcony it's working already my
heart is racing
i can hear it and it's making me hungry
please eat the salmon instead
wow chuck it it tastes different today
it tastes like home you're always
welcome here buddy
thanks gimme sweet divine
i'm so proud of you steven seeing your
little pinkers walk into the room
makes these past two months worth every
second such a good boy
we love you buddy you're gonna make me
cry
day number 53 of feeding my pet
seagull to gain his trust
get the snackos yes sir i'll see
what we have in stock
tasty tuna sounds divine
we get the balcony scooch over little
man
let's play hide the tuna no pretty
please
did i stutter so sorry die
whoopsie why seagull why you hit the
tuna
never do that again
gimme he's getting more comfortable
coming inside
my little buddy is so brave and his
little pinkers are looking stronger than
ever
water please let's see if he can drink
out the tub
that's a sweet tub make it rain baby
why do you always choose violence it's
funny
and sexy gotta go buddy got another
colonoscopy
fifth one this week day number 54 of
feeding my pet seagull to gain his trust
recently he's been looking a little
chubby so this week we're going on a
seagull diet
excuse me just a little one buddy it
will make you stronger
no if you stick to it i'll buy you a toy
boy
deal kitty snackos with big protein
for his chunky pinkers
we what the hell is that seagull cookies
i'll give it a try
cookie catch no too dry
have a quick sip much better
all done so dry ready for my toy boy
not yet buddy you'll get it when you
lose a few pounds we
he looks so sad i'll just get a kfc
day number 55 of feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
hey recently he's been looking a
little chubby so this week we're going
on a seagull diet
starting with some fresh snackos just
gotta find the seagull section
little wormies sounds divine should i
get him a cool seagull jacket
please it's a little small maybe if you
stick to your diet
deal oh these are so gross
are those wormies you know it buddy
delicious you missed one gotcha more
please
have a quick sip and i'll get the
dessert gimme
yes you're doing so well on your diet
buddy
your little pinkers are looking
healthier than ever looks like we have a
runner
chuck it divine see ya buddy
gonna get another kfc you are so cheeky
day number 56 of feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
hey hey buddy i'll go get your
snackos
a tasty wormy bird cereal are the worms
fresh
made them myself gimme
nice and moist you're splashing all over
me i don't care
you cheeky goose more please
tasty all done
it's so warm today you must be thirsty
so much
divine give your pinkers a little soap
too
oh yes so refreshing
always glad to help out buddy see ya
i'm about to kick some ass
nobody steals my roof get lost crow
you're so territorial i've made you so
strong
day number 57 of feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
hey hey buddy i was just out on my
unicycle
and i decided to stop by the sea and try
find steven a cool shell
or stone trash none of these are good
enough for my little buddy
and i hope nobody steals the unicycle so
pretty
gonna take this one home for him i
searched the beach for a full three
hours
but couldn't find a cool shell these are
the best i've got
and i'm almost embarrassed to show them
to him i just hope he knows that i tried
my best
somebody just stole the unicycle and it
made me really sad
but thank god i have a pet seagull to
make everything better
a gift for me not just any old gift it's
a gift
from the sea they are precious i'll put
this one on your favorite chill-out spot
i will treasure it forever want some
wormies
we
divine see you tomorrow buddy bye
day number 58 of feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
hey hello my son your phalanges
look so tasty
they are not yours to digest yesterday
we went to the beach to find steven a
gift
a pet rock i'm testing him to see if he
can look after it and not lose it
i love my rock time to see if it's still
there
oh my god well done stephen you make me
so proud
philangies no what about the pinky i'll
be gentle
control yourself this is the last day of
your diet we are having wormies
you are so ravenous ravenous for
philangi
stephen i told you no whoopsie
cheeky little bird it's a good thing i
am immune to seagull rabies
no rugrats you keep me on my toes and
make every day a dangerous
wee and exciting adventure and you mean
more to me
than you could ever understand you are
my only friend
you're gonna make me cry day
number 59
of feeding my pet seagull to gain his
trust hey
i'm starting to get worried about my
little buddy it's so windy
and i've not seen him all day also the
rock i gave him two days ago
has disappeared and today was the last
day of his seagull diet
he was such a good boy and only bid me
once this week
i even went to the store and got in the
toy boy i promised
because he stuck to his diet along with
his favorite snacko
chef chef but he's an hour late and
nowhere to be seen
i miss my little buddy crybaby steven
you had me so worried kimmy
juicy want some more please
divine gotta go need to protect my
babies
wait a minute don't forget your toy boy
he's gone
and back to protecting his eggos already
i'll save it for tomorrow
you're doing such a good job and i can't
wait to meet the babies
day number 60 of feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
hey hello son go to the other
window on my way buddy
i'll get the snackos
big tasty tuna tuna baboona you know it
buddy
come grab a slice can you get rid of the
candle
sorry about that buddy i forgot how
anxious you get around fire
too many bad memories you're safe now i
can still hear the screaming
you poor thing tuna that pain away
it's working you are so ferocious
divine quick sip please
want to chew on your toy boy no
more for me i guess what about that
grandma do you want to poop on her
or should i we can do it together follow
me
wait up buddy i'll meet you down there
day number 61
of feeding my pet seagull to gain his
trust hey
hey buddy we have a little appetizer
and a quick sip to cleanse the palate
cleansed
i'll be back in a jiffy somebody sent
you a snack oh
sick be a good boy don't poop on the tv
fresh salmon yes please only the best
for my seagull
and they cut it into seagull size pieces
just for him
looks delicious can i taste of course
brilliant catch tastes so fresh
try the skin so oily to moisturize your
pink knees
it's working divine sorry we've not used
the platform recently
we're working on a new one that goes
window to window
and allow him to walk across to the
other side or he can just chill there
all day
and watch some tv i can't wait buddy see
you tomorrow young man
bye feeding you is the best part
of my day day number 62
of feeding my pet seagull to gain his
trust hey
hey buddy for the past two months we
have been trying to get him inside the
house
but sadly every attempt has either ended
in failure
or rabies but i love my little buddy
so i'm never giving up
what you're building buddy just a little
seagull balcony
will it take long maybe a little suck on
this while you wait
out with the old we and in with the new
she's so sturdy like a chrysler i've
trained you so well
oh my god he's doing it
more please and back
divine i'm so happy i could cry
well done stephen you've made these past
62 days
worth every second you're growing up so
fast and i truly cherish every day
we get to spend together shut up
day number 63
of feeding my pet seagull to gain his
trust i've never seen him sit like this
before
it's been a long day my pinkers are
sweaty needing a quick sip
yes please here you go little buddy
today is a special day i've got some big
news to show you
i'm so excited i'll go get it along with
your snackos
gimme sweet meat buddy try the face
the chin was so tender ready for the
surprise ready freddy
because you did so well on your diet
last week and made some serious gains
you just made the cover of seagull
fitness magazine
look at page 69 oh my god steven
are those real all natural baby you make
me so proud
this deserves another snack oh oh my god
he's lying down on the window ready for
another movie
say no more divine
good job buddy i feel so at peace when
stephen is doing well
die i just wish he wasn't so violent
giving my pets eagle
a cheeky sweet treat looks girthy pace
yourself buddy
what do you think steven is it tasty
the flavor is okay but the texture is
all wrong
keeps getting stuck in my beak and it's
pissing me off
your palate is so sophisticated earlier
today while giving my pet's eagle
his afternoon sip usually a wholesome
and joyous occasion he spat right into
my mouth and eyes
it tasted like wormies gotcha i
didn't know he had such a good aim
i'm kinda impressed and really hope i
don't get sick
day number 64 of feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
look at those cheeky feathers blowing in
the wind feed me
i'll set up the platform and get the
snackos please hurry up i am starving
sit tight buddy wormies don't take too
long
we did you say wormies only if you sit
down
and be a good boy sitting you are so
clever
wormies please here you go little man
oh baby we've got a runner
so tasty have a quick sip oh my god
wormies don't you dare be right back
buddy gotta kick some ass
this is so intense hey well done
buddy have a victory sit
divine gonna get the glovies and try
give him a pet
excuse me maybe i should try just with
the gloves first
they are covered in salmon jimmy i don't
think it's gonna work
i'd use my hands but they look too much
like sausages
and one of these days they will be
inside me it would be some good protein
but i need them to play my banjo wormies
will have to do
what about your footsies no means no
steven
then it's time for a kfc so cheeky
i'll see you tomorrow day number 65 of
feeding my pet seagull to gain his trust
hey back in a jiffy i'll get some
snackos
and maybe some glovies i want to try
give you a pet
in your dreams i dream about it
every night
gotta make sure the snackos are extra
tasty so he doesn't go for my phalanges
again
get the glovies just in case chef chef
we it's tuna time we
take a seat buddy you are such a good
boy
and good boys get tuna control yourself
you're making a mess i don't care
have a quick sip and i'll get the
platform scoochie
is it sturdy give it a test it's sturdy
divine we good job buddy
i really hope these are seagull proof
sit stephen
be gentle always buddy
boopy quite soothing i'm so happy
maybe tomorrow he will let me pet his
little pinkers pinkers cost extra
how about another lobster please
see you tomorrow little buddy love you
buddy you fill my life with happiness
day number 66 of feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
hey hey buddy want some snackos
please
i'll go grab your favorites and some
water
with a wormy garnish delicious jump up
we it's snack o'clock only if you sit
down and wait
like a good seagull deal seagulls who
can sit
get tasty salmon oh no nice job
butterfingers
it's not my fault it's so wet same
have a little sip no tuna your wish is
my command
don't you forget it so divine
looks like we have a trespasser hello
that was pathetic boopy time
just let me get comfortable i'll get the
glovy
ready for boopy boopy
gotta go buddy my babies need me you are
such a good papa
you taught me so well i can't wait to be
a grand papa
yesterday after feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
hey i watched him fly back over to
his nest to his newborn babies
i am so proud of my little buddy i was
his papa
now he is a papa of his own did
you see them
they are so small i'm so happy for you
buddy they are my everything
just like you are to me i couldn't have
done it without you buddy
such a beautiful night for seagull
babies can you be their grandpappa
i'm so glad you asked nothing would make
me happier
we make a good team anything you or the
babies need
i'll always be there for you buddy for
the past 67 days
i've been feeding my pet seagull to gain
his trust every day we spend together is
so much fun
and he's become one of the best buddies
i've ever had
and since day number 69 is only two days
away
i really want to get stephen something
shiny to celebrate his favorite number
but to do so i need some help right now
we have 2.3 million followers on tick
tock
and around 5 000 on youtube can we get
stephen to 100
000 so i can give him the shiny play
button of his dreams
it will also give us a place to post
some longer steven videos
as well as the daily episodes we do on
here feed me
yes sir fresh fish oh for my sego
we what's its name david schwimmer
crunchy and juicy kimmy
quick sip divine brb buddy
oh my god someone's trespassing on
steven's roof
we sorry about that nobody goes near my
babies
your natural instincts are so pure
you are my champion day number 67 of
feeding my pets seagull to gain his
trust
hey hey buddy we just got a
package in the mail
i'm so excited to show you but i'll go
get the wormies first
fresh and wet wormy bird cereal just for
you buddy
we have a little chew
so tasty wait till you see this we got
some new merch
of you wearing your leather jacket
driving through the desert in a chrysler
living the dream divine summer 69
so soft and moist i look so cool you
make it so easy buddy
you're such a little rock star wait till
you see this one
another cheeky pinkers on the back
little face on the front
did you get one for me not yet buddy
we're still trying to figure out your
size
you keep making gains and it's hard to
keep up but we will keep trying
you're splashing in my eyes but i don't
care
time to go buddy need to feed the babies
you're such a good papa
look at them run over to him so adorable
i'm so proud of my little buddy
i could cry but i'll save the tears for
when i get to meet the babies
day number 68 of feeding my pet seagull
to gain his trust
recently my chunky little man became a
seagull daddy
just like myself so i went to the
store
to get him a cheeky gift to congratulate
my little buddy
and whipped him up some tuna baboona his
favorite snacko
get inside me come get it daddy give me
sip big sip for a big boy
sit before you eat you know the rule
anything for tuna
good boy go crazy and make sure to take
extra for the babies
they will be so strong just like their
papa have a little rinse
and i'll get your present present just a
little something for you and the babies
to steve daddy420 thanks for being so
divine
you shouldn't have i'd do anything for
you buddy one more for the road
time to go buddy the babies need me on
you go little man
we we this melts my heart every single
time
i can't wait for episode 69 day number
of feeding my pet seagull to gain his
trust i can't believe
how far this series has come when we
started stephen was just a baby
and i was just a clueless seagull
daddy
but now he's all grown up and so
incredibly talented
and he even became a daddy himself
creating this series has given me so
much happiness
and made me so proud of my little buddy
so to celebrate his favorite number
i went out and got him some special
balloons
along with his tastiest snacko he's
gonna be so surprised
gonna hide them in the corner because i
think he would attack them
hey hey little buddy are those
balloons for me
you know it don't you ever call me
a
i'm sorry i am boiling with rage
try this piece forgive you buddy you've
got some stuck to your lips
it's a piercing it suits you so well
catchy
well done please be more careful
better it's so warm today you must be
thirsty
parched want another chunk oh
please oh god it landed on his back
you idiot sorry about that buddy want a
little boobie
just a quickie only way i know how
cheers buddy
here's to 69 divine days together and to
the next 69.
time to go buddy can i stay for a little
longer what about the babies
i'll bring them the fallen salmon you're
such a great papa
bye we papa hey babies
it's snacko time forgive me so far
raising stephen
has been my most rewarding life
accomplishment happy day 69 everyone
[Music]
are you still here piss off