welcome to the effortless English show
with the world's number one English
teacher AJ Hoge where AJ's more than 40
million students worldwide finally learn
English once and for all
without the boring textbooks classrooms
and grammar drills here's AJ with a
quick piece to help you learn to speak
fluent English effortlessly hi I'm AJ
Hoge the author of effortless English
learn to speak English like a native
though too effortless English club comm
and join my VIP program effortless
English club.com you speaking English
powerfully speaking English fluently in
six months fluent in six months is it
possible can you do it can you speak
English fluently powerfully in six
months six months from today and the
answer is yes yes you can absolutely yes
you can let's talk about what this means
to be fluent and how to do it first
let's just talk about this word fluid
fluent in six months fluent what does
this word fluent mean fluent well fluent
has the same root as the word fluid
fluid means flowing or moving like water
okay water like movement right so if you
think of water think of a river or a
stream how does it move right it it kind
of it moves effortlessly that's why I
use the name effortless English water
moves effortlessly and smoothly right
that's how water flows or moves so
fluent or fluency we're talking about a
son
buthe movement now if we're talking
about English what are we talking about
it's the smooth movement of words of
phrases of sentences of the language it
means you speak in a way that's fairly
effortless and smooth the opposite of
fluent would be to speak like speak like
this and right that's the opposite of
fluid it means it's the words are not
coming out smoothly they're not coming
out easily they're not coming out
naturally right that's not fluent so
just we're talking specifically about
speaking when we say fluent or fluency
which I'm not speaking and how the words
come out that's the meaning of fluency
that is the real meaning of fluency so
flowing like water I often try to use
the phrase powerful powerfully speak
powerfully so again you're confident
when you speak the words come out fairly
easily they flow out this does not mean
let's talk about what fluency does not
mean it does not mean perfection right
if you're fluent you're conversationally
fluent it means you're fluent when you
have a normal conversation you're not
perfect you're not perfect you will make
mistakes you'll mix grammar mistakes you
might make some pronunciation mistakes
hey I make mistakes sometimes still so
you're gonna make mistakes it's not
perfection
number two fluency does not mean like a
native speaker okay so when you speak
fluently it does not mean you speak at
the same level as I do I learned English
as from when I was a baby so it does not
mean like a native speaker that's a much
higher level of English speaking that's
very very advanced okay you don't need
that advanced level to speak fluently
for your words to come out easily for
you to communicate effectively a fluency
is sort of the first level communicating
effectively powerfully the words
fairly easily what else do you need a
huge amount of vocabulary to speak
fluently no you don't because again
we're talking about conversational
fluency so when you are fluent then
you're conversationally fluent what does
it mean it means you speak and
communicate fairly easily effectively
powerfully in normal conversations
normal everyday conversations normal
everyday topics so not talking about
special topics like economics or
business or something from you know
school no everyday you know talking
about the weather talking about your
feelings how you feel
talking about what you did today or
yesterday or what you're going to do
tomorrow you buying a train ticket yep
going shopping those everyday normal
conversations that we have for that you
only need about 3,000 words of
vocabulary
some people say less some people say a
little more I'll just give you the
average look around 3,000 words that's
not a huge amount it's not small it's
not tiny but it's not huge so if you can
use 3,000 words
fairly easily in natural phrases you're
fluent you're conversationally fluent
are you finished with English at that
point no you're not you still have a
long way to go if you want to be like a
native speaker close to a native but you
can certainly be fluent in six months so
what it means is you speak powerfully
naturally smooth fairly smoothly with
mistakes you will definitely be making
mistakes still after six months don't
worry about it
as long as people understand you as long
as you're communicating well you're
fluent let's talk about the next part of
this fluent in six months six months
what do we mean by that six months well
honestly if we talk about six months
it's not talking about months is not
really the best way to talk about time
for your goal of speaking English in six
months
as you can imagine imagine we have two
students one student only listens to
English one hour per week and the other
one listens to English ten hours per day
after six months there's going to be a
huge difference between these two if
someone only does one hour per week they
will not be fluent in six months it's
not enough time really we should talk
about hours rather than days or weeks or
months or years it's the hours it's a
number of hours you spend learning
English that's important so when we're
talking about getting fluent in six
months there are two important things
there's quantity it means the amount the
amount of hours especially and there's
quality quality it's how you use those
hours every day because how you learn is
also very very important you could spend
five hours a day learning English but do
it in a way that's not effective low
quality so you need both quantity and
quality to achieve this goal let's first
talk about the quantity how many hours
do you need how many hours do you need
to become fluent conversationally fluent
well it's different for every person I
can't give you an exact number I'll give
you a very general number let's say
about 700 hours about 700 hours of
quality effective English learning study
practice training about 700 hours now
for some people it will be more might be
a thousand and for some one might be
less so we'll just say as a general
average guess about 700 hours now here's
some good news you already have some
hours right you probably learn English
in school for many years
that was low quality a lot of those
hours were not very good but still it's
better than nothing okay if you learn
English for five years in school you at
least learn some vocabulary through
memorization maybe you can't use it very
effectively maybe your head is filled
with grammar and you're confused you're
not fluent yet
but it's still better than zero so you
still have some hours already that's
good news that will help you it means
you don't quite need seven hundred maybe
you only need five hundred to get
fluency which is great good news for you
the other part of this that's quantity
that's the amount of hours you need in
six months the next part is quality it's
how you do it is very important as I
said in school low low low quality you
might learn English in school for a
thousand hours but the problem is your
memorizing lists of vocabulary that you
quickly forget you're memorizing long
lists of grammar that you can't use when
you speak too complicated you forget
you're taking tasks you're stressed
you're bored a lot of time in class
you're not you're not really focused
you're kind of bored when you're doing
your homework you're bored you're half
asleep so you might have a thousand
hours in school but it does not really
equal a thousand quality hours and maybe
it only equals about a hundred hours
really because it's so low quality so
you want to get the highest quality from
every minute from every hour that you
learn English that is what the
effortless English system does so what
do I mean by quality number one power
right it is this a powerful way to learn
it means you are focused you are focused
and concentrating every minute so if
you're listening to English but you're
kind of falling asleep you're sitting at
your desk that's low quality that's no
good you're wasting a lot of your time
you need to be a your brain needs to be
awake you need to be focused you need to
be listening carefully to every word
every phrase that's the highest quality
alert awake maximum concentration it
needs to be understandable this is
something else for quality English
learning you must understand it if you
don't understand it you're wasting your
time so this is the problem if your
lower level and you listen to a movie or
a TV show you're wasting your time it's
too advanced you
understand anything so most of your time
is completely wasted you watching out 2
hours or an hour of TV but really you're
getting almost no quality English
learning so you must understand it it
can be a little difficult but not do
difficult very very important
understandable is super important that's
part of quality next you need to have
some emotion positive even negative
sometimes but especially strong positive
emotions will help you learn much faster
that's also part of quality it's why I
use stories a lot in effortless English
just think about it when you learn
something with no emotion just gonna
flat it's much more easy to forget but
if you learn something with excitement
or energy or passion or sometimes even
fear or humor laughter you are more
likely to remember it and to remember it
a long time so it needs to be emotional
and energetic emotion and energy go
together
so again a low energy low quality way to
study English is to sit at your desk
listening or just reading a textbook
right as low energy your mind starts to
go to sleep you're wasting a lot of your
time but if you're up if you're moving
if your your hearts you know leading you
got energy going through your body
you're feeling good you're smiling
you're awake your brain wakes up
everything is much more effective
everything you do you will remember
better you will learn faster this is so
important you need the highest quality
time to achieve this goal I'll give you
a quick example of this let's say you're
trying to learn the verb to cuddle to
cuddle that's a nice little word to
cuddle now you could the low quality way
the school way the normal way to learn
to cuddle would be to look in the
dictionary for the verb to cuddle and to
write down the meaning and then to
memorize it the title the cuddle Dakota
little is repeated a lot right is it's
good more
so it's probably gonna be low energy
there's no emotion you're trying to
memorize it and then you probably have a
list of a lot more words you're also
trying to memorize so when you get to
the end of the list you've forgotten the
first one you forgot cuddle and then you
got to go back and try it again again
and again and again and again it's
boring it's ineffective you waste a lot
of time what does it mean by the way to
cuddle the cuddle means to be like
affectionate like to hug and kind of rub
with someone it has a romantic idea okay
so you can it's not really sexual okay
but it can be if you have a girlfriend
boyfriend they like to cuddle right
they're always touching and hugging and
rubbing against each other oh but you
can also do it you know children like to
cuddle so if you have a child you can
cuddle and hug them and oh it feels so
good or even with a dog a puppy right a
puppy you can play it on you hug them in
oh yeah maybe it's not like super
romantic kissing but you know kiss them
on the head and again it's more of this
action of rubbing and holding and
hugging to cuddle so you've got the one
way the old way to learn it you just
have try to memorize it to hug
affectionately imagine a different way
of learning this word imagine that a
super sexy hot guy or girl whichever you
prefer
comes up to you and you think oh this
person is so so amazing so attractive I
love them so much I want them and they
come up to you and say let's cuddle
that's good ah and then they they hug
you mister you start rubbing against
each other and holding each other hmm
and there and again they're whispering
the word in your ear oh it feels so good
to cuddle with you oh I love cuddling
with you now how are you going to feel
you're going to feel your hearts gonna
be beating super powerful emotion
there's also physical feelings happening
at the same time which one is more
memorable are you going to remember
studying it from the dictionary
definition trying to memorize the old
way the normal school way or are you
gonna remember this super
emotional experience of this hot guy or
girl cuddling with you and saying the
word in your ear
obviously cuddling with the guy or the
girl it will be much more memorable I
guarantee you will never forget that
word again this will become one of your
favorite words you'll know you'll you'll
learn it instantly and you'll never
forget it that's an example an extreme
example of the highest quality of
learning in this case vocabulary right
because it's got the maximum amount of
emotion
now of course normally day to day it's
hard to achieve that super high level of
emotion I wish we could it's hard to but
still we can get much more emotion if we
learn vocabulary and learn phrases and
even grammar using stories using
physical movement all the things we do
in effortless English or design to bring
the emotion higher bring the energy
higher so that you remember everything
much faster and longer that's how we get
faster more powerful results because the
quality is so much higher with
effortless English let's talk about
another example I want you to train like
a champion
imagine that English instead of like a
subject you study in school more instead
imagine it's more like a sport it's an
activity that you're training for like
you would for a sport right to be a
champion you're going to be a champion
English speaker you are a champion
English speaker
how would you train like a champion I do
do Jitsu Brazilian jiu-jitsu that's why
it's my hobby so let's imagine a
jiu-jitsu - jiu-jitsu fighters -
jiu-jitsu students ok what is just a
normal person like me like like most
people who learn jujitsu and the other
one is Andre Galvao who is a world
champion let's look at the difference in
quality how they train and quant
how do they train jiu-jitsu and how do
they get results what are the results
how are they different what's different
about a champion and a normal person
because again I want you to be a
champion in English not just a normal
school learner a normal person for
jiu-jitsu mmm usually goes to class two
or three times per week two or three
times a week is the kind of normal
average jiu-jitsu learner now that's
what I do most of the people I know
train two to three times per week
what does Andre Galvao do world champion
he trains twice per day maybe more two
times per day that's fourteen times per
week instead of two or three
so his quantity his amount is much much
higher I guess what it's also much more
quality the other thing when a normal
person learns a new technique in
jiu-jitsu they practice that technique
maybe ten times
maybe twenty times I'd say at the most
probably fifty times how many times does
Andre Galvao practice a new technique
that he's working on a thousand times or
more he practises each new technique
1,000 times or more the amount of
repetition that a champion gets in their
practice in their training is much much
higher again so much higher quantity
repetitions it's the amount of time the
number of hours per day and also the
amount of repetition that they get is so
much higher for a champion and then the
quality what about the quality the
amount of focus so for a normal digital
learner they think of it as kind of a
hobby that's how I think if you Jitsu
it's a hobby so I go and I try to pay
attention I'm focused of course and I'm
awake when I'm there I'm enjoying myself
but Andre got our or another champion is
much much higher than that they are toad
focused right they are super high-energy
they are serious they are concentrating
every minute they are learning every
minute they're training the intensity
the emotion is super high they're also
consistent normal people who are
learning something like jiu-jitsu or any
sport as a hobby yeah you know some days
you feel good and you try really hard
and some days maybe you're a little
tired a little lazy you don't try your
best and it's kind of up and down day to
day it's different
a champion like on during about every
moment every day every training it's a
hundred percent effort all the time a
hundred percent energy all the time a
hundred percent passion and emotion all
the time every minute every hour every
week every month of training the
emotional quality the energy is so much
higher than just regular normal people
and of course what's the result under go
bow super fast improvement world
champion normal people still improving
the slow slow improvement hey I'm
getting a little better at Jiu Jitsu but
it's very slow most people you know they
improve but slowly nothing like a
champion normal people will never become
world champions we can learn from this
example because we see this in all
sports in all different skill areas this
same idea of quantity and quality that's
what determines the amount of success
you have how powerful your results are
and how fast your improvement is so you
I want you to be a powerful champion I
want you to be the Andre Galvao of
English learning you can be a champion
English speaker you can speak English
powerfully and fluently in six months
six months from now you can do it you
will do it when you use the effortless
English system the highest quantity you
can get and of course most important
is quality every single time you listen
to English learn English train with
English quality quality quality and
that's what effortless English is about
now another important point don't let
anyone else tell you that you cannot do
this don't let anyone else tell you you
can't do anything in life not just about
English in anything there are always
people out there who will tell you you
can't do it it can't be done you can't
be fluent in six months you can't make a
lot of money you can't start your own
business you can't you can't in
ying-ying ying-ying Union alright
there's always these negative people in
life I promise you any time you try to
do something amazing any time you try to
succeed any time you push yourself there
will be people telling you you can't do
it there'll be people trying to make you
feel weaker alright there's I don't know
if it's jealousy I don't know if they're
disappointed in their own life I don't
know why they do it but they do they're
just a lot of negative people in the
world who will criticize you will tell
you you can't do it you shouldn't do it
all the time don't listen to these
people champions do not listen to
negative people champions just ignore
those people see my job is the opposite
I always call myself an English coach
not a teacher I think teachers are too
negative I just don't like the word
teacher coach right a coach my job is to
be your coach and as your coach I want
to destroy doubt I want to destroy
weakness okay I want to build your power
I want to build and increase your
confidence I want you to believe in
yourself I want you to dream bigger I
want you to dream more powerfully I want
you to believe that you can do it that
you will do it whenever you want in life
certainly English but anything else that
you want in your life you
and do it it is possible you can be
powerful in your life you can speak
English powerfully you can be fluent in
six months you can eventually become
like a native speaker if that's what you
want you can do it you do have the power
trust yourself
don't listen to all the people say now
now now you can't you can't no you can
and you will will it always be easy no
but you're strong you will find the
strength you will find the power you can
and you will be a champion just believe
in your self that is my message to you
think like a champion act like a
champion train like a champion with
English and you will speak English
powerfully and fluently in six months
maybe less maybe more it's your decision
you can and you will do it be a champion
and trust yourself and go to effortless
English club.com
effortless English club.com join my VIP
program see you next time
you