You may think that I'm talking foolish
You've heard that I'm wild and I'm free
You may wonder how I can promise you now
This love that I feel for you always will be
But you're not just time that I'm killin'
I'm no longer one of those guys
As sure as I live, O..  this love that I give
Is gonna be yours until the day that I die
Oh, baby, I'm gonna love you forever
Forever and ever, amen
As long as old men sit and talk about the weather
As long as old women sit and talk about old men
If you wonder how long I'll be faithful
I'll be happy to tell you again
Ooo Darling... I'm gonna love you forever and ever
Forever and ever, amen
They say time take its toll on a body
Makes a young men's brown hair turn gray
Well, honey, I don't care, I ain't in love with your hair
And if it all fell out, O.. I'd love you anyway
Ooo... They say time takes its toll on a mem'ry
Make's people forget things they knew
Well, it's easy to see, O.. it's happenin' to me
Caus I've already forgotten every woman but you
Oh, darlin', I'm gonna love you forever
Forever and ever, amen
As long as old men sit and talk about the weather
As long as old women sit and talk about old men
If you wonder how long I'll be faithful
Ooo... Just listen to how this song ends
Oh Darling.. I'm gonna love you forever and ever
Forever and ever 3x, Amen...
Hu...... Hu.. Hu.... Hu... Hu...