Well hello and welcome to this
English lesson about Halloween.
For those of you that don't
know what Halloween is it's a
tradition. It's an event. It's
not really a celebration. I
guess you could call it that.
It's something that happens at
the end of October every year.
And it involves candy and
costumes and a lot of other
things which I will be
explaining in this lesson. Uh
Halloween for me as a child was
a very enjoyable time. Because
my parents would take me out
for Halloween I would get dressed up and
we would go to all of the
neighbour's houses and we would
get lots of candy. Sometimes we
would even get pop like soda.
Uh and one of our neighbours
even gave us money at
Halloween. So that was kind of
cool. But if you don't know
what Halloween is it's coming
up this weekend. Stick around
for this lesson and I will
explain all of the aspects of
Halloween to you. That you need
to know to have a good
conversation about it in
English. Or at the very least
to understand and other people
when they talk about Halloween.
So as you can see here most
graphics or images that you
find for Halloween. They'll
have things like skulls and
bats and spiders and witches
hats and jack-o-lanterns which
I'll talk about later. But
they're not images of fun
things. Which is kind of
strange because Halloween is
something that happens once a
year. And generally it's
something that is fun.
Halloween happens on October
31st. It's in a couple of days.
And on that day Uh it's usually
fairly cool weather in our
area. But in spite of the cold
kids will go out and they will
go from house to house. They
will go from door to door. And
they'll ring the doorbell or
they'll knock and then they'll
say trick or treat. Now I think
a long time ago trick or treat
meant either give me a treat.
Give me some candy or I will
play a trick on you. But it's
not very often that kids
actually play tricks on people
at Halloween. Ninety-nine point
percent of the time kids say
trick or treat and the person
at the house they are at will
give them some kind of candy or
chocolate so trick or treat I'm
going to talk about this on two
slides because trick or treat
is what kids say. So they ring
the doorbell ding dong. When
the door opens they hold out
their Halloween bag and they
say trick or treat and then the
person usually gives them some
kind of candy. We also use it
as a verb though. So you can
say that you're going to go
trick or treating. Okay well
not exactly a verb but you can
say you are going to
participate in the act of trick
or treating. So someone at work
yesterday just said are you
taking your kids out to go
trick or treating this weekend?
And I responded by saying no my
youngest kid is too old for to
go trick or treating. Usually
in our family once our kids are
about 12 years old they don't
go out trick or treating
anymore. We don't take them out
trick or treating. Um just so
you know with little kids
parents usually go with when
they go trick or treating. And
when they're around age 12 or
13 they might go with a group
of friends trick or treating.
Um but our kids are too old to
go trick or treating. But we
will be home. I'll show you
something in a sec. We will be
home on that evening and we
will of course be handing out
candy. Um usually kids will
dress up in a costume. So they
will decide what they want to
be for Halloween. Okay. They'll
decide how they want to dress
up for Halloween. So a common
question will be this. What are
you gonna be for Halloween? And
that means what costume are you
going to wear? What character
or what are you going to dress
up as? When I was a kid you
could either be a cow, a
pirate, a cowboy, or a
princess. I think we only
really had four Halloween
costumes at our house and so
you would choose one of those
when you went out. Of course I
used the verb to dress up
already. Um either you say I'm
going to be Mario for
Halloween. I'm going to wear a
Mario costume for Halloween. Or
I'm going to dress up as Mario
for Halloween. A few different
ways to talk about how you are
going to dress up in order to
go out for Halloween. And maybe
you'll wear a mask. You could
see this kid has a little mask
on. Um she has a mask that has
a little it looks like a little
beak. Maybe she's trying to
pretend to be a bird. Um so you
cannot only dress up as people.
You can dress up as animals as
well. As you might have heard
when I said I would dress up as
a cow sometimes for Halloween.
I think my mom actually made
the cow costume. I should ask
her about it today. I'm going
to see my mom tonight. I should
ask her about the cow costume.
We'll probably have a good
laugh about it. Some of the
most popular costumes at
Halloween the probably the most
popular costume is to dress up
as a superhero. When I give out
candy this weekend I will
probably see a few Batmans,
some Supermans, some Wonder
Woman's probably a few Black
Widows probably Iron Man
Captain America. All of the
superheroes that you see in
movies usually show up at your
door but usually a lot because
they're kids. Um so you will
see a lot of superheroes. I
think Batman is probably one of
the most popular ones. Although
last year I did see a lot of
kids dressed up as Iron Man as
well. Um another common costume
is to be a pirate. If you're
not sure what a pirate is a
pirate is someone from a long
time ago who would sail around
on a boat and attack other
boats and steal all of their
gold and other things that were
valuable. Uh so for some this
has survived as a as a
Halloween costume quite often.
Uh I think because it's simple
if you wear a white poofy shirt
and a hat and find a plastic
sword you're basically a
pirate. So it's a simple
costume for parents to put
together for their kids to
wear. Uh sometimes you just
dress up as normal people. Kids
will dress up as construction
workers. Uh they'll dress up
well I was gonna say as
teachers but I've never seen
that happen. Um but kids will
dress up as construction
workers. They will dress up as
firefighters. Um I think I have
one here. They will dress up as
regular jobs as well. Um as I
mentioned one of the costumes
we had as a kid was a princess
costume. I think my mom found a
dress somewhere and so my
sister sometimes would go as a
princess. Still a very very
common costume at Halloween to
see kids come as a princess. Oh
and I I went the wrong way. Um
sometimes kids dress up as a
mummy. Although this costume
doesn't always survive the
evening. A mummy is someone
yeah well I don't know if
you've ever watched a movie
with mummies in it. Uh
mummification is something they
do to people after they pass
away thousands of years ago in
Egypt. Um and they would put
them in the pyramids but
mummies have lots of white
strips of cloth around them. So
it becomes kind of I guess a
relative easy costume although
most of the time when someone
dresses up as a mummy the the
the cloth starts to fall off as
the evening goes by and then we
said firefighter another very
common costume is to dress up
as a ghost I think this is a
common costume as well sorry
I'm not ignoring you I'm just
pulling up my slides over here
for a second cuz I need to kind
of follow along where did they
go
I can't. I the alphabet's not
working for me in my brain
right now. I'll find them
later. Uh a ghost is a very
common costume because all you
need is an old white sheet and
you cut a few holes in it and
voila that's a French word but
we use it in English too.
Voila. You have a a Halloween
costume. So you will often see
one or two ghosts. Um really
short ghosts. Uh during the
Halloween season or on the
evening of Halloween. Sometimes
people dress up as witches. So
a witch is a character who
maybe If you read books you'll
read about witches. I think
there's witches in Macbeth if
you ever read Shakespeare.
Witches sometimes make potions
and they do magic and sometimes
they're considered to be bad
people. But there are things
like yeah I'm trying to think
here. There is a good witch
isn't there? Uh in why can't I
remember the name? Maybe
someone could tell me what
movie The Good Witch is. Oh The
Wizard of Oz. There's a good
witch. Um so a witch is kind of
a evil woman. Uh that but not
always. Sometimes they're good.
Yeah. But sometimes people
dress up as witches. I'm not
explaining this one very well.
You should look at the spelling
of witch though. We have a few
spellings of the word witch in
in English. Excuse me. I'm not
quite sure what that was. But
this is the scariest picture I
have in the slideshow. These
are zombies. Zombies sometimes
people dress up as zombies.
It's become a lot more popular
in the last 15 or 20 years. I
think zombie movies have become
very popular. A zombie is
someone who has well they're a
a fictional character who has
died and come back to life. So
sometimes people will dress up
as a zombie. I'm not a big of
dressing up in ways that scare
people like that. But you
probably have watched movies
with zombies. And if you go out
for Halloween you will
definitely see one or two kids
dressed up as zombies. It does
happen. What do you get at
Halloween? You get candy or you
get chocolate bars or candy
bars. Um you go to a house you
ring the doorbell and then
someone comes. So we're ready
to go here. We have the this is
the box that we bought for
Halloween to hand out to kids.
So you could see there are I
don't know how close I can put
this. Will it focus? Here we
go. So there are four different
kinds of chocolate bars in
here. In my part of Canada I
call these chocolate bars. In
some parts of the world they
would call them candy bars. We
usually don't hand out candy.
We usually hand out chocolate
bars. I think because I like
chocolate bars. And so that's
what we hand out. These
chocolate bars are quite small.
So we usually should I open it?
If I open it well I start
eating them. I might start
eating them if I open it. But
I'm gonna open it to show you
Jen said we can't open this
till actual Halloween. But you
can see let me get one of each
of these out. I'm not gonna eat
them. I promise. Uh you can see
that they're quite small. Um so
we usually let kids this one
has a coffee flavour. It's kids
don't really like that one. Um
in Canada smarties are actually
a form of chocolate and then we
have Kit Kat which you might be
familiar. We usually let the
kids who come to our door. We
usually let take about five or
six a small handful. Um we
don't actually have a lot of
kids come to our house for
Halloween. So we usually give
out quite a bit of chocolate.
We would just refer to all of
these things as treats. So the
candies, the chocolate, all of
it is simply called treats.
Sometimes people hand out
licorice. They hand out small
bags of potato chips. They hand
out chocolate. Um we would just
refer to all of them as treats.
And now you can see why kids
say trick or treat. Because
they get a treat. So I
mentioned when I was a kid that
one of our neighbors would give
us money. And that neighbour
still does give out money. We
have a neighbour who instead of
getting actually our kids would
get candy. They would get
chocolate and they would get a
loony which is $1 in Canada.
And I think the last time we
went out a few years ago they
got a toonie from our
neighbours. So at some places
they will hand out money. It's
rare though. But it does happen
sometimes. Uh we also had a
neighbour that would give each
of our kids a can of pop. You
might call it soda in your part
of the world. Um my kids really
liked going to that neighbour
because they liked getting a
can of pop for Halloween. Um
and it was yeah. That's not a
common thing to get. Most kids
if you go trick or treating in
a city if you go to a house you
will get one little chocolate
bar or one little candy. Okay.
That is the most common thing
to happen. But because I live
out in the country I think the
treats were a little bigger and
better because people knew kid
weren't going to a lot of
different houses. Um when kids
go out for Halloween they will
take a bag with them. They will
have a bag to go trick or
treating. Um usually it's just
any old bag. We would just use
reusable grocery bags. But
sometimes kids will have an
actual bag that has you know a
jack-o-lantern on the side and
they'll take that out when they
go trick or treating. They'll
have a special bag when they go
out to get candy. Um but yeah
you do need a bag because
you're usually gonna end up
with almost half a bag of candy
depending on how long you go
out for and how many houses you
go to. So many people let me
get this a little bit bigger
for you. There we go. So I'm
not sure if you can see this
but some people will decorate
the outside of their house for
Halloween. We don't decorate
our house for Halloween.
Sometimes we'll have a couple
jack-o-lanterns out which I'll
show you in a moment. Um but we
don't put up lights and we
don't put up scary things. But
some people to decorate their
house for Halloween which means
they'll put out you know some
lights and pumpkins and some
other things which I'll talk
about to make their house look
a little bit spooky. So the
English word spooky means a
little bit scary or a little
bit frightening. People will
try to maybe they'll have a
little speaker outside playing
spooky sounds. Maybe they'll
have you know different things
on the front of their house
like if you look in this
picture you can see there's
cobwebs and a candle and a
spider Jack will answer him.
Let's talk about all of those
things. So pumpkins are the
most common thing to see
outside of someone's house for
two reasons. Uh one it's very
close to Thanksgiving right
now. Canadian Thanksgiving was
two weeks ago. American
Thanksgiving is about three
weeks after Halloween. So the
same some of the same
decorations that people put
outside their house for
Halloween. Like pumpkins also
work as decorations for
Thanksgiving which for
Americans is coming up in a few
weeks. None of the spooky
decorations stay out for
Thanksgiving. But some people
might have bales of straw. They
might have pumpkins and other
things. So that it kinda works
for both holidays. But if you
need a pumpkin you will usually
make a trip to a pumpkin patch.
This is a very common fall
activity for people in North
America. You will go with your
family especially if you have
little kids. You will go with
your to a pumpkin patch and you
will pick out a pumpkin or two
and you will buy them and take
them back to your house and
maybe put them on your front
step or outside your front
door. I have not gone to a
pumpkin patch for a long time.
Um in fact I don't know if I've
ever gone to a pumpkin patch
with our kids. Now maybe once
off to ask Jen but I know a few
of my colleagues with little
kids are going to a pumpkin
patch tomorrow on Saturday to
pick out some pumpkins to
decorate their house. Uh and
what people will do is they
will make what's called a
jack-o-lantern. A
jack-o-lantern is a pumpkin
where you remove everything
from the inside. You cut a hole
in the top and you take off
what's now like a lid and you
clean out the inside of the
pumpkin. All of the seeds and
there's some you know gooey wet
insides that you take out and
then you will carve a face in
the front or another design and
you will put a candle or a
flashlight or a little lantern
lantern inside the and it's a
really cool it looks really
cool in the dark okay you can
see here let me make this
bigger you can see here that
the pumpkins glow orange so the
light comes out the front many
people will do this as an
activity close to Halloween
with their kids they'll buy a
pumpkin they'll make
jack-o-lanterns kids do this
often at school as an activity
in our area as well Um
sometimes people will put
spiders outside their house.
You can see there's a big
spider fake spider on this
pillar. And this house in
particular. This is a pretty
standard front door for
someone's house close to
Halloween. People will decorate
and it will look like that.
Spiders are also scary and
spooky. Um all of the things
that frighten people show up
around Halloween. Um and then
people will put up fake spider
webs or what we sometimes call
cobwebs. So spiderwebs cobwebs
are the little web that a
spider will make in real life.
But people will actually buy
fake spiderwebs and put
spiderwebs up in the front of
their house to make it look a
little more spooky as well. And
then interesting people will
often have some kind of
skeleton. This year in North
America a few people have
bought really really tall
skeletons. They're like 12 feet
tall so three metre tall. I
think that would be almost four
metres tall. I they scare me. I
don't like skeletons but people
will sometimes decorate the
front of their house with
skeletons. You can see now how
Halloween is a very weird
thing. Because it's about kids
dressing up and going out to
get candy. But it is also about
people trying to scare each
other a little bit. So it's fun
for kids but it's also kind of
scary. Um it's kind of a it's a
weird it's a weird thing to
celebrate in my opinion. Um
people will often have like
little fake bats on the front
of their house. A bat is a
small animal that flies around
at night and eats insects. So
people will buy fake bats. You
understand the word fake I
think right? They go to a store
and they buy a bat that's made
out of plastic. And they'll put
a few bats on the of their
house as decoration. And then
there's always some kind of
monsters somewhere I think this
might be Frankenstein. I'm not
100% sure, But monsters are any
kind of you know imaginary
being that is meant to scare
people. So sometimes people
will have fake monsters at the
front of their house. Um just
to give people a little bit of
a fright to scare people a
little bit. Um let me see. Oh
yes. Let's go one more. And
sometimes people will put
tombstones or what we also
would call gravestones in their
yard. They'll actually have
fake ones and it'll say R I P
on it. Can you understand now
why I said this is a strange
thing Halloween. Because it's
it's about fun and kids go out
for candy and then people
decorate their houses to be
really scary. So it's kind of
weird. But a tombstone is where
after someone dies and they're
buried in a cemetery or a
graveyard. They'll put a
tombstone there with their
name. And so people will
sometimes put fake tombstones
on their front yard. And RIP
means rest in peace. So yeah
kind of a strange thing to do.
So someone asked what are the
three most common things to do
on Halloween. So number one if
you're a kid you go out trick
or treating and you get candy.
Number two if you're old you
probably stay home and hand out
candy. But number three if you
are a teenager or someone in
your 20s maybe even in your
30s, you might go to a
Halloween party. Um these are
fairly common at universities.
Right now on the news last
night they said the police are
warning university students not
to have big Halloween parties.
Um so we have a few
universities close to us. Uh so
on the news they said the
police are concerned that the
Halloween parties this year
will be too big because of the
pandemic and COVID. Um so
generally those are the three
things you do. If you're a kid
you go out trick or treating
and you get candy. If you're
old like me you hand out candy.
And if you're younger if you're
in your late teens or you're in
your 20s and you're young and
why in free, you might go to a
Halloween party, you might
dress up even though you're an
adult, you would wear a costume
and go to a party. Um so
there's something called a
haunted house. So a haunted
house is a house where you pay
money to walk through the house
and then they try to scare you.
It's kinda hard to describe
unless you go to one. You can
only go to a haunted house
around this time of year.
Sometimes if you go to a
pumpkin patch to get a pumpkin
they might also have a haunted
house there. So a haunted house
is basically an old building or
place where you go and you pay
money get scared. It's kind of
weird to think about. It's done
for entertainment. It's done
for fun. I have only been to
one haunted house in my life.
Uh and it did scare me. It I
think I mentioned it earlier
when I was younger. I went to a
haunted house where you rode a
little you were in a little
car. It's kinda hard to
describe. It was like a little
mini roller coaster haunted
house. I don't know. I'm not
making any sense. But it scared
me. I don't like haunted
houses. You might watch a
horror movie. So earlier we had
the question about the
Halloween movies or Chucky or
there's a whole genre of movies
called Halloween movies. Um and
these are movies that are
designed to entertain people by
scaring them. Okay. I've only
seen one horror movie in my
life. I think it was Pet
Cemetery by from Stephen King.
Um and I didn't like it. I
really like movies. But I am
not a fan of horror movies.
Some people love horror movies.
They love movies where there's
just a lot of violence and
people running around in the
dark and it's scary and there's
monsters and I don't like them.
I just don't I just do not do
not like horror movies at all.
Um here's a movie poster from a
really old one. Um but I will
not be celebrating Halloween by
watching a horror movie. I
mentioned earlier that people
will do pumpkin carving. Uh
pumpkin carving is something do
after you buy a pumpkin. You
can see here that what you do
is you cut out the top of the
pumpkin and then you use a
knife to cut usually a face but
sometimes people will do like
really decorative carving.
They'll really do something
cool and there are actually
pumpkin carving competitions in
some places around us right
now. So if you are really good
at it you could win a
competition. And then one thing
that shows up this time of
year. This isn't specifically
about Halloween. But we have a
of things that you can buy that
have pumpkin spice flavour. So
you can go and get a coffee
that's pumpkin spiced flavoured
coffee. You can get pumpkin
spiced flavoured cake. You can
get pumpkin spice flavoured
anything. You can get pumpkin
spiced flavoured candles. I
know that sounds weird because
you don't eat a candle but it
smells like pumpkin spice. The
only way I can describe pumpkin
spice is you have to you have
to experience it to know if you
like it or not. I'm not a big
fan of pumpkin spice.