Teacher Prix what's the difference between
go to go in go for that's what you're going
to learn in this video coming up hey student
I am Teacher Prix and I’m going to help
you talk to anyone anywhere anytime in English
now this preposition mix well that's a common
question for English learners it is a vocabulary
lesson to help you improve your conversation
skills and comprehension as well so guys let's
dive into the content okay when we use go
to that's actually the most common combination
you will find with the verb go I was once
reading an advanced book and basically they
even gave a percentage okay in 95% of the cases
you will see go + to when when you're
showing movement in the direction of a place
that's the most common situation of go + to okay whenever you're giving me that idea
that you're going to a place in the direction
of a place you will use the preposition to
plus go for example I’m going to Boston
next week no I’m not going to Boston next
week I would love to but I can't my best friend
goes to work by bike okay he uses his bicycle
so my best friend goes to work by bicycle
not true my best friend goes to work by by
subway I think yes by subway sometimes by
uber well he can so you go to okay Linda
and Peter went to Portugal last month and
had a great time okay well I don't know Linda
and Peter but I have a student who went to
Portugal a few months ago and she loved that
it was amazing she visited her family it was
great okay now some disclaimers here even
though you use go + to to indicate in
the direction of a place with the words home
home yes there here somewhere uptown downtown
no okay you don't use the preposition to you
just use the verb go okay hey what are you
doing where are you going well I’m going
uptown for a meeting do you need a ride I’m
going uptown for a meeting do you need a ride
maybe I’m driving uptown okay I’m going
uptown and my friend or my sister or my wife
or my husband asked me what are you doing
where are you going I’m going I’m going
to a meeting uptown okay I’m going uptown
I’m going uptown for a meeting so this would
be possible no to. I’m going uptown for
a meeting there you have it no to hey where
are you going I’m going home but it's five
I know I need to go home
there you have it so no to okay with these
words home there here go there go here go
somewhere go there you have it another common
construction with go to is to use go to and
another verb to indicate the reason the purpose
to something I went to the beach to relax
okay so I went to the beach to relax very
nice I’m going to Boston to meet my friend
I’m going to Boston to visit my friend in
this case the preposition to here is giving
purpose okay I I’m actually even going in
a different direction here I say where I’m
going I’m going to the office to do something
I’m going to school to do something I’m
going downtown downtown no preposition too
okay I’m going downtown to do something
this is a very common construction with the
verb go then to the place then to the purpose
okay the thing you're going to do so I’m
going to my parents’ house to see my family
I’m going to my parents’ house to my parents’
house not home okay I’m going to my parents’
house to visit my family oh but teacher couldn't
I use home here I’m going to my parents’
home no you use house okay it's not your
home home is usually more personal it's my
place my beautiful home when I’m going to
other people's houses I usually use the word
house instead of home there you have it now
go for okay so this is also a very common
construction and in this case you're going
to use go plus for the preposition for and
a noun okay now and o u w no n o u n now
so when we want to show the purpose of the
movement you're going somewhere but what's
the purpose pizza let's go for pizza ah I
love going for pizza all the time anytime
anywhere with anyone let's go for pizza we
need more pizza in the world why don't we
go for brunch it's it's 11 a.m. you know not
11 it's just an example it's already late
for breakfast so why not why not go for brunch
example okay why don't we go for a few drinks
someday you know maybe someone is talking
to you flirting with you and then the person
invites you to go for a few drinks to go for
a few drinks the person is not saying the
place itself the person is saying the purpose
where are we going well for drinks maybe more
let's stop there right and finally go plus
in if possible smash that like button my friend
it really helps the channel grow subscribe
I make these lessons for you but now go in
it means to enter so let's take a look at
some examples when I go in there I always
enjoy the atmosphere when I go in there I
always enjoy the atmosphere so when I go in
that place when I go inside that place okay
inside that place that's the idea I’m entering
remember that in most situations you will
use to but here my idea is to enter therefore
I will use the preposition in I always enjoy
the vibe you know such a beautiful place I
love it okay maybe you're walking down the
street and you see a beautiful shop hey let's
go in this shop it looks amazing let's go
in let's check it out okay so let's enter
this store let's enter this shop I don't know
why I used shop let's go in this shop looks
beautiful I want to check it out I want to
see inside I want to see what is inside so
let's go in Alex went in the store to check
if they still had play stations available
so he went in he went in the store to check
so he entered the store he went in he went
in the store to check if they still had play
stations available there you have it my friends
now I invite you to a short challenge post
one example with each verb go to go plus to
go plus in go plus for okay follow this lesson
understand the differences and post your three
examples here in the comments other than that
share like and subscribe I’ll see you next
time bye