Well, I'm sure you've noticed
that the year 2021 is
slowly coming to an end,
and I just wanted to make
this last video of the year
as a thank you to all of you,
to all of you who watch my
English lessons here on YouTube.
I have had a very
enjoyable year making
English lessons for you.
It's a lot of fun to come up with ideas,
to go out with my camera and
to get all of the footage
and then to do some editing,
and then lately Audrey has
actually been doing some editing for me.
So that's been fun as well.
I'm not sure if you noticed
that change back in September.
The editing got a little bit
more cooler, I would say.
But anyways, I enjoy
coming up with the ideas.
I enjoy shooting the videos.
I enjoy thinking about how
the lessons should look,
and I enjoy delivering the lessons to you.
But above all, I just
want to say thank you
for watching these English lessons.
It's fun to see a lot of views on a video.
It's fun to see my subscriber count grow,
and none of that is possible
if you don't actually like
the lessons that I'm making.
So thank you very, very much for watching.
I thought I would kind of recap the year
by looking back on some highlights,
some things that I really
enjoyed about the past year.
I'll look at a couple of
videos that did really well.
I'll talk about a video
that did really well
that actually was a surprise to me
and a few other things as well.
So let's get started with that.
The top performing video this past year,
the video that had the
most views was the video
"Learn 60 English Action
Verbs in Under 10 Minutes."
This was a video I made last January.
I went outside on a winter day
and I had a big list of
English action verbs,
and I tried to act them
all out as best as I could,
and people obviously really
enjoyed seeing me act out verbs,
like to flick and to punch,
and I think I even danced a little bit.
The second video,
the second most popular
video this past year was
"How to Order Food at a
Restaurant in English."
This is a video I actually made
a couple of years ago already,
but it continues to remain one
of the most popular videos that I've made.
I think because I go out in the world,
and I actually have English conversations
as I order the food.
So I'm going to try and
do a few more videos
like that in the year to come.
There was one video that was
very much a surprise for me.
On Friday, I do live English lessons
where I teach a series of
vocabulary words on one topic,
and I did one a little
while ago on everyday items.
I usually repackage those
videos, so they're a bit smaller.
I remove all of the viewer questions
and make it a pure lesson.
And that repackaged version,
the lesson-only version
of "Free English Class!
Topic: Everyday Items"
has 305,000 views,
and I only did the video a few months ago.
And it continues in the last few weeks
to be one of my best performing videos.
I think the reason is
because people don't always know the names
for the simplest things
that we use in life.
I actually made this lesson
because it was a list of things
where I didn't know
the French word for it.
I know you're learning English.
I'm continually learning French.
It was actually a list
of words where I'm like,
"I don't know the French
word for this or for that."
So I guess because it was
a very useful lesson to me,
when you reverse it,
it was also a very useful
English lesson for all of you.
If I look back on the year,
one of the highlights of the year
for me was definitely
doing a collaboration
with Lucy from "English with Lucy"
and with Rachel from "Rachel's English."
I have a lot of respect and admiration
for both of those English
teachers on YouTube.
They make incredible lessons
and continue to do so.
By the way, there's links
to both of their channels
in the description below
and all the other videos
I talked about as well.
But working with those
two was just awesome,
and I look forward to next summer
when hopefully I can find some time
to do more collaborations
with other YouTubers
who teach English as well.
By the way, I still teach during the day.
I go to a school and teach.
So I don't always have a lot of time
for collaborations from
September until about June,
but in July and August,
I usually have a little bit more time,
and so hopefully I can find some time
to collaborate more with
other teachers on YouTube.
And then of course,
there's my second channel,
which some of you might know
about and some of you don't.
The most popular video
on my second channel was
"Fall Flat and Fall Into Place,"
learning those two
phrases, had 8,000 views.
Quite surprising actually for me
to see that channel turn into
a real resource for people.
It's something I started because I used
to wait by my van for my kids to come out
in order to go to school.
So I thought I would use my phone
to shoot short little videos,
and it grew into three
four-minute videos every week.
Not as many viewers as on my
main channel, but that's okay.
It's still fun to do,
and I really enjoy it,
and people, I think, get
a lot of value out of it.
It's also a place where you
get to know me a bit better
because the last minute of
each video is usually me
just vlogging a little bit
or reflecting on my day.
So if you ever wanna hear me speak faster,
head over to "Bob's
Short English Lessons,"
my other channel, a great place I think
to learn little English
phrases three times a week.
And then what's my plan for 2022?
Well, I'm kind of a boring
person, more of the same.
I don't have any huge
plans to change anything.
I'm still gonna do a
live lesson every Friday.
I'm gonna do live lessons on Saturdays.
I might scale back a bit on that.
I'm not sure. Three a month
right now sounds good.
I'm gonna keep doing that for awhile.
I'll do a nice compact six
or 10-minute lesson for you every Tuesday,
and I'm just gonna keep
on doing what I do.
I think that I'm very
comfortable doing this now.
I enjoy it, and the response I get
from all of you is really, really good.
I don't want to think about it too much,
but there is a possibility
my main channel might hit one
million subscribers in 2022.
We'll see, I think that
will be quite a day
if that does happen.
I'm fairly confident it will,
but who knows. It's YouTube.
Sometimes views go up and
sometimes they go down
and who knows what can happen,
but I'm fairly confident that
that will happen at sometime,
and it might even be in 2022.
Anyways, to wrap up, let
me check my notes here.
Don't worry about me
running out of topics.
I have 42 more ideas on my list right now.
So there's plenty of
ideas for lessons in 2022.
I do want to get out more to make lessons.
I do want to go places.
So hopefully this pandemic
goes away eventually,
and I can get back out to different places
to make English lessons out in public,
which I think they end up being
the best kinds of lessons.
Anyways, let me look
down at my notes here.
Anything else that I have planned?
Nope, I'm just gonna keep doing the same
as what I've been doing,
trying to make good English lessons
for all of you on a weekly basis.
So once again, I think I
should just end this video
by saying thank you.
If you're sitting somewhere
in your kitchen or living room
or maybe you're on the subway
and you're watching this video,
I'm talking directly to you.
Thank you so much for being a subscriber.
Thank you for watching my videos.
Thank you for doing something
really hard in life.
Learning a language is not easy
and I have a lot of respect
for people who take on that challenge.
So you are awesome.
Thanks for watching and have a great 2022,
but don't forget to enjoy
the last few days of 2021.
Bye.
(upbeat music)