-Everyone knows that
you're an amazing singer,
so I thought it could be fun
if you and I
performed a few songs.
[ Cheers and applause ]
Thank you. But.
Thank you.
Oh, but here's the catch.
To mix things up a bit,
we fed these songs
into Google Translate.
And we're going to perform
the jumbled lyrics right now.
It is time for
"Google Translate Songs."
Here we go.
-♪ Google Translate Songs ♪
-So, if you ever use
Google Translate,
you know that
it's not always perfect.
For example, when translated
to Lithuanian and back,
"The Tonight Show
Starring Jimmy Fallon"
becomes "The Tonight Is Played
By Jimmy Fallon."
-True.
-So, we did the
same thing with --
You've done that before?
We did the same thing
with song lyrics.
Some people have
done this online.
It's super fun.
Camila, since since you're
my guest, you will go first.
Okay?
-Okay.
-You will be singing the Google
Translate version of "Bad Guy"
by Billie Eilish --
which, when translated,
is called "Evil Young Boy."
[ Laughter ]
Roots, whenever you're ready.
♪♪
-Yeah.
I am gonna channel
my Billie Eilish.
♪ Comfort ♪
♪ Demi's nose
wears a shirt ♪
♪ Your fingertips
are quite lazy ♪
♪ Reaches around
without asking ♪
♪ What if you did
some crimes? ♪
♪ An evil young boy ♪
♪ That sounds like
a bumpy boy ♪
♪ That's your husband ♪
♪ Sternum's
under pressure ♪
♪ My text is evil ♪
♪ Your mom gets
kind of weird ♪
♪ My daughter's
a desert ♪
♪ Elminate your dad ♪
♪ I'm an evil boy ♪
♪ Ghosts ♪
[ Cheers and applause ]
♪♪
-Bumpy boy.
-Yeah.
-It was bumpy boy.
-"I'm a bumpy boy."
[ Laughter ]
"Bumpy boy" is great.
Alright. Alright.
Here we go.
I will be performing
the Google Translated version
of "All Star" by Smash Mouth.
-Love that song!
-Me, too.
It's now called
"Hot Ball."
[ Laughter ]
Here we go --
"Hot Ball."
♪♪
-♪ People who don't speak
said the world is bent ♪
♪ I left my sharpest knife
in the house ♪
♪ The girl who could not think
had a finger and a finger ♪
♪ Things existed
on her. face ♪
♪ Whoops ♪
♪ A-hoy,
you're a hot ball ♪
♪ Fun is happy ♪
♪ Hang out ♪
♪ A-hoy,
you're a stone man ♪
♪ Entertain me ♪
♪ Have cash ♪
♪ Shiny things
are not metal ♪
♪ But the rocket bursts
smash the fungus ♪
[ Cheers and applause ]
Wow.
-The original lyrics.
-That is. That's the bonus
lyrics of the original song.
-I personally think
that is pure poetry.
-Yeah, it is pure poetry.
Thank you.
For our last one here,
let's do a duet
of the classic Shaggy song
"It Wasn't Me."
[ Cheers and applause ]
But we'll be singing
the translated version,
which is called
"I'm Not the Self."
-That's actually --
That's very spiritual.
-Yeah, I'm not --
I'm not the self.
-[ As Shaggy ] Very, uh --
-[ As Shaggy ] That's the way
Shaggy wants to do it.
"I'm Not the Self."
-He's not the self.
-Alright, here we go.
Roots, whenever you're ready,
give me the beat.
[ Light laughter ]
♪♪
-Oh, yeah.
-Yeah.
-♪ Welcome, sugar,
take my hand that is bruised ♪
♪ Slipping with
the girl of doors ♪
-♪ You imagine there
are empty butts ♪
♪ Slapping on the
toilet ground ♪
-♪ I was spotted on a mantle ♪
-♪ I'm not the self ♪
-♪ I was harmful to the couch ♪
-♪ Bathing very much
with her now ♪
-♪ I'm not the self ♪
-♪ She took a picture
of receptions ♪
-♪ I'm not the self ♪
[ Normal voice ]
Camila Cabello, everybody.