Hello, everyone. Let me read an excerpt
for you from my book. "We shall soon see
that the hand is divided into three
zones or parts, which are bound by
certain lines to be hereafter.
hereafter explained." Huh? Did you
understand any of that? I didn't. So,
one of my things that I like to do is
really, really get you out of your
textbook, and get you into speaking
real-life English. And we can do this
with private lessons. I have a website,
www.englishwithronnie.com, where I teach
you all the proper things, all the fun
things, and how to speak naturally; not
like a person from — oh, I don't know —
the 1800s. And in today's lesson, we're
going to go through some of these
things; things that you've learned in
grammar books — oh, god — things that
you've learned in your classes or from
people. And, honestly, we just don't use
them when we speak normally to people.
Idioms. That's number two. But let's
start with number two. I'm never going
to go to a shopping center or the
grocery store, and use idioms when I'm
speaking to people. Nowhere would I use
an idiom. And to prove my theory, I
spent two hours listening to the radio.
More than that. And nobody in the land
of radio used an idiom. So, take your
idioms, throw them away. Okay? Just
learn to speak normally. But we're going
to get back to those.
Let's look with the first one. Look at
the first one. "Who" and "whom". Wow.
So: "Whom do you trust?" Mm, unless
you're living in the 1800s, we would
just never use the word: "whom". Okay?
So, take it out of your vocabulary; you
don't need that. Just put: "who". We
would say: "Who do you trust?" You can
trust me. But this word: "whom" — take
it out; we never say it. But there's one
thing you have to know when you're
learning English: You have to know your
purpose. Are you learning English
because you'd like to be a creative
writer? Hey, if you want to be a
creative writer, maybe you want to learn
to use "whom", but this is all about
speaking and communicating with people.
If you're working at a job or you'd like
to get a job where they use a very
formal 1800 language — maybe you want to
learn about "whom", but no. But know who
you are, know your audience, know who
you're talking to. Old people — they're
cool to hang out with — they're probably
are not going to say: "whom" either. So,
get that out of your brain.
As I said, the wonderful idioms. Here's
one: "The grass is always greener on the
other side." You're not gonna have a
conversation with this about someone.
You're not gonna be walking down the
street and go: "Wow. There's that really
hot guy I want to talk to. Hey, how's it
going? The grass is always".  What? No,
just talk to the people like normal
humans. "Hi. How are you?" This is one
thing that I.  never ceases to amaze me
about high-level English courses. I see
all these high-level English courses,
and people who are advanced in English,
and they're studying idioms. It's like:
"Oh my god. There has to be more than
idioms." Don't worry about idioms. If
you want to learn idioms, because
they're fun and clever, go ahead; but
we're not going to use them in normal
speech. So, be careful what you're
studying in your advanced or
intermediate classes.
Oh, everyone hates it. Yes! Present
perfect. Guess what? You don't need to
use it. Now, if you're just beginning to
learn to speak English: Just use the
simple past — it's all you need. If
you're advancing and you're getting the
hang of things in English, and you'd
like to improve your English, of course,
you can step into the boundaries of hell
with the present perfect. But, as I
said, if you're just beginning and the
present perfect really, really makes you
angry — forget about it. Just use the
simple past. An example of the present
perfect is: "I have eaten". Good for
you. I can also just say: "Yeah, I ate".
Uh-huh. It's the same idea. Nobody's
gonna be confused and go: "Oh, hold on.
That was the simple past." But it
doesn't matter. Just use the simple
past. Bye-bye present perfect. Toilet.
See ya.
Oh, this is a fun one: Reported speech.
Now, grammar textbooks love to teach you
the reported speech. And you gotta
change the grammar around and make sure
the time reflects in the day. (blows
tongue). Ronnie says: (blows tongue).
This is how we say these in normal
English. And if you don't believe me,
watch a video. Not only this one. Watch
a movie, listen to people speak, go on
all those social media things that
you're so addicted to, and listen to how
real people actually talk about
something that's reported. "She said
that she had eaten already" is reported
speech. Yeah, we don't say that. We use:
"went" and "goes". Let me show you how.
"She goes: 'I ate already'. Or: "He
went: 'Oh my god'". So, instead of
having to change all the grammar around
in the sentence, all you have to do is
put: "goes", instead of: "said"; and you
can also use "went". I can say: "She
went: 'I ate already'". It doesn't
matter. You can use: "went" and "goes".
Doesn't matter the grammar; it doesn't
matter the time. You don't have to
change anything. Reported speech,
bye-bye. If you're writing as a creative
writer, you can use reported speech, but
we never use it when we speak.
Next one. This is fun. Fuji, this for
you. "Who" in relative clauses. So,
you've learned in your textbook; it's
very proper grammar. Okay? "She is the
one who ate it." By the way, a "relative
clause" is giving more information about
the subject. So, I'm giving you more
information about the subject: "she".
So, the rule is: If it's a person, you
have to use: "who". You have to say:
"She's the one who ate it." Do you know
what? When we speak, we don't say that.
We just say: "that". Because in the
relative clause, without a human.  with
a person, we use: "that". I can say:
"Oh, this is the book that my great
grandmother gave me." I can say: "She is
the person that gave me the book." So,
when you're using relative clauses, even
if it's a person — ignore the grammar
rule. You don't need that rule. Rules
are (blows tongue).
Number seven. Number five. Number seven,
yes. Stative verbs. Yeah. Yeah, these
are fun. Right? So, you've learned about
stative verbs. "Stative verbs" are verbs
you cannot use with: "i–n–⁠g"⁠. Example:
"I'm having a car". No, that's wrong.
You can say: "I'm having a baby", but
you can't say: "I'm having a car". And
these are rules of stative verbs. You
must say: "I have a car". If you're
talking about possession — things that
you buy; not babies — you can say: "I
have a car", not: "I'm having a car".
But thanks to our modern society,
specifically, a restaurant that serves
millions and billions of people; has
some golden arches over there. Their
slogan is wrong. Their slogan is: "I'm
lovin' it". Hey, guess what? "Lovin'" or
"love" is a stative verb, but doesn't
matter. We don't care anymore. We say:
"Wow. I'm loving your new car."
Grammatically wrong, but that's how we
speak. You're in a restaurant, and the
waitress comes by and says: -"Hey. How
is everything?" -"Oh, I'm lovin' the
soup." That's not.  that's fine. Hey.
People at the table are like: "Oh, you
just used a stative verb wrong." Nobody
cares. We don't care about that; stative
verbs. The next one is, of course, the
opposite is: "hating". Okay? "Ah, I'm
hating you right now. You've ruined my
life!" You can say that — that's fine.
We should say: "I hate you." But we have
to say: "I'm hating my new job. I.  Er.
It drives me crazy." And notice I don't
say: "hating"; I say: "hatin'". "I'm
lovin'"; "I'm hatin'". Sounds like a
country.
Another verb that we can use in this
stative form, but we're not supposed to
— don't tell my mom — is: "costing". So,
if you have to pay a lot of money for
something, you can say: "Wow. It's
costing me so much." Or you go into
someone's apartment, say: "Wow. How much
is this place costing you a month?"
Grammatically wrong. Feel free to point
that out to them, but it's how we change
language. So, I can say: "Well, this
must be costing you a pretty penny."
See? That one.  that idiom is so old.
We don't even have pennies anymore, so
come on. Come on. "Understanding".
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm. "Oh, do you know what?
I'm not really understanding you." Oh.
Grammatically wrong, but: Hey, guess
what? We can say that. "I'm
understanding you now! Yeah!" Cool.
Again, your grammar teacher would faint
or roll over in his or her grave. But
guess what? Rule's off. You can say
that. So, I hope that you are
understanding all of this lesson, and
just be careful about grammar and all
these rules you have. Make sure that
what you're learning is actually
relevant and up to date, because the
last thing you want to do is sound like
someone that came from the 1800s and is
hanging out, enjoying life. So, I'm
Ronnie; and grammar (blows tongue).