I'm sure when you
think about the future,
there's things that you're hoping for.
There's things that you're planning to do,
but maybe you're not quite sure
how to express how you
feel about that in English.
Well, in this English lesson,
I will teach you a whole bunch
of phrases that you can use
to talk about things
that you're hoping for,
goals that you have set,
and things that you are
planning to do in the future.
(upbeat music)
Before we get this lesson started,
I should mention one thing.
I'm sure you already
know how to use phrases
like I am going to, or I will,
to talk about things you are
going to do in the future.
And in this lesson,
I'm not going to help you
learn the future tenses.
Instead, I'm going to teach
you some other phrases
that English speakers commonly use
when they're talking about
things that they are going to do.
So stick around for that.
Before we get started, though,
if this is your first time here,
don't forget to click
that red subscribe button,
and give me a thumbs up
if this video helps you learn
just a little bit more English.
The first three phrases that you can use
to talk about your dreams and goals
all start with the same word.
They start with the word someday.
And the first phrase is
the phrase I plan to.
I really like France.
I'm a French speaker, but
I've never been to France.
So someday I plan to go to France.
You can see how someday
refers to a day in the future,
not a specific day, but
because I speak French,
and because the country
of France is really cool,
someday, I plan to go to France.
So that's the first phrase.
The second phrase is the phrase I hope to,
and you can use this again
with the word someday.
Once I was talking to a student,
and the student said this.
Someday, I hope to become a doctor.
The student was studying
really hard in my class.
Their plan was to go to
university, and to become a doctor.
And the way they expressed that dream,
the way they expressed that goal
was to say someday, I
hope to become a doctor.
The last phrase that you can
use with the word someday
is the phrase I would like to,
and we shorten this to I'd like to,
so you might say something like this.
Someday, I'd like to visit Canada.
Someday, I'd like to see
a Toronto Raptors game.
I've watched them on TV, but
I've never gone to a game.
So someday, I'd like to go and
see a Toronto Raptors game.
So those are the first three phrases
you can start all of your
sentences with someday
to talk about something that
you want to do in the future,
one of your dreams, or one of your goals.
Another way to talk about
your dreams or goals
is to simply state your dream or goal.
And the phrase we use to
do this is the phrase,
one of my dreams is,
or one of my goals is.
For me, I would probably say this.
One of my dreams is to
have 1 million subscribers
on YouTube.
That would be kind of surprising,
and I don't even know if I
would be able to believe it
if it happened.
You might say this.
You might say one of my goals
is to become fluent in English.
So it's a very simple way to do it,
but this is the phrase we most often use
when we talk specifically
about a dream or goal.
We say one of my dreams
is, or one of my goals is.
Another way we talk about our
dreams or goals in English
is to use the phrase I dream of a day.
This is a phrase we once again use
to talk about something
we really want to happen.
You might use a phrase like this.
I dream of a day when
I can own my own house.
You might use a phrase like this.
I dream of a day when COVID
is gone from the world.
I certainly dream of that day.
I dream of a day where
there is no more pandemic.
That would be really, really awesome.
But anyways, another phrase that we use
to talk about the future,
to talk about a dream or goal
is to say I dream of a day.
Another way to talk about something
that's going to happen in the future
that you're excited about
is to use the phrase
I'm looking forward to.
Christmas is coming up,
and I'm looking forward to Christmas.
It means I get a break from school.
It means I get to spend
some time with my family.
So I'm looking forward to Christmas.
You might be looking forward
to your next holiday.
You might even just be looking
forward to the weekend.
I know today I'm making
this video on a Friday,
and I'm looking forward to the weekend.
Eventually this day will be over.
It will be the weekend, and
I'll be pretty excited about it.
But right now I'm just
looking forward to it.
Obviously, when something's in the future,
you have to wait for it to happen.
A phrase that we use though
to talk about how we feel
when we want something
to happen really badly
is the phrase I can't wait.
My son went to university this past year.
And during the summer, a
few times he said this,
I can't wait to go to university.
I can't wait to go inside
the house right now,
because I'm outside.
I have a jacket on and no gloves,
and it's actually quite cold.
So I know it's a small thing
that I'm looking forward to.
It's a small thing that I'm going to do,
but right now I can't wait to go inside.
I do enjoy making these videos,
but my hands are getting
a little bit cold.
Well thank you for watching
this little English lesson,
where I hope you learned a
few phrases that you can use
to talk about your
dreams and goals in life
when you have your next
English conversation.
Remember if this is your first time here,
don't forget to click
that red subscribe button,
and give me a thumbs up if
this video helped you learn
just a little bit more English.
And if you have the time,
why don't you stick around,
and watch another English lesson?
(upbeat music)