Hello, if you're watching
this English lesson on Tuesday,
September seventh,
there's a good chance that
as you're watching this,
I'm in my classroom,
teaching my first classes
of the school year.
As many of you know,
I'm a high school teacher
here in Ontario, Canada,
and Tuesday, September
seventh is the first day
back at school.
So, wish me luck.
Wish me luck is a phrase we say to people
before we do something new
or difficult or stressful.
It's a phrase we say because
we want people to respond
in a nice, positive way.
So wish me luck, but you
might not know how to respond.
So in this video, I'm going to
show you five different ways
to respond when an English
speaker says to you,
wish me luck.
Well, hello and welcome
to this English lesson
where I'm going to show
you five ways to respond
to the English phrase, wish me luck.
Before we get started though,
if this is your first time here,
don't forget to click that red
subscribe button over there
and give me a thumbs up if
this video helps you learn
just a little bit more English.
So, someone has said to you wish me luck,
the best way to respond
and probably the most
common way to respond
is to continue to use the word luck.
You can say good luck or best of luck.
Both of those phrases are
just great things to say,
maybe you have a friend
who's starting a brand new job
tomorrow and they say to you,
"I'm starting a brand new
job tomorrow, wish me luck."
You could totally respond
by saying good luck
or best of luck.
Both of those phrases
indicate that you hope this,
the beginning of their new
job goes really, really well
and that they enjoy it.
So either good luck or best of luck.
The second way that you can respond
to the English statement,
wish me luck is to say,
I hope it goes well.
Now you can also be
specific instead of saying,
I hope it goes well,
you can mention the thing
that the person's going to be doing.
Maybe you have a friend
who has a job interview.
You could say to them, if
they said, "wish me luck."
You could say, "Hey, I hope it goes well."
Or you could specifically mention
the job interview and say,
"I hope the job interview goes well."
So the second way that you
can respond to this statement
is to say, "I hope it goes well."
Or to specifically say
what you want to go well
for that person.
In my case, you could say,
"I hope your first day
back at work goes well."
This third way of responding
is actually quite similar
to the second way.
You can specifically talk
about the thing the person
is going to be doing.
You could say things like this,
"I hope you have a good
first day back at work."
Let's imagine you have a
friend who's going on a trip
and they've said to you,
"well, I leave in a few
hours, wish me luck."
You could respond by saying to them,
"I hope you have a good flight."
"I hope you have a good trip."
"I hope you have a good time
when you go on your trip."
All of those would be great responses
if they said, wish me luck.
So notice once again,
you're mentioning the specific
thing that they are doing.
So in my case, as I start work tomorrow,
if I said, "wish me luck," you could say,
"I hope you have a good first
day back at school, Bob."
And I would respond by saying, thank you.
A fourth way that you can
respond is to simply say,
"all the best."
Maybe a friend of yours
or someone you know
is going back to university
and they say to you,
"Hey, I'm heading out for
university in a couple of days."
You could, and if they
said, "wish me luck."
You could respond by
saying, "all the best."
It's short. It's sweet.
It's a great response.
And it simply means that you hope
they have a really good time
when they're at university
or in other situations that
they just have a good time
whatever they're doing,
that they are successful
and enjoy themselves.
You can add to this phrase
a little bit if you want,
you could say, let's say a
friend of yours is taking a test.
You can say all the best
on your test tomorrow
or something like that.
But I like to use the phrase all the best.
It's short. It's sweet,
I think it communicates exactly
what I would want to say.
If someone said to me, wish me luck.
I think this would be my favorite
response, "all the best."
A fifth way to respond is
to simply tell the person
that you're sure that things will go well,
maybe you have a friend
who's going to play a game
later today.
Maybe they're on a football
team and you could say,
"I'm sure the game will go well",
if he was to say to you, wish me luck.
Maybe you have a friend
who is going to be taking
their driver's test and
you can say to them,
"Hey, I'm sure your test will go well."
So a fifth way to respond is
to simply assure the person
that you think everything
will go really, really well,
whatever it is that they're doing.
So again, if I said to you,
"Whoa, it's the first day
of school, wish me luck."
You could respond by saying,
"I'm sure you'll have a great day, Bob."
"I'm sure you'll do a good job."
"I'm sure the school day will be awesome."
And of course, lastly,
you can always combine a whole bunch
of these phrases together.
And in fact, English
speakers often do that.
If I was to say to you wish me luck,
you could respond by saying,
"good luck, I hope you have a good day."
"I hope your day goes well."
"I'm sure you'll do a good
job teaching your classes."
"Best of luck."
"All the best."
"I'm sure it will be great."
So again, you don't have to combine
that many of them together,
but when you are responding
to that statement,
when someone says to you, wish me luck,
you can always say two
or three of the phrases
I've just taught you.
And I think people will be
very happy when you do that.
Well, thank you for watching
this little English lesson,
where I hope you learned
a few ways to respond
to the English phrase, wish me luck.
Thank you so much for watching.
If this is your first time here,
don't forget to click that red
subscribe button over there
and give me a thumbs up if
this video helped you learn
just a little bit more English.
And if you have the time,
why don't you stick around and
watch another English lesson.