I don't know about you, but I
don't like it when people are rude.
Politeness is generally
very important,
especially if you want people
to help you with something.
If you want someone to do something
for you, there are different ways of
expressing it in English, depending
on how polite you want to be.
If I say:
"Open the window!"
it's quite direct, isn't it?
It's the imperative form,
which is more or less an order.
"Open the window, please!"
Adding the word 'please'
does make it more polite,
but it's still quite direct.
"Can you open the window, please?"
Now we are getting more
polite, but why is this more polite?
Well, one reason is because
this is now a question.
So it's more of a
request than an order.
And because it's a question,
it's easier to say no.
Let's now use could instead of can.
"Could you open the window,
please?"
Could is more polite than can
and this is where
it begins to get interesting.
Why is:
'Could you open the window, please?'
more polite than:
'Can you open the window, please?'
Well,
it's all to do with the relationship
between can and could and the
idea of distance, of remoteness.
'Could' can be described as
the remote form of 'can'.
Sometimes that distance is time.
"I can swim."
That's an ability
I have now.
"I could swim when I was four."
That's an ability
I had at a time in the past.
Sometimes that distance is between
what is real and what is imagined.
"I can't do that in my head."
This is something that is not
possible for me to do now.
"I couldn't do that
even if I had a calculator."
This is something
that's not possible for me to do,
even in an imagined situation
where I have a calculator.
And sometimes distance
is in relationship.
"Can you open the window, please?"
"Could you open the window, please?"
Could puts more social distance
between speaker and listener.
That makes it more polite as it's less
uncomfortable for someone to say no.
Now, we're not talking
about actual distance here.
We're not saying you have to be
physically further away to be polite,
but it is a good way to visualise it.
The further the speaker is away,
the easier it is to say no and
'could' puts you further away.
Open the window!
Open the window, please!
Can you open the window, please?
Could you open the window, please?
And in English, we can make
that distance even further too
using past forms
and modal structures.
I was wondering if you wouldn't
mind opening the window
if it's not too much trouble.
For a simple request
like opening a window,
that one is probably
a bit over the top.
One very important thing to remember,
perhaps more important
than the words themselves,
is the way they are spoken.
It's only polite if the
tone of voice is polite.
You can make a polite
form of words less polite
if you stress it in
a different way. For example:
"Can you open the window?"
"Could you please open the window?"
So sounding polite is a combination
of words and the way you say them
and when it comes to words,
'could you' is more polite than 'can you'
and longer phrases with past forms
and modals are more polite still.