Okay. Sometimes when you're
speaking English or you're
online, you have problems
because you're in sticky
situations. So, "sticky
situations" means that you feel
uncomfortable or you don't
really know what to say, or how
to act, because someone has made
you feel weird.
So, I'm here to help you about
this. And job interviews. Oh my
god - the worst. People ask you
questions. You're like: "Oh, I
don't know. I don't know. I
don't know." Don't tell them the
truth. Don't tell them that
you're.  "Oh, okay." So, if
English is not your first
language, or if it is, sometimes
we help dealing with things. So,
let's get into this.
Where do these things happen?
So, uncomfortable questions can
happen when you're outside
walking your dog, they can
happen on social media; sticky,
sticky situations. Facebook,
Instagram, YouTube, comments or
messages.
I have a YouTube channel; you're
watching it. And people say
things like.  That are just
wrong. And that I take thing.
They take what I say and make it
very different from what happens
from reality. That's a dangerous
thing. Know what you're
commenting on, first of all, and
know how to comment back.
If you're on Facebook, and
people are saying bad things
about you - this.  This can be
terrible, especially if you'r
younger and you're ver
vulnerable. So, make sure tha
you know how to handl
yourselves in this situation
Because if you type a comment
and then you type an answer; an
then they answer: "Blah, blah
blah", it can get very, ver
dangerous out there. There'
many examples of people gettin
killed, people getting sho
because of Facebook social medi
comments. Careful
These can happen in real life.
So, someone could say to you:
"Oh, hey. How old are you?"
That's none of your business.
Really? Is it? Which can be a
legitimate question, if it's
your friend or someone; but if
it's a stranger - no, no. That's
not their business. "How much
money do you make?" These are
considered rude questions. And
when someone asks you them,
you're put in a ver
uncomfortable situation. And yo
want to tell the truth, but yo
know you shouldn't, and: Wha
are you going to do
-"Hey, sweetheart. Can I get
your phone number?" -"Oh, I.  I
don't have a phone." Ring-ring.
"Mom, that's a bad time to call
me now." So, what do you do if
somebody says: "Hey, sweetheart.
Can I have your phone number?"
You say: "No." And then the
person is like: -"Well, why
not?" -"Because I don't want
to." -"How old are you?" -"It's
not your business." -"How much
money do you make?" -"Why?"
You can ask them a question.
"Why do you want to know how
much money I. ? How much money
do you make?" Oh! You can ask
them a question back. -"How old
are you?" -"How old are you? Do
you want to know how old my dog
is, too? It's not your
business."
So, you have two options, here.
One: You can give them a
"snarky", which means sarcastic
answer, like I usually do. Or,
following the voice of my mom:
You can choose to ignore the
people. This isn't as fun,
though. Oh. It means you're not
playing the game, are you? So,
the solution to social media and
real-life problems: You say
nothing.
Somebody types nasty comments
about you on your Facebook page,
or on your Instagram, or on your
YouTube channel - you say
nothing; you don't reply.
Nothing. Nothing. Absolutely.
Because: Why? They're waiting
for you to say something.
These people are called:
"keyboard warriors". "Warriors",
like a soldier. And "keyboard"
is the thing that you type on.
So, these "keyboard warriors"
have nothing better to do than
sit on YouTube, and comment on
people's videos. Well, get a
hobby, go ride a bike, go walk
outside. Okay? Because their
lives are so terribly tragic,
that they can think: "Oh, I'm
going to go on people's videos
and leave these bad comments."
Okay.
Also known as "trolls". "Trolls"
go through videos and say:
"Ah-ha-ha. I'm going to leave a
bad comment. And I'm going to
call this person this name."
Nice grade three. Okay? Go back
to grade three; get off your
keyboard. But say nothing.
That's what my Mom told me. So,
I don't like that. I like to
fight.
So, maybe you're in a job
interview and they ask you a
question. Frank, thank you very
much for giving me this advice.
And you have no idea what the
answer, because job interviews
are sticky. They.  They ask you
something, but you know you
shouldn't tell the truth because
then you'll lose the job.
Hey, guess what? You can say to
them: "Let me get back to you on
that one." So, they could ask
you a question, like: "So, why
exactly would you like to work
for this company?" Real answer:
"I need a job. And you had a job
interview, and I'm here. And you
should hire me." Bad answer.
Good answer: "That's a good
question."--I have no idea--"Let
me get back to you on that one."
So, hopefully what will happen
is the interview will be very
happy with your answer, continue
with the job interview, and
completely forget to go back and
ask you the question you
couldn't remember or you didn't
know the answer to. It's magic.
Because the job interviews:
"Dunh-dunh-dunh" done all these,
good. Okay. Yes/no. Hired. Good.
They forget to ask you most of
the time, unless you've got a
genius working on your job
interview.
The other thing that you can say
is.  They might ask you
something you're not comfortable
about at all, and you're going
to find out that there's many
things that they're not allowed
to ask you. They're not allowed
to ask you about your age, your
race, and many other
discriminatory things in a job
interview. And if they ask you
one of these things, or
something that you're just like:
"No. Do you know what? Nah. No,
no, no."
You can say: "I'm not
comfortable talking about that."
And this might set off a little
alarm for the interview, going:
"Oh. Did I say something
illegal? Well, I hope that was
allowed in my jurisdiction." So,
it actually makes the job
interview.  Interviewer
nervous. You're like: "Yes.
Ha-ha. Give me the job."
It's a crazy world out there,
and people are going to attack
you, but stay strong. And if
something makes you
uncomfortable, talk about it.
Say things: "Ha. Hey, guess
what? I'm not playing your
games. Bye."