hello my name is emma and i am very excited today
because i am going to teach you how you can make
grammar fun that's right grammar can be fun
you might not believe me um because i know
grammar english grammar specifically makes a lot
of students feel like this okay a lot of students
when they learn english grammar like the present
perfect um the past continuous the future simple
they feel very stressed and they feel very bad
because grammar can sometimes be boring and it
can sometimes be difficult okay so if this is how
you feel about grammar if you find it really hard
or maybe you love grammar but you want to find
another way to learn grammar this video is for
you so my tip today is that one of the best ways
to learn grammar is by using songs and music
and why is this well i want you to think when you
listen to music a lot of the times you probably
feel like this music makes people feel very happy
so while grammar might make you feel bored or
you might find it difficult music can make you
feel happy so by combining or putting together
music and grammar you can have a fun learning
experience okay so let me first talk about why
it's good to use music when you're learning
grammar and then i'm going to talk about how
you can use music to learn grammar and some of my
favorite songs you can use you can use to do this
okay so let's get started so when we use a song
songs have a lot of great grammar points in them
okay if you've ever heard the bare naked ladies
they have a great song that we're talking about
we'll talk a little bit about later called if i
had a million dollars this song is wonderful for
learning the second conditional okay we have songs
that are great for learning the present perfect
songs that are great for learning the past
tense and i'm going to talk about these songs
and how you can use them but if you think about it
why can these songs really help you learn grammar
well first of all when you use music okay and you
sing a song when you sing you're actually using a
different part of your brain than you do when you
speak and by using a different part of your brain
it can actually help you remember things such as
grammar or such as different words in the song
so using singing can help you remember
if you think about stress a lot of the
times when you're in english class and
learning grammar you might feel stressed
stress is bad for learning music can help
you feel less stress so it can lower stress
and by doing this music can actually increase
learning it can make learning go up okay you can
learn a lot more when you're not stressed music
has a lot of repetition if you think about songs
you often hear the same lyrics again and again
in the chorus this repetition is good for memory
there are a lot of fun activities you can do when
you're using music and you can learn a lot about a
person's culture from the music okay so i'm going
to share a little bit of canadian culture with you
today when i talk about some canadian bands you
can use when you're learning grammar and finally
i have a lot of favorite songs i love to use with
my classes for grammar so i'm going to share these
with you so these are some of the reasons why
music can be so helpful with learning grammar now
let's learn how we can use music okay so the first
step is thinking about what kind of grammar do
you want to practice okay so maybe in your english
class you're learning about the second conditional
maybe um you you're not in english class but
you just want to learn grammar on your own
and that's okay too um so i'm just going to give
you some examples and there's many other examples
but some examples of songs you can use when you're
learning these different points of grammar okay
so the first example i'm going to give is if
you're learning what we call the simple present
okay so that's sentences like i run i eat you
know i eat a hamburger i um read a book these
are all examples of the simple present tense
and so that has to do with what's happening now
so two great songs for practicing the simple
present tense the first one is a really sad song
by marian faithful and it's called as tears go by
okay so what you can do is if you want to practice
using any of these songs you can go on youtube
and listen to them and just type in as tiers go by
you can also check out jules song you were
meant for me this is another great song you
can use when practicing um grammar from the simple
present tense okay in terms of simple past tense
so simple past is when you have an ed ending
so for example i looked at the store i bought
some ice cream yesterday i did my homework these
are all examples of the simple past tense okay so
sometimes we have regular simple past which is ed
endings and sometimes we have irregular endings
now if this is confusing to you that's okay the
main point is if you're talking about the past
you can listen to these songs for grammar points
we have yesterday by the beatles which is a great
song when you're learning about the past tense
because the beatles tend to sing very slow so you
can really hear the words and you can really hear
the grammar in this song and it's about yesterday
so you know it's about the past there's also
another song by andy williams called yesterday
when i was young or at least andy williams sings
it there's different versions but yesterday when
i was young is another great song when you're
looking at the past tense if you're looking
at the past continuous sense tense sorry um last
kiss by pearl jam is a wonderful song for this one
in terms of the simple future so this is when we
use the word will and we talk about the future
you can use the shirelle's or amy winehouse
will you still love me tomorrow that's an
excellent song for this tense or if you like
the beatles you can also use when i'm 64
where they talk about what they're going
to do in the future when they're 64.
if you like um you know maybe other types of
music the proclaimers has a great song called
i will walk 500 miles so you can check that
song out too that has a lot of this tense in it
for students looking to learn more about the
present perfect and this is always a really
challenging tense for students this is when we say
things like have you ever i have never um i have
eaten an apple before okay so this tense is really
challenging some great songs for it are have you
ever seen the rain okay so um there's different
versions of this song you can listen to the one
from rod stewart or any other musician who sings
this but have you ever seen the rain is great for
this uh tense you can also check out youtube's
i still haven't found what i'm looking for
this is another great song for the present
perfect if you're learning the second conditional
i'm going to talk about a song to help you
with that in a moment but some other songs
are if i were a boy by beyonce if i fell in love
by the beatles and finally if you're learning
should have like you know something that you
regret you can use bruno mars i should have
bought you flowers okay so these are just some
examples of great songs you can use to help you
learn english grammar now i'm going to show you
how you can use a specific song to kind of get
an idea of activities you can do okay so um a song
that i really like using when teaching the second
conditional and the second conditional is if i had
a million dollars i'd be rich that's an example
so a song i really like using for teaching the
second conditional is a song by a canadian band
and i'm canadian so i like canadian bands and
this canadian band is called the bear naked ladies
okay so the song they sing is called if i
had a million dollars okay you can youtube it
and find the song um and you know listen to it
and in the comments you can tell me what you
think of the song okay some students love it some
students maybe they're not as big of a fan of it
but it's a great song for learning the second
conditional okay so how can you use this song
um if you want to learn grammar well let's
look at some ideas for activities you can do
so the first thing i would suggest is just listen
to the song listen to it a couple of times and you
know think about the song listen for the grammar
is there anything you can hear about the second
conditional maybe before listening to the song
you can even look up what the second conditional
is if you don't know that grammar yet
okay and then you can just listen to it
the next thing you can do is look for the
lyrics you can google the lyrics of the song
or find them on youtube and try to find examples
of the grammar so in this case you can look for
examples of the second conditional so i've just
written out some lyrics from the song here there's
a lot of examples of the second conditional in the
song but for example if i had a million dollars
i'd buy you a house if i had a million dollars i'd
buy furniture for your house like a chesterfield
or an ottoman so these are lyrics from the song
and so i'd look at them and i try to think okay
where is the second conditional in this song
well when we talk about the second conditional
we're talking about a sentence that has the
word if in it okay so just looking oh here's if
here's if okay so two examples it also has wood
in it um or the contraction of wood which is
in this case i would becomes eyed so this is
an example of part of the second conditional
okay and then i can look at um you know what
goes with if what tense so in this case if i
had a million dollars i'd buy you a house if i had
a million dollars i'd buy furniture for your house
so look for the grammar look for examples of it
and if this is hard for you maybe it's because
you haven't learned the second conditional yet
so i recommend studying the second conditional
first and then using this as a guide so after
you find examples of the grammatical tense
you want to study then you can think about why
are they using this tense okay why are they
using the second conditional here what does
it mean in this case when you see if i had
and i'd buy what they're saying using the second
conditional is they're talking about uh imaginary
situation so something that's not true the singer
does not have a million dollars but he's imagining
what would life be like if i did have a mat or if
i did have a million dollars and what would i do
okay so we use the second conditional
to talk about an imaginary situation
something that's not true but we want to imagine
what we would do if it was true so in this case
this person if they had a million dollars
they do not have a million dollars but if
they did they would buy you a house okay and if
they had a million dollars they would also buy
furniture for your house so they're using this
to show they don't have a million but if they
did this is what they would do the next thing you
can do after you think about why they use this
tents is you can actually sing the song okay so
you can find a copy of the lyrics and sing along
okay sing it until you remember the words and then
after you do that you can test yourself okay cover
up some words in the song so for example when i
sing it if i and i cover this up so i can't read
it i have to try to remember what was the word
they used there what verb tense was it in okay
if i oh okay if i had so you can test yourself
and practice singing the song by covering up
the verbs and seeing if you can remember um
the verbs they use and the tenses they use
okay um the final thing you can do as a fun
activity is you can actually make your own lyrics
with the grammar you're interested in so
if you're practicing the second conditional
you can change this if i had a million
dollars maybe you can change it to if i had a
dog okay if i had a dog i'd what's something i
can say about if i had a dog maybe i'd walk it
so you can change the lyrics to maybe something
that you might say in everyday life and this can
help you practice using the second conditional so
change the lyrics and sing your own lyrics to the
song and see how that goes okay so these are just
some ways you can use music when learning grammar
and there's many other ways to use it these are
just some suggestions i hope you check out the
songs i recommended today and i also hope that
you check out or you write in our comment section
songs you use when you're using when you're
learning grammar maybe people who watch can
share some ideas they have about using music
when learning different grammar points okay
i'd also like to invite you to check out our
website at www.invid.com there you can do a quiz
to practice what you've learned in this video
you can also subscribe to my channel i have a
lot of different resources on grammar as well as
vocabulary slang business english writing and a
whole bunch of other resources so check that out
until next time take care and thanks for watching