I’m learning Spanish again and it’s so hard
for me to understand native speakers. And if
you’re studying English, I know I, and my fellow,
native speakers can be difficult to understand.
I struggled with this myself in college when
I studied in the Dominican Republic, and then
after college when I studied German in Germany
for six months. I get it. So when I started
teaching English, it was so important to me to
develop a technique to help students hear English
differently, to be able to join conversation and
not just be stuck in written communication.
The technique involves learning a specific aspect
of spoken English with your mind, we do that through a video,
then training that into your body with audio
exercises, and then getting feedback from teachers
along the way. And I’ve been helping students with
this technique for five years now, and it works.
And to the rest of you guys like myself, keep
working hard because it’s
working, and I'm so happy.
You’ll hear more from him soon.
Wouldn’t you love right now to practice, say, a
tricky sound in American English or a reduction
and then have a teacher say,
“Yes, that sounds perfect!”,
or “Wait, that reduction still
needs to be shorter, try this?”
The best way to feel confident speaking English
is to get help and guidance from trained teachers.
And can you believe you get that as a part of
my online school, Rachel’s English Academy?
I’m going to introduce you to these six
fantastic teachers today and show you
how they can guide you to the materials in
my Academy for transformation and success
in your spoken English, confidence
that you can almost not imagine.
On November 5, I turn 43. And to celebrate
my birthday, I’m offering a huge sale,
the last one of the year, 81% off your intro
month in the Academy with the code Rachel43.
The sale is for 5 days only, it ends Sunday,
and you can end your subscription at any time
if you don’t feel like this method
and these teachers work for you.
What’s my academy? Well, this is the 30-second
elevator pitch. It’s an online training ground for
spoken English. We teach the concept, we give you
the audio to train that concept into your habits,
and then we give you the teacher resources to
check in to make sure you’re on the right track
with your training. Hundreds of exclusive videos
and audio lessons, a method for self-training and
self-improvement, a re-shaping of your habits and
ideas about speaking English, teacher feedback
and support. All online, all available 24-7
for you to work on as it fits your schedule.
One of the most important things we can do
for you in the Academy is change how you hear
English. This is Tom, one of our teachers
that you may work with in the Academy.
The idea of learning how to listen. Because I
think, if you kind of train your ear to begin
hearing the musical quality of American
English it makes it a lot easier to imitate.
Do you recognize Tom? He’s been teaching with me
for over 10 years and he’s been in my
YouTube and Facebook videos before.
If you’re in my Academy, you can work
with Katie. She talks about how, with the
method and materials in the Academy, students
start to hear things they didn’t hear before.
One thing that’s happened to me as I’ve been
working with the students from Rachel’s English
Academy is after a couple of weeks or so with the
daily practice, they come back and say “Wow! I
can understand things in conversation
that I had no idea were happening before,
just even little things
like reductions and flap Ts,
some of the other things that are so
characteristic of American English.”
Isn’t that fantastic? It’s what makes us
unique. These are your teachers. Most of
the work is done on your own with the best
method and materials available, but then,
how do you know you’re doing it right?
You’re not doing this alone. Through our
private groups you’re with a team
of teachers but all the other students too.
This is one of our students, Al.
I’ve imitated so many Hollywood scenes as many as
possible and of course, imitating so many scenes
on movies or TV shows without
knowing the technique was hard.
Like I constantly make mistakes and nobody
even corrected me until I found this academy,
Rachel’s English Academy. And I can say
that this academy has been my lifesaver.
Al had the right idea, but since she wasn’t
learning the language with the supercharged
brain of a young child, she needed a little
bit more concrete information and guidance
which is what she got in the academy.
And with that information and guidance,
the change in students can be truly
amazing. This is our teacher Laura,
talking about singing and noticing the
changes through student’s hard work.
Sometimes I’ll be working with somebody and while
we’re working on something and we’ll put it aside
for now, they’ll keep visiting it in their
practice time and then when I see them again
maybe some times gone by, and they’re
using it as if it’s just another natural
part of their speech now. And I love
hearing that, I love noticing that.
That’s the best part. Hearing a student
speak naturally and comfortably. Now,
because we’re talking about changing a habit here,
that doesn’t happen overnight. It doesn’t happen
with watching a video and learning something. You
have to add training. I wish I could do that part
for you but I can’t. It’s best to sign up
for the Academy only if you have a minimum
of 15 minutes a day to learn the tips and
tricks about what makes American English
sound American, and the training to bring
those qualities into your own voice and body.
I asked Josh, another one of our
fantastic teachers, to talk about
what he notices in successful students, and
guess what, it goes back to listening.
My favorite success story is
that with students in the academy
and those for the students who really get
their ears tuned into the sound of English.
And it really opens up the way they listen and
what they say and how they use the language.
Sometimes students spend a lot of
time working on an individual sound.
But once you can actually train them and get them
to actually notice that difference, it changes
everything about the way they approach it and they
really get really, really motivated from that.
In the Academy we cover every topic
in spoken English: placement & pitch,
melody & intonation, rhythm, all
the sounds, reductions and more.
I asked our teachers what their favorite
course is and why. This is Ms Stokes’ answer.
Without question, the Stress 3 course
is my favorite. It’s the place where
you get the most bang for your buck. Your
time investment pays off so much in that
course. I don’t know a better place to
improve rhythm and just to immediately
sound so different in terms of the prose and
thought groups, just the style of your speech.
Stress three is my personal favorite too.
It focuses on reductions. You put in
time training, you get a huge reward.
Now let’s meet Alicia, another one of
the students in my Academy. She’s going
to talk about what she thinks
transforms students the most.
The other thing that I think help students really
transform in the academy is getting
specific direct feedback from teachers.
In the Facebook and community groups,  in
one to one lessons and in Whatsapp classes.
So this combination of practicing with the
sound boards, and then getting really
specific personal feedback from teachers
is the winning combination to help improve
your English and help achieve your goals.
I just love the investment that
our teachers make in our students,
and the investment that our students make
in themselves. Katie said it really well.
The Facebook and community group
students are “total badasses”.
They post videos of themselves practicing
with the content in Rachel’s Academy and
we as teachers get a glimpse into what they are
working on, we get to help them make adjustments,
give them feedback on how they’re doing,
it’s so beneficial for them. Also they are just so
encouraging and supportive of each other.
Everybody is working on the same journey,
they maybe working on specifically different
things in the Academy but they learn from
each other, and they get to support each other
throughout this process and it’s so fun to see.
Our students uplift each other.
You sign up for the Academy,
you get access to all the materials. The videos,
with the tips and tricks, and the audios to
train with. Every day you can log on and step
through the method. And in the community groups,
the students and the teachers motivate and
support each other. So now is the time,
now is your chance to get started in the Academy
and save some money with this discount code,
our last sale of the year, to celebrate my
birthday, another lap around the sun! Get
access to the materials, the methods, and yes,
these teachers in our private community group
just for students. You post a video of one of the
challenges we give you, and you get personalized
feedback, often a video, from our teachers. The
code is Rachel43 for 81% off your first month.
What do our students think about our teachers?
This is Kostas, he’s a long-time
student, active in the community.
I haven't stopped since then and I’m not
going to stop. I’m not going to stop because
Rachel and her team, they gave me
hope. They gave me hope, and you know,
you see back then, I would never dare to try to
do an American accent. It was, I would never dare.
I would, I would, even if I was in a private
room, and I would try to do an American accent,
I would just, sometimes I would cry. I would
just, you know, turn into a red
apple. And I would just shut down. I would
hear my voice trying to do an American accent,
and I would just start crying immediately because
it would trigger me that I will never become what
I want to become. I will never be able to compete
with all these Australian actors that so easily
can do American accent. And I would never be equal
and it really, it really hurts, it really hurts,
and you know, when you try so hard, and you
just, you don't have someone to back you up.
But when I met Rachel, through Rachel's English
Academy, I got her and her team to back me up.
Kostas, we do have your back and I am so glad
for your successes. Since posting that video,
he’s been cast in a play where he
has to have an American accent.
Now I'm practicing this. This is a script. It's
a, it's a script for a play here in Melbourne.
I wouldn’t be able to do this play
if it wasn’t for Rachel and her team.
If I didn't have Rachel and her team, this
simply wouldn't be possible right now. So.
Thank you Rachel and your team. And to the rest
of you guys like myself, whatever level you are
at, keep working hard because it's working. I'm
so happy, that I, you know, that it's working
because now I can do this and I'm following
my dream and who knows where I'm going to be
in a year from now. Because now I can pick up the
script and I apply everything I'm learning, I've
learned and I keep learning. And polish my accent,
you my pronoun-, you know my punctuation, and,
you know, I, I just know. I read and
I know how to say the word. It's,
it's just perfect. It's wonderful. And I owe
everything to Rachel and her team. So, thank you.
Kostas, we are so proud of you. You have put
in the time, you continue to put in the time,
you’re an inspiration. A lot of my students
don’t need to sound American, after all,
accents are beautiful. They just want to be more
confident and fluent in speaking English. And
our teachers, through our private communities,
help them. This is Ella, a student from China.
I also like the big support team from the Academy.
Like all the teachers in this team are awesome.
Every time when I submit my own recording to the
Facebook group, the teacher can always identify my
mistakes, small mistakes that
I could have never realized
myself. And they always give me very clear
and easy to follow instructions to improve.
The teachers can be so precise in
their feedback because we’re using
video. I really find that
so effective. This is Dave.
And then the second part about this Academy, which
is I like about, is that they have beautiful and
caring staff. So each time I upload uh,
my video challenge on the community group,
I usually get like a feedback within one or
two days or so, which is very efficient in my
personal experience, in my personal opinion. Even
though this mistake are tiny or small, I think
this is very important to me because I was able
to incorporate this moment mistakes into my daily
speaking habits, and I think in long-term runs
has a prolonged effect in my pronunciation skills.
So these feedbacks are very valuable and no
other classes would able to do that I say.
And you already know Al.
The teachers are so encouraging
and very expert. Um,
they can correct my mistakes in the most specific
way, so I could, I can just change my habit,
I can see my improvements and now I
can feel so confident in my English,
and I really, really want you to also feel
what I feel when you speak in English.
This is Gabriella from Brazil.
Through the Facebook group, I met
my colleagues and the teachers.
So there I can post my videos and I have fast
feedback from my colleagues and teachers.
And actually, in my first posted video, I got
surprised when I saw a comment with a video
from a teacher. So it was amazing because it
was a video about my improvements, about what,
about what I was doing about that post that I
did. So it was specific for me, it was specific
for that assignment, it was specific for that
post. So yeah, it was amazing feedback for me.
All of you students inspire us teachers to hone
our craft and keep working hard to become better
teachers. I can’t tell you how lucky I feel to be
a part of this community of teachers and students,
all supporting one another, knowing one another,
caring about one another. It’s such an uplifting
and motivating group of people. So come
join our Academy. I want to see you there.
Tom wants to see you there.
I love the Facebook group, I love the community
group in the Academy because I think that the
students are unbelievably brave to share their
practice with the community. And what is great,
and the reason that I love that community so much
is that it is a safe place to share your practice. People are
unbelievably supportive. There are so many
moments where someone will share a video
and they’ll get lots of comments saying,
“Wow! Way to go, you sound awesome! I’m so
inspired to go work on that material now.” And
that kind of connection, student to student,
that wouldn’t happen without those faces,
that Facebook group and the community group.
And so to me, being able to be there as a teacher,
to provide you know really positive, constructive
feedback to kind of help a student understand
where they may still have challenges but also to
highlight for them where they having successes and
to create a space where you can kind of feel that
forward moving energy of progress of getting
better. That to me is what that Facebook group is,
that community group and it’s an awesome thing
to be a part of so you know as a teacher,
I get to be a part of it because I’m offering
concrete feedback for what you can do to improve,
what you can do to kind of continue on your
path, but other students are also kind of
chiming in with their thoughts and most of
the time just lots of motivation and it is,
it’s really inspirational to be in there and see
all of that activity. It’s a lot of great energy.
Laura wants to see you there.
For me as a teacher, I get to check in
on people’s progress as they work through
the daily plan. And it’s great to see people who
stick with it for a long time and you can hear
them work through each module
and improve and keep getting
smoother and smoother and clearer
and clearer in their language.
Josh wants to see you there.
I love the attitude that the students bring
to the academy. They’re all so motivated to
learn they’re all so grateful for all
the help they get through the academy.
Alicia wants to see you there.
I love that I’m meeting students from
around the world and then I’m helping
them improve their English and reach their
goals. I love students encourage each other,
support each other and cheer
each other on these groups
and I also love seeing their progress over time.
I love seeing the students come in in module 1
and then work through one challenge at a time
and just get better and better and better.
Katie wants to see you there.
It’s been so great just to know all of them, uhm,
they also have a strong desire and motivation
to speak English and to better
themselves, I’m so impressed by them,
they are willing to put in the hard work and just
super dedicate it so I love getting to know them.
Ms.Stokes wants to see you there.
These are people who are highly motivated,
self-driven, goal-driven and I’m continually
inspired of how much progress they’re
able to make at their own pace.
To hear more from Kostas, Ella, and my other
students, see this video or the link in the
video description. And be sure to subscribe
to my channel here on YouTube and turn on
notifications on so that we can keep in touch.
I make new videos on the English language every
week and I would love to see you back here.
For now, keep your learning going with this
video and let me know in the comments below
if you have any questions about the Academy.
I can’t wait to see you there. That’s it and
thanks so much for using Rachel’s English.