Every night you dream at least, at least 10
dreams a night. Do you remember your dreams?
If you do, you're well on your way to having
some fantastic times when you close your eyes.
Today I'm going to teach you about one of my
favourite things in the world ever - dreams
and dreaming. Maybe you know the Supertramp
song: "Dreamer". I'm not going to sing it
for you, but I'm going to teach you
about some things I know about dreams.
The first one is I want you to ask yourself
this question: When you dream, do you dream
only in black and white or do you dream in
colour? It's interesting because everyone's
different. When I dream, I always dream in
colour. Some people only dream in black and
white, so it's a cool little thing you can
ask your friends, ask your family, and see,
you'll find out everyone's different. Some
people only dream in colour; some people only
dream in black and white. I do not know the
psychology behind it. I think it's interesting,
but I don't know why.
The second question that I have for you is:
When you dream, are you yourself? This means
first-person. So, are you...? Are you doing
the action? Or are you watching or seeing
yourself do the action? Some people are both,
and can do both; it can switch. For me, I
am always myself doing the action. Some people,
it's like they're watching a movie, and they
are the star in the movie. And other people,
like I said, can switch and do both. At one
point of the dream they can be a main character,
and the other point or other dream, they can
watch themselves. How about you? Tell me your
answers in the comments. Tell me. Do you dream
in black and white, or colour? And are you
yourself in the dream or do you see or watch
yourself in a dream? We'll do a little survey
and find out from answers all around the world.
What happens when you dream?
Let's go into some terminology, some vocabulary,
if you will, about dreams. Commonly... We
don't really have a word for them because
we don't call them "night dreams", but we
do have what are called "daydreams". "Daydreams"
are what you maybe do at work when you're
supposed to be working or at school when you're
supposed to be learning, or just at the end
of the day on the bus. Daydreams are basically
like you are physically there, but your brain
is imagining different things. This is one
of my hobbies, daydreaming. I remember when
I was young-I'm so old now-I would just sit in
my room for hours and daydream about everything
and anything. It was fantastic. My imagination,
massive. So daydreams happen during the daytime,
yeah? And "night dreams", we don't actually
call them "night dreams", we just call them
"dreams". Are you a dreamer? "A dreamer" is
someone who dreams, daydreams all the time.
They don't really get a lot done. But I'm
a dreamer. You got to have dreams, right?
Let's go through a couple of kinds of types of
dreams. The first one is "lucid". So "lucid
dreams" mean you realize in the dream that
you are actually dreaming. Now, this, ladies
and gentlemen, can be really cool because
you might wake up during the dream, and you
go: "Hey, I'm dreaming right now." If you can
do this, if you can realize you're having
a lucid dream, you can then begin to control your
dreams. This is one thing that I experimented
with when I was younger is that I would realize
that I was dreaming, and I would change my
dream and make it more into a fantasy. A
fantastic fantasy of feathers and fudgesicles.
This is a really terrible kind of dream, it's
called a "nightmare". Nightmares are also
known as "bad dreams". Usually when we're
children, we're sleeping, we might
[screams]
wake up, screaming or crying. Maybe we have
dreams about monsters. This would be a nightmare.
Bad dreams or nightmares cause anxiety, so
something bad is happening to you in the dream,
you might dream of death, somebody's dead.
Maybe you watched a zombie movie, and in your
dream, you're being chased by zombies. It's
on a subconscious level, so things that we
might have done in the day or talked about
or seen can come back in our dream. They can
come back in a bad way, and become a nightmare.
You might wake up screaming, or crying, or
something bad has happened
in your dream world.
And some people have what's called a "reoccurring
dream", a "recurring dream" means you have
the same dream over and over again. Again,
lucid dreams, if you can control them, some
people can control them; nightmares and recurring
dreams, it's almost impossible to control
them. Now, reoccurring dreams will happen, we
don't know when, we don't really know why,
but it'll be the same situation and the same
dream over and over again. It can go on for
years. People say you have this because you have
some issue or some problem that's unresolved,
means you haven't fixed a problem. Other people
just don't know why we have reoccurring dreams.
Have you had a reoccurring dream,
or do you have those? I never have.
The next word is "prophetic dreams" or known
as "psychic dreams". And you might hear the
word "psychic" on TV or in crazy movies where
there's a person that can tell you your future
or foretell the future. These people might be
doing it for money, or they might actually
have a gift to be able to foretell the future.
But some people can have psychic or prophetic
dreams, which means something will happen in
the dream and then it'll come true in the
future. So your dream foretells the future.
This happens to me quite a lot. It won't be
the same situation, but the emotion or feeling
that I have in the dream will happen in real
life again. It's pretty creepy, but
interesting. I've gotten used to it.
These are some common themes or common things
that people have analyzed dreams, and they
tell you about why you dream this. So, the
first one: being chased. So if you're running
and running and running, and someone chases
you, they tell you that... "They" being the
dream experts mean that you're not addressing
something in your life. So not addressing
something means you're not solving a problem
you have in your life, or you're not admitting
to a problem you have. So, you're being chased
because you're not stopping, and going:
"Hey. I got a problem."
Anytime you dream about water, it always has
to do with your emotions, and the different
types of water can mean different things.
For example, if you're at a lake and it's
very calm, this is going to mean that maybe
in the future you're going to have a calmness
or everything's going to be relaxed. If you
have a dream where maybe you're in the ocean
and waves are crazy, this means your emotions
are going to get very high and very tense.
Death, example you have a dream that somebody
dies, actually it doesn't that somebody's
going to die. It actually means there's going to
be a dramatic change in your life, so something
in your life is going to change in a big style,
in a big way. Maybe you're going to move or
something is going
to change your life.
Falling, this happens to me a lot. This is
cool. People say that if you fall in your
dream, you always wake up before you land.
Apparently, if you die in your dream, you
die in real life. I don't know. I've never
died in my dream. Have you? Have you come
back from the dead? Are you a zombie? So dreaming
of falling, if you are falling very slowly
almost like you're floating, it means that
you're letting go of some emotions or you're
letting go of some problems. But if you're
falling really quickly, I'm going to die,
it means that you're going to lose control of
a situation or you already have lost control
of a situation, or you're going to lose control
of a situation. So the forms, how fast you
fall, depends on the
interpretation of it.
And the last one, apparently this is a really
common or popular dream. People have dreams
that their partner-boyfriend/girlfriend, husband/wife,
whatever-are cheating on them, that means
that they're having sex or doing bad things
with other people. This is actually a really,
really common dream, and it's a fear of being
wronged. "Wronged" means someone does something
bad to you. So this is a fear we have, that
someone's going to hurt you in some way, or
you have a feeling of being... Sorry, a fear
of being left alone or abandoned because if
someone cheats on you, probably
your relationship will be over,
and the person's gone
out of your life.
So, other things you guys can do to help
you with your dreams. I hear people say:
"I don't dream." You do dream, but the
thing is you don't remember your dreams.
We only remember the dreams
that you wake up during.
If you want to, just for
fun, you can make a dream
diary. So if you wake up, you write down your
dreams. And you wake up in the morning, go:
"Whoa.
I don't remember that." You don't remember
it because it's gone. So if you write it...
Wake up and write it down and you
can read it, it's really cool.
Last piece of advice or a myth, a legend,
my grandmother or my gran told me that if
you have a dream that the stone is missing
from a ring... For example, I have a ring
and I have an amethyst in it, if I have a
dream that a stone is missing from the ring,
it means that someone close to me is going
to die. Have you ever had that dream?
Maybe it's true, maybe it's not.
All of these things that I've told you about
being chased, and water, and death, these
are all people's interpretations of dreams. I
do not believe that your dream and my dream,
if it's similar, has any similarities whatsoever.
I think people's dreams are as individual
as each other, so you can go on to the internet,
and look up: "Oh, I had a dream about a van.
What does a van mean?" And you're going to
get maybe five different interpretations of
it. It's your chance to think about it, and
reflect on what dreams mean to you. Not anyone
else or not anyone's interpretation
of it, but try it out.
The last thing you can do just before you go
to bed, try this social experiment. Before
you go to bed, eat cheese. The stinkier, the
smeller, the grosser the cheese, apparently
the more vivid or crazy
your dreams will be.
Sweet dreams.