Hello everyone, welcome back to my channel
Sparkle English where I teach you how to
improve your level of English. Today is going
to be a very important beginner grammar lesson
on the difference between A, AN, SOME, and ANY.
These are very common words in English and it's
important that you know how to use them. First,
we need to learn the difference between countable
nouns and uncountable nouns. Countable nouns have
a singular and plural form. In plural, these nouns
can be used with a number, which is why they are
called countable nouns. For example, we could say
I have one dog, or I have two dogs. Uncountable
Nouns can only be used in the singular form. These
nouns cannot be used with a number, which is why
they are called uncountable nouns. For example,
we can say I have money, but we can't say I have
one money, or I have two money. So now let's learn
when we use AP or n, we use the articles AP,
or N in front of singular countable nouns,
is used when the next word starts with
a consonant sound. So for example,
I have a cat, I need a laptop. Because cat and
laptop both begin with a consonant sound, we use
AP, and is used when the next word starts with
a vowel sound. For example, I want an ice cream,
he's eating an orange. Both ice cream
and orange begin with a vowel sound.
So we use and we use some and any with plural
countable nouns and uncountable nouns. Some
is generally used in positive or affirmative
sentences. For example, I have some bad news.
She invited some friends over for dinner.
Any is generally used in negative sentences.
For example, there isn't any milk
left. She doesn't have any friends.
We can use either any or some in questions.
However, there is a small difference.
We usually use any in requests for information.
For example, do you have any wrapping paper?
Does she play any sports? And we
usually use some in offers and requests?
Can I please have some cake?
Would you like some coffee?
So now let's review ah, and some and any in a
bit more detail and do some practice together.
Okay, so before our quiz, we're going to
quickly go over these again. We use r and n
in front of singular countable nouns, we use an
in front of a singular countable noun that begins
with a consonant sound. So for example, I have
a banana. And we use an in front of a singular
countable noun that begins with a vowel sound. For
example, I want an orange. We use both some and
any with plural countable and uncountable nouns.
Some is mainly used in affirmative sentences.
For example, I bought some balloons for the
party. Natasha has some homework to do before bed.
Both of these are affirmative sentences.
So we use some in the question form, we can
use some in offers and requests. For example,
would you like some tea? Can I have some pie?
Any is mainly used in negative sentences and
questions, example, and doesn't have any dates
this week. There isn't any coffee left. Both
of these are negative sentences. So we use any
and not some. We usually use any in questions
with requests for information. For example,
are there any cute guys at the party? Do we
have any flour? So now we're going to do a quiz,
you have to fill in the blanks with an n sum or
any? There will be eight questions in this quiz.
Question number one, Joe doesn't have ___
friends. Question two, I'd like ___ cake please.
Question three. Do you get ___ presents on your
birthday? Question four, would you like ___ water?
Question five: Do you know ___ famous people?
Question six, I have ___ small dog. Question
seven, make sure to bring ___ umbrella.
And finally eight, we didn't buy ___ bread. The
correct answer for number one is any. Joe doesn't
have any friends. Because this is a negative
sentence we use any question to I'd like some
cake please. This is a positive or affirmative
sentence, so we use some. Now you might be
confused about this word cake. And you might
wonder, could we put I'd like a cake. And that
would also be correct. If you wanted a cake, you
would want the complete cake. If you say I'd like
some cake, you want a piece of that cake? Question
three, did you get any presents on your birthday?
This is a request for information. We're
trying to find out information. So we use any.
Question four: the answer is some. Would
you like some water? And that is because
this is an offer. When we are offering
something to someone, we use some.
Number five: The answer is any.
Do you know any famous people?
Again, this is a question and it's also a
request for information. Just like number three.
Number six, the answer is a. I have a small
dog. Dog is a singular countable noun.
And we have small and that's a consonant sound. So
we can't say an; we have to say a. Number seven,
make sure to bring an umbrella because umbrella
is a singular countable noun. And also it begins
with a vowel sound. And finally, we didn't buy
any bread. This is a negative sentence. So we
have to use any. So let me know in the comment
section how many you got correct out of eight.
And if you had any difficulties, which ones were
most difficult for you? If you have any questions,
let me know in the comment section. Make sure to
like this video and subscribe to sparkle English
for more videos on how to improve your level
of English. I will see you in my next lesson.