Hello, I'm Emma from English!
In this lesson, you'll learn how to use
these little, useful words correctly in English sentences.
Both of these words indicate a degree.
They give us more information about
an adjective or an adverb or a noun.
So, here 'too' means that it is
more than what is wanted or what is needed.
So, it's usually a negative thing!
You are more hungry than you want to be!
This is really frustrating for you
because you can't concentrate!
So here, 'enough' tells us
that it is the amount that we want or we need.
It's the right amount and this is a positive thing!
You have what is needed, you are good enough.
Ouch! That is really mean!
Not enough means that it is
less than the amount that you want or you need.
It's a really negative thing. It's a pretty mean thing to say.
So, let's look at the structures for each of these words
with adjectives and adverbs first.
So, 'too' comes before an adjective or an adverb.
Remember that using 'too' with an adjective
or an adverb usually suggests that it's a negative thing.
It's more than what is wanted or needed.
So, it's not correct to say that the movie was 'too good'
when you really enjoyed it!
It's also not correct to say that your friend is 'too funny'.
It sounds really strange to native English speakers
because it suggests that it's more than what you want
or what you need it to be.
Use 'really' or 'very' or 'so' instead.
That sounds better!
There are some exceptions to this though,
when you're speaking colloquially
- especially in Australia, where I'm from!
Like... For example, if someone asked me,
"How are you?"
I'd probably say, "Not too bad."
This is really common in Australia and it means 'good'
but that's an exception.
Okay, what about 'enough'?
'Enough' comes after the adjective or the adverb.
Now, what about when 'enough' is used
in a negative sentence?
'Enough' comes after the adjective or the adverb
but 'not' comes before.
And this has the same meaning as 'I'm too weak'.
... Which means 'it's too cold'!
You can also use 'too' and 'enough' with nouns.
So again, this means that we have more of the noun
than we want or we need.
You would choose 'many' if the noun was countable.
And you would choose 'much'
if the noun was uncountable.
Now, if you are not sure about
which nouns are countable and which are uncountable,
you should check out this lesson right here
because I'll explain it for you there!
So, what about 'enough'?
Well, with a noun 'enough' comes before the noun.
Again, this means that we have the right amount,
the amount that we want and that we need.
And to make these sentences negative we add 'not'
- usually before the main verb.
The 'be' verb is a bit of an exception here, to the rule.
The structure is a little different.
When the 'be' verb is the main verb,
then 'not' comes after the main verb.
So, these handy little words will definitely help you to
express yourself more clearly in English
and now you know exactly how to use them correctly.
Make sure you practise them.
Write some examples if you want,
add them in the comments below!
Remember that 'too'
means that it's more than the necessary amount.
'Enough' is the necessary amount, it's the exact amount.
And 'not enough' is less than the necessary amount.
And if you've managed to make it through this lesson
all the way to the end
then you are going to get a special reward
because you're about to find out how you can get
mmmEnglish courses for under five dollars!
Now, on Monday the 27th of November
(yes, that's soon!)
You are going to be able to buy all mmmEnglish courses
on the mmmEnglish website, for under five dollars.
Now, they have never been that low, ever!
So, I want you to make the most of it if you can!
Go to the website
and check it out on Monday the 27th of November.
Practise using my imitation lessons
to improve your pronunciation
and your English expression when you're speaking.
They're all available at huge discounts, only on Monday.
So, don't miss out!
And now check out that lesson right there
and practise using 'enough' and 'too'
with the adjectives that I teach in that lesson.
Or, if you want to try something else
check out that playlist right there.
Keep practising and I will see you again next week!
Bye for now!