(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone.
And welcome back to English with Lucy.
I'm here once again in front
of possibly the most
beautiful tree in England.
I don't know, no offence to other trees.
Now, today we are going to
be talking about small talk
because I don't want to jinx it,
but it seems that the world is,
or some places in the world
are slowly opening up again.
Here in the UK, supposedly
we have Freedom Day
on the 19th of July where nightclubs,
bars and everything open up again,
and people have the choice
to not wear masks anymore.
Let me know what the situation
is like in your country
in the comments section down below.
And when I heard about this
Freedom Day from the pandemic,
I suddenly thought, oh, my word,
I have not been in a big room of people
having to make conversation
in a year and a half.
So I thought today we
could talk about small talk
and I'm actually going
to give you 50 different
small talk questions that you can use
in your next social event,
because not only are you learning English
you are also probably a
little bit out of practise.
There's nothing worse than
trying to make conversation
in another language and
just having loads of boring,
embarrassing silences.
So all of these questions
or nearly all of them
are open-ended.
So you can get really good
answers from the other person.
As always I have created a free PDF
that goes with this video if
you'd like to download it,
all you've got to do is click on the link
in the description box,
you enter your name
and your email address,
you sign up to my mailing
list and then I send the PDF
directly to your inbox,
and then every week
after that you will automatically
receive my free PDFs.
Plus all of my news offers
and course information.
Before we get started,
I would like to Thank
the sponsor of today's video, Skillshare,
which is an online learning community
with thousands of inspiring classes,
for creative and curious people.
There are so many classes to choose from.
From writing to design, to animation,
to business, to productivity.
I recently took a class,
could email productivity work smarter
with your inbox by Alexandra Samuel,
and it transformed my email game.
Emails used to stress me out so much,
and this 45 minute class
just taught me to filter
through everything and
organise my email game.
Skillshare is curated
specifically for learning.
Meaning there are no ads and
they are always launching
new premium classes so
you can stay focused
and follow wherever your
creativity takes you.
The first 1000 of my
subscribers to click on the link
in the description box will
get a one a month free trial
of Skillshare premium
so you can start
exploring your creativity.
Right.
Let's get started with the small talk.
I have divided the 50 small talk questions
into five different categories.
The first one being travel,
which is something that
most of us haven't been able
to do a lot of recently.
But hopefully things are
getting back to normal
and we will be able to attend conferences
and make small talk with
people we don't know.
Yes.
The first question, a really good one
if you're in a new country and
you're speaking to a local,
do you know of any
hidden gems around here?
A hidden gem is something
really, really great,
a really great place or restaurant,
that tourists don't generally know about.
In fact, not many people know about it.
You kinda have to hear
about it to go there.
When I travel I always ask
around for the hidden gems.
You could also put it
in more simple terms.
Is there anything I should
know about around here?
Are there any places I should know about?
Now generally when it comes to small talk,
it's really good to ask open questions.
Questions that can't be
answered with a yes or no,
because if the answer with
no and it really shuts
down the conversation,
but I think this next one is an exception.
Have you got any trips planned?
If they say, no, you can
move on to another topic
of small talk.
If you know the person you're talking to,
and you know, they went
on a trip recently,
you can say, "Tell me
about your trip to Hawaii.
"Would you recommend it?"
If there's one thing I've learned,
people love talking about
their past holidays.
Another great topic to bring
up is food whilst travelling.
You could say something like
I love trying new cuisines.
Have you been anywhere
with really great food?
If you're with a fellow foodie,
then you know conversation
is going to flow.
The next one is a great one
for international conferences
where you know that the majority of people
have come in from another location.
One question I like to
ask in those situations
is have you got any tips for jetlag?
I really, really struggle with it.
So if you do have any tips
please do put them in the comment section.
Now what about if you are in your hometown
but someone else has come in to visit.
You could say let me know if
you need any recommendations.
I know this area pretty well.
That's a great opportunity
for them to follow up with.
Yeah, actually I'm looking for
somewhere for dinner tonight,
do you know anywhere?
And then you panic because
you've lived here for 10 years
and you've hardly gone out.
That was like me in London as a student,
I lived there for three years
but because I never had any money
I never went to any restaurants.
So when people ask me,
"Where should I go in London?"
"I have no idea."
I just ate microwave meals.
Another great question is
asking what sort of holiday
or trip someone prefers.
You could say, do you prefer
a fly-and-flop holiday
or an adventure?
A fly-and-flop holiday is
what it says on the tin,
you fly out to the destination,
you flop on a sunbed and
you remain there for one
to two weeks and then you fly home.
Another interesting question
to do with the pandemic is,
has the pandemic affected
your travel plans at all?
And this will probably
open up a lot of moaning
from the other person.
It would, for me, the
pandemic ruined a honeymoon.
And the last one number 10 is
so when are you heading back?
What do you want to do before you go back?
Right, let's move on to the topic of work.
Maybe you're trying to get
to know your new colleagues
or your existing colleagues
that you've hardly met before.
It's really nice to have a
couple of small talk questions
up your sleeve to combat
those awkward silences.
The first one.
So how did you get into marketing?
How did you get into sales?
So really nice general one.
And it invites the person to tell
you a little bit about their work history.
Two really interesting ones
are what is the best career
advice you've ever received?
And then the next one,
what's the worst career
advice you've ever received.
I use this one a lot
and I get some really interesting answers,
especially for the worst career advice.
The next one, a nice theoretical one,
if you were guaranteed to be successful,
what job would you want?
That's a really interesting one.
I don't even know how I would answer that.
You'll get your partner thinking there.
Another really fun one
is what is the craziest
thing a boss has ever asked you to do?
I think the craziest thing
a boss has ever made me do,
he didn't ask me,
is I had to knock on
his door in the middle
of the night to beg for him to pay me.
It was two months late
and I needed my money.
This next one is a nice
way of making someone
feel part of your conversation.
You could say, I was just
talking to a colleague
about our first jobs, what was yours?
Everyone who is currently
working has a first job.
A really good and easy one is how long
have you been working at company?
How long have you been
working at Lucy International?
My whole life darling.
(laughs)
A topic that's in the
news quite a lot recently.
What do you think about
this four-day work week?
I've been seeing that coming
up a lot on my news apps
and I think it sounds
like a fantastic idea.
If people can still
maintain good productivity,
give the people an extra day off,
work to live, don't live to work.
Bring it back to the pandemic,
have you had to work from home recently?
How did you find working from home?
That's a really good topic
'cause that shook up the lives
of many people over here in the UK.
And I'm sure all across the world as well.
And the last one, have you
got any plans for the weekend?
I remember Friday and sometimes
even Thursday afternoon
when I did work in an
office all we could talk
about with the weekend and I loved it.
I used to count down those hours
until it was five o'clock
on a Friday evening.
Oh yes.
All right, next topic, current
events or current affairs.
Now, obviously people are going
to talk about the pandemic.
So one question you could
ask is has the pandemic
affected you much?
But remember that lots of people have lost
loved ones in this,
so they might not want
to focus too much on it.
Another one is this person
is from another country
you could say, how are you
all getting on back home?
This invites them to open
up about how the pandemic
has affected their country if
they want to talk about it.
Another variation is how has the pandemic
changed life for you?
Some really great conversation
starters are the next three.
I read in the paper that,
I saw on the news that,
or I heard on the radio that,
and then obviously you can
speak about what you've seen,
heard, or read recently.
If you know that your conversation
partner is a sports fun,
you could say, did you catch the game?
Even if you don't know which game it was,
hopefully just by saying the
game they'll know which game
you were talking about,
but make sure you have
a game up your sleeve
for if they say, what game.
If there has been an interesting
or negative situation
in another country, and
you've been following
it on the news,
you could ask something
like, have you been following
what's been going on in, for example.
Again, if the person is from another town
or city or country, you could say,
so what's the latest
news where you're from?
And the last one,
a really interesting
question that somebody
asked me the other day is which
news outlets do you prefer?
And then they asked why.
And this can invite the person
to share kind of indirectly
a little bit of their political leanings,
which is quite interesting.
Right.
The next topic is social events.
I haven't been to a big social event,
well, I've said it before
in a year and a half.
And I'm nervous.
I'm very, very nervous.
So I can't imagine how nerve
wracking it will be in a second
language or a foreign language.
So here are some questions
for you to have up your sleeve
to fill in those silences.
The first one, what brings you here?
What brings you here?
And that invites them to
say, oh, well I work with,
or I know or I'm going
out with, for example.
If you meet somebody and
you have a mutual friend,
you could ask, so how do you know, Tom?
For example.
I always find a compliment goes a long way
as long as it's a genuine one.
So you could say, wow,
your dress is so unique,
where did you get it from?
I'm in two minds about the next question.
Are you enjoying yourself?
Sometimes it can be a
little bit patronising.
So you've got to say it in the right tone.
But if somebody says,
no, that opens up a bonding opportunity.
If you're also not enjoying
yourself you can say,
oh, Thank God me neither.
I hate social occasions.
If you aren't enjoying a social situation,
you could say something like,
I really don't normally like
crowded events like these,
how about you?
And if the person says, I love them,
then you know, you might not be friends.
But if they say, God,
yes, I hate them too.
Friend for life instantaneous.
If you see somebody who is
hovering around on their own,
you could go up to them and say,
do you know many people here?
And if they say, no,
well then you can stand
and chat with them instead.
I absolutely love it when
I'm on my own at an event,
and somebody comes in to save me.
I really, really liked that.
Right.
More pandemic.
A really good way of bonding with someone
else is to kind of share
a bit of vulnerability.
And one thing you could say is,
hello, I've actually not
been around another human
in a whole year so I'm feeling
really awkward right now.
How are you feeling?
That's a good invitation
for you to bond over.
Just feeling out of practise
and not knowing how to behave
in social situations anymore.
Another one I'm desperate for everything
to get back to normal.
What have you missed most?
Or when is the last
time that you were able
to go to a proper party like this?
And you can both bond over
how much you've missed out on.
And the last one I really
liked this one, it's very meta.
What is your best tip
for figuring out small talk these days?
I love it 'cause they can
instantly say something like,
just don't talk about the weather.
So then you know, not to talk
to them about the weather.
But that actually brings
me onto my next topic.
The weather, come on, I'm British.
Of course I'm going to talk
to you about the weather.
I did save this one for last,
because I know that it's almost a cliche
to talk about the weather in Britain
whilst participating in small talk.
But our weather just changes so much.
When I started filming
this video, it was sunny,
and now it looks like it's going to rain.
Look at me I'm talking about the weather.
If it's a beautiful day,
you can say it's such a
beautiful day, isn't it?
And then everyone else
goes, oh yes, it is lovely.
Yes, very nice.
Haven't had one like this in ages.
Or an alternative,
we couldn't ask for a nicer day, could we?
And everyone else goes,
no, no we couldn't.
It's wonderful.
It's just stuffy.
So nice.
Fortunately, we don't have
many days like that in the UK
so we don't get to be,
Oh, yes, yes, yes, lovely,
too frequently.
If it's very sunny, you could say,
did you bring the sunshine with you
or did you order the
sunshine, oh, it's lovely.
And then you can have a little joke
about yes, yes, I brought
it with me in my suitcase
from Spain.
So in the UK, we have a
love-hate relationship
with the meteorologist,
with the weatherperson,
because when they tell us
it's going to be sunny,
we love them but when they
tell us it's going to rain
we just don't believe them.
And then we get caught out
and about with no umbrella.
One great topic to bring
up is I saw on the weather
this morning that it's going
to rain, it's going to hail,
it's going to be sunny,
there's going to be snow.
What do you think?
And then you can follow
up with what do you think?
Do you believe them?
Do you trust them?
Another version is, do you trust
the weather forecast today?
Because they said it's going
to rain but it looks lovely.
If it has been raining a lot,
you can say can you
believe how wet it's been?
Or can you believe all this
rain we've been having?
If you're in a foreign
country you can say,
is the weather normally like this?
Is it usually like this?
A really interesting one
is what's the worst weather
you've ever experienced.
And that invites them to
talk about maybe a country
they've visited or just a prolonged period
of terrible weather.
So I've got two more small talk questions
about the weather that
kind of take the Mickey.
They joke about small talk
relating to the weather.
The first one is why do we
always end up making small talk
about the weather?
And then that invites you
to make some small talk
about the weather together.
And the last one is, is
it okay if I try to talk
to you by pretending that
I'm really interested
in the weather?
(laughs)
I think that's a great
one to use at a situation
like a conference where small talk
can get a little bit much.
Right.
That is it for today's lesson.
I hope you enjoyed it, and I
hope you learned something.
Don't forget to check out Skillshare.
Remember that the first
1000 of my students to click
on the link in the description box
will get a one month free
trial of Skillshare premium.
You can also download the free PDF
that goes along with this lesson.
Just click on the link
in the description box,
enter your name and your email address.
You sign up to my mailing
list and I send the PDF
and all future PDFs to
your inbox directly.
Don't forget to connect with
me on all of my social media.
I've got my Instagram
and I've got my website,
englishwithlucy.co.uk,
where I've got a really cool,
if I do say so myself pronunciation tool,
where you can click on different phonemes
and hear me pronounce those phonemes
and words containing those phonemes.
If you'd like to practise your vocabulary
and your listening skills even further
then I have got a vlogging channel
where I document my life here
in the English countryside
and every single blog is fully subtitled.
I will see you soon for another lesson.
(coughs)
I promise it's not COVID and
it can't pass through lenses.
I recently took a class called,
what is it called, right?
A fly-and-flop is what
it says on the card.
It says on the cards,
what it says on the label.
Tin.
Don't forget to connect with
me on all of my social media.
I've got my Instagram.
What else have I got?
I think what I was trying to
say is you have an ologist.
But if really muscly,
you have a meteorologist.
Terrible.
(upbeat music)