It all started in elementary school.
Nope, not in kindergarten.
This Mary Jane
here did not know a word of English.
I was 7
in my second year of elementary school
when we started to have one hour
English class per week.
This is when I learned
the English alphabet
Here I learned how to say How are you?
My name is Maria.
I learned to count in English 123456.
We learned how to put together
a sentence: subject verb object.
We learned pronouns.
I you, she me
us the verb to be to have the main verbs
in general.
There is/There are, prepositions of time.
Preposition of place:
This all continued
in middle school,
which is between eleven
and 14 years old in Italy.
The lessons were themed and followed
the structure of the textbook.
So each lesson would be something like,
I remember in middle
school we might have been 12
this native English speaker
came to our class
to do English conversation.
He was a 20 year
old, long haired,
huge Australian rugby player
who came to play this season
with the rugby team of Udinese
and probably thought
about making some side money.
At this point
most of the English tests
we were doing where written.
They were things like fill up
the blanks
and rearrange this group of words
to form a correct sentence.
We would
sometimes read out loud
from the textbooks in the class,
but we would really never speak English.
So I don't remember speaking English
with this guy that day.
At this point
all we could say was really,
I don't think we could understand him
either.
In fact,
we were never taught English
pronunciation in school.
Neither was it
taught to my English teachers.
Almost all the English we would hear
was from an Italian adult who had been
probably once
in an English speaking country.
But let's go on with high school,
which is more interesting.
In Italy high school's
from 14 to 19 years old.
Here my English teacher was a very strict
and rigid, Friulan, mature lady, in love
with the British culture and literature.
In fact,
she also had a good British
pronunciation herself.
Problem is that she never thought about
teaching it to us.
At this point,
we had two or three hours
per week of English lessons,
and they were taught in Italian.
In particular,
these lessons were divided into two
types either grammar or literature.
The grammar lessons became more detailed
and specific.
Plenty of time
was spent in learning
to capitalize all the
I pronouns, all the names of the months,
the nationalities, titles.
plenty of time
to learn the past
simple and past
participle of the irregular verbs.
My teacher in particular
had a little obsession
with present perfect and past perfect.
Forms like I have done, I had done.
If you hear me overusing them,
now you know why.
We also thoroughly studied
the continuous forms of the past tenses
like I was doing. I have been doing.
I had been doing, not to mention
all the various future forms
like I will have done
or I will have been doing.
But in high school,
probably more than half of the hours
spent of English classes
where English literature and culture,
where English means from England.
When I say
literature, I mean mostly stuff
like Chaucer and Shakespeare,
which is not exactly
the most useful literature to understand
modern spoken English.
And of course, all these lessons
were taught in Italian.
By the way,
my English teacher
was a fantastic teacher,
despite a little bit rigid.
She just never spoke English to us.
For sure
to my spoken
English by far
the most educating experience
has been two weeks
cultural exchange
my class has done
with a Dutch school class.
We student hosted Dutch students
in our families for a week
and they did the same with us
for another week in the Netherlands.
Two weeks of that
had pretty much the same effect
on my oral
communication skills
as several years of lessons
in the classroom.
This is Mary Jane at 19 on her last day
of what we call
"scuola" (school before univeristy).
As you can understand
from the Serbo-Croatian
text on our shirt,
she was surrounded
by many foreign languages,
but could really speak none .
At this point
we all had been studying English
in school for twelve years.
We could write it very correctly,
although with a limited vocabulary,
we could read it easily.
If we had a dictionary available.
We could speak it very, very little.
In my case, everything
changed in my third year of university
when I participated
to the Erasmus program,
which is a European program
that allows you
to study abroad
for a semester or two semesters.
So I ended up living in Germany
for a year.
During this year,
I very much focused on learning German,
but if you are a student abroad
you are in contact
with other foreign students,
so you will end up
speaking English anyways.
After this experience,
I started traveling pretty often.
I also had international friends,
so I started using English
on a regular basis.
After I finished university,
I also discovered YouTube
and I started watching YouTube
both in Italian,
but especially in English.
And this is really where my understanding
of English skyrocketed.
At this point my speaking
skills were very good.
But I had always spoken
with other foreign people,
never with natives,
so my pronunciation
was still very uncertain.
I just dropped off my luggage.
I'm here in the Greenwich Village
after spending three days in Midtown.
The real reason why I am so fluent in
English nowadays
is because I focused on my pronunciation.
How did I do that?
Well,
there was no course
of English pronunciation at the time.
No textbooks, no nothing.
But I really, really needed it
because in the meantime,
I started my YouTube channel.
and it was in English,
and so I needed to be as fluent
as possible to get decent views.
So I simply started analyzing
as much as I could listening
to other native speakers speaking.
I was helping myself with YouTube
and with real people
because in the meantime,
I started traveling here
to New York City,
being in contact with Americans.
This was a pretty long process.
And really, it's
all documented on my channel
because my channel is turning
four years this month
and you can really see
from my first video to the other ones
ttill the last ones,
how my spoken English developed.
This is why I proceeded
to create my English
pronunciation course for Italians,
because the pronunciation
is such a crucial part of the language.
And in Italy,
nobody really teaches it to us.
So I basically collected
all my knowledge
that I learned in years
of analyzing native speakers
and condensed it
into a video course
that I then put on sale on my website.
I do not do sponsorships on this channel,
but I do promote my products.
So this is my product
that if you are Italian,
you want to improve your English,
you can buy directly on my website.
My journey to become fluent in English,
starting from a normal Italian public
school education
has been very long,
but for sure it could have been
way shorter
if only someone taught me
a little bit of pronunciation.
My next video is going to be next Sunday.
If you don't want to miss it out
subscribe to the channel,
make sure the notifications are on.
And now see you there bye!