hey guys welcome to lingua marina today
we're gonna talk
about disagreeing with people and i know
these situations
happen very often and when i first came
to the us
i used my russian russian culture where
we disagree with people like say
no you're wrong like we're very
straightforward people
in russia in america it doesn't work
that way it can be actually
really offensive if you just say no
you're wrong
i think it's this this and that so when
i was
studying here and i went through a
filmmaking course
when i was just dealing with people they
would kind of
correct me sometimes say marina that's
not the right way to disagree with
people you should do this
this and that so i decided that in this
video i'm gonna
collect all of my experience i'm gonna
share some tips and tricks that you can
use to disagree with people
without becoming too angry without
starting a fight so if you're interested
in
both learning some new vocabulary and
also learning some
cultural aspects of living in the us and
most of the western world i guess
please continue watching this video
first of all when you disagree with
people please
start with facts when you disagree with
someone
it's not like a personal thing it's not
just that you want to show a person that
you disagree with everything they do
well sometimes we have those situations
we're not going to talk about them
but disagree with facts like for example
if somebody tells you it's going to rain
in an hour
you'll be like i actually just checked
my app and it's not going to rain
what does your app say so you know talk
about facts don't say oh
no you're wrong you are stupid you
haven't considered this this and that
having even looked
at your phone this is too much also when
you talk about facts it just makes you
more convincing
because when you're talking facts you
actually have a ground to disagree
when you're talking just based on your
emotions and what you think about
another person
that doesn't really support your opinion
the second
tip here is to just be indirect
and being indirect is a thing that can
confuse you when you come to the us
because a lot of americans are very
indirect with everything
if they disagree with you or they don't
like something
they can start their phrase by wow
you're amazing and i really like your
work and you're like
and then it's going to be followed up by
but unfortunately we think
that this it doesn't meet our investment
criteria or whatever
when i was fundraising for a lingua trip
with my husband all of the replies from
investors and we had like
over 50 meetings i guess we had more but
all of the replies would start with
you guys are doing an amazing job your
company is great
but and then they would say that they
basically don't want to invest
so and that was super confusing because
at first you think like if the people
think that your company is great
why don't they invest so this is the way
of how americans are
indirect with their feedback they would
always start with something positive
and then disagree or say something
negative and even the the negative thing
that they're saying it wouldn't
sound too negative it would sound like
if it's their fault
not your fault that they're not
investing or they don't want to hire you
or they don't want to accept you to the
university or whatever
and so what you've noticed here from my
from my story it's like
always going from you to me
so i would never say oh my god your idea
is horrible
i would say if i want to sound polite
and indirect i would say
i don't really think that this idea
would work
i don't think that would be a good idea
you see how i am
trying to be polite i'm not saying it's
a horrible idea and also i am trying to
take away somebody else's pain or
somebody else's fault to me
i just don't think it's a good idea
instead of saying
it's a horrible idea or instead of
saying you're wrong you're stupid
i would say i am not sure i can't agree
gotta say i'm not too sure i agree with
that so you see how i'm always talking
to another person through
myself i'm not sure i can agree with
this
i'm not sure this idea is gonna work i
don't think it's the right thing to do
so it's always about me
not about another person here's another
thing don't be
overpolite as well like don't overdo and
i think you could overdo
being polite by saying sorry because i
think a lot of
americans and a lot of native speakers
use sorry
way too often even if you know that the
most common situation
is when you're running and it's a rush
hour and somebody bumps into you and you
say
i'm sorry like it's it's even not your
fault you were just there and
the person another person didn't notice
you i would avoid saying
sorry just because you have a different
opinion but again it's up to you
quick pause here disagreeing with
someone directly
is one of the most common mistakes
people make in english
and i made it many many times and people
were like
eh because there are some grammar
mistakes that you make
there are vocabulary mistakes that you
make and there are cultural mistakes
well i wouldn't call them mistakes
necessarily but you need to understand
a culture before you can actually speak
like a native speaker
so if you struggle with making mistakes
my team at linguatrip and i have created
a workbook
that actually goes through 365 mistakes
that are very very common for non-native
speakers in english
just imagine you get this workbook and
every single day
you learn how to not make another
mistake an example of a mistake
when i came to the us i said i and
dimitri my husband we started a company
which is completely wrong
dmitri and i have started a company
because when you're talking about
yourself and somebody else
somebody else goes on the first place in
the sentence
those kinds of mistakes are in that
workbook with
real examples with very intuitive
explanations
and we have a special prize for you
today the link will be down below
check it out download it and learn how
to speak english
better every single day by tackling
one of the mistakes that a lot of
non-native speakers make in english
the link will be down below now let's
get back to the class and learn some
phrases
that would help you disagree with a
person in a polite way
are you sure that's possible and also
please pay attention to
the way you pronounce this phrase
because i say are you sure that's
possible
it's kind of you're being sarcastic when
you're
genuinely wondering are you sure that's
possible
it sounds a lot more polite the same
with
i wonder if it's true like again once
you play with your intonation there is a
completely different meaning to the
phrase
it sounds a lot better when you say i
wonder if that's true
let's check really i wonder if it works
like that
i wonder if it still works this way
interesting really
really interesting this word interesting
we keep laughing at it with our friends
because whenever whenever
we use it like i tried something i think
it was food at restaurant
and i hated it and i was like because i
wanted to be polite i said
that's an interesting flavor and
everybody started laughing because they
know
what i mean under interesting i mean
horrible when you say like
for example you see this course online
that tells you
you're gonna become rich in three days
after taking this course i'm gonna teach
you how to buy a lambo in a month
and you're like interesting really and
um
with this interesting you just say that
you know i don't believe that's gonna
work
but again watch your intonation don't be
too skeptical maybe that's the real
course where you get rich in in three
days or whatever
another way to disagree indirectly is
just to state your opinion and when you
start your phrase with well
or actually these words would indicate
that you're actually
disagreeing so people will get you
disagreeing without you actually saying
that you're disagreeing if you know what
i mean
let me give you an example let's not
invite friends and go to a restaurant
tonight instead
actually i think we'll have a better
time with our friends
you know this actually i think we should
invite them
that just indicates that you disagree
let's look at another example
titanic is the best movie of all time
well in my opinion citizen kane is
better
by the way watch citizen kane one of the
best movies i watch is classic
and everyone well a lot of people in
america i know
watched it and when you learn a language
it's important to know the context
so when you're speaking to a native
speaker and they've mentioned citizen
kane you're like oh yeah marina told me
to watch it and i watched it
and now i can support the conversation
so always always
try to watch movies that people are
talking about try to follow
different people try to learn what's
going on in the world so not only you
can sound good at english but also you
can support conversations i found it
really really important
because um okay quick quick story when i
first came to the uk
my friends were discussing all of the
stories like there was a rabid story
that everyone read when they were a kid
and i didn't read it because i grew up
in russia and we had completely
different fairy tales
and i'm just teaching emily my daughter
all of the local
stories and all of the local fairy tales
because i want her to be in context
when she goes to kindergarten when she
goes to school i want her to know
what other kids were reading when they
just lived with their families
so it's really important to be in the
context and this is why i highly highly
highly recommend watching
citizen kane when we go back to the
example when i say well
i actually think citizen keen is better
so this well
indicates that i'm disagreeing you can
also acknowledge another person's
opinion
before actually stating your opinion
because it would just help other people
understand that you're listening to them
not just disagreeing and there are some
phrases that you can use for that as
well
i see what you're saying but and then
you continue
i see what you're saying i understand
where you're coming from
but i understand where you're coming
from that's a
valid point but that is a valid point
and after this but you can introduce
your opinion
there is some truth to what you're
saying but don't you
think that if you ask me i think we
should
and then you suggest instead i think we
could god all together invite our
friends
my suggestion would be to do something
my suggestion would be an alternative
solution might be
i would recommend that we what do you
think about
having lunch outside instead another
helpful tip
is to find common ground which means
that you pick
some things that you actually agree with
in another person's statement
and then you add something else while i
agree with you
on and then you state the common ground
have you considered
blah blah blah an example would be well
i agree with you on the point that we
have to change your strategy
have you considered a less aggressive
approach
now there are some phrases that are a
little more direct and they're a little
more
like when you have to cut it because
sometimes you get to a point
where you don't want to be too polite
let's learn those phrases as well you
have to know them
i'm afraid i disagree i'm afraid i have
to disagree
i'm afraid i have to say no i'm not sure
about that i'm not so sure about that
not necessarily necessarily again those
phrases can be said with such an
intonation
and such context that they don't sound
impolite
i don't see it that way i didn't see it
that way or
you can simply say yes but yes
but let's wrap up this video with some
informal phrases that you can use to
disagree
no way oh my god no way this is not true
this isn't happening no way you must be
joking
somebody tells you you need another
handbag and you're like
you must be joking i already have 20 of
them you must be joking
you can't be serious let's go to maltese
next month
you can't be serious i'm having a baby
you can't be serious but sometimes it's
just impossible to disagree with a
person all the time and you can wrap up
your conversation with a phrase
let's agree to disagree and then you
part
still being friends without having to
fight let's agree to disagree
thank you guys so much for watching this
video up to the very end if you're not
yet subscribed to this channel
please hit subscribe and hit the like
button i'll see you very soon
in my next videos bye-bye