- Hi!
- Hi.
My webcam is broken.
– Holy shit. You are so cute!
– Thanks.
- Do you really think so?
- Yeah I do.
Can you stand up so I can see your full body?
Wow. It's like love at first sight.
But… come on. I was topless.
Yes, but.
But? You should show me the same…
Otherwise it's unfair. Please.
What? Topless?
Yeah, topless.
- I don't know…
- Come on! You are so cute.
Show me just a tiny bit, please?
Okay, wait…
(Parents arguing off screen)
Damn, you are so hot.
Can you turn around?
Spin around so I can see your whole body.
Holy shit, you're so pretty.
– Have you been modeling?
– No…
Come on, I was topless.
But… There's a difference if a girl is topless and if a boy is.
No there's not. Come on.
I just want something to dream about.
But I don't know you.
Yeah you do…
Okay, so what do you want to know?
– Nothing… I just…
– You can show me just a tiny bit… a glimpse.
Please. You are so freaking cute.
Well… Okay then. Really fast.
What, did you get all shy in front of me now?
Really really fast.
Okay… That doesn't count.
I didn't get a chance to see anything.
But…
– One more time, please…
– Okay…
What are you doing?
I just want to have something to dream about.
I want you to get on all fours… In doggystyle.
And then I want you to finger yourself.
– Or do you want your mother to see those pictures?
– Stop.
– I'm gonna send them to all your Facebook friends.
– Please stop.
I mean, what is worse?
You as a little topless whore… Ann-Christin Larsson -
That's your mother's name right?
– Just do as you're told!
– Stop!
What is worse? Doing this
or all your friends seeing the pictures?
Huh?
Stop feeling sorry for yourself.
All you want is to make guys horny.
I'm gonna count down from ten, then you'll
be in doggystyle and finger yourself. Okay?
Just stop it!
– I will send the pictures to your mother.
– Stop! I don't want to.
I'm counting. Ten. Nine. Eight. Seven.
– Stop!
– Six. Five.
– Okay!
– Okay what?
– Okay I'll do it.
– So do it, damn it! Do it.
Get in doggystyle.
Aren't you going to eat anything?
What's the matter?
Nothing…
– I can tell there's something wrong.
– It's nothing.
Okay.
– Mom?
– Yeah?
– Never mind.
– Are you sure?
Hi.
– Are you William?
– It doesn't matter who I am.
Please can't you just leave me alone?
- Get inside.
- Please (silent).
I said go inside!