When you're learning a language,
you want to learn how to
pronounce each word correctly.
In this English lesson,
I'll show you seven things that you can do
to improve your English pronunciation.
(upbeat music)
Tip number one. You should
do some warmup activities.
I'm not sure if any of you are singers,
but singers will often warm up their voice
before they sing in front of people.
These same techniques can be very good
to help you develop the right muscles
and motion of your mouth
to make English sounds.
I actually do warmups before
I do my livestream on Fridays.
I don't sing during my livestream,
but I want my voice to be ready.
You can do something like this.
You can go e-e-e, e-e-e,
oh-oh-oh, oh-oh-oh,
ah-ah-ah, ah-ah-ah.
Sorry. It sounds a little silly.
You might wanna do this
where someone can't see you.
And you might wanna practice
your consonants as well.
T-T-T, P-P-P, Th-Th-Th.
If you do this regularly,
it will help you develop the right muscles
in order to make the right English sounds.
Tip number two. Make a video
of yourself speaking English.
The best way to do this
would be to find a video
of someone else speaking English
and then record yourself
saying the same things
as the person in the video.
Then you can compare the two videos.
You can look at how the
person in the original video
makes the sounds.
You can look at how they form
the sounds with their mouth
and then you can watch your video
and see if you're making the same shapes
with your mouth when you
try to say the same things.
So tip number two,
make a video of yourself speaking English,
and it's best to find
someone else in a video
speaking English and copy
them and then compare the two.
And then try to correct how you're forming
each sound with your mouth.
Again, this might look a little silly,
but it's a very good tip.
Tip number three. Record yourself.
This might sound a little
bit like tip number two,
but I want you to only
record the audio this time.
Again, find a recording of
someone speaking English
and try to record yourself
saying the same thing.
Then listen to it and
compare it to the original.
And in this situation,
don't do it right away.
Record yourself and
listen to it the next day
or listen to it a few days later.
Have you ever noticed that
when you hear yourself
on a recording, you don't
always sound like yourself?
This can really help.
This can help you to identify the things
that you've said wrong and
it can help you correct them.
Tip number four. Act out an
English scene with a friend.
So this one of course requires a friend
and it requires that you have a script
or that you've written down
what you've heard in a TV show.
So find a scene in one
of your favorite TV shows
and write down what the two
people are saying to each other.
Then find a friend who's
also learning English
and reenact what you saw.
So you have the original recording
that you can listen to later.
You have a friend that
you can practice with
and hopefully this makes
the practice more fun.
And then you can correct each other.
It will help you to mimic an
actual English conversation.
So tip number four.
Find a friend, find a script,
or write down the words that
two people say in a TV show
and then practice it with a friend.
Tip number five. Read out loud.
I cannot stress this enough.
It is very important when
you are learning English
to take the time to read out
loud every once in a while.
When you read out loud
you don't have to think about
what you're going to say.
You already have it on
the page in front of you.
And if you're reading anyways
because you enjoy reading in English,
why not take the time
every once in a while
to read out loud?
When you read out loud,
you practice using all of the
muscles that you would use
to speak English in a normal conversation.
So whenever you're reading a book,
whenever you're reading
the news on a computer
or on your phone, take
some time to read out loud.
Tip number six. Sing along.
Out loud, like, not quietly.
Whenever you listen to an English song,
sing out loud and sing loudly.
You'll probably wanna do this
when there are no other people
around, but sing out loud.
When you sing, you use a lot more force
than when you just talk.
When you sing,
you tend to over pronounce
and overemphasize words,
and this can be a really good thing.
So find a song.
Learn the lyrics to the song.
Learn the words to the song,
and take some time to sing it out loud
every once in a while.
Maybe choose a song for the
week and plan to sing that song
out loud four or five
times as the week goes by.
So, tip number six.
Find a good song. Sing that song out loud.
Sing it with gusto.
That's an English word,
but I wonder what language
it originally came from.
It means to sing with a lot
of joy and a lot of energy.
Tip number seven, the last
tip. Practice shadowing.
I'm going to explain this technique again.
I've explained it in other videos as well.
Shadowing is when you
find an English recording.
You find a recording of someone
speaking English or a video.
You play part of it, and you hit pause,
and then you say what
the person has just said
in the video or in the recording.
You can do this with my videos.
Some people do this with my videos
on my second channel.
They'll write out what I've said
and then they will shadow
what I've said in each video.
But you don't have to use my videos.
Find any video on YouTube
where someone is speaking English clearly.
Hit play, listen.
Hit pause, say what they've
said, and then hit play again.
And keep doing that until you
get to the end of the video.
Shadowing is a great technique
for improving your English pronunciation.
Well, hey, thanks so much for
watching this English lesson
where I gave you seven tips, seven things,
that you can do to improve
your English pronunciation.
I hope they work for you.
Try at least one of
them, if not all of them
and see if your
pronunciation does improve.
Remember, if this is your first time here,
don't forget to click
that red subscribe button.
Gimme a thumbs up, leave a comment.
And again, if you have some extra time,
why don't you stick around and
watch another English lesson?
(upbeat music)