Hey there!
Welcome back to my channel and welcome If
you are new!
I am Maria, and today I'm going to help you
improve your vocabulary in a very short amount
of time.
[intro]
The goal of today’s video is to help you
see if you are speaking textbook English,
and if so, I will give you some better alternatives
used in everyday real English conversations.
Before we get on with the video, don’t forget
to subscribe to mu channel so you don’t
miss out on new lessons from me.
NOW Let’S GO!
We’ll be looking at 10 phrases that will
help you advance your English and sound more
natural in your speech.
Now, let’s get started with the first one.
1.
Textbook: " Let's meet today.
"
Native: " Let's catch up today.
We use this phrase to talk to someone who
we have not seen for some time.
Hey, what are you doing later?
Let’s catch up today!
2.
Textbook: " I'm tired.
Let’s finish working for today.
"
Native: " I'm tired.
Let’s call it a day.
"
We use this phrase when we quit work and go
home, or when we want to say that a day's
work has been completed.
It's past five o'clock so let's call it a
day.
3.
Texbook: " I'm very happy.
"
Native: " I'm over the moon.
To be over the moon is an idiomatic expression
for saying someone is feeling extremely happy
and delighted.
They’re going on vacation tomorrow and they
are over the moon!
4.
Textbook: " He might be lying, but we have
to trust him for now.
"
Native: " He might be lying but we have to
give him the benefit of the doubt.
"
If you give someone the benefit of the doubt,
you treat them as if they are telling the
truth, even though you are not sure that this
is the case.
5.
Textbook: I visit my hometown very rarely.
Native: I visit my hometown once in a blue
moon.
Once in a blue moon is an idiom expressing
something that is happening very rarely.
"Do you ever eat pork?"
B: "Only once in a blue moon.
I prefer beef."
What’s something you do once in a blue moon?
Tell me in the comments!
I’ll go first: I used to watch movies every
night, but now I do it once in a blue moon.
6.
Textbook: Can you guys help me with my homework?
Native: Can you guys pitch in with my homework?
To pitch in means to join in and help someone
with something.
7.
Textbook: I am scared to do this.
Native: I have cold feet.
To have cold feet means, to experience anxiety
right before you attempt to do something.
I was going to try bungee jumping, but I got
cold feet.
8.
Textbook I have the ideal situation—a wonderful
family and a great job.
Native: I have the best of both worlds—a
wonderful family and a great job.
If you say that someone has the best of both
worlds, you mean that they have only the benefits
of two things and none of the disadvantages.
9.
Textbook: " I'm going to get married tomorrow.
"
Native: " I'm going to tie the knot tomorrow.
To tie the knot means to get married and have
a marriage ceremony.
10.
Textbook: Basketball is not so difficult.
Native: Basketball is not rocket science.
Something that is not rocket science means
that you don’t think that something is very
difficult to do or to understand.
So, there you have it!
What did you think of this video?
Let me know your opinion in the comments!
iF you found it helpful and valuable don’t
forget to subscribe to my channel so that
you don’t miss out on my future lessons!
Until the next video, I wish you a great day
ahead, stay ZEN and I’ll see you in the
next one