If you avoid using some English grammar
tenses because you're not really sure
how to use them or why you should,
it can lead to unnecessary
grammar mistakes.
It can also make it far more difficult
to say exactly what you want to
say in English conversations. In
today's Confident English lesson,
we're going to do an in-depth
exploration of the past continuous
tense in English, also known
as the past progressive.
This means we'll review the past
continuous structure so that you use them
accurately and more importantly,
you'll learn six real-life
examples of when to
use the past continuous. What that means
is by the end of this lesson today,
you'll be a hundred percent ready to
confidently answer three questions I
have for you using the past
continuous tense in English.
But first, if you don't already know, I'm
Annmarie with Speak Confident English.
Everything I do is designed to help you
get the confidence you want for your
life and work in English.
One way I do that is with these Confident
English lessons where I share my
top fluency and
confidence-building strategies,
advanced level vocabulary and targeted
grammar lessons just like this
one today. So while you're here,
make sure you subscribe to
my Speak Confident English
channel on YouTube so you
never miss one of these
Confident English lessons.
Before we look at six specific
examples of when to use the past
continuous form,
let's focus on the structure so
that you're able to use this tense
accurately. In the positive form,
we have a subject and then the
past form of the verb to be was
or were followed by an
I N G verb. For example,
I was planning to call you,
but I lost track of time.
Then in the negative form,
once again, we have a subject.
The past form of the to be verb
- was or were - followed by
not and an I N G verb. For example,
she wasn't sleeping when you called.
She was working with her
phone on do not disturb.
In addition to making sure
the structure is accurate,
it's also important to be
careful with your word choice.
We don't use stative verbs
in the past continuous
form.
Stative verbs are used to describe
a state of mind or a state of
being. These are verbs, such
as believe, like, dislike,
hate, love, need, prefer, realize,
seem, understand or want. For example,
we would not say when I was
younger I was preferring to
drink coffee that doesn't work in
English. Instead, we would say,
when I was younger, I
preferred to drink coffee.
Stative verbs imply continuous
or ongoing action,
so the use of the past progressive form,
which can also imply continuous
or ongoing action in the past
is unnecessary. With all of that in mind,
let's get into six real-life
examples of how and when to use
the past continuous in English.
The first use is to provide
background or context when telling
stories. Of course, when you tell a story,
you are referencing the past.
You're talking about something
that already happened,
something you experienced,
and to help make a story more
interesting. You provide context,
in other words,
the background to help set the
tone of the story or to create a
mood. Doing all of this creates a
mental picture for your listener.
This is when we use the past
continuous tense for telling stories.
Let me give you an example.
Imagine you're telling someone
about a recent vacation and to
highlight just how relaxing it
was from the very first day,
you might share some background details.
What was happening the moment you
woke up that first day in telling
your vacation story, you might say,
the very first morning I woke up,
the waves were gently rolling up on shore.
The sun was just inching
up over the mountains,
warming the sun and the palm
leaves were rustling in the breeze.
It was the perfect start to my vacation.
All of those background details are in
the past continuous tense and they helped
to provide context. Let's take
a look at another example.
Think for a moment about an important
historical event you've experienced
and imagine someone asking
you, what were you doing when?
What were you doing when you
first heard the election results?
In telling that story and providing
some background details, you might say,
I was at an election party.
A group of us were chatting and the music
was blaring when they first announced
the results, there was so much noise
that we didn't hear them right away.
This example leads me to use number two.
We used the past continuous to
highlight overlapping events or
interruptions. Let's start by
talking about overlapping events.
In other words,
when two things are happening at
the same time to show that two
events are overlapping and to
indicate which ones started
first, we use the past continuous.
There are two structures we typically
use to highlight these overlapping
events.
The first one is to use the past
continuous followed by when and the
past simple form.
I was chatting with friends
when they announced the results
or we could reverse that when
they announced the results.
I was chatting with friends.
In both cases the use of the
past continuous highlights,
which of the two events started first.
The second structure we can
use is to include a specific
indication of time that
highlights something was
happening before and after. For example,
at midnight at 7:00 PM in September
by the age of 12.
Let me give you a few examples of how
we might use these indications of time.
Number one, by the age of 12,
I was playing concerts in major
cities around the country.
This tells us the statement was
true before and after that specific
indication of time. A second example,
by the time I was in my mid thirties,
I was already putting away a
significant portion of my paycheck
toward my retirement
savings, and number three,
I was cooking dinner at
7:00 PM last night. Again,
this highlights that you were
cooking dinner before and after that
period of time, and now let's
talk about interruptions.
The past,
continuous shows what was
happening when an interruption
occurred. For example,
imagine you missed an important call
from a loved one and when they finally
reach you, they want to know what was
going on. Why didn't you answer the phone?
In your response, you might say,
I was cooking in the kitchen and the
kids were watching TV at full volume.
When you called, I didn't hear
the phone. In another example,
perhaps you've had a chaotic
morning and in describing
this entire morning to a coworker,
you might include this detail.
The kids were sleeping deeply
when the alarm rang and jolted
them awake. Before we
move on to use three,
I want you to look again at those
examples with interruptions and notice
that we're using that same structure
we used with overlapping events.
We're using the past, continuous
with when and the past simple.
Use number three is to emphasize a length
of time such as all day or all afternoon.
Now, why might it be useful or
important to emphasize a length of time?
Let me illustrate with an example.
Imagine you've recently accomplished
a major milestone at work.
You and your team have just
finished an all-consuming project
and do you want to emphasize how
much time you've spent on it,
the past continuous combined with
phrases that explain the length of time
help you do this In describing this
effort to others, you might say,
we were working on this
project nonstop all year.
It's hard to believe it's finished.
In addition to using a phrase such
as all year, you could use all day,
all night, all month,
all week, all morning,
all afternoon, all evening.
You could also use for
hours, for days, for weeks,
for months, for years.
Here's another example many
parents might identify with.
Imagine being a new parent
and telling a friend just how
difficult it was to get good sleep
last night in that conversation,
you might say it was a terrible night.
She was crying all night
and we hardly slept.
The fourth use of the past continuous
tenses on this list today is to discuss
past habits using words such as always,
and usually now you might
be thinking Annemarie,
I thought we used the present simple
to talk about habits, and you're right,
we do. If there is a habit I currently
have, I would use the present simple.
For example, I always read before bed,
but what if a habit is no longer true?
Perhaps you've broken a bad habit
or maybe you grew out of one.
This is where the past
continuous is helpful.
It tells us about a past
habit that is no longer true.
To do this,
we use the past continuous form
combined with adverbs and adverb.
Phrases that describe
frequency such as always,
constantly, usually, rarely, all the time,
the entire time. For example,
imagine you're reminiscing about
your first year in your current
job. While you reflect on
that time, you might say,
during my first year I was
constantly making mistakes.
There was so much to learn.
You could also use the past continuous
tense combined with an indication of
frequency to describe
some annoying past habits.
For example, in describing where
you used to live, you might say,
the entire time we lived
in that neighborhood,
our neighbors were constantly
yelling and partying every other
night. In the end,
we decide to sell the house and move
to a more peaceful neighborhood.
Our fifth use of the past continuous
form is in making a polite
request using the structure.
I was wondering if in
using this highly polite,
indirect way of making a request,
we're using the past continuous form.
We tend to use this structure
when we want to be overly polite
because we're worried someone
will say no. For example,
if you're asking a friend
for a favor and you say,
I was wondering if we could
borrow your truck for our move,
or if you're inviting a coworker to
your house for the very first time,
you might say,
I was wondering if you're
free this weekend we're
having a few friends over for
a backyard barbecue. We'd
love for you to join us.
You can also use this structure
without the word if to ask
indirect questions.
This is useful when you're not
sure if a question is appropriate.
For example, I was wondering
what you're doing this weekend.
A direct way of asking that question
is, what are you doing this weekend?
Another example is we were wondering
when you'll have a decision,
A direct way of asking that is simply
when will you have a decision? Now,
as I said, this structure
can be a very polite,
indirect way of making requests,
but it's important not to overuse it.
This structure of I was
wondering if is considered
vague language,
vague language can be difficult to
understand and it can make your meaning
less clear.
The last use of the past continuous
form on this list today is to indicate
a change of mind.
Have you ever made a plan and then
changed your mind at the last minute?
Of course you have. We've all done that.
The past continuous helps to
identify what our original plan was
and what we decided in
the end. For example,
imagine you made plans to move
to another city at some point in
time. In the past,
originally you were thinking
of moving to one specific city,
but in the end you changed your mind
and decided to move somewhere else.
In talking through that
process, you could say,
I was planning to move to
Washington DC originally,
but in the end I decided to
move to New York. Similarly,
let's say that you're talking to
someone about your upcoming plans for a
vacation.
In the process of planning the
cost of airline tickets and long
delays at airports changed
your original plans,
you might tell your friend,
we were originally planning to go back
to Europe because we haven't been in
years,
but the cost of airline tickets and
the long delays changed our minds.
We decided we'll go
somewhere closer to home.
Now that you have these six
clear uses of the past continuous
form in English, it's time to practice.
I have three questions for you.
I want you to answer these three
questions using the past continuous
question. Number one, think
about your last vacation.
What was the first day like?
Share some contextual or background
details about your vacation.
Question number two,
what was a past habit that
you broke or grew out of?
You can use a sentence structure
such as when I was a kid.
I constantly, I always, I usually,
and then continue with the past continuous
form. And then question number three,
tell me about a time when
you changed your mind.
What was your original plan and what
did you decide? In the end, as always,
you can share your answers to those
questions with me in the comments below.
If you found this lesson helpful to you,
I would love to know and you can
tell me in one super simple way.
Give this lesson a thumbs up here
on YouTube and while you're at it,
don't forget to subscribe so you never
miss my future Confident English lessons.
Thank you so much for joining me today
and I look forward to seeing you next
time.