In this one hour English lesson, you are going to
learn lots of advanced English grammar, vocabulary
and sentence structure. But you're going to do it
by completing tests. So you're going to complete
different tests throughout this lesson to test
your knowledge and then improve your knowledge
at the same time. Because this is a long lesson,
what I've done is I've divided it into five short
sections. So we will complete one section you'll
test your knowledge you'll learn lots and then
we'll move on to the next session. And you can
come back and complete these times and review
the lesson materials at any time. Welcome back to
JForrestEnglish training. Of course I'm Jennifer
and this is your place to become a fluent,
confident English speaker. Now let's get started.
Here's how the test is going to work you're
going to see a question and you'll see four
options you have to decide which option best
completes the sentence. I'll show you the
question for only five seconds, which isn't
a long time. So feel free to hit pause,
complete the question and then hit play and I'll
explain the answer. Are you ready? All right,
let's get started with question one.
To Text Sue. It's her birthday today.
The correct answer is C. Don't forget to text
Sue. It's her birthday today. The key word in
this question is to which is the infinitive
to text. Now there's only one possible option
in the choices below where you can have the
infinitive and then see don't forget to test
now if this question didn't have to, and it was
just the base verb well, then a B and D would be
correct and C would be incorrect question
to Mary with jogging today. Of the rain.
The correct answer is C in spite of the rain
and that's your key word here of in spite of
and despite have the same meaning but you
don't say despite of you just say despite
if you want to learn more about this I have
a full lesson explaining this. I'll leave the
link in the description below. Question three.
I think I'm allergic to your cat. I can't stop.
The correct answer is B sneezing. Now this is
a tricky one because you can have grammatically
stop plus infinitive stop to sneeze and you
can help stop plus gerund stop sneezing,
but the meaning is different. When we're
talking about no longer doing an action,
we use stop plus Geron and based on the context
of the question. We're talking about no longer
doing an action so we need the gerund if you want
to learn more about this, I'll leave a link in
the description below. Question four. If you don't
know the meaning of a word you can in a dictionary
and the answer is C. You can look it up in
the dictionary. Now this one is a vocabulary
question because you need to understand what
these expressions mean. To look something up
is another way to say to search for or to find
that specific information. Now we use this all
the time because every time you Google,
you're looking up information. So I use
this expression literally every single day.
Hey, what's up this restaurant closed? Table
girl? I don't know if you look it up. Oh, we
need to look it up. We shouldn't look that up.
You'll use this every single day. Question
five. My doctor me I should exercise more
and the answer is a my doctor told
me I should exercise more. Now this
is one that students confuse a lot. I hear
students say told to me I told to her. No,
that doesn't work grammatically. We don't want
to somewhat get rid of that too. I told her I
told you she told me so that's what we need.
and also I hear students they say me she said
me to exercise more. No we don't want me after
said she said I should exercise more we want
applause after said. if you want to learn more
about this I have a full video explaining it.
you can find the link in the description below.
Questions fit my boss me to her dinner party.
And the answer is C. invited me to her dinner
party. Now this one is both a vocabulary
question because the only logical choice is
invite. But it's also because of sentence
structure. We could change the sentence
structure and make it work. For example,
my boss suggested that I come to her dinner
party, we could say that but I have to completely
change the sentence structure. So all the options
could work. If we change the sentence structure,
the only logical choice with the sentence
structure is the My boss invited me because
you invite someone to something my boss invited
me to the movies to her house to the restaurant,
a specific location now if you want to
learn more about suggested because a
lot of students they suggested me, which is
incorrect. I'll leave a link to a video on
that topic in the description below. Question
seven. Sorry, I didn't quite what you said.
And the answer is, hey, sorry, I didn't quite
catch what you said. This is an expression to
cat. Something in this context is the exact same
as here. I didn't hear what you said. But notice
option D is in the past four. And that doesn't
work grammatically. So it has the same meaning
but it's the wrong verb tense. So a cat is
exactly the same. Now this is an expression
you can use all the time, especially since you've
probably struggled to understand native speakers.
So when somebody says something to you, and
you don't quite catch it, you can say sorry,
I didn't catch that. I didn't catch that. I
didn't quite catch that. Wait. It's just a word
would add to me a little bit. I didn't quite catch
that. So add that to your vocabulary. You'll use
it all the time. Question Eight. I don't sleep
in now, but I sleep in until noon on weekends.
And the answer is C I used to I used to sleep
in on weekends. Now notice all the options
are slightly different sentence structures. And
they're all grammatically correct if you use the
correct meaning, but for here, we're talking about
an action that used to take place in the past. So
an action you routinely did in the past, but you
no longer do now. And for that we need youth with
a D you don't hear it in pronunciation, but it's
there in spelling. I used to work at the bank,
but now I work at the mall. So I'm routine action
in the past but you will no longer do it now,
students confuse this sentence structure all the
time. I have a detailed lesson on this. You'll
find a link in the description below. Question
Nine. I don't need help but thanks. And the answer
is but thanks for offering thanks for offering
thanks for offering. This is one that I hear a lot
of mistakes with as well. Now notice here I have
things for after four because four is preposition
you must use the gerund verb for offering thanks
for and then you can use a gerund verb or you can
use a noun. Thanks for your help. Thanks for
your offer your offer. Thanks for offering.
And your final question number 10. The film
sounded interesting but it to be really boring.
And the answer is C. It turns out to be really
boring. This is a vocabulary question because
you need to understand what these expressions
mean we use to turn out when we're talking
about the end result of something. So let's
say you're trying a new recipe and it's for
chocolate chip cookies. You've never made this
recipe before. Your friend could say how did the
recipe turn out? How did the cookies turn out?
Your friends is asking about the end result.
Basically your friends is asking were they
good? Were they bad? How did the recipe turn
out? And you have a bite? Oh, it was awesome.
They were delicious. The best chocolate chip
cookies I've ever had. And in this context,
they're talking about the movies end result.
How did the movie turn out? It was really
boring. It turned out to be really boring.
So how did you do with the quiz? Put your score
in the comments below. And if you learn some new
expressions or new sentence structure, make sure
you practice your new expressions or sentence
structure in the comments below as well so you
get really comfortable and competent with them.
So here's what the test will work. I'll
show you the question and you'll see the
multiple options. Now I'll only show
it for a few seconds. So hit pause,
take as much time as you need and when you're
ready for the answer hit play. I'll share the
answer and I'll also explain why the answer
is correct. Are you ready? Let's get started
with question number one. There are about
20 or so people waiting in the office.
And the answer is so there were about 20 or so
people waiting in the office. Now this is just
an expression we use or so to me approximately
around there are around 20 People approximately 20
people but notice the word order there are 20 or
so people compared to there are approximately 20
people so the sentence structure is a little bit
different. But this is a great casual expression
to have in your vocabulary. I have 10 or so
emails to reply to. I have approximately 10
emails to reply to question two there was
a problem with the cell phone but I it now
I have fixed it now. I fixed it. Now we need
the present perfect verb tense because we're
talking about a past action that's complete. The
cell phone is fixed right now. So the action is
complete. But there was a result in the present.
We know about it because of the keyword now but
I've fixed it now. Now what we're talking about
a past action with a result in the present the
best choice is the present perfect if you want to
learn more about the past simple and the present
perfect. I made a video on this. You'll find the
link in the description below. Question three,
I think going to the post this weekend. Be a good
idea. And the answer is would be a good idea. What
is the best choice because we're talking about a
hypothetical, it would be a good idea to go to the
coast. If you change the word order. You can see
that it would be awkward and unnatural to say it
should be it should be a good idea to go to the
coast may have should with recommendations or
advice you should go to the polls this weekend.
I'm recommending that to you. I'm advising you,
but what we're just talking about a hypothetical
would is the best choice question for the thing.
Once a film gets a bad review,
it's hard for it to do well.
The thing is, the thing is, this is an expression
we use in English we use it before we introduce
an idea The thing is I don't think he should
go to the coast this weekend. So it's just
an expression that we use and based on the
options is is the only possible choice to
complete this expression. Question five I some
old drawings when I was cleaning out my closet.
I came across I came across some old drawings.
The phrasal verb to come across something is
used when you find something accidentally
I wasn't looking for the drawings. I found
them accidentally oh wow, look at these
drawings. I haven't seen them in years.
I had no idea they were here. Based
on the context the only expression
that made sense is came across but number six
she managed to play tennis despite a sore arm
and the answer is despite how about a
sore arm after despite you need a gerund
verb because despite is a preposition
despite having a sore arm. Number seven
longer do we need to file that form? And the
answer is no longer No longer do we need to file
that form. This is an alternative structure to
saying we don't need to file that form any longer.
If you use the expression we don't need
to you made the choice any longer because
we don't use double negatives in English.
So you couldn't say we don't need to file
that form no longer that doesn't work. But
if we're starting with no longer do we need
because do we need is a positive you're making
it negative with the choice no. This is simply
an alternative sentence structure. To be honest,
the more popular or common sentence structure
is we don't need to file that form any longer.
Number eight, they are to have arrived already.
And the answer is they are
supposed to have arrived already.
The expression is to be supposed to they are
supposed to have arrived already. Based on
the sentence structure the only possible choice
is supposed to a lot of students make mistakes
with the expression supposed to I made a lesson on
this topic. I'll leave the link in the description
below. But number nine by the time they at
the concert the tickets were already sold out.
And the answer is by the time they turned
up at the concert when a person turns out
at or to a location it means they arrive
at that location. So if you're at a party,
you could ask someone when's Julie supposed to
turn up when she's supposed to arrive? It's simply
a phrasal verb and based on the options, this is
the only expression that makes sense. Number 10.
I was able to get to the top of the mountain
and the answer is as I am, this is a
useful way to describe yourself or to
describe a situation beautiful as it was I
didn't take a picture as smart as he is he
didn't pass the test number 11 I'm 100%
certain that everything okay in the end
and the answer is I'm 100% certain that everything
will be okay. In the end we use the future symbol
will be when we're making predictions about
the future. Now even though I say 100% certain
it's still making a prediction because I don't
control the future the outcome of the future is
still unknown and I'm making a prediction
of the future number 12 as a cab driver I
but I'd love a bigger paycheck. And the answer
is I get by I get by but I love a bigger paycheck
by putting in a paycheck. I know we're talking
about money and the expression that by in terms
of finances we use that when you're just able to
pay for everything you need, but you don't have
very much leftover I get by I get by question
13 I don't want to spend the weekend with her.
And the answer is as much as much as I enjoy
her company. This is an expression and it's
the only grammatically correct choice and
the best choice based on the options much
as I enjoy her company. Now notice once I enjoy
her company, that's a positive but then the next
part of the sentence is a negative. I don't want
to spend the weekend with her. So this is a great
transition sentence that you can use. Much as
I enjoy studying English. I don't want to spend
my whole weekend doing it. Number 14 The fact of
the is our company has to increase its revenue.
And the answer is the fact of the matter
is, this is an expression the fact of the
matter based on the options this is the best
word choice to complete this expression. The
fact of the matter is and then you state your
applause The fact of the matter is I need to
improve my English. And finally question
15 The company has doubled its revenue.
It still has a lot of problems to overcome.
And the answer is however it still
has a lot of problems to overcome.
All of these options are transition words. The
only transition word that's used for a contrast
is however, and notice this is a contrast
because idea one the company has doubled this
revenue that's positive but then idea two there
are still problems to overcome. What's negative,
right so we're dealing with a contrasting
situation. However, if you want to learn
more about transition words, you can look in the
description for a link I have a separate video
so how to do on this advanced vocabulary test.
Make sure you share your score in the comments
below and if you got any wrong, just do some
practice so you feel more comfortable with them.
Are you ready to see if you know these 50
Confusing English words. So here's how this
video is going to work. I'm going to show you
a sentence and you're going to have two options
and you have to define which option correctly
completes the sentence. Now I'll only show the
sentence for a couple of seconds. So make sure
you hit pause, take your time to read it to
answer it and then hit play and I'll show you
the answer and I'll explain why the answer is
correct. Are you ready to go? Number one, there
were people at the party than I had expected.
The answer is fewer. There were fewer people at
the party than I had expected. And the reason
is we use fewer with countable nouns. You
can count how many people there are, but we
use less with uncountable nouns. So I could say
there was less rain you can't count rain. There
was less rain this year compared to last year.
Number two, I've jumped in the a big project
and the answer is mixed. Mixed. This is a tricky
one simply because of pronunciation when you hear
this in spoken English, I'm in the midst of a
big project. It's easy to confuse this with mist.
And to be in the midst of something is
simply to be in the middle of something.
So I'm in the middle of a big project number
three Wow not sure it's really your hair.
And the answer is complement with an E. These two
words sound exactly the same in pronunciation.
It's spelling that is different, but they have
different meanings complement in this example
is when one thing your shirt combined really well
with another thing your hair. Compliment with an
eye is when you say something nice to someone.
I love your shirt. Thanks for the compliment.
If you want to learn more about compliment and
compliment you can look in the description for
a link on a video on that topic. Number
four that movie had quite an eye on me.
The answer is it had quite an effect on me. The
pronunciation is very similar effect effect.
There's a slight difference. But the spelling is
important because offense is a verb and effect
is a noun and we need a now you know that because
there's an article in the sentence with the verb
I can say that movie affected me. If you want to
learn more about effects and effects you can look
in the description for a link on that. Number
five quizzes are a great way to your skills
to home more skills. Again similar pronunciation
but the correct choice is home. This is an
expression to home one skilled this is simply to
improve one's skills. Number six I didn't know
at the party. I didn't know anybody at the party
didn't is negative. In the English language. We
do not like double negatives you can only use one
negative in a a clause. And since I already have a
didn't I can't use the negative Nobody, I have to
use anybody. Number seven. I don't like carrots.
I don't like carrot either. Now this is the same
as number six because I don't don't is a negative.
Neither is also a negative so we can't use it.
We want either I don't like carrots either. To
use neither I could say you don't like carrots.
Neither do I neither do I. If you want to learn
more about either and Deezer you can look in
the description for a video I created on this.
And number eight, she has more she needs. She has
more than she needs similar in pronunciation. That
then but they're two totally different words than
we use in comparisons. More than less than fewer
than comparison. Then is an adverb. It's used
in time references, first all eat lunch, then
I'll go for a walk number nine joining Social Club
is for all purposes, the solution to loneliness.
For all intents and purposes, this is an
expression in English for all intents and
purposes. This simply means in almost every
situation in virtually every situation,
but when you say this at a natural pace for all
intensive purposes, for all intents and purposes,
it sounds like intensive. Intensive is a word that
people are very familiar with intense and is not
something that people are familiar with, but the
correct expression is intents and purposes. This
is a very useful business or academic expression
isn't really used in casual conversation too much.
Number 10. We can discuss this after the
meeting. We can discuss this further after
the meeting further and further. Both mean more.
We can discuss this more in more detail after the
meeting we use further when we're talking about
figurative and we use farther when we're talking
about literal. For example, we need to walk
farther we literally need to walk more we need
to walk farther to see the waterfall. If you want
to learn more about this look in the description
for a link on a separate video number 11. You can
down here you can lie down here, lay and lie they
have the same meaning the lay is transitive it
means an object. For example, lay the baby down
here lay the blanket down here you lay something.
A lie is intransitive. So there's no object lying
down here. Lie yourself down here. Lie down
here. Number 12. That sweater is too for you.
That sweater is to leash for you. This one is
confusing because of the spelling do I need one
or two? It's easy to forget. Lose with one oh
is the opposite of When did you lose the game?
Did you win the game? Did you lose the game? Lose
with two O's when we're talking about clothing is
when it doesn't fit closely to your body. So
this shirt I'm wearing is not loose. It fits
closely to my body but this sweater for example
is loose number 13. We should worked harder
we should have worked harder. Now this is
a mistake that many native speakers make
because in spoken English we take have which is
the grammatically correct choice but we reduce
it we say it quickly and it sounds like oh
you should have you should have you should
have worked harder. So sometimes need speakers
forget that it's actually have a knot oh because
that's what it sounds like in spoken English.
So in spoken English you can absolutely say
you should have you should have worked harder
but in written English just remember that the
correct choice is have number 14 I shouldn't have
to the party. I shouldn't have gone to the party.
Our verb here is dope. The past simple is wimps
and the past participle is gone. This structure
requires the past participle the third form
of the verb. Yesterday I went to the party.
I've gone to three parties this month. And
finally number 15 Do you trust the most?
Do you trust the most? Who at home it can be very
tricky for students and native speakers to know
the difference. Just ask yourself do you need
she or her? Do you mean a subject or an object?
she or her he or him? I trust her the most we
need an object not a subject. So you use home
who is your friend? She is my friend.
In this case. We need a subject so we
use who so how to deal with this quiz.
Share your score in the comments below.
So here's how this question will work. I'll show
you a question and there'll be a blank and you
have to decide which option which verb tense
best completes the sentence now I'll only show
the question for a few seconds. So hit pause take
as much time as you need. And when you're ready,
hit play and I'll share the correct answer
and I'll explain why that answer is correct.
Are you ready? Let's get started.
Question one, my flight at 9am tomorrow
and the answer is my client sees at 9am
Tomorrow. Now both B and C are future
verbs and we need a future verb because
we have the key word tomorrow so I know
we're in the future. But we use the present
simple in the future on one specific occasion
and not with timetable events with scheduled
events. So transportation runs on a schedule,
you get a ticket and it tells you the time. We can
consider that a scheduled event. If you're going
to a party, a wedding a meeting in the future
and there's a scheduled event you can simply say
my meeting starts at two o'clock next Tuesday.
Question two she two books so far this year.
And the answer is she has written two books
so far this year. Your key word here is this
year. This year is still in progress if
it weren't complete, I'd say last year
she's written two books so far this
year. So which bird tent Am I using?
The Present Perfect has written we use the present
perfect for actions that started in the past but
are still in progress. So the books she has
written those are complete. Those two books
are sitting on her shelf, but it's possible
for her to write more books because the year
is still in progress the present perfect
number three, your eyes are red and puffy.
And the answer is how have you been crying?
Have you been crying? The verb tense here
is the present perfect continuous. We need a
continuous verb in this context because the
focus is on that action. The focus is not
on the result. The focus is on the action
of crying. I want to emphasize the action
crying How do you cry the present perfect.
That sounds awkward because there's no focus on
the action question for if I were you, I'd quit.
And the answer is if I were you, if I were
you now having i and we're side by side may
sound unnatural to you because the past form
of the verb to be with the subject I is was of
course right. I was tired. I was angry. You
were tired. You were angry. She was tired.
They were tired. But this isn't in the past
simple. This is in the subjunctive and the
conjugation for the subjunctive verb is were for
all subjects. I, you, he she, it, we they were.
Now why does the question need the subjunctive?
Because it's hypothetical. I'm not you. That's a
hypothetical situation. If I were you, but I'm not
you. I mean, right. If I were younger, if I were
older, if I were taller, if I were shorter, those
are all hypothetical situations. Number five a day
at the bank sent 2009.
And the answer is Dave has been working at the
bank since 2009. Now where are you saying the
present perfect continuous because the action
started in the past and continues on till now.
When did they start working at the bank? Dave
started working at the bank in 2009. Where does
they work now today at the bank, right so actually
that started in the past and continues until now.
Question sits Carmen has a hair appointment
tomorrow, Carmen, her hair cut tomorrow.
And the answer is Carmen
getting her hair cut tomorrow.
Now the first sentence is just to provide
context. So you know there's a scheduled
event. And that's important because we use the
present continuous, not the future simple. We use
the present continuous when we're talking about
a scheduled event in the future. Let's say I have
a plane ticket to go to Australia. In five years,
even though it's five years, a lot of time away is
still a scheduled event. So I would say I'm going
present continuous. I'm going to Australia in five
years because it's a scheduled event. Question
seven sound me well, to Paris at least five times?
And the answer is Samuel how you gone to Paris
at least five times. Now there's no indication
of time. In this example. There was no past
reference last year last month, and there's
no future reference either. So I know we're just
talking about in general, and we use the present
perfect has gone we use the present perfect to
talk about life experience, the things we have
done or haven't done in our life. And the reason
is because our life is unfinished. Our life is in
progress. It started in the past and it continues
until now. So while we're alive and still living,
we use the present perfect to talk about our
life experience. Question Eight, I think Sarah,
a promotion next year. And the answer is I
think Sarah will get a promotion next year.
So my keyword here is next year so I know I'm in
the future. And notice the other keyword I think I
think we use the Future Simple to make predictions
about the future. I think Sarah I don't know this
100% It's a prediction. I think Sara will get
a promotion next year. Number nine the client.
By the time I checked my messages.
The client Hi Paul, by the time I checked my
messages, this is a past perfect. The past perfect
is used to talk about a past action, a completed
past action that takes place before another past
action. So on our timeline, we have two past
events. The client called I checked my messages.
Now we use the past perfect for both the first
pass option which is the older action, and we use
the past simple for the second pass action, which
is the newer action on our timeline. The client
had called by the time I checked my messages
and finally questions and I can't believe they
their baby by the time we get there. And
the answer is, I can't believe they will
have had their baby by the time we get there.
Which vertex is this? The future perfect. We
don't use the future. Perfect too often, but it's
still an important verb tense. We use the future
perfect to talk about a completed action in the
future. So let's say right now it's summer 2022
And the baby is due in the fall 2022. So right now
in summer, its future action, right. But let's say
I'm traveling to visit this couple in the winter
of 2022. So I'm going to take my timeline from
now and I'm going to change the timeline to
winter 2022 and by winter 2022 The baby will
have been born so that action all go into future
action. Now when I change the timeline to winter
2022 The action will actually be in the past. So
did you know all of these verb tenses make sure
you share your score in the comments below and do
some example sentences practicing the verb tenses
that you found most difficult maybe that future
perfect so you can do that in the comments below.
Are you ready to add the top 10 phrasal verbs to
your vocabulary? Now make sure you watch right
until the end because I'm going to sleep with
you to see how well you know how to use these
phrasal verbs. Phrasal verb number one to add up.
We use this phrasal verb to say that something
seems reasonable or likely and that something is
usually a story, an explanation or a reason. So
let's say your coworker took a week off of work
because she had to care for her sick mother.
But then she comes back to the office a week
later and she's really tanned and it's winter.
You might say something doesn't add up. Her story
doesn't seem reasonable. Or likely something
doesn't add up if she was taking care of her sick
mother while fishing habitat. I bet she took the
week off to go to the beach to go on vacation
to beat down. This is a very simple but useful
phrasal verb. We use this phrasal verb only with
the sun when the sun is shining very strongly.
So if you're sitting on a patio, and it's sunny
outside and it's really really hot, you can say
Wow, it's really beating down it being the sun. If
you say it, you don't have to define the subject
and now as the sun because we always use this
phrasal verb with the sun so it's not necessary
and the context of sitting on a patio on a sunny
day is all unique. So it's really meeting down.
Now you can use an object and say us it's really
beating down on us noticed I have to add an extra
preposition ON beat down on someone or something.
You can use a something you might say you should
move your laptop. The sun is really beating down
on it on your laptop. And that's not very good for
your electronics right so you should put your
laptop in the shade number three to tidy up.
This is when you organize or arrange things in the
right place. So you can take a bedroom and office
a kitchen any individual room or you can take an
entire house even and you might say this weekend,
I need to tidy up or this weekend I need to tidy
my office up. So you're going to go in your office
and you're going to put all this things the
objects in the right place. So this is a very
useful phrasal verb number four to talk down to.
When you talk down to someone you talk to them
in a way that makes them feel less intelligent
than you or less important venue. So this is
a negative phrasal verb. This often happens with
adults and children, adults and teenagers parents
and teenagers, a teenager might complain or a
young adult might complain that their parents
always talk down to them. They talk to them in a
way that makes them feel less intelligent or less
important. This often happens in the workplace,
especially with someone in a higher position and
someone in a lower position that someone in a
higher position might talk down to that person
even though that person has a lot more experience
than them. And there's no reason to do that. So
this is used in a negative way but they commonly
happen so you'll hear this phrasal verb a lot
when people are complaining about other people.
Number five to sum up this means to summarize the
main points. We commonly use this phrasal verb
when you're ending a presentation or a speech
in your conclusion when you want to summarize so
at the end of your presentation, you might say
to sum up if we want to increase our profits, we
need to diversify our product line so that's the
main point of your presentation you elaborated on
that main point and now you're saying to sum up
to summarize so this is an excellent phrasal verb
to add to your business vocabulary to sound very
advanced, professional and natural numbers fix
to joke around when you joke around it means what
you're saying shouldn't be taken seriously. You're
just joking. You're just being light hearted.
You're just having fun. But we commonly use this
to reassure someone. So you might say, Oh, don't
get mad. I was just joking around. So maybe you're
making comments about someone in a light hearted
way, but they took it seriously and you reassure
them Don't get mad. I was just joking around.
Now sometimes you might tell someone you shouldn't
joke around about job loss. So maybe somebody is
making comments about other people losing their
jobs and they're not taking it very seriously. But
you want that person to note that's inappropriate.
That's a serious topic you shouldn't joke around
about job loss is affected many people number
seven to eat out. This simply means to eat in
a restaurant. So rather than saying last
night I went to a restaurant for dinner,
we just simply say last night I ate out last
night I ate out which means I ate in a restaurant
this morning. I ate out before work. So because
it's morning obviously we're talking about
breakfast so you can use it for any meal of the
day. So you might suggest to your friends if you
want to save money, you should stop eating out you
should stop eating out all the time. So you should
stop eating in restaurants because of course
it's more expensive. So this is an excellent
phrasal verb to add to your daily vocabulary to
sound like a native English speaker number eight
to drum up. Now when you drum something up,
it means you increase support or interest in
someone or something. So let's say your company
introduced a new product, but sales are lower
than expected. Your boss might suggest everybody
needs to brainstorm ways to drum up interest so to
increase interest to drum up sales to increase
sales. So if you put drum up before the noun,
it just means increase. Let's drum up
support increase support drum up enthusiasm,
increase enthusiasm. Number nine to speak
up. When you speak up. It means you speak
more loudly. So right now I'm talking at this
volume. But maybe you could say, Jennifer,
I'm having a hard time hearing you. Can you speak
up? Can you increase the volume of your voice? And
I'll say sure I can speak up and then I'll speak
more loudly. So this is an excellent phrasal
verb for a language learner because often you
don't understand someone the first time and part
of the problem might be that they're speaking
too quietly. So you can say Can you speak up?
Can you please speak up? Or do you mind speaking
up and then the other person will speak more
loudly. Number 10. To work out a problem or a
situation this means that the problem or situation
becomes better it improves. So let's say you're
having a conflict with your boss, your coworker
might say don't worry, I'm sure you'll work it
out. Work it out. The it being the situation,
the problem the complex, I'm sure you'll work it
out. I'm sure it will improve. I'm sure it will
become better. We also use this with problems in
general not specific to complex. So let's say you
lost a lot of money in the stock market. That's a
problem. But your friend can say oh, don't worry,
I'm sure it will work out. So in this situation
that you lost a lot of money. I'm sure it will
all work out in the end. So that is a very
common expression that native speakers use
to reassure someone that a situation or problem
or complex will improve I'm sure it will all
work out in the end. Now you have 10 new phrasal
verbs added to your vocabulary to sound fluids
advanced and natural English. Awesome. John, are
you ready for your quiz? Here are your questions
hit pause and take as much time as you need and
when you're ready, hit play to see the answers.
So how did you do with that quiz? Let's
find out here are the answers. Hit pause
compare the answers to your own and
whenever you're ready, hit play.
Alright, so what was your score out of 10? Make
sure you share your score in the comments below
and if you got any wrong don't worry that just
means you're learning and just keep practicing.
Do some example sentences below share your score
and do some example sentences with your favorite
phrasal verbs from this lesson to help you
remember that amazing job with this lesson.
Think of all the grammar all the vocabulary, all
the sentence structure everything you learned in
this lesson. Now of course you need to repeat
these concepts we'll come back and review this
lesson anytime and practice some of your new
grammar and vocabulary and sentence structure in
the comments below. And if you found this video
helpful, please hit the like button, share it
with your friends and of course subscribe. And
before you go make sure you head on over to my
website JForrestEnglish.com and download your
free speaking guide. In this guide, I share
six tips on how to speak English fluently and
confidently. And until next time, happy studying.