Hi there.
Today, let's talk about
'Charity at Christmas'.
I'll explain the vocabulary as well  here.
Let's talk about 'Charity at
Christmas' and something that's
more of a social issue in the UK.
One of the things that people in the UK
sometimes do at Christmas, they volunteer.
Or they make charitable
donations, donations to charity.
The idea is that even with our cost of
living crisis, most of us are warm and
comfortable and have enough to eat.
So it's a time to think of
people for whom this isn't true.
Time to think about people
who don't have those things.
Christmas is often seen as a time
where people give something back.
They do something to make a
difference, a positive difference
in other people's lives.
So, which charities do people in the
UK think of particularly at Christmas?
Listen to this podcast to find out!
One of the issues that's
foremost in people's minds around
Christmas time is homelessness.
' Homeless', H O M E L E S S is an
adjective, and that's used to describe
someone who doesn't have a home.
And 'homelessness'?
So H O M E L E S S N E S S.
That's just the noun associated with this.
So we would say 'Homelessness
is a problem in the UK'.
If you haven't visited the UK, you
might think, 'Well, it's a rich country.
Why are there homeless people?' You
may not be aware that homelessness
is a problem in the UK - but it is.
There are lots of homeless people in
London, or we might say 'homelessness
is a big problem in a city like London'.
So one of the things that people often
do at Christmas is they volunteer
to work for a couple of days at a
homeless organisation or charity.
Vocabulary here?
The word 'charity', C H A R I T Y.
Well, it's an idea, a concept.
It means 'giving, being generous,
being helpful, usually to people
less fortunate than yourself'.
That's the idea of 'charity'.
But we also  use that noun  as a word for
organisations  that do charitable work.
So, examples that you've probably heard
of would be Oxfam, the Red Cross, or
the WWF, the Worldwide Fund for Nature.
They're 'charities' or
'charitable organisations'.
The noun 'volunteer', V O L U N T E E R.
And the verb 'to volunteer', same
spelling - it means you 'offer your
time, your skills, your energy, and
you agree to work for free to help
towards a particular goal or purpose'.
One of the things that people in the
UK sometimes do around Christmas, they
volunteer for the homeless shelters.
The word 'shelter', S H E L T E R.
You might talk about 'an animal shelter'
in a field or a 'bus shelter' on a
street where you're protected from
the rain while you wait for your bus.
We might also use it in the context
of a 'bomb shelter' as well, where
you're protected safe from bombs.
So 'to shelter' means to find
somewhere safe and a bit protected.
Some statistics on homelessness?
These are from the Ashley Foundation,
which is a homeless charity that
operates in some northern towns,
Blackpool, Blackburn, and Sunderland.
The Ashley Foundation, they estimate
that in the UK there are around
9,000 people  who 'sleep rough'.
'Rough sleeping' is
another term that we use.
That means they're living on the streets.
They're sleeping without
being in a bed or a building.
They're perhaps in a doorway somewhere.
That's 'rough sleeping'.
Just thinking a moment
about the weather in the UK.
I know that there are plenty of places
that are colder than the UK, but right
now the range of temperatures for today?
So it's cold outside,  minus four degrees
centigrade to plus two degrees centigrade.
Not great, if you're outdoors, you
don't have much to eat and you don't
have anywhere where you can get warm.
And you may not actually see
homeless people in the UK.
Often  what they'll do is ride on
buses or on trains for the day.
They get a seat and at
least it's warm on there.
That's better than being outside all day.
But many homeless people also sleep
in tents pitched on pavements.
That figure of 9,000 is the
estimate of the Ashley Foundation
for the number of 'rough sleepers'
last Christmas, Christmas 2021.
They think that this year the
number will be somewhat higher.
The Ashley Foundation also quotes research
done by Heriot-Watt University in the UK.
This research says that homeless
people are 17 times more likely to be
physically attacked on the street than
somebody that has a home to go to.
Homeless people are very
vulnerable health-wise.
Being out in the cold, rough sleeping,
not attending to their healthcare needs.
This is all part of it.
It's generally not good for your physical
health, and it tends to mean that homeless
people have shorter life expectancy.
They can't expect to live as
long as the rest of us do.
Homeless people are also vulnerable
mental health wise - that means 'the
health of your mind, your psychology'.
It's not good for you psychologically
to live on the street.
It feels fairly hopeless and quite
often it is mental health problems that
cause people or are part of the cause of
people being homeless in the first place.
But of course, having nowhere to
live doesn't help your mental health.
As I said, you might be really
surprised to find that a country like
the UK has a big homelessness problem.
How and why does it happen?
Often it's a series of difficulties.
Someone might lose their job
or a relationship might end.
They may find themselves unable
to pay the rent or their mortgage
anymore, so they may lose their house.
Perhaps they sleep on a friend's sofa
for a while, but after a bit this isn't
a good arrangement anymore and bit by
bit, they move towards homelessness
- eventually they end up homeless.
Often people who're homeless have
drug or alcohol addiction problems.
Quite commonly, homeless people have lost
the support of their family and friends.
It might be teenagers,  young people
who have run away from home because it's
not a good environment there for them.
They sometimes end up being homeless.
Housing is expensive in the
UK and theoretically the state
will provide housing for people.
The trouble is there are
long waiting lists, and this
doesn't happen very quickly.
Another reason for homelessness?
People sometimes come to the UK
as migrants from other countries.
They may not have a plan in place.
Not everyone can get a job or
settle into UK life very easily.
So homelessness can happen
for a number of reasons.
And once you're homeless, once you have
no fixed address, no regular access to
technology or electricity even, no means
of receiving mail or email, you become
'outside of the system' and it's a process
that's quite difficult to turn around.
So how can you help
people in this situation?
Well, the Ashley Foundation suggest first
of all, giving your old coats or jackets,
especially warm ones, to the charity.
They also suggest making a donation.
That means 'giving money'.
Or  you can volunteer at one
of their homeless shelters.
Another good thing that the
Ashley Foundation do - they
run an app called Street Link.
You can download this app to your
phone and on the app you can alert the
local authorities to a homeless person
that you have seen, rough sleeping.
When I say 'alert the authorities'
that means in order to get them help.
And this may result in the homeless
person being offered ' temporary
accommodation', so being offered
somewhere to sleep for a short time.
It also may mean that they
can access healthcare as well,
see a doctor if necessary.
So that app sounds a really good idea.
Even getting someone a bed for
the night, even something that
short term can be really helpful.
So if you're in the UK, and if you want
to volunteer and give your time to help
homeless people, then Crisis UK  is the
best known national organisation for this.
The Ashley Foundation is great,
but it tends to operate just in
those northern towns, Blackpool,
Blackburn, and Sunderland - that's
where they seem to operate.
Crisis UK have services in the
main cities like London, Edinburgh,
Coventry, Swansea, Oxford etc.
I realise that most people listening to
this podcast are not based in the UK,
but it could be that there is a problem
with homelessness in your country.
And there are plenty of
international organisations that
you could  volunteer with  that help
homeless people across the world.
And of course volunteering and donations
are always welcome through international
organisations which help people in
countries like Ukraine and Syria.
OK, so that's 'Charity at Christmas'.
Let me wish you a very happy
Christmas and let's look forward
to 2023 and hope it's a great year.
All the best!
Enough for now.
Have a lovely day.
Speak to you again soon.
Goodbye.