How many times have you negotiated this
past year? You might be thinking, Well,
never. I don't really negotiate
in English as part of my job,
but let me ask you this.
When was the last time you
negotiated for an extended deadline
or asked for a change
in your job schedule?
When was the last time you asked
for a promotion or a raise at work?
When was the last time you negotiated
with your spouse or partner to finish up
the dinner dishes or when was the last
time you negotiate with your kids to wake
up and get dressed on time for school?
It's surprising just how often we
negotiate in our everyday lives.
Knowing how to successfully negotiate
not only helps you resolve conflict or
get what you want,
but it also helps you build
better relationships and create
lasting solutions. And this
Confident English lesson today,
you're going to learn
four essential strategies,
plus 20 phrases to help you
successfully negotiate in English.
But first, if you don't already know,
I'm Annemarie with
Speak Confident English.
Everything I do is designed to help you
get the confidence you want for your
life and work in English.
One way I do that is with my weekly
Confident English lessons where I share my
top fluency and confidence
building strategies,
targeted grammar lessons and
communication skills training,
just like in this lesson today.
So while you watch this lesson,
make sure that you give it a thumbs up
and subscribe to my YouTube channel so
you never miss one of these lessons. Now,
let's get right to it
with strategy. Number one,
identify your ultimate goals,
limits and alternatives.
Before you enter into a negotiation,
you have to know what you want
in the end. In other words,
you need to know your ultimate
goal. To help you figure that out,
ask yourself this question,
What do I want the outcome
of this negotiation to be?
When you know the answer to that question,
it's important to communicate
it clearly and directly in the
negotiation without any bells
or whistles. In other words,
without any enhancements or extra
additions, you want to keep it simple.
For example, you might have a
meeting with your boss and say,
I want to discuss getting a raise that
matches my current level of expertise and
responsibilities. With that statement,
it's extremely clear what you
are looking for. With that said,
we don't always get exactly what we want.
There tends to be a compromise
somewhere in that negotiation,
so you need to be prepared for that,
and that's where knowing your ultimate
limits and alternatives is important as
well. In other words,
if you have an ideal amount for
the raise that you're looking for,
what is the bottom limit? What is the
ultimate minimum that you'd accept?
That's your bottom limit,
or are there any alternatives you're
willing to discuss? Instead of a raise,
are you willing to look
at increased benefits?
Knowing the answers to those questions
are essential Before you go into
that negotiation, in
thinking through your goals,
limits and alternatives,
essentially what you're doing
is identifying your bottom line.
And once you know what
that bottom line is,
here are several phrases you can use
in English to communicate it. Clearly,
I draw the line at X
because of Y. For example,
I draw the line at getting a raise
because I want to see an increase in my
salary. With that statement,
what you're saying is you're
not interested in alternatives,
you're not willing to discuss anything
else other than an increase in your
income. Similar to saying that you're
drawing a line or setting a boundary,
you can say X is
non-negotiable because of Y.
A raise is non-negotiable because I
want to see an increase in my salary
or anything less than X
will not meet my needs.
And lastly, I'm willing
to meet you halfway at X,
but anything less than
that is non-negotiable.
When you're willing to
meet someone halfway,
you're willing to compromise
With this first strategy,
I'm using several example sentences
around the topic of asking for a raise
at work. I did that intentionally
because asking for a raise is often quite
uncomfortable and I want you to
know how to do it successfully.
So let's finish strategy number
one with a scenario that really
brings all of this together.
Let's say you've been in conversations
with your boss about a raise
and your boss has proposed an
alternative rather than an increase in
salary, the company wants
to offer other benefits.
You're not really interested in that,
so here's how you could respond using
what you've learned in this strategy.
An increase in my salary is non-negotiable
because it will ensure that I'm
able to keep up with the current cost
of living in this city and it matches
my current workload here in the company.
There's one last thing I want to mention
here before we go on to strategy number
two, and I want to underscore the
importance of identifying your goals,
limits and alternatives.
Negotiating is also cultural,
and in English speaking culture,
it's common for us to
seek a win-win solution.
In other words, a situation
in which everyone wins,
everyone gets something that they
want. Going into a negotiation,
knowing your upper limits,
your bottom limits,
and any alternatives you're open
to discussing will help you have a
successful win in the end. And that
leads me into strategy number two,
find common ground and build rapport.
This is part of creating
an environment of seeking a
win-win solution.
What this means is rather than go
into a negotiation or discussion
immediately demanding what you want,
it's important to enter into the
negotiation slowly and keep in mind the
relationship you have
with the other person.
If you know that individual or
even if it's someone new to you,
a potential client, it's
important to establish rapport,
to build a relationship, and
we do that through small talk.
Small talk allows us to
identify common ground and also
feel out where the other person
is, what is their point of view,
how are they doing?
All of that will inform how you
begin the process of negotiating.
So once you're ready for that negotiation,
that meeting that you've scheduled,
start with some basic small talk questions
such as, how's your day going? Or,
I heard you just got back
from vacation. How was it?
Then once you've had a little bit of
time to get comfortable with each other,
you can transition into the
point of the conversation.
You might do that with something such
as, Well, I don't wanna waste your time,
so let me get right to the point.
I'd like to discuss a raise that
matches my current level of expertise
and the responsibilities I
have here at the company.
Before we move on to
strategy number three,
let's look at one more example of a
small top question you could use if
you're meeting a potential
buyer or a potential client.
Imagine you're meeting with a potential
buyer of your product for the very first
time. You've shaken hands,
you've just sat down and you're
feeling a little bit awkward.
How do you get things going?
Here's a small talk question you could
use in organizing this meeting with you
today. I had the opportunity to interact
with quite a few of your team members.
You seem super organized. What's
the secret in your organization?
With that small top question,
you are creating a
friendly open environment,
starting out with something positive and
allowing a little bit of small talk to
occur before you get into the negotiation.
And now, strategy Number three,
understand the other side just
as you want to know exactly
what your goals, limits
and alternatives might be.
You want to have a sense
of what the goals, limits,
and alternatives of the
other side might be.
Knowing what the other side is thinking
or what their point of view is will
allow you to make a better
decision and weigh your options
before you go into the negotiation.
To weigh one's options means
to assess the pros and cons of
a situation or potential
decision. In addition to that,
understanding the other side's
position will help you have stronger
arguments. When you're ready
to discuss what you want,
not only can you anticipate what the
other side wants prior to the negotiation,
you can also ask questions during the
conversation to get better insight,
and here are several
questions you can use.
What do you think is a fair
and reasonable solution,
outcome or number and why?
Could you please tell me more about
how you arrived at X? For example,
could you please tell me more about
how you arrived at that decision,
or could you tell me more about
why you arrived at deciding?
Offering benefits is a better
choice than offering the raise.
Similarly, why do you believe X?
Why is X important to you?
Why is it important to you to offer
benefits as opposed to an increase in
salary?
What part of my proposal
causes hesitancy or what part
of my proposal is causing you concern?
Each one of those questions will
help you understand the other
motives and anything influencing
their decision. As a result,
you are more equipped to
respond appropriately,
argue for what you want or
compromise successfully.
The last strategy for a successful
negotiation in English is to
establish trust and everything that
we've talked about prior to this strategy
helps you do that. Establishing
common ground, building rapport,
asking open ended questions to
better understand someone's motive or
situation. In addition
to those strategies,
here are four more techniques
you can use to gain trust.
Number one, speak directly and concisely.
We talked about this a bit
in strategy number one,
when I said it's important
to communicate what you want.
Clearly this is essential
for the other side,
so there's no gray area or
room for misunderstanding.
What this means is using concrete,
straightforward language,
for example, rather than give a
range of numbers, for example,
we'd like to have this finished
within the next three to five months.
Be clear with what you want,
provide dates and the specific results
you're looking for. For example,
we want this finished by
January 5th next year.
Do you notice the difference?
Rather than giving some gray
estimate of three to five months,
we're giving an ultimate
deadline of a date.
Reducing the potential for
misunderstanding or miscommunication is
part of building trust.
The second technique you can use
is to show interest and openness.
Instead of bending the
truth in the negotiation,
it's important to be sincere and honest.
When communicating your goals and the
reasons for them to bend the truth is a
fantastic expression to know. In English,
it means to say some of the
truth, but not all of it.
There are some things that you're
hiding so that you are likely to get the
response that you want.
In addition to communicating your
goals with sincerity and honesty,
it's important to also ask those questions
we talked about in strategy number
three with sincerity and honesty,
express genuine curiosity
to understand someone
else's position,
what they're having to think through
and the decisions they have to make in
order to meet you halfway.
The third technique you can use to
build trust is to actively listen.
Now,
I have a whole lesson on the topic of how
to show that you're actively listening
in English, and I'll leave a link to that
lesson below if you want to know more,
but here are a couple of
keys to actively listening.
In English speaking culture,
we maintain eye contact. Now,
we don't stare nonstop. Of course,
we occasionally blink and look away,
but maintaining eye contact indicates
that we're focused on you and
what you're saying.
What you're expressing is important
enough for me to listen carefully,
and I tell you that through eye
contact. In addition to that,
we also tend to ask clarifying
questions or repeat what
we heard you say to make sure we
understood correctly. For example,
you're saying it's not possible for your
team to get this finished by January
5th. Is that correct? Or if I understood
you correctly, you're thinking X,
Is that right? What I heard you say was X,
Have I understood correctly? And lastly,
could you clarify what you meant
by and then repeat what it is
that you're not really sure about?
Before we talk about the fourth
technique you can use to build trust.
Let's look at a scenario where you
might hear some of this language.
Imagine you're traveling with a
friend and at the very last minute,
your friend wants to change the itinerary
for the last couple days of your trip,
and you're not really so sure about this.
You like having a plan
and sticking to the plan,
so your friend proposes an idea and
you summarize what you've understood by
saying, I think I understand.
So what you're saying is,
rather than go to the museum today,
you want to save it to the last day of
our trip because you think it won't be as
crowded. Is that right? In saying that,
you're letting your friend know that
you've listened carefully and you're
working hard to understand
their side. Now,
you may or may not agree with that.
You may want to stick to the plan,
but you are acknowledging that you've
heard and understood what your friend has
suggested.
And now the fourth technique you can
use in strategy number four for building
trust is to use inclusive language.
Let's compare these two sentences.
I want a solution that satisfies
these conditions versus
we need a solution that
satisfies these conditions.
What do you notice about those
two sentences? Of course,
the first one begins with I.
I'm creating a conversation
in which it is me against you.
We want different things. We're
not in this together. However,
when I switch to inclusive
language with the word we,
I'm recognizing that we
both want a solution.
We both want an ideal outcome to
this particular need that we have.
We're in this together.
We're going to work together to find
a solution that makes everybody happy.
Now that you have these four strategies
on how to successfully negotiate in
English as well as several phrases you
can use, I have two questions for you.
Number one,
give me an example of a situation in
which you might need to negotiate in
English. It could be a situation
at work or outside of work.
What strategy or phrase did you learn
today that you will use to help you
next time? And number two,
if you have a go-to strategy to
help you successfully negotiate that
I didn't share today, I would
love to know what it is.
With both of those questions,
you can share your answers
with me in the comments below.
That's also a great place to
share any questions you have.
If you found today's lesson
helpful, be sure to let me know.
You can do that in one very simple way.
Give this lesson a thumbs up here
on YouTube, and while you're at it,
don't forget to subscribe as well.
Thank you so much for joining me,
and I look forward to seeing you next
time for your Confident English lesson.