-Hello, lovely students and welcome back to
English with Lucy! Does any of this sound
painfully familiar to you? Your grammar and
vocabulary are good, but you know that your
wording doesn't always sound natural. You can
follow conversations in English, but you miss
out on jokes, nuance and hidden meanings. You can
speak well, but you still don't feel 100% relaxed
and confident when you talk with English-speaking
friends or co-workers. English still requires so
much of your energy, and it leaves you feeling
drained, and maybe you feel that your current
English level prevents you from showing your
true personality and intelligence, and that
doesn't feel very nice. Could you relate to any
of that? If yes, you are in the right place. I
have created a solution for you. Introducing
the beautiful British English C1 Programme.
This programme is a 12-week course designed to
take you from upper-intermediate B2 English to
advanced English, the C1 level, as defined by
the CEFR. If you think you already have the C1,
keep watching. In this programme, we cover a
lot of C2-level content. We really overshoot,
so this could be really relevant for you too. When
you achieve the C1 level, you will feel confident
having deep conversations about any topic.
You will also be able to understand jokes,
nuances and hidden meanings. You will feel
totally capable of working in an English-speaking
environment. I'm going to help you tweak your
already good English skills so that you can move
towards perfection and native-like fluency. The
programme works by making sure you focus on nuance
and pronunciation from day one. We take everyday
situations like family, work and leisure and teach
you the advanced vocabulary in context through a
storyline. And we take real native conversations,
break them down and analyse them so that you
understand 100% of the meaning and the implied
meaning. We even train you to write beautifully
with targeted writing training sessions. This
programme is truly unlike any other. Let me show
you the four elements that make it so unique and
so effective. Number one, the most important, in
my opinion, nail the nuances. Have you ever been
in a group situation where someone says something
that is seemingly meaningless and everyone laughs
apart from you? I can relate to this so deeply.
It happened throughout the learning stages of my
second and third languages. Often, this is due
to a very subtle but impactful concept. Nuance,
nuance, a beautiful word in itself. Nuances are
the subtle differences in meaning between words,
phrases, grammatical structures and ideas.
And these shades of meaning might seem small,
but they can greatly affect how we understand
what is being said. Once you master these,
you can express yourself in exactly the way you
want, sound completely natural whilst doing it,
and totally understand others. This is exactly
what we teach you in this programme. Number two,
and this is a totally new concept. For my
programmes, we've introduced story-based
learning. This is a method that is going to keep
you engaged and motivated throughout this entire
programme. The entire programme comes in a story
format that develops over the course of 12 weeks.
Every reading and every listening tells part of
the story. You won't want to miss a single week.
The story is based on real-life situations, so
you've got ample opportunities to learn slang,
pronunciation, and relevant vocabulary. Number
three, advanced conversation breakdown. Elevate
your fluency through real conversations with
interesting people in my life. In this programme,
you have 12 really interesting conversation
lessons. We take these conversations and we
break them down so that you can understand
100% of the words, and more importantly,
100% of their implied meaning. We look at the
nuances of their grammar, the rules they do use or
don't use. We discuss the pronunciation rules that
they follow, or break, again, those all-important
nuances. We analyse the humour they use. We
break down their vocabulary and their spoken
English. There is so much to gain from these
conversation lessons. My conversation analysis
technique allows you to move from good English
to native-level English fast. And number four,
pronunciation from day one. I cannot overstate
the importance of pronunciation. Pronunciation
is integrated throughout the entire programme
so that you eliminate bad habits and form good
habits from day one. We have 12 pronunciation deep
dive sessions, but pronunciation is also woven
throughout every other lesson, especially those
conversation lessons that I mentioned before.
Many students receive poor pronunciation education
in their formative years of learning. This
leaves them with bad habits that are difficult to
unlearn. In my classes, we break those bad habits
and we focus on correct, clear pronunciation.
I've trained thousands of students to speak with
Beautiful British English pronunciation. Modern
RP, that's my accent. If that's what you desire,
we can work on that. If you just want to speak
clearly and be understood, this programme will
help you massively with that. Whatever your goal,
you'll be able to fit in and live life speaking
and sounding the way you want. Now, I said there
were four key elements. There's actually one more,
and this one is for students that really
want to make fast progress. It's optional,
but previous course students have said that this
was the most valuable part of the programme for
them. The VIP Feedback Pack. With this option, you
get weekly feedback opportunities. 12 writing or
speaking tasks that my team of expert C1 teachers
will correct and provide feedback on. This is
your opportunity to put what you've learnt into
practice, receive corrections, and supercharge
your progress. For me, one of the most amazing
points is the pronunciation feedback. My teachers
are just amazing at pinpointing those little
tweaks that you can make to sound truly natural
when you speak. If you don't want feedback, don't
worry. You still get access to the private course
community and my teachers. Every question you
have about the course will be answered in the
private course community. This way, you'll never
get stuck. You'll never remain confused. This is
the perfect course for busy people. Self-study
materials with teacher support. So what do you get
in the Beautiful British English C1 Programme? You
get 12 really interesting modules that teach you
easy to digest fluency elements through story to
help you sound undeniably natural in three months.
Each module has five to six video lessons with me.
That's over 60 in total. The lessons are really
visual and they all have optional subtitles. We
have five lesson concepts, vocabulary, grammar,
writing, pronunciation, and conversation. We
cover listening, reading, speaking, and writing,
all the skills throughout the programme. We have
downloadable lesson PDFs and mind maps so that you
can visualise and revise more complex grammar and
vocabulary concepts. These are perfect for visual
learners. If you're unsure that you know enough
grammar to participate in a C1 level programme,
we've included B2 level revision PDFs so that
you can refresh your memory and prepare yourself
before you start each C1 level grammar lesson.
We have included hundreds and hundreds and
hundreds of exercises, transcriptions, listening
tests, reading comprehensions, gap fills, grammar
quizzes, spelling tests, there are so many. This
way you can put what you've learnt into practice
and boost your memory and retention. We've also
included pronunciation lessons and exercises so
that you can speak clearly and be understood by
native speakers. We also have weekly speaking and
writing homework with personal teacher feedback if
you opt for the VIP feedback pack. Everyone gets
16 weeks of access to our private course community
where you can connect to like-minded learners and
stay motivated. My expert team of teachers will
help you out and answer your questions so you
never get stuck. Take a look at what some of my
amazing previous course students have to say.
- I feel more confident when I speak English
and I can read an article faster than before.
I learned so many new words, idioms
and phrases. I'm so happy about that.
- I've learned lots of grammar, vocabulary
and even pronunciation. I feel much more
confident with my speaking. There was a
lot of exercises. That's just amazing.
You can check your knowledge.
That made me enjoy the journey.
- I love the way Lucy explained grammar and
vocabulary. That helps me a lot. And I
loved the conversation lesson the most.
- I highly encourage you to enrol. You will
enjoy it and you will definitely not regret it.
- I'm so proud of them. They did so well. I
really hope you can join them. At the end of
the Beautiful British English C1 Programme,
you have a final exam. You will also get a
digital certificate of completion. You can use
this to prove your attendance of a C1 level
English course. The Beautiful British English
C1 Programme starts on Monday the 22nd of May.
It lasts for 12 weeks, but you have lifetime
access to the course content. We also offer a
30 day money back guarantee. As long as you
haven't completed over 20% of the lessons,
if you try the course, it's too hard for
you. It's too easy for you. Don't worry,
we can refund your course fee. No
problem. I want my students to be
happy and satisfied. We are running an amazing
introductory offer. You can save up to $150.
There is a deadline. Enrollment closes and the
introductory discount ends on Sunday the 21st
of May at midnight. To view the course and
enrol, click on the link in the description
box. If you have any questions, please send me
an email. I've left the email address below.
I can't wait to welcome you through the doors
of the Beautiful British English C1 Programme.