- Oh my gosh, look at this! - Look at that!
I'm proud of that. - You should be so proud of
yourself. - Do you want a bit of cranberry sauce?
- No, I'm okay. - Do you not have cranberry sauce?
I don't eat cranberry sauce. - You need cranberry
sauce on turkey. - I know. - Oh my goodness,
I'm so excited. This is the first... - Laura, I
like these plates as well because they're quite
deep. - Yeah. - They're kind of like, they go like
in. - They cushion in it all in. I need to, yeah.
I'm so excited. Is that good? This is amazing.
Thank you so much. - Merry Christmas. - Oh yeah,
Bucks Fizz. - Merry Christmas. - Merry Christmas,
Bucks Fizz. What is Bucks Fizz? - Bucks Fizz is
orange juice and champagne, traditionally. But
I think you can have a cheaper version with
Prosecco. - Now you're gonna say prosecco. What
is the difference between Prosecco and champagne?
'Cause I do not know. - Oh, that's good. That's
a good carrot. Um... - This is amazing. - I think
Prosecco is just cheaper. I think it's just like
a, I think Prosecco is like a sparkling wine,
but I think Champagne... - So the more expensive
thing, is champagne? - Yeah. - So, what's the
difference between, so is Champagne a different
drink? - Champagne is a different thing. Yeah,
and Prosecco is just a sparkling wine. I'm going
to try the turkey. This is the first time I've
ever cooked turkey in my whole life. - Yeah, I
know, that's, I'm very excited. - That's good. I'm
proud of that. - People don't usually like turkey
on Christmas Day. Well, people don't usually like
turkey, but in the UK, people traditionally have
turkey on Christmas Day. - Yeah. - But everyone
complains about it. Do you like, you like turkey,
don't you? I do enjoy it. - I think when we, when
we do this again, I think we do need the plate
warmer because putting the cranberry sauce on my
turkey has made it a little bit cold, 'cause the
cranberry sauce is so cold. - So, well, yeah, but
that's the cranberry sauce's fault. - Yeah, but if
it had heat coming from underneath the plate, see
what I mean? It would, like, heat everything up. -
You just had the cranberry sauce, made everything
cold. - Yeah, I don't know, maybe, I don't know,
maybe my logics don't work. Is your turkey cold or
is it warm? - Mine’s… Well, I lost a lot of
heat when I cut it because I cut it a while
ago. - Maybe we should only rest it for, like,
10 minutes, then, instead of 20. It's hard, is
it? It's hard to get it right. - It’s difficult.
- But this is why it's good to practice. Good to
practice, so you know what you do next time. So,
I think my one thing is, I would probably get
the turkey served sooner, but it's still really
good. I really like it. It's not dry, is it? - No,
it's lovely. It's really nice. Usually, turkey is
dry. That's the complaint people have. Yorkshire
puddings, Laura, this is delicious. Thank you so
much. I was talking to 'cause, this just 'cause
this is a Christmas dinner. I was talking to
somebody, um, about Christmas, and I said,
"Oh, Christmas, I'm excited for Christmas." And
she said, "Oh, of course you are, because you're
a man." Oh, she said, "A woman at Christmas,
they dread it because they've got to do all of
the cooking, they've got to do all of the present
buying, got to do all of the wrapping, all of the
decorating." So, she was, I felt a bit awkward
because I was sat there like “I’m sorry!” What
do you think? Do you agree? - Oh, traditionally,
definitely. I've seen, I used to work in a pub,
and, um, on Christmas Day, all of the men would
come in to the pub at about 11:00 to have a
drink with their friends while the women cooked
dinner. - Yeah. - Shocking, that. - Yeah, that
is bad. - Shocking. - Do you think times will be
changing? - Well, you're definitely not like that.
You're a modern man, you all the way through. When
I was doing this, you were cleaning up everything,
like washing up the dishes as I was going. -
I appreciate that I can't cook as well, but so
I'll help in other ways, so I will clean, clean
everything. - Well, yeah, there's barely anything
to wash up now, there's just these two plates
and that bowl, probably. - And these glasses,
and that's it. So, yeah. - Pigs in blankets are
sensational. Pigs in blankets, a little sausage
wrapped in bacon. - Amazing. - Double meat. -
Yorkshire puddings. What is Yorkshire pudding,
Laura? - Yorkshire pudding is essentially, it's
this thing here, which just looks like a big flob
of batter, um, but Yorkshire pudding is so easy.
It's flour, I did 100 grams of flour, plain flour,
not self-raising. - It’s like a cooking show. -
Three, three eggs. - Yeah. And then, um, uh, milk,
semi-skimmed milk, 125 L. Mix it all together,
mix, mix, mix, mix. Salt and pepper. In the oven
for like 20 minutes. Done. So good. And it tastes
like it's kind of—it's essentially the same recipe
as pancakes; you just cook it in a different
way. And it's like a slightly different, um,
thing. But it's so good… - It’s strange when
you break it down. When you say what it is,
you… - I love Christmas dinner so much.
- Yeah. I’m wolfing this down, Laura.
- Me too. - I am wolfing it down, honestly.
- And everything is made from scratch,
isn't that good? - Everything. - This is my
first ever… - Can you imagine the satisfaction,
though, if you grew everything? - Oh my
goodness. That would be really cool. - I’m
not growing a turkey. - No. But my dad, um… -
He grows veg, doesn’t he? - My dad grows veg,
so he must have a lot of satisfaction every
time we have Sunday dinner. Because… - So far,
I'm really happy with this, I think this
is really good. - If this is a—so this
would be… - This is my first-ever Christmas
dinner. Is that successful? It’s good, innit?
- So successful, Laura. So successful!
- “So successful”. - So Ho, ho, ho. - Ho, ho,
ho. - So let's talk about the components of a
Christmas dinner. Traditional Christmas dinner. In
the UK So. - Okay. No, but I—I think what's good
to do with this—what a Sunday dinner first? Sunday
dinner. Go on. Sunday— Oh, sorry. I'm—yeah, you're
eating! Sunday dinner. Veg. So, something like
broccoli, cauliflower. You don't like cauliflower?
Broccoli, cauliflower, potatoes, peas, carrots.
Maybe now, people have some things like parsnips.
Mhm. We have parsnips today. Um, what else will
it be? Peas. - Yeah, essentially, meat, potato,
and veg and some extras. - And the meat. So people
have either beef or lamb or chicken. People don't
usually… - Pork. - Pork. But people don't have
turkey for a Sunday dinner. - No, no. - Then when
it's Christmas Day… - Turkey comes out. - Things
come a-changing. - Big boy. Big boy turkey comes
out. - Turkey is the meat. - Turkey. Got to be.
Yeah. - And we sprinkle in there some cranberry
sauce on the turkey. - Oh, amazing. Cranberry
sauce on the turkey, stuffing. - And then the
pigs in blankets. - Pigs in blankets is a fun—is a
Christmas thing, 100%. - You have to. - You can't
do—no one's doing pigs and blankets in July. Pigs
and blankets is a Christmas staple. So you have
your pigs— You have your little sausages
wrapped in bacon. Parsnips, I think, are
very Christmass-y. - Are they? - Well. They’re a
winter veg, aren't they? - So, they're more—you'd
find them in the winter. - I don't know, um,
but that's cool. - Yorkshire pudding… - Oh my
God. - Amazing. And then all doused
in gravy. And then that's perfect.
- Starters at Christmas. Do people have starters
on Christmas Day? - Some people do. - Did we have
a starter? Yeah, we had a starter in the
restaurant with your dad last year. - Oh,
yeah. Some people go to a restaurant if
they don't want the hassle of cooking. Um,
but I think most people are tired enough
cooking the dinner that they don't want to
do a starter as well. - It’s true, and
it’s loads. - And also, traditionally,
guess how many calories on average people eat
on Christmas Day? In the UK? - I saw this. You
watching it on telly. - How many? - 6,000. -
6,000. So, if you're eating 6,000 calories,
you don't need a starter as well. Do you know
what I mean? You're going to eat enough that
day. - Yeah. - We’re going to be so full. - We’re
going to be so full. - But then—then we'll also
have all this turkey left over, so I'll probably
want a turkey sandwich. - Yeah. Not today. - Yeah,
I don't have any bread today. - Have to go to the
shop. - But I would on Christmas Day. - This is
so lovely. This is so lovely. - It’s good, innit?
Is it a success? - Thank you so much. A massive
success. - I think so too. I really like it.
I think it's harder to enjoy it when I've made
it because this is no worse than any Christmas
dinner I've ever had, but because I've made it,
I'm critiquing it more. - Possibly. Yes. I think
that when I cook, I enjoy it more because I know
what all the—like if I make some pasta, um,
and there's some little chilli flakes in it,
and then I get a hint of the chilli, maybe
you wouldn't notice it, but I do, and I go,
"Oh yeah, that's the chilli that I put in." So I—I
think I appreciate it more when I've cooked it,
weirdly. - Yeah, I think I normally do. I think
with this, because there's, like, so much pressure
of making Christmas dinner amazing, I think I'm
a bit more like, "Oh, is it okay?" Every bite,
I'm going, "Please be okay." - Exactly. -
And it is, it’s really good? - What’s your
favourite? Except for, like, obviously, because
I think a lot of people would say that a Sunday
dinner is a British person's favourite food, but
except for that, because that's a bit of a cheat,
what are the British food is there? - Fish and
chips? - Fish and chips. But do you like fish
and chips? - Um, I've gone off it a bit. - I have
as well. - We were saying this the other day. - I
have. - I think it's too fatty. - Every time I
have a bit of chips now, I wish I had something
else. And that’s… - It’s too much. I think I like
fish and chips. - I don't know if I do. - If you
gave me a portion that was like that much fish
and maybe about eight chips, I think I'd really
like it. - Yeah, like a mini fish and chips.
- But there’s always so much of it. - But you
get—you get, like, 'cause my mom and dad, when
they order a fish and chips, they get, like,
a bag. And it sounds strange, but they get a
bag between, like, three of us or four of us,
right? - Yeah. - And maybe you might think… -
Like, one meal between three people? - Yeah.
But it's not. But it's not, though, is it? One
bag of chips is loads when you actually open
it up. It's weird. Maybe people listening
might think, “A bag of chips?!” It comes in
a—comes in paper. - Yeah. Traditionally, it came
in—in newspaper. - Newspaper, yeah. - Um, yeah,
I think the issue with—I have this terrible thing
where whatever is put in front of me, I will eat
the whole amount. I do not know when to stop. I
am not able to go; ‘that's enough now’. So, if I
have a whole portion… - I’m getting a bit now. -
Are you getting full now? - A bit. - Berwyn! - I
will eat it. - You better. Slaved away over
that all morning. - Go on, carry on. - Um,
if there's a big portion of fish and chips in
front of me, I'll finish the whole thing. There's
no way that I'm going, ‘and I'll just put that
away,’ like I'll do the whole— And then I end up
feeling awful after I've had fish and chips 'cause
I overeaten. You know what I mean? - Is that just
fish and chips? - What, that makes me feel ill? -
Yeah, everything, just overeating? - No, anything
that's like fried and greasy. - That’s the appeal
of it, to be honest. I've taught a lot of people
who have come to Britain, and they want, they
really want to try fish and chips, and they do.
Everyone who's tried it has said they don't like
it. Yeah. But they've all gone to London, and I
think London fish and chips are a different thing.
- Too posh? - No, no, no, no. I think it's too,
like, it's just churned out, like it's not like
the. I bet the chips—oh, that's the air fryer. Um,
I bet the chips are, like, in a bag frozen for a
while, and I bet the fish were caught, like, two
weeks ago. Whereas if you go to the fish and chips
by the sea, yeah, it's fresh, it's all fresh. And
I can, I can understand that. I can understand if
the seabreeze is, is hitting your face, and like,
you can smell the Sea and the salt and the
sand, having a, having a fish and chips. I can,
I can understand the appeal of it a little bit.
It's quite nice, but even then… - I’d only need
a kids portion. - Yeah, no, I agree, actually. -
I do think fish and chips is best if you can have
a kids portion. - Who’s eating all that? - Oh,
it's loads; it's way too much. - So there's fish
and chips, there's steak and—well, what would you
say, a pie in general? - I love a pie. Any kind
of pie. - Well, I didn't realise that pies are
British, aren't they? - Well, and other places,
but yeah, we love a pie here. - Yeah, I thought—I
thought—somebody said that pie is a British food.
Like, the pie. - Really? No, surely other… -
Think about it. - Other people would have been
doing pies before us. - Would they have? 'Cause
what's the whole point of a pie? Keeping in things
inside, fresh and warm. Mining, people going… -
Are you telling me none of the Nordic countries
thought of a pie before this? - I’m… - I think it
was kind of people were coming to that conclusion
around the same time. - I think it was us. - We
invented the concept of a pie? - Mhm. - Well,
if we did, go us. Pies are great. Pies are
so versatile. You have savoury pie… - I
was teaching somebody, I was teaching somebody and
they said that, and I believe them. - Well, there
you go. - It sounds—sounds believable. What’s your
favourite pie? - Chicken, but with not—some pies
have got a chicken with like a white sauce in it
and, like, a creamy sauce. I don't like that. I
like it to be. - No. - No, yeah, it's too creamy.
- Chicken pie… - It needs to be with gravy. With
gravy. - I do like a chicken pie, but maybe not
the white sauce. Yeah, yeah, I agree. - Chicken,
stuffing— I haven't made that in a while. I used
to make that a lot. Do you remember? Chick—I used
to make a chicken stuffing and potato pie. I'll
do it soon in the winter. - Could we use the
turkey? The leftover turkey? - Could do, just
depends on how much we got left 'cause we might
not have enough to make a substantial pie. -
Don’t burp. If you weren't on a podcast now,
you'd be burping, wouldn't you? - It’s the bucks
fizz! - Pie. My favourite pie is Steak and Ale.
Steak and Ale or steak and kidney, steak and
kidney pie. My Nan. used to make a lovely steak
and kidney pie. - Kidney?! - It’s kidney. - No,
it's not. It's kidney bean. - No, no, it's kidney.
It's kidney. Steak and kidney pie. - I’ve always
wondered that, and I've always thought it must
be kidney bean. - No, no no. It’s a kidney.
It’s like a sheep’s kidney. - Awful. - You’re
eating a turkey now! You’re eating turkey’s,
just like, muscles. - Yeah. Nice! Is that what
meat is? Is it the muscles? - Yes! - Is that
what it is? - Yes! What is it? What else is
it? - I don’t know. - Have a think. Would it be
the bone? No. Would it be the skin? No. Would it
be the… - We do need to heat these plates because
it’s already cold now. Have you noticed? - No,
I haven’t noticed, to be honest. - Okay, well
it’s fine because, yeah… - But, we’ll have a
heat… - We’ll get a plate heater, yeah, we’ll be
fine… What were we saying? Kidney, no, I think,
just the idea of it being kidney— I think I’ve
had a steak and kidney pie, though but I always
thought it was kidney bean! - Well, you must have
liked it. - No, I'm not a fan of that. - Why would
it be called steak and kidney pie if it was kidney
bean pie? - Yeah, but the bean probably just took
too long to say. - No. - I always do this. Do you
do this? Do you leave your favourite bits till the
end? - No, I go kind of gradually. I kind of leave
a bit… - The end of my plate will always just have
parsnips and potatoes on it. - Not just— Oh yeah,
you don't, you don't. My sister always leaves the
pigs and blankets. - Yeah, I've got one pigs and
blanket there I’m ready to have. - One pigs and
blanket or one pig in blanket? - Well, you never
say singular, do you? - I’m—I'm tired; you know
this is hitting me. - You’re going to get the
Christmas dinner snooze afterwards. - I'm going
to be comatose. - I love that feeling, though, and
after you've eaten Christmas dinner and you just
go into the living room, stick the tele on. - Box
of celebrations. - Oh, and you just—you just FEG,
and people go like, should we go for a walk?
Should we play a game? People like, oh yeah,
I'll do that in a minute, and everyone just..
- Yeah, I know, but it's annoying 'cause you're
wasting the day there. - I know, but it feels so
good. - It does; it does. This turkey is so nice,
though. Well done. - It’s good, isn’t it? -
Thank you so much. - So, I think what I've
learned from this, I want to give the potatoes
3 minutes longer, and I want the turkey to be
taken out a bit later. - I’m not listening to
you; sorry. I was just trying to get pig in
blanket on my fork. Potatoes later, no earlier!
- Other than that, I think that's perfect. Then,
but I’m happy— Yeah, I think that's really good.
I'm very proud of myself for my first… - You
should be so proud of yourself. You should be
so proud of yourself. Would you like, to pull
a cracker? - Now? - Yeah. - Okay, let's do it. -
Let’s do it. - You always win. - I do. - You know
what? I think there's been about three years in
a row where I haven't won. Do you remember we did
the, um, the live streams last year for Christmas?
I didn't win a single one. There you go; carry on;
enjoy. Open it up; what does it say? So inside a
cracker, usually there's—well, is there always a
joke? I'd be disappointed if there wasn't a
joke. And a hat! Put your hat on! - Oh yeah;
okay; all right; is that the order? You've got
to do hat then joke? - Yeah, 'cause you’d look a
bit silly going like saying the joke… - My prize
is I've got some stickers. - Great, some lovely,
yeah. Usually, there's some terrible gift inside,
like a plastic comb or like a notepad or a little
jumping frog thing. Um, yeah, I feel a bit,
I feel a bit… - Quite small, that. - I feel
a bit ridiculous now. Do you know what
annoys me as well? - What? - On Christmas
Day? - What? - Everybody puts on their
hats and goes, "Oh yeah, lovely, lovely,
lovely," and then before the meal's even finished,
people haven't taken them off. I've got mine all
day. - You went to sleep with yours last year.
- Yeah, I did last year. Come on; there you go;
I promise you… - You cannot win a cracker; you
can have that one, though. There you go. - Yeah,
yeah, of course. You’re not gonna… - So, you
ready for the joke? - Oh, I've got some stickers
too. - Okay; what do you call a boastful snowman?
Um, a boastful snowman; so somebody boastful is
somebody who's proud and like bragging, so… -
You've got this; come on. - Proud…? - Come on;
what do you call someone who's bragging about
themselves? - Bigheaded…? - A snow off! - Yeah,
that's a pretty good one because if you're a
showoff, you boast about it, but he's a snow off;
he's an Iceman. - Would you like mine? - An
Iceman? A snowman. Yes. - Who gets to be in charge
of the pencil case? - Don’t know. - The ruler;
that's quite a good one. - I like that one. - Um,
and then sometimes on here; here we go; this
is a ridiculous one. Some ‘Merry Mindfulness’,
have you got this as well? - Yeah, I’ve got that
as well, what does yours say? - “Press pause and
just Christmas” - Is that what is says? - And
something to chat about. Oh, here we go; there's
a question underneath; ah, this is an interesting
question. If you had to live with one historical
figure forever, who would you choose and why? -
I think someone like Gandhi would be quite quiet,
I think he'd probably just stay in his room.
He’d probably just… - You and Gandhi forever;
poor Gandhi, he’s come back…. - I’m trying
to think of someone who wouldn't interfere
with my life, I feel like he would stay in his
room; he'd do his meditation, and he wouldn’t…
He would just chill. - That's what—that's what
you imagine. But what if—what if—what if he has
raucous parties? - I don't want someone who's
going to interfere, so Gandhi or… - What did
you say? - I don't want someone who's going to
interfere; Gandhi or who else was like… ? Marcel
Marceau. - Who's that? - A mime. - A mime? -
Yeah, 'cause then he’d just keeps schtum. - I
would say historical figure… what are you doing?
- There’s more yorkshires. - Laura, I’m getting
full. - Well, I want them. - Alright; okay; um,
a historical figure I would say for forever is
a different thing, isn't it? - Yeah, that's a
long time. - A historical figure… Would Gandhi
even speak English? - Yeah, I think so. - Did he
speak English? - Think so. - Um, someone like—no,
I was going to say like Julius Caesar, but he'd be
a nightmare! - Oh God! - He'd be a nightmare; um,
someone like—I don't know, I really don't know.
Richard—no, not Richard III; I'm having awful
suggestions. - Think of like calmer people.
- But historical people usually aren't calm;
they're—they're famous because they did something
really, really big. - What if I just eat all of
these? - That would be mental? I mean, if you
want them, you can have them. Anne Boleyn. - Anne
Boleyn? - Yeah. - She was a bit of a Rebel. -
Alright; um, Catherine of Aragon. - Yeah. - I
would have any boys, that's for sure; historical
joke for you there. What’s the question on yours,
Laura? - It says, if you could build your ideal
isolation station, what would it look like? Like
a place where you would isolate? - Right; like a
man cave, I suppose. - Yeah, or like if you had
to go and work in a remote location somewhere, you
had to be isolate. What would you—what would you
put in there? - I took with me to University every
year; mhm; like back and forth every year, like
back home for the summer and then to University
again; like books; like 12 books that I thought,
yeah, I like the idea of sitting down and just
reading one of those books. Didn't open them once
in four years. So, no books. - Have you read them
now? - I have… No, no, I haven't. I would say I’d
just have lots of… like a big TV; I like watching
films. What about you? - Some kind of like home
gym? - Oh yeah, that's a good idea. - Cause if
I was bored I could at least do exercise rather
than just sitting around; and some Yorkshire
puddings. - I'm—I'm full, Laura. - You’ve barely
eaten anything! - What do you mean “barely
eaten?!” There was a mountain of food;
there was a mountain of food; you watch this back;
there was; there was a mountain of food here;
I eating two York puddings, like four slices
of turkey, about three parsnips, two potatoes,
three broccolis. - Yum, and I'm still going— I'm
going strong on the Yorkshire puddings. Here we
are, and who will be ill later on? You just said
this earlier… - It’s what you do on Christmas;
you gorge. - Yeah, I know, but it's not Christmas,
not Christmas; it's not real Christmas day today;
oh my God. - I love Christmas. - I'll keep
chipping away. - Oh, you don't have to chip away;
that makes it sound like a chore; just chill; it's
all right; it's fine; you're good. - I don't know,
Laura. - I'm going to have one more Yorkshire
pudding; then that's it; I won't have any more
'cause that's silly; I can't have otherwise I'll
be having four Yorkshire puddings. - Four. - But
they are good; they're good yorkshire puddings,
I’m proud of these. - They're delicious;
amazing. See, your hat's gone. - Where? -
It's fallen off! - Oh, it was small. It's
too small. - You got a small— big head. I’ve got
a small head. - I love roast dinners; have you
noticed that when you describe a roast dinner to
someone, it never sounds good? - People just go,
“Yeah, it's just… What, veg and meat?” But then
do other—do people in other countries—surely other
people in other countries have had vegetables and
meat at the same time? - Yeah. That’s what I mean,
so like when you say it to people, it's like,
“Okay?” But it's—it's the combination of it
all with the gravy and, oh, it's really hard. - I
think it's the traditionalism of it, the tradition
of it; um, I think it’s… when it's especially
because it's usually people have it on a Sunday.
It's just nicer; it's just like a safe time. -
The associations you have of it. - What do you
associate with Sunday dinner? - Sundays. - Yeah,
but like… - Um yeah; um, but not being at school;
obviously, that was always fun. We’d go to church
in the morning, then we come home, have a roast
dinner, and then we go back to church. So, we went
to church twice in a day. We would do the morning
service and then the evening service. So, I
associate eating a roast dinner and then knowing,
'Okay, I've got two more hours to do what I want,
and then I've got to go back to church.' So,
I'd always... - See that’s annoying, though. -
Yeah, I know. - 'Cause I actually kind of agree
with you. When I had a Sunday dinner, I used
to associate it with, 'After this, I've got,
like, the afternoon and then the evening,'
but then it's school tomorrow. So, actually,
I wish maybe Sunday dinner was on a Saturday.
- Yeah, but like the hour after Sunday dinner,
I used to love that. ‘Cause I’d I have a full
belly. I'd just eaten a really nice thing,
um… - I always had coffee. - &eah, nice coffee,
and with some biscuits or something— An After
Eight! - Yeah! - I love After Eight. We should
get After Eights for Christmas Day. Should
get After Eights? - Yes, we should. - They’re
really good. Um… then…. I was going to take a
picture of this, but I didn't. Oh well. - We
got the video! - We got the video evidence.
Um, uh… - After Eights. - After Eights,
yeah, and then an hour where I can just
do what I want. - Did you not do your...
No, you did your homework at school. - No,
I never did homework. I used to… sometimes I
used to… my mom would make a coffee or something,
and then in the time she was making a coffee, I'd
run upstairs and try to do some homework. - Yeah,
that's a good plan. And then I could just chill,
watch some TV, full belly, and then it'd be like,
Mom would go, ‘Right, want to get ready?' And when
she said that, ‘right’… - So did you get changed
out of your Sunday, like, church clothes? - So,
at my church, we used to have to wear a uniform,
which is very different 'cause I went to a special
kind of church, and we wore… - ‘Special’... - And
we had to wear a uniform. So, I'd be in my uniform
in the morning, and then I would wear... 'Cause my
uniform was like a polo shirt and then a skirt.
So, I would just change out of my skirt into some
jeans, keep my polo shirt on, put a jumper over
the top, and then I just... Yeah. - Sid your heart
sink when she... When your mom went, 'Right?' -
Well, yeah, but that's the mom, ‘right’? Which
everyone can relate to. Or the parent thigh slap
or when people go, ‘Well.’ - ‘Right’. - Sometimes
it's a good thing if your parents
have taken you to someone's house,
and you don't want to go to their house. -
Yeah. Absolutely. - And they’re talking to,
like, their friend. - And they're on the way out
of the house. - And you’re just sitting there
like… - And you’re like 'Right, we're getting in
the car, we're getting in the car, we're getting
in the car,' and then somebody says, 'Oh, tell
you what, did you want that coat for that? Oh,
yeah! Let me just come upstairs,' and then you're
like, ‘No!’ - It’s like, ‘Oh, come on!’ - I have
so many memories of being in someone's house, sat
on the floor. - Or waiting for your mom to come
off the phone. - Yeah, yeah, and you’d just be
sat on the floor waiting for your parents to go.
they'd be talking to their friends or whatever,
and then… - Lovely, a lovely, burp. Lovely,
Laura. I can't believe it. - And then you’d hear…
- I’m going to get some more Bucks Fizz just to
finish this off 'cause we've only got a bit left
in the... - Okay, can I just finish what I was
going to say? - Yeah. - And then you hear the
parents going, 'Well,' and then you go, 'Right,
that's my cue. We're going home. We're going home.
Woop Woop Woop!’ Oh, I'm so full. - It was so
exciting that... - Yeah. - Laura. - Did you like
that? - I loved it. That was good, wasn’t it? - I
thought it was delicious. - That was really nice.
Something else that I associated with... - Thank
you. … Sunday was, and you definitely wouldn't
have associated with this: football. - Oh
no. - Just like, um… - My hunch... I just looked
in the camera. My hunch was, uh, intense. - Um,
I'm going to put that bottle in there. -
Okay. - Um, no, yeah, we used to have, yeah,
so like having a full belly and then watching
whatever team is on, and it's always a good game
on a Sunday. So it's like, I don't know, for some
reason, I'm thinking like Tottenham, Tottenham,
Manchester United or something on a Sunday. Oh,
and just... And you just know I'm just relaxing,
watching this with a coffee. It's great. - No,
when you were having football on, we had Songs
of Praise on, I think, which, is, so essentially,
church in the morning. - Yeah, and it's a... Then
Songs of Praise is like… - Is church. - Is
it just a televised church service? - Where
they sing songs of praise? They sing songs for
Jesus. So we go to church in the morning… - And
there's always a crowd of people there. - Yeah,
singing. - Because they... And they all really,
really sing because they know, 'Oh, I'm going
to be on the television.' Whereas actually,
if that church was not on the television...
- Well, they take the cameras to a church,
a random church in the UK, and they...
They do the songs from that church. - Yeah,
they... There's a Welsh version of it as well.
‘Dechrau Canu, Dechrau Canmol’ What? - Which is,
‘Start Singing, Start Praising’. And it's
the same idea. They did it in my church a
couple of times. - Well, there you go. So,
church in the morning, church on the telly,
church in the evening. - Is there any novelty in
watching that Songs of Praise on a Sunday for you,
or did you hate it at the time? - Um, I think
now there's no 'cause it's Nostalgia. Now it
feels like, 'Oh, that reminds me of when I was a
kid and my childhood home and everything.' But,
um, at the time, yeah, I just wanted to be
upstairs and doing my own thing. And, like,
or I do remember being in the living room after
eating a Sunday dinner on a Sunday, obviously,
and then, um, uh, like sitting on the floor with
my toys while the parents were sat on the sofas,
like napping probably 'cause they were so tired.
Um, and I just be playing with my toys. Have
you ever had a roast dinner not on a Sunday? -
Today’s a Saturday. - True. Probably Christmas
Day is the day where you're most likely to have
a roast dinner not on a Sunday. - Christmas
day doesn't feel like it's a day of the week. -
No, no, people know this. People go, like, 'Oh,
Christmas is on a Monday this year, isn't it?’ I
was like, ‘Is it?’ - Because we don't have normal
jobs. - That's true because we don’t have normal
jobs. - But if... If... If you had a normal job,
you would have to... - You would know. -
…You’d go, like, 'Oh, Christmas is on, uh,
Monday, which means I get three days
off because it's Saturday, Sunday,
and… then Christmas.” It’s like… How? - Well I
think you get two days off 'cause I think... I
don't know. I don't know how it works. Um, but
yeah, no, I... I like, yeah, Sundays are a nice
memory for me, I think. Even though I spent a lot
of it just going backwards and forwards to church,
I think overall Sundays are a nice memory. -
For me… - Sunday evenings, no. Sunday evenings,
you're thinking about school. - Yeah, but then
also I think... I could... I could cry about it
now. It's so lovely, just like... Like, you're
finishing, you're like, 'You had your Sunday
dinner, then you, like, you watch the football
or whatever,' and then, like, maybe, like,
'Cause my grandparents would have come around,
then they've gone, and then maybe you have, like,
some biscuits or something for tea or something
like that. And then, like, it's especially in
the winter time, it's dark outside, and you feel,
like, so, like, cozy. Going upstairs and, like,
just playing, like, a video... It sounds stupid,
just playing a video game, but, like, that was,
like, my safe space just to go, 'I'm just going to
enjoy this, and knowing I've done all my homework,
all I've got to worry about is, like, the next
day.' - Yeah. And, like, yeah, that was so
lovely. Yeah. - Don’t cry. - My nan used to come
over. She... I know. Oh, yeah, it's nice. My nan
used to come over, uh, on a Sunday, and she
only lived, like, a 5-minute walk away. Well,
10 minutes for her. She was slow, and, um, she...
Because every time she came over every Sunday,
I would... She would have a room inspection. She
would look at mine and my sister's bedrooms to see
who is the tidiest. And my sister never— Was never
the tidiest, and being, I was like a little swot,
I'd like properly… - “Look at mine, Nan, look at
my room!” - I'd like— But it was a good excuse.
It was a good excuse 'cause I would really,
really, really tidy my bedroom every week,
and it was a really good reason for me to get rid
of some stuff that I didn't need, etc. And then
she'd come upstairs, she'd be like, 'Yeah, very
nice, really, really good.' And I’d go, 'Yeah,
look at this, look at this, very tidy, look, I've
even folded all my clothes.' And she'd be like,
'Oh, yeah, very good. - I remember that
feeling when you would decide to tidy your
whole room and then you want to show it off
to your parents. I remember doing that. Used
to love doing that. - And then I'd go, 'Do
you want to see my sister's room?' She'd go,
'Oh, go on then,' 'cause she knew it was going
to be bad. And then I'd go in and go, 'Look,
she's got her magazines under the bed, look, she
hasn't done this, and look, what's this, like,
old spoon doing here?' - You are such a little
brother. You're the most little brother thing
ever. I used to love doing that, though. I would
go, ‘Right, I'm going to really do my room,' and
then I'd go, like, 'Mom, do you want to come see
my room?' And I'd love, like, opening the door
and going… - She’d walk in, 2 seconds later,
‘right’. She'd leave. - Time to go. - Well,
speaking of which, Laura, I think we should
go and relax. - And tidy up, probably,
wash up. - I can't believe I haven't finished
it, but we did have a lot of food, please. - It
was a lot of food. - It was delicious, Laura.
- Thank you so much. - I need to sleep and a
coffee. - A coffee. - And a mince pie. - I can’t—
We've had a bottle of Bucks Fizz. - Can we have,
um, maybe a mince pie in, like, an hour? Let
this go down, and then have a mince pie. Does
that sound good? - Cup of coffee and a mince
pie. - Where’s your wrist support? It's, uh,
I've taken it off to eat 'cause it, yeah. - Oh no.
He’s got carpal tunnel syndrome. - For context,
I've got... I'm... I'm transcribing too many
podcasts for you guys. Um, I've been working
too much on the computer, so… Um yeah, Smashing
English. - Messed up your hands. Get it back
on. - I will, I will. - After we washed up. - Yes,
yes, exactly. - Right. Thank you for joining us
for our Christmas dinner. Merry Christmas. I was
going to shake your hand. - Oh, yeah. Sorry. Yeah.
Merry Christmas. Give you one more cheers.
- And a happy New Year. - Merry Christmas!