You must wear a mask. You have to wear a
mask. They must be at home. They have to be at
home. Must or have to? In today's lesson I'm
going to teach you about these two verbs.
I'm going to divide this lesson into two
parts. Part one, choice. Part two, probability. What?
Choice and probability? What's that? Don't worry,
I will explain everything step by step. At the
end of this lesson I have a test for you with
10 questions. Can you please let me know how you
did on the test? Did you get 10 correct out of
10? Or maybe, 6 correct out of 10? Let me know,
I really love hearing from you. Well, my name's
Arnel, let's start. First things first. The
grammatical structures. You can see I have:
Subject, must, have to plus base verb. What's the
base verb? Well, the base form of the verb, is verb
number one: Eat, ate, eaten. Play, played, played.
Eat and play are the base form of the verb. You
can see, must remains the same for all subjects.
I must go, you must go, he must go. He musts go?
She must goes? The forms stay the same. You can see,
have to, changes depending on the subject. I
have to go, you have to go. But, he/she/it, has to
go. And we always keep the base form after, to.
She has to goes? Never. There's one more thing I
want to add in this part. You might hear or see
this. I have got to go, you have got to go. This
is perfectly correct, it's just a little less
formal. In today's lesson I'm not going to go
into, have got to, because I really just want
to focus on must, and have to. I do have a lesson
on this topic, I'll leave the video link in the
description and comments down below for you.
Part one, choices. You can see my line here.
I have no choice and, your choice. What do I mean
by that? Well, no choice means you cannot choose.
We're talking about obligations like rules
and laws. Your choice means you can choose. We
can use must and have to when you do not have
a choice. The verbs mean the exact same same
thing. Citizens must pay tax. Citizens
are people who have a passport from
that country. So for example, I can say she is an
Indian citizen. He is a Mexican citizen. Citizens
have to pay tax. Notice the pronunciation,
have to. Have to. There's 'f' sound, have
to. Yes, you can say, citizens have got to
pay tax. But again, I'm not going to focus
on that. Students must wear a school uniform.
Students have to wear a school uniform. No
choice. If you want to hunt deer in the woods,
you must have a hunting license. You have to
have a hunting license. I know have to have seems
strange, but there's have to plus the base form
of the verb. Perfectly correct. Have to have. With
all of my examples so far you can see there's no
choice. If you don't do these things there will
be a punishment. You might need to pay a fine. A
fine is money you need to pay, it's a penalty, or
maybe you might go to jail. Those are punishments.
Okay, so if we can use these verbs in the same way,
are there no differences? Are they exactly the same?
With rules and laws must is more common in formal
written English, official contexts. Let's look at
a sign. Employees ... wash hands before leaving the
restroom. Must or have to? Which one do you think it
is? Right, must. Have to is perfectly correct.
You could see, employees have to wash hands
before leaving the restroom. But again,
this is written, it's a sign. I want to
show you a couple more examples of
must being more common in written,
formal contexts. Imagine you want to
visit the White House in the USA. Let's
go here. I have the White House
website, you can visit the white
house if you want. I'm going to
quickly scroll through this. Must,
must, must. All of the examples with must
give you a rule. There's not a single have
to on this page. If you want to read the full
sentences, I'll leave this website link in
the description below for you, but I think you
get the idea. Here's a common question: Is this
American English or British English? Both. Must and
have to are common everywhere. Let's say you want
to visit Big Ben in London. The Big Ben
tour is not suitable for everyone. Visitors must
be aged 11 and over. Visitors have to be aged
11 and over, perfectly correct. But again, this
is written. Okay, I'll bring up the grammatical
structures once again. Remember earlier in this
lesson I said: The forms stay the same. So if
the forms are always the same, how do we know
if we're speaking about the past, the present, or
the future? I think we need a chart. Okay, I have
rules and laws here. We are still speaking about no
choice. Past, present, and future. And must and have
to. You can see with must there is only one
form. Citizens must pay tax. This is true now,
right? Students have to wear a school
uniform. This is also true now. When I
was in school I had to wear a school uniform.
Next year, students will have to wear a school
uniform. Here's a headline from National
geographic.com. You've had to cancel your
vacation. Here's what to do next. Here we see
the present perfect tense being used. So you
can see, have to is much more diverse in terms
of tense. There is no mustard. There is no will
must. So, in your speaking or writing, if
you want to change the tense you need to
use, have to. You have to, use have to? Things
change in the negative, take a look. You can
see I must not go. You must not go. He/she/it
must not go. The forms don't change. I do not
have to go. You do not have to go. He/she/it, does not have to go. Remember that, does.
The correct structure is: Subject, do not have
to, plus base verb. We do not say, I haven't to
go. Look, in the negative must not remain the same,
no choice. Let's go to the zoo. Visitors must not
touch the animals. I think that's clear. You must
not do it, it's dangerous. Many zoos have a petting
zoo. What's a petting zoo? A petting zoo is a mini
zoo where you can go to pet the animals. Like in
this picture, here. And the verb pet is this. So you
can pet a cat, you can pet a dog. We have a petting
zoo, you can pet the animals. Have you seen Jurassic
world? In that movie there's a Dinosaur petting
zoo. Anyway, if you go to a petting zoo, would
someone say this: You must pet the animals, you
have to pet the animals. No, nobody would say that.
It's not a rule or a law, nobody's going to take
your hand and force you to pet the animals. Would
someone say: You must not pet the animals? No, if you
must not pet the animals, why have a petting zoo?
It's your choice, right? You can pet the animals or
not. We can say, you don't have to pet the animals.
You can pet them if you want, or you can just look
and take pictures, it's your choice. I want to give
you another example. Let's compare two different
parks. Ah, it's a sunny day. It's the perfect day
to take your dog out. An park A, we can see a sign:
Dogs must be on leash and under control at all
times. This is a leash. Hmm, shouldn't this say, on A
leash? Well, with signs articles: a and the, are often
removed. We can see a dog walker here with her dog
on a leash. She is following the rules, very good.
In park B, your dog doesn't have to be on a leash,
it's your choice. Here, we have some dogs playing
together. Maybe this is a dog park, but this couple
decided to keep their dog on a leash. You can
see, don't or doesn't have to means your choice,
whatever you want. Question: In which park will
you need to pay a fine if your dog is not on a
leash? Right, Park A.
We've looked at rules and laws. But what if
we're speaking about personal obligations?
For example, I must stop worrying so
much. I must fix the sink today, the
dripping is driving me crazy. You must remember to
thank Julie for the flowers. With these examples
here, you can see these obligations are coming
from the speaker, this is perfectly correct.
However, this is more common in British
English. Americans would tend to use, have to.
I have to stop worrying so much. I have to fix a sink
today. You have to remember to thank Julie for the
flowers. I have to. I have to. I have
to what? What's the verb? This is really
common especially in spoken English.
If the verb is already clear you do
not need to repeat it. In this specific
episode he means I have to kill someone,
but he doesn't need to say it. Everyone
in that room they know what he's talking
about. We should invite Dan and Julie to
our party. Do we have to? Or, less commonly,
must we? It's clear speaker B means, do we have
to invite them? Must we invite them? Okay, let's
move on to part two. Part two, probability.
What's probability. I'll explain that as
we go through the lesson. Here, we have Nick.
What what do you think Nick's favorite color
is? Hmm, blue t-shirt, blue walls... everything
is blue. His favorite color must be blue.
His favorite color has to be blue.
His favorite color has got to be
blue. But do I know this? Am I 100%
sure? No, I've never met Nick. I'm 95%
sure. This is what probability is when we
look at the evidence around us. So we feel
very strongly about something. It's like
the very first example I gave you in this
lesson, they must be at home. I don't know that, I
didn't see them inside. But their lights are on,
they must be at home, they have to be at home.
In your grammar books you might see the term,
deductions. This is the same thing. When you look
at a situation, you look at the evidence and you
come to a conclusion. But again, you're about
95% sure, you don't know this is an absolute
fact. How old do you think Leanne is? I've never
met Leanne, I've never seen her passport. I don't
know, she must be in her 20s. She has to be in
her 20s. In, English when we say someone is in
their 20s, in their 30s, in their 40s Etc... We mean
between the ages 20-29, 30-39, 40-49. I can say, my
parents are in their 60s. So Leanne must be, has
to be in her 20s. I don't have any bread at
home, do you think the gas station will have
bread? They must have bread, they have to have
bread, everyone buys bread. Honey, I bought this
sweater for you to wear to my parents Christmas
party. You must be joking, you have to be joking.
We can take a picture like Christine and Frank did last
year. Just like part one, things change
in the negative and past. Present, Leanne
must be in her 20s, Leanne has to be
in her 20s. I'm almost certain. But
how can we express the opposite? How
can I say something is impossible?
Leanne can't be in her 20s, Leanne
cannot be in her 20s, Leanne mustn't
be in her 20s? Leanne doesn't have
to be in her 20s? You can see the
change is pretty dramatic in the
negative. Let's take this to the
past. When Leanne graduated from medical
school she must have been in her 20s. She
had to have been in her 20s. I know the
structure is pretty long. Subject, must
have plus past participle. Subject, had
to have plus past participle. The past
participle is verb, number three: Eat, ate eaten.
Play, played, played. Eaten and played are my past
participles. How can we make this negative
in the past, impossible in the past? Leanne
started medical school when she was 27,
she can't have graduated in her 20s. She
couldn't have graduated in her 20s, impossible.
Some of you might be wondering, but what about
the future? Well, there isn't really a future
form for this. We would use other structures.
For example: She will probably graduate
in her 20s. She's going to graduate in her
20s. There isn't really a specific form
for these, for the future. Let's do another
example. Imagine you have a history test
and you see this question: What year did
the Titanic sink? Sink is an irregular verb.
Sink, sank, sunk. I didn't study for the test,
but I feel pretty strongly about this.
The answer must be 1912, the answer has
to be 1912. I mean, 1880 is too early. 1950
is too recent. It must be 1912. Let's make
this impossible. The answer can't be
1950, the answer cannot be 1950, that's
impossible. So we're using the present because
we're talking about the test, now. But let's take
this to the past, to the actual event. The
Titanic must have sunk in 1912, the Titanic
had to have sunk in 1912. Past impossibility, the
Titanic can't have sunk in 1950, it couldn't have
sunk in 1950. If it had sunk then we'd have
better pictures of it, but we don't. Have you
seen the movie Titanic? I love that movie.
If you haven't seen it maybe you've heard
of it. We're going to watch a little clip and of
course I'm not going to explain the whole movie,
that would take 3 hours. But in this movie some
people are searching for a very special diamond.
They don't know where it is but this character,
he's pretty certain he knows where the diamond
is. So the diamond had to have gone down with
the ship. So the diamond had to have gone
down with the ship. Based on the evidence he's
95% certain. Notice how he contracts to and have.
Had to have. Had to have gone down with the ship.
So the diamond had to have gone down with the
ship. So the diamond had to have gone down with
the ship. Let's do one more example before the
test. Is this your phone? No, it must
belong to one of my students. It has
to belong to one of my students.
I mean, who else? It can't belong
to one of my students. I have a
very strict no phones in class
rule. Imagine the teacher puts the phone on
her desk, has her lunch break, she comes back
and the phone is gone. A student must have
taken their phone. A student had to have
taken their phone. Who else? A student can't
have taken the phone. A student couldn't have
taken the phone. My office was locked during
my lunch break. Maybe it was another teacher.
How are you feeling? Let's move on to the
test. Test time, 10 questions in total. Can
you please choose the best answer for
each question? Pause the video to do
this. Okay, here are the answers. How did
you do? Please let me know your score in
the comments below, I love reading them. I love
reading your comments, thank you so much. I'll
explain the answers in case you're curious
why you got something wrong. But to do this
I need my notes, because I haven't memorized
all of the the answers. Okay, are you ready?
Number one: Must not is clear. it's illegal to
text while driving. Number two: Has to. Because
the subject is she, she has to. Number three: It's
your choice, you can wear a costume or not. Number
four: Last year, so the past is clear. And this
wasn't our choice, we were forced to do this
because we were sick. Number five: Again, this
is a law. Number six: Well, if a restaurant is
always really busy you are 95% sure they have
good food. Number seven: We need has to, because a
subject is he. And if someone does something
5 days a week you can be pretty certain that
that they enjoy it. Number eight: Can't, because
we think that's impossible. Brothers with two
different nationalities are not so common. Number
nine: We need the past form because we see, saw. Is
it possible to use option C grammatically? Yes,
but it's a logical conclusion that the same
product comes from the same store. Number 10:
Something wasn't possible. I was in New York
last week. I can't be in two places at the same
time. Wow, thank you so much for watching this
lesson I hope you learned something new,
and I'll see you next time! Bye!!!