I'm absolutely addicted. Who is tidier?
Legs are just everywhere. I've lied to you.
what is my worst habit? This is a conversation
killer. I'm just trying to think of any other
pet peeves you have. That's not true. That's
the most obnoxious-looking jacket I've ever
seen in my life. Can't keep up with myself.
Now cry and laughter. Why are you crying?
Hello, lovely students and welcome
back to "English with Lucy." Today
William and I, because you may have noticed that
my husband is here with me. Hello, everyone. We've
got a listening/conversation lesson. I think it's
going to be interesting for you, but also for us.
We might end up learning something about each
other. Maybe, hopefully not because we've been
together for nearly six years. So we're going
to have a conversation on camera and for your
benefit on screen as we are talking, interesting
vocabulary words and phrases will appear. I have
also created a free e-book for you. It contains
the full transcript of this conversation, all of
the key vocabulary along with the pronunciation,
the definitions and examples, and a quiz so you
can put what you've learned into practise.
It's going to be an awesome resource. If you
would like to download that free e-book, where do
they have to click? Here? No. Where do they? Oh,
down there? Yes. Okay. Just down there on the link
in the description box. You then enter your what?
Email address. And your name. And your name.
Full name. Sorry. Can I ask, do you ever watch
my videos?Sometime. You then join my mailing
list and the e-book will come directly to your
inbox. And then after that, you've joined the PDF
club. You will automatically receive all of my
free weekly PDFs in e-books, along with all of my
course updates, offers, and general emails. It's a
free service and you can unsubscribe at any time.
Okay. I'm really excited to start this. Me too,
but I have no idea what the questions are gonna
be. Well, neither do I cause of one of my lovely
teachers pre- , prepared them. Okay, I'll
go first. What is my favourite food?Fruit,
as a general answer, fruit, but to
be specific, watermelons. Yeah. Oh,
there's nothing like a good watermelon. And part
of the fun of a watermelon is that they're not
grown in England and you can't access them.
So when you go abroad and there's a great
watermelon. I sound like a total weirdo,
don't I? Watermelon. You can't access them.
I don't know. I think the majority of people
whenever they go abroad and come to exotic fruit,
I mean coconuts, for me. Oh yeah. Will loves a
coconut. This isn't my question. No. So don't
take over. No, sorry! Okay, that was a really
easy one, I've made no secret of the fact that
I'm absolutely addicted to fruit. Total fruit fan.
Well, I also normally buy you a watermelon every
birthday. That's true. And Easter. Because you
don't like chocolate eggs. I do like chocolate
eggs, but I prefer, I prefer a watermelon. I
mean you can get chocolate anytime, but good,
in season watermelon, in the UK. That's a luxury!
Yeah! What did Will wear on your first date?
I know this like the back of my hand because I
remember calling my mum afterwards and being like,
he's so nice but he wore a fleece 'cause I thought
that was so weird. But there's this brand of
fleece that only farmers seem to wear called a
Schoffel or Schoffel. I'd never seen it before.
It's a very soft fleece with a leather
trim. And I just thought, I just,
I'd never been out with a farmer before and I
thought that's a farmer. You'd also just come
back from Spain. Yeah. So if they were selling
them in Spain, I would've said that they're in
the wrong market. Yeah, that's true. Okay. My
turn. What was the first film we saw together?
Oh, I do know this because it was our fourth
date. "Beauty and the Beast." Yes, it was. It
was. And do you remember how I impressed you on
that date? Actually, I did it in two ways. Yes.
You brought beer to the cinema. In my handbag. In
a cinema that didn't serve any alcohol. I brought
only one for you because I'd also just passed
my driving test by that point, it was February,
and I drove you there in my little car and it
was traumatic 'cause I wasn't a very confident
driver. No. But I brought you a beer to have
to relax after I traumatised you. That was very
thoughtful. Oh, this is a tough one. How would
Will describe himself in one word? Interesting.
Laid back. Yeah. Predictable. You're very laid
back. No, as in predictable answer, yeah. Yeah,
or chilled. Chilled. Yeah, I'm okay with chilled.
What would you say? To describe myself? In one
word? Trying to think of the longest word I know.
No. Good. Good! Spontaneous. No. Laid back I
would say, I've always been laid back. Yes. In a
good way though. It's better than being uptight.
Yes. Opposites attract. You're looking at me
like it's one thing we need to work on. Yeah. No,
I wouldn't say I'm particularly uptight but
I'm definitely not as laid back. I mean, you
are horizontal to be fair. But I do, I like it.
You bring a lot of balance to the relationship.
Yeah. Life is all about balance. Okay. My turn.
Who is better at remembering important dates?You.
Why? Because my memory's appalling. No, it's
not appalling. My mind thinks very quickly.
So when I think of something, unless I write it
down five minutes later, it might have drifted
off and something else has come in and replaced
it. I like the way you didn't say that you're
forgetful. You said I think too quickly.
I'm not forgetful. I'm just too fast.
Life cannot keep up. So many ideas.
Yeah. You come from laid
back to think too quickly.
Yeah, I can't keep up with myself. Now, cry
and laughter! Why are you crying? Kinda,
lights are bright on there. Yeah. it looks like
you punched me in the face. Yeah. Don't say that,
you'll start rumours! So when we started
going out, you were a farmer. I mean,
you didn't leave the farm. There was no option
really. Yeah, my social calendar was empty. And
it was only when we moved away that we started
having lots more options, lots more opportunities
to see other people, go away. And then we almost
went through a phase where there were too many
invitations and too much going on and there were
multiple invitations on each weekend. And so I
put in place a shared calendar. Yeah. But then
we've had issues with you agreeing to things, but
not putting it in the shared calendar. I've gone
the other end of the spectrum, haven't I?Yes. I
just said yes to everything. Yeah, there were
quite a few times where you'd suddenly realised
that you'd said yes to about three different
people on the same day. But you know what? It's
good problems to have. Look at us complaining
about having too much fun.Too popular. Yeah.
Who is tidier?Now, that's a hard one. Yeah, I'm
wondering what your answer's gonna be. Yeah. So
am I. I say that we are like swans, okay? We
glide along beautifully like that. Everything
looks fine. Yeah, looks just like a swan. But
underneath the surface of the water, it's like
legs are just everywhere. And I feel like that's
what our personal life is like. Our business life.
We're talking about tidying here. I'm getting
there, okay? Okay. Right. From the outside,
the house looks tidy and amazing but if you dare
to open a cupboard, a load of crap. I think a lot
of people can relate to that. I hope so. I hope
a lot of people can relate to that. Yeah, I think
probably part of my problem growing up was I had
the tidiest mum on Earth and I almost rebelled
against it. I felt like your mum was very tidy as
well. She was, she had to look after three boys,
so. So we were spoiled and we never learned
to tidy for ourselves. I would say we're both
pretty similar in tidiness as in like both
quite untidy. What do you think? Yeah, well,
what do they call it? Agree to disagree.
Do you think I'm untidier? I think I'm
slightly better. Okay. I'll accept
that. For the sake of the video. No,
for the sake of our marriage. Sorry, I've
still got tears in my eyes, they are red.
From when you claimed you think too quickly.
And now they are back again. Yeah, cool. Ooh,
this is a good one. Who is more adventurous?
Ooh. So in general, I would say you.
Would you? I feel like diving into
something new, you're a little bit
more up for it compared to me. But
when we actually get there, I feel
like I probably then take the reins.
I think this could describe our whole
relationship. I feel like I'm very quick
to go for something and adapt to it. And then you
end up doing it better in the long run. And I'm
thinking of every board game we've ever learnt. I
always learn the instructions really quickly and
I win for like the first 10 rounds and then you
get it and then you like absolutely take over.
Yeah, I would agree with that. I think that's
spot on. Although with sports and taking risks,
maybe you're--You never come to the start line.
What is Will's pet peeve or biggest pet peeve?
When people say 110%? Yes. Yes. I understand
the idea. Sorry, I'm taking over now. No,
I love that you're such a YouTuber,
looking at the camera. No, I love
the way the question is what's your pet
peeve and I'm like I'll take over from here.
Yes. I just think people take it too far. You
can't give more. It's just a saying. No, people,
they use it in every "Apprentice" video under
the sun. Oh, so this is a TV show in the UK and
America where people compete for a job position.
I remember you coming back from trying to,
I think you'd gone with your dad to buy a new
car or something for the farm. It was a new
farm vehicle. And I remember you coming back and
said, "Everything we asked him, the guy just said,
'110%, 110%, mate.'" Do the wheels work? 110%.
How good's the engine? 110%. And it just comes
across as insincere. Yeah. It's just doesn't
make sense. Okay. It doesn't make sense. I'm
just trying to think of any other pet peeves
you have. Whenever I touch you with a cold
foot. Yeah, I think every guy can relate. Guys,
do you hate it when I touch you with a cold foot?
Because we need to talk, basically.
Okay. Who is more honest?
I would say it's a 50-50 split. Can you elaborate
on this 50-50 split? Mhm. You want me, you
want me to elaborate? Yes, it's a
conversation lesson, Will. Like,
you are looking at me like I was dishonest about
something this morning. No. No. I just, it's
just the students are waiting. They know 50-50
splits by now. I can't think of a time where
I've lied to you. Ah, but this was years ago.
What was that? And this was when I pretended to
be on the farm when I was actually going to
London to collect the engagement ring. Yes.
What a terrible lie. Yeah. I don't think I've
ever really lied unless-Keyword there. Really? No,
I think it's just like you have the odd white lie,
don't you? Yeah. You know, but nothing serious.
But I think more as like honesty as a personality.
I'm not one of those people that will, you know,
not be able to sleep unless I tell the absolute
truth and how I'm feeling in every single
conversation. If someone asks me, do you like
my dress? And I don't like it I'm not going to
cause a scene and tell them that I don't. But I
know some people stand by that and and think, no,
if I don't like something, I'm gonna say it. Yeah.
I'm quite good at letting things go. I'm quite
tolerant. Yeah, that's another word I would use
to describe you. Tolerant. Tolerant. That makes
me sound like a nightmare. Yeah, I was gonna say
the word you'd go for is tolerant. Yeah. And me?
Tolerable. Yes. Persistent. This is a good
question. Who is Will's celebrity crush.
Oh, Jennifer Aniston. Yeah. Jennifer Aniston. I
had to tell you that. I thought you were gonna
say a a different answer. What was I gonna?
I would like to think Scarlett Johansson,
although she never really has. Messaged me. No.
Messaged you. Never really
what? Come up in conversation.
I think she's mine if I had a female one?
Yeah. Yeah, Jennifer Aniston. Yeah, Jennifer
Aniston. Okay. This is a good one. What's the
first gift I ever gave you? I think it was a red
British and Irish Lions rugby jacket. I went to
the ends of the Earth for that and by the ends
of the Earth, I mean Luton. The jacket itself.
So the British and Irish Lions, for those of you
who don't know, it is a combination of England,
Scotland, Ireland and Wales. And they
play every four years-- Rugby. Rugby
against the southern hemisphere, whether it's
South Africa, Australia, and New Zealand. And it's
something that's on my bucket list of going on
one of their tours. It lasts two weeks to a month.
And I've always followed them ever since I was a
young child, I always wanted their kit. And there
was one jacket in particular that I saw that year,
which I really, really wanted. And I almost bought
it for myself. But when I went to purchase it
online on a website and it said there's one left
in stock, I said, you know what? I'm gonna buy
it tomorrow. And I went back the next day and it
had gone and I was distraught. And this must
have been two weeks before Christmas Day and
Christmas Day came and I opened up my present
from Lucy and there was this bright red British
and Irish Lions rugby jacket. And you then
told me the story of how you got it. It was
really hard to get in time for Christmas.
But then the even better part of the story
is that we went to a friend's house to stay
over and there was this really obnoxious guy
who saw the jacket hanging on the back of a
chair and was like, "Oh my God, that's the
most obnoxious looking jacket I've ever seen in my
life. Who the hell's is that?" And I was like, oh,
that was my Christmas present to Will because
it was a very bright red. Oh, bless that guy.
He said if I could put a percentage on how
much I hate that, it would be 110%. What
song did you dance to for your first dance?
"Smack My Bitch Up" by The Prodigy. Lucy.
That's not true. "Say a Little Prayer"
by Aretha Franklin. Yes. It was amazing,
beautiful, romantic. What is my
worst habit? Where do you start? Oh,
this is a conversation killer I think. We'll
make it the last question. I think your
worst habit. Barking orders. Barking orders.
What a terrible way of saying it, Will. No.
Barking orders. Well, I do say that to you. Yeah,
it's true. I don't bark though. No, I've got a
good one actually. Okay. Worst habit was probably
lack of driving that your reluctance to try and
overcome your driving fears. I'm better. Yes.
I still, when I approach a roundabout and I get
there, I'm still not 100% sure who goes first.
And it's like an innate thing. It comes from
naturally., I do not know whether what side
is my left and what side is my right. And
you can say to me, oh, hold up your fingers like
that. But it's still, it's the fact that I don't
immediately know. Most people just... Do you just
know what side of your body is your left and what
is your right. Yes. I have to check. And then
that takes me a second and then by that point,
someone's already beeped me behind in the
car and then I'm freaked out. Oh yeah,
but it's always been that way. I mean even
when I'm working on Excel and it's like delete
left column, delete right column. I always
have to be like left, right, one, two. Okay,
it's that one that needs to be deleted. See,
I believe if you practise something enough,
whatever it is, you will overcome it. It just
depends how long it takes you to then overcome
it. You have witnessed me struggle with
my lefts and rights. It's something more
than just a lack of practise. You're perfect,
don't beat yourself down. And manipulative.
Okay, you can ask me one more question. What
did Will want to be when he was younger? Ah,
there are various things I think. I remember once
you met your friend's dad who was an investment
banker and was really rich and cool. So you wanted
to be an investment banker. For one night. Yeah.
I know that you wanted to be a farmer
for quite a large part of your childhood.
Did you ever want to be a rugby player? Yes.
You wanted to be a rugby player as well.
What about when you were a little child? Did
you ever want to be like a fireman or something?
I think it was probably something to do with
farming. Yeah. Yeah. Growing up on a farm helps.
Do you know what I wanted to be when I was a
child? I know you wanted to work in makeup,
but that was later on. No, it wasn't makeup.
What? Reconstructive plastic surgery. I did
not know that. You didn't know that. That's the
first question in all of this that I didn't know.
When I was younger, I really loved making faces
out of clay. And so I thought the perfect job
for me would be to be a plastic surgeon but
I wanted it to be a reconstructive one. So
like people in car crashes and stuff, I could
like make their faces look the way they did.
And so I even did chemistry and biology and things
at A Levels to carry on this until I realised no,
I don't have a medicine degree in me. I'm not
dedicated, hardworking or possibly intelligent
enough to do that. So then I want to do
marketing and now I'm a YouTuber. Natural
progression. My parents are so proud. Okay, that's
it from us. I hope you enjoyed learning a little
bit more about both of us, but more importantly,
I hope you learned lots and lots of interesting
vocabulary. If you would like to read the
full transcript and get a full list of all
the vocabulary we used, all of the pronunciation,
the examples, the definitions, we've included some
listening comprehension questions. We've got a
quiz on the vocabulary. Download the e-book. I
know you're getting ready to point in the right
direction. Where do they click? Just here? Yes.
Yes. You click just down here. You sign up for the
mailing list and it'll come automatically to your
inbox and you'll be signed up to my newsletter.
You'll get all my future PDFs, my news, updates
and offers. Don't forget to connect with me on
all of my social media. I've got my Instagram
and my Facebook. I've also got my website where
I've got loads of lessons and a free interactive
pronunciation tool where you can click on phonemes
and hear how they're pronounced, and hear me
pronouncing words containing those phonemes. I've
also got all of my English courses now and Will
has helped create these. It's been an amazing
project, hasn't it? It's a team effort. Yeah,
'cause we actually work together now and it's
been really awesome. So we've got a B1 programme,
the B2 programme, our pronunciation programme.
And our C1's coming out in May. It is, I'll leave
a waiting list down below or if it's already
out, then I'm sure we'll put a link somewhere
and we've got our challenges as well. I think
we'll see them soon for another lesson. Bye-Bye.