Welcome back to JForrest English.
I'm Jennifer.
And today we're going to read a news article
together an advanced news article so you can
learn all of the natural Expressions, Advanced
vocabulary, and complex, grammar naturally
and easily.
Let's get started, our headline nice and short
life on Mars.
A very interesting topic, a new study published
in the journal science,
Shows definitive evidence of organic matter
on the surface of Mars, organic matter, simply
means living matter matter.
That is living.
For example, in this picture, it looks like
there's some green when you see green, you
think plants.
So it looks like living matter, organic matter.
Now, let's take a look at this shows, evidence
shows definitive evidence.
When I See This I say, wow definitive evidence.
Definitive is an adjective.
That means firm, final or complete.
So this evidence is firm its final.
You can think of it as
not
to be questioned.
So you can't question this evidence.
It's firm and final.
So real evidence, it makes it a lot
stronger
of organic matter, on the surface of Mars.
Now, notice here, we have the journal science
and you see those science has a cap.
Capital S, this is because it's a proper noun,
and you need to capitalize the first letter
of a proper noun, proper noun,
and as a proper noun because the name of the
journal is science, that's why it has a capital
S. But if you were just talking about this
subject science, I love science.
Class, you don't need to capitalize it because
in this case it's not a proper noun.
The
Otto was collected by NASA's nuclear-powered
rover Curiosity again.
This is a great example, curiosity, which
you probably know as a noun curiosity is a
good thing when you're a student.
But in this case, it's the name of the Rover.
The name of the Rover is curiosity and that's
why we have a capital first letter.
It's a proper noun, it confirms the Rover.
Citee confirms earlier findings that the red
planet once contained.
Carbon based compounds, I'll be honest with
you, I'm not exactly sure what a carbon-based
compound is.
It's a compound that contains carbon, that's
all I know about that.
Red planet is another name for the planet
Mars because it is red.
So, when you see red planet, you know, they're
talking about Mars,
These compounds, they're talking about the
carbon based compounds.
Also called organic molecules are essential
ingredients for life as scientists understand
it.
Now notice how they explain what these compounds
are, or why they're important because the
average
person
like me who doesn't have a scientific background
has no idea what a carbon-based compound is.
So they explain what this is.
So now I know
No.
Okay.
Essential meaning very important extremely
important.
Important and not just important very important.
Essential ingredients for life as scientists
understand it.
So now I know you can't have life without
these carbon-based compounds and they have
found definitive evidence that these compounds
exist on Mars.
The red planet, essentially saying that life
on Mars is possible.
I've summarized all of the lesson notes and
you can find them in our free lesson PDF,
you can look for the link in the description.
Are in the first comment, let's continue the
organic molecules were found in Mars's Gale
crater a large area that may have been a watery
Lake over 3 billion years ago, the Rover encountered,
traces of the molecule in rocks, extracted
from the area, when you extract something,
it means you remove it or take it out.
So they have a raw
Rock.
And within this rock, there are molecules,
so they took those molecules out.
They extracted it.
This is also the terminology you use.
If you need to get a tooth removed, you
can
extract a tooth, which means simply to remove
it.
So, to remove or take out to remove or take
out and you remove something generally from
something else.
So, you
Act the molecules from The Rock.
The Rocks, also contain sulfur, which scientists
speculate helped preserve the Organics even
when the Rocks were exposed to the harsh,
radiation on the surface of the planet.
Remember, we're talking about the planet Mars.
Now, let's take a look at this verb.
Speculate a very common verb,
When you speculate on something, it means
you essentially guess what the answer is and
you do that because you don't have enough
information to be certain if you're certain,
it means you 100%.
No.
So you can present that information as a fact,
but if you're just guessing you use the verbs
speculate.
So when your audience here, speculate that
They know that you are not 100% certain you
are in fact guessing so scientists speculate
so they don't actually know that this is 100%
correct.
It's their best guest based on the information
they have scientists speculate helped preserve
the Organics even that when the Rocks were
exposed to the harsh
radiation.
Let's take a look at harsh.
Harsh is an adjective.
So, I could say exposed to the radiation,
which means the radiation affected it.
It was in the same area as the radiation,
so it was exposed to the radiation to the
harsh radiation.
So harsh is an adjective.
That modifies radiation, and harsh means unpleasant,
unkind cruel.
More severe than necessary.
So radiation is very strong and they're saying
that this radiation was very severe, perhaps
more severe than it, usually is the harsh
radiation on the surface of the planet.
Let's move on.
Scientists are quick to state that the presence
of these organic molecules is not sufficient
evidence for ancient Life on Mars as the molecules
could have been formed by non living processes.
So here, they're casting some doubt Incheon
Life on Mars.
So, they're saying right now, we don't have
enough evidence to say that previously,
In ancient times, there was Life on Mars so
that would be ancient life.
So not sufficient is saying we don't have
enough evidence not sufficient, so not enough
not
enough to be convincing not enough.
And in this case to convince
You could say, I don't have sufficient time
so in that case is not enough time to do something.
I don't have sufficient time to complete this
article.
I don't have enough time to do it.
So the scientists are suggesting, there could
be another reason why these molecules are
there.
But it's still one of the most astonishing
discoveries, which could lead to Future Revelations.
Let's take a look at astonishment as an adjective.
This means surprising or it can be amazing.
That was astonishing that was amazing, but
maybe it was that was astonishing.
It was surprising at the same time, so it
depends on how it's being used in this.
This case, it could be really either the most
astonishing discoveries which could lead to
Future Revelations.
Let's look at Revelation in this case, it's
a noun, it comes from the verb reveal.
So when you reveal something, you make that
information known.
It's the same case as all Revelation a revelation
is when a fact becomes known.
Now it can be
When a unknown
fact
becomes known.
So before we didn't know it and now we know
it, it's a revelation or it can be when a
secret fact becomes known.
So certain people knew it but the general
public didn't not.
So when the general public found out what
a revelation, remember this comes from the
verb to reveal.
You and you reveal a secret which means you
share a secret that you previously had not
shared especially when one considers the other
startling fine that Curiosity uncovered around
5 years ago.
Remember curiosity is the name of NASA's rover
which is the machine that operates on the
surface of the planet Mars.
Now let's look at startling as an
- a startling fine.
When something is startling.
It's surprising but usually in a worrisome
way.
So you could say, I went to the doctor and
I got some startling news that doesn't sound
very good because it's news that surprised
you but generally in a negative way, in a
worrisome way.
So especially when one considers the
The other startling find that Curiosity uncovered
around 5 years ago.
So we'll find out what that startling find
is that surprising fine but somehow in some
sort of a
negative
way perhaps a worrisome way the Rover analyzes
the air around it.
Periodically periodically is an adverb that
means from time to time periodically from
time to time.
So, consistently means all the time, but periodically
means perhaps once a week, or once a day,
so on a schedule, but not all the time, which
would be consistently.
Are you enjoying this lesson?
If you are?
Then I want to tell you about the finally
fluent Academy.
This is my premium training program, where
we study native English speakers on TV movies.
He's YouTube and the news so you can improve
your listening skills.
A fast English and learn Advanced phrasal
verbs, idioms, expressions, and vocabulary,
and grammar and pronunciation all in a very
natural fun, engaging way and you'll have
me as your personal coach so you can look
in the description or the comment section
for more information on how to join.
Now, let's continue on and in 2014, it Rover,
it found that
Are contained another of the most basic organic
molecules, and a key ingredient of natural,
gas methane.
So the Rover found another molecule on the
planet.
Mars methane, one of the characteristics.
A methane is that it only survives a few
hundred
years.
So, a few hundred to me.
That sounds like
Jared, maybe 400 maybe 500 because a few is
more than 2 because 2 is a couple a couple
hundred years is too and few is generally
more than 2 but less than definitely less
than 10 325.
I would say a few hundred years.
This means that something somewhere on Mars
is replenishing.
The supply when something is real
One ish, it means it's filled up again.
So for example, if a lake had water and then
there was a drought, very dry conditions and
all the water evaporated.
So if you put more water in that Lake, your
replenishing, the lake.
You're filling the lake again.
So there are saying that something on the
Planet.
Mars is replenishing.
The supply of methane, which could be the
startling, find it.
Surprising.
And maybe there's reason to be concerned.
What is this?
That's replenishing.
The supply.
How is it doing this?
What does it mean for us on earth?
That could be the startling part
According to NASA, Mars immense thousands
of tons of methane at a time.
The verb.
Mm, it simply means to to produce or to send
out to produce.
Or send out, but we use this in very specific
cases.
We use it with gases.
In this case, we also use this with sounds
sounds.
So the, the truck emits, a lot of gas for
one.
And a lot of noise.
Oh, the sound that that truck is emitting,
or the building is emitting.
It's really hurting my ears.
We also use this.
S4 light.
So the airport emits, a lot of light, its
blinding Mars, immense, thousands of tons
of methane at a time, the level of methane
Rises and Falls as seasonal intervals in the
year.
Almost as if the planet is breathing, it sounds
a little strange.
Perhaps, that's the startling information
here.
NASA specs, the methane comes from deep under
the surface of the planet, the variations
in temperature on the surface of Mars, cause
the molecule, which is methane to flow upwards
at higher or lower levels.
Okay?
So this is the, scientists are speculating
because if you suspect something,
you don't know for sure.
I'm sure otherwise you would say NASA knows
the methane comes but they suspect, which
means they're about, 80% sure they're guessing.
So again, you could also use the verb speculate,
NASA speculates, the methane comes from deep
under the surface so they don't know.
100%, for example, in the winter, the gas
could get trapped
Underground.
I see crystals.
Okay, so, this is what's happening to the
methane.
These crystals called clathrates melt in the
summer and release the gas.
So, this is their theory on how this gas is
being released at different times of the year
in winter.
It's frozen.
The gas is Frozen in these icy crystals, but
in summer when these
Crystals melt, they release the methane.
Again, this is not a fact because there are
speculating they suspect.
This is what is happening.
They don't know it to be true.
However, the source of the methane is still
a complete mystery.
Complete is an adjective and it means very
great or the highest
possible.
So we're seeing it's a mystery, but not just
a mystery.
Imagine the greatest mystery you've ever thought
of, that's a complete mystery, it's a very
great mystery, the highest mystery possible.
It's a complete mystery.
So the source meaning, how the methane is
there originally?
Where does the methane come from?
That is a
Complete mystery, the world of astrobiology
considers.
Both of these studies, a historical milestone.
A milestone is an important event and it's
an important event in history, or in your
life as well.
An important event in history or one's life.
For example, one of the big Milestones is,
when you graduate from school, that's a milestone.
That's an important event in your life.
When you graduate, when you get married, when
you get your first job when you have a baby,
E, you buy your first car, buy your first
house, these are all Milestones, but of course,
there are also historical milestones.
And this, the information found in these studies
is one of those Milestones.
According to this information, Mars is not
a dead Planet.
So of course, a dead Planet would be a planet
that cannot sustain life.
On the contrary we use this as a transition
word.
We want to introduce a contrasting point.
So, dead planet is the one point.
Now, the contrasting point would have to show
something with life and we can use on the
contrary Mars is not a dead planet on the
contrary.
It is quite active with life, with molecules
with organic matter and maybe changing and
becoming more
Edible, if you describe something as habitable,
it means you're able to live there because
the conditions are appropriate.
So able to live there, for example, a very,
very old house that has a lot of damage might
not be habitable is not suitable to live there.
You're not able to live there or after a flood
or not.
Cyril disaster.
Maybe your home is no longer habitable.
Of course this means.
Further research is necessary.
Scientists say they need to send new equipment
to Mars equipment that can measure the air
and soil with more Precision.
More Precision, is another way of saying,
more accuracy accuracy, they need to be more
accurate.
There are already missions.
Underway underway means they're in progress.
Now in progress now,
In progress.
Now the European space agency's exomars ship
lands in 2020 and will be able to drill into
the ground on Mars to analyze what it finds.
Additionally, NASA is sending another Mars
Rover in the same year to collect samples
of Martian, soil and return them to Earth.
So,
Martian.
This comes from the word Mars.
Just like, if you live in Italy, you're an
Italian.
If you live on Mars, you're a martian.
That can be something you can maybe look forward
to.
So live on Mars equals Martian, Martian soil,
Italian wine, Pizza tomatoes.
For example, Martian soil,
And notice how Mars Martian Earth also have
that Capital first letter because they are
proper nouns.
Remember, we talked about proper nouns at
the beginning.
Proper nouns.
So you need Capital first letter and here
NASA is in all capitals because we also capitalize
acronyms.
So each letter stands for something to be
honest, I don't know what NASA stands for.
I
The essay is space agency.
National, what's the a Association space agency?
That doesn't sound right?
What is the acronym for NASA?
Do, you know, put it in the comments because
honestly, I'm not sure, I'm pretty sure essay
is space agency, but I don't know what the
n and the A stand for because nobody ever
says it.
Everybody says NASA.
Let's continue again.
Let me know in the comments.
The possibility of Life on Mars has fascinated
humans for Generations.
It has been the subject of endless science
fiction, novels and films.
If you describe something as endless it means
again and again and again.
So how's you know, there are always movies
and books about aliens.
Martians life on other planets, right?
So again and again and again non-ending.
Again, and again, non-ending endless.
Are we alone in the universe?
Ooh.
Or have there been other life forms within
our solar system if the current missions to
the red planet?
Which again means Mars Mars.
If the current missions to the red planet
continue.
It looks as if
we may discover the answer very soon.
Wow.
Isn't that a interesting way to end an article?
So that's our article on Mars.
Now I will go back and I'll read the article
from start to finish and this time you can
focus on my pronunciation Life on Mars.
A new study published in the journal science
shows definitive evidence of organic matter
on the surface of Mars.
The data was collected by NASA's nuclear-powered
rover, Curiosity it confirms earlier findings
that the red planet once contain carbon based
compounds, these compounds also called organic
molecules are essential ingredients for life
as
as scientists understand it.
The organic molecules were found in Mars's
Gail cater a large area that may have been
a watery link.
Over 3 billion years ago, the Rover encountered,
traces of the molecule in rocks, extracted
from the area.
The wrongs also contains sulfur, which scientists
speculate helped preserve the Organics even
when the Rocks were exposed to the harsh radiation.
On the surface of the planet, scientists are
quick to state that the presence of these
organic molecules is not sufficient evidence
for ancient Life on Mars as the molecules,
could have been formed by non-living processes,
but it's still one of the most astonishing
discoveries which could lead to Future Revelations.
Especially when one considers the other startling
find that Curiosity, uncovered around five
years ago, the Rover, analyzes the air around
it, periodically, and in 2014, it found the
air contained.
Another of the most basic organic molecules
and a key ingredient of natural, gas methane.
One of the characteristics of methane is that
it only survives a
200 years.
This means that something somewhere on Mars
is replenishing the supply.
According to NASA, Mars immense, thousands
of tons of methane at a time, this level of
methane, Rises and falls at seasonal intervals
in the year.
Almost as if the planet is breathing it NASA
specs, the methane comes from deep under the
surface of the planet.
The very
Patience in temperature on the surface of
Mars, cause the molecule to flow upwards at
higher and higher levels.
For example, in the winter, the gas could
get trapped in underground.
I see crystals these crystals called clathrates
melt in the summer and release the gas.
However, the source of the methane is still
a complete mystery.
The world of astrobiology, considers both,
Both of these studies as historical Milestones.
According to this information, Mars is not
a dead planet.
On the contrary.
It is quite active and maybe changing and
becoming more habitable.
Of course, this means further research is
necessary.
Scientists say they need to send new equipment
to Mars equipment that can measure the air
and soil with more Precision.
There are already
Missions under way the European space.
Agency's exomars ship lands in 2020 and will
be able to drill into the ground on Mars to
analyze what it finds.
Additionally, NASA is sending another Mars
Rover in the same year to collect samples
of Martian soil and return them to Earth the
possibility of Life on Mars has fascinated
humans for Generations.
It has
on the subject of endless science fiction,
novels and films.
Are we alone in the universe or have there
been other life forms within our solar system
if the current missions to the red planet
continue?
It looks as if we may discover the answer
very soon if you like this lesson then make
sure you subscribe because I put lessons like
this every single week and make sure you get
this free speaking guide where I share six
tips on how to
Speak English, fluently and confidently.
You can get it from my website right here
and why don't you get started with your next
lesson right now?