- Hello lovely students
and welcome back to English with Lucy.
So many of my students
want to improve their conversation skills,
but sometimes it can be really hard
to think of the right question to say,
and it's even harder to
think of a good response
to keep conversation going.
If you want to keep a conversation going,
it's really important that
you ask open-ended questions.
This is a key part of small talk.
I really want to help you practise.
So today I have got 100
open-ended small talk questions.
Open-ended questions are
questions that people cannot reply
yes or no to.
They have to say more than that.
I am going to be asked these 100 questions
and I am going to give you genuine answers
so you can learn from me.
And to help you even further,
I have created an e-book for this lesson
that you can download for free.
It contains all 100 questions.
It contains the full
transcript of my answers
with key vocabulary and a quiz.
It is the ultimate small
talk conversation e-book.
If you would like to download
my free small talk conversation e-book,
all you've got to do is click on the link
in the description box.
You enter your name
and your email address,
you sign up to my mailing list,
and the e-book will arrive
directly in your email inbox.
After that, you will automatically receive
all of my free PDFs and lessons
along with my news updates and offers.
Right, let's get started with
the small talk questions.
I'm already nervous.
- [Will] First topic,
general small talk questions.
Question one, how was your day today?
- It's been pretty busy,
but I've had a good day.
Thanks.
- [Will] Two, what did
you do last weekend?
- Last weekend I visited
my family in Bedfordshire
and we celebrated my brother's birthday.
- [Will] Three, what hobbies or interests
do you have outside of work?
- I really like running, and
I've just bought a treadmill,
so I'm enjoying using that.
- [Will] Four, have you
watched any interesting movies
or TV shows recently?
- I've really been enjoying
watching "The White Lotus."
It's quite relaxing
because it's set in a holiday destination.
- [Will] Five, what type of music
do you enjoy listening to?
- I honestly don't
listen to a lot of music,
but I do really like Taylor Swift.
She always makes me smile.
- [Will] Six, do you have any pets
and what's unique about them?
- Ooh, good question.
I have a dog and a cat.
And what's unique about them
is they have Spanish names
because I love Spain.
Diego, the dog, and Alfonso, the cat.
- [Will] Seven, what's
your favourite thing
about the current season?
- Ooh, we're coming into spring,
and I love seeing all of
the bulbs that I've planted
in my garden start to peek
up and show their petals.
- [Will] Eight, what's the
most recent book you've read
that you've enjoyed?
- "L'amica geniale," "My Brilliant Friend"
by Elena Ferrante, an Italian author.
I read it in English,
but my goal is to read it in Italian.
- [Will] Nine, what's your
favourite type of cuisine
to eat, and why?
- Ooh, that's hard.
I love so many different types of cuisine.
I love Lebanese food.
Anything that involves
fresh fruits and vegetables.
- [Will] 10, do you
prefer living in a city
or a rural area, and why?
- I absolutely prefer
to live in a rural area
because I find nature so relaxing,
although I do miss the
conveniences of living in a city.
- [Will] Second topic,
work and career small talk questions.
Question 11, what do you do for work
and what's one thing you enjoy about it?
- I run an education company.
So when I'm not on YouTube,
I'm making my English courses,
my online English courses.
And my favourite part of the
job is receiving feedback
from my students who
have taken the courses.
- [Will] 12, how did you get started
in your line of work?
- It all started with this
YouTube channel here in 2019,
and then slowly it grew into
something a little bit bigger.
- [Will] 13, what project
are you currently working on?
- We are currently
working on a huge project,
which is our C1 level course,
our advanced English course.
It's going to be amazing.
It's going to come out in May.
So if you're watching this in the future,
check the description box.
I will leave a link.
And if you are interested,
I have left the waiting list
so you'll be the first to know.
- [Will] 14, what do you think
the future of your industry looks like?
- I think it has a lot more
artificial intelligence involved.
- [Will] 15, what's one
thing you've learned recently
that's helped you in your job?
- I have learned to listen
carefully to criticism,
but to not take it all to heart.
- [Will] 16, what's the
best professional advice
you've ever received?
- Well, it's not the most impressive,
amazing, mind-blowing
piece of advice ever,
but when my YouTube channel
was starting to take off,
I was starting to make
a little bit of income,
I asked my dad if I should do it
or if I should continue
with my planned career path.
And he said, "Give it a go."
"Do it for two years."
"If it doesn't work, you'll only be 23."
"All you've lost is a little bit of time."
It ended up being the best piece of advice
I've ever followed.
- [Will] 17, what do you think sets
successful people apart in your field?
- I think they are
excited about what they do
and what they create.
- [Will] 18, what's one
challenge you've faced at work
and how did you overcome it?
- One thing I found really difficult
is managing a team of people.
That's not ever something I
thought I was going to be doing.
And I've been trying to overcome it.
I'm still learning.
Recently, I have opened my calendar
so that at the beginning of every month,
everyone who works for me can
check in for a 20-minute chat.
We start this next week,
so I hope that we'll
help me be more in touch
with my employees.
- [Will] 19, do you have any career goals
you're working towards?
- I would say more of a lifestyle goal.
I would like to not have
to work all the time
whilst my children are young.
I am not expecting children at the moment,
but I would like to
have them in the future.
- [Will] 20, have you ever had
an interesting work experience or job?
- I worked in a juice
bar for a number of years
and I learned a lot about fruit.
And I love fruits.
That was great for me.
- [Will] Third topic,
travel small talk questions.
Question 21, have you
travelled anywhere recently
and where did you go?
- Most recently, we visited Thailand,
and we went to Phuket and Koh
Yao Noi, and it was beautiful.
- [Will] 22, what's your favourite place
you've ever visited and why?
- That would have to be Seville.
I totally fell in love with the city
and its culture and its people.
- [Will] 23, where would you like to go
on your next trip?
- We really would like to go to Vietnam.
I am desperate to try
pho, I think it's called.
The bone broth soup and with noodles, pho,
and I just really am
desperate to see that country.
- [Will] 24, do you
prefer relaxing vacations
or adventure trips and why?
- I like to have a good balance.
I do need to get the
relaxation out of my system.
I need to read a book,
I need to lie in the shade,
I need to swim,
but I go a bit stale if I
stay relaxing for too long.
I need to do things and see things.
- [Will] 25, what's one unique
or exotic food you've
tried while travelling?
- Most recently, mangosteen.
That fruit blew my mind.
It was so delicious.
I wish I could eat it everyday.
- [Will] 26, what's the craziest
or most memorable thing
you've done on vacation?
- I would say climbing
to the top of Lion's Head
in Cape Town at sunrise.
That was absolutely beautiful.
- [Will] 27, what's your
favourite way to travel?
- In style.
- [Will] 28, do you
prefer travelling alone
or with others?
- Always with my husband.
Well, my husband was a farmer
and now he works with me.
And before, I used to travel a lot alone
and I used to think,
"Damn it, he would love to see this."
I always used to feel so sad
that he couldn't come with me.
So now it's such a pleasure
to travel together.
- [Will] 29, have you ever had
a negative travel experience
and how did you handle it?
- Yes, I once turned up at
a supposedly five star hotel
that was nothing like the photos,
and I very calmly explained
that I was going to move to another hotel
and I'd like a refund.
And luckily, they did comply.
- [Will] 30, what's
one cultural experience
you've had while travelling
that you'll never forget?
- La Feria de Abril in Sevilla,
the feria in Seville.
It's just this incredible party
with striped marquees everywhere.
Everyone wears flamingo dresses.
(gasps) I can't wait to go back.
- [Will] Fourth topic,
hobbies and interests
small talk questions.
Question 31, what's one hobby or interest
you are passionate about?
- Exercise.
It just makes me feel so good.
- [Will] 32, what's the most recent hobby
or interest you've taken up?
- I would say learning
Italian with my tutor Aliche,
who is amazing.
I found her on Languator,
which is a platform that I'm a part of.
You can find your own tutor
for the language you are learning.
There's a link down below.
- [Will] 33, do you
have any hidden talents
that people might not know about?
- I can play the violin, and
I'm also really flexible.
- [Will] 34, what's one
thing you've learned recently
that relates to your hobby or interest?
(Lucy speaking in foreign language)
- I've learned to speak
Italian a little bit.
- [Will] 35, have you ever taken a class
or workshop related to
your hobby or interest?
- Ooh, well, a workshop I took recently
was a jewellery making workshop
where I learned to make a silver bangle,
and that was great fun.
- [Will] 36, what's the most adventurous
or daring thing you've done
related to your hobby or interest?
- Well, to do with language learning,
I think going to Spain
at the age of 16, 17
and spending a week there.
Immersing myself in the
language was quite daring.
I spent ages saving up for
the language course myself
and it was fantastic
and the start of my language
teaching career basically.
- [Will] 37, what's one
thing you like to learn
or accomplish related to
your hobby or interest?
- Well, if we're going to
talk about language learning,
I always like to learn
how to make people laugh
in the language I'm learning.
That gives me a lot of satisfaction.
- [Will] 38, do you prefer indoor
or outdoor activities, and why?
- Well, it's hard to say.
If the weather's good, outdoor 100%.
But I'm English, I live in England,
so I've just bought a
treadmill to run indoors.
- [Will] 39, what's one
activity or interest
you'd like to try in the future?
- What do I wanna do?
I don't know.
- Golf?
- No.
(Will laughing)
Oh, I don't know why, but I
really want to try archery.
- [Will] 40,
what's the most interesting
thing you've learned
unrelated to work or school?
- How to run a business.
It is such an amazing experience,
and I learned absolutely
nothing about it at school.
- [Will] Fifth topic,
food and drink small talk questions.
Question 41, what's your
favourite type of food, and why?
- Fruit, because it's so refreshing,
it tastes amazing, and
it makes me feel good.
- [Will] 42, do you enjoy cooking
and what's your favourite dish to prepare?
- I love cooking,
and my go-to dish is
actually normally a risotto.
I can whip up a good risotto
with very few ingredients in my fridge.
- [Will] 43, what's one unique
or exotic food you've tried and enjoyed?
- Well, in Thailand we actually
went on a cookery course
and we learned to make pad thai
and mango sticky rice
and green Thai curry,
and that was amazing.
- [Will] 44, do you have
any dietary restrictions
and how do you manage them?
- I don't.
I'm very, very lucky to have
no dietary restrictions,
so I don't need to manage them.
- [Will] 45, what's your
favourite restaurant or cafe
and what do you like about it?
- I love a good local pub.
We've got some great ones around us.
And for me, the best
part is on a sunny day,
an unexpectedly sunny day in England,
sitting outside in a pub garden.
- [Will] 46, what's one dish or cuisine
you've been wanting to
try but haven't yet?
- Vietnamese food.
I need to try pho.
- [Will] 47, what's your
favourite type of alcohol
or non-alcoholic beverage?
- I really like wine and gin for alcohol.
Non-alcoholic, I love fresh fruit juice.
Fresh fruit and vegetable juice.
- [Will] 48, do you prefer sweet
or savoury foods, and why?
- Definitely savoury.
Sometimes sweet foods can be overpowering.
And also, because we eat
them at the end of the meal,
I often don't have room.
I'm not very good at managing my appetite.
- [Will] 49, what's one
food or drink you've tried
that you didn't like?
- For me, it's anything that
is really, really spicy.
I can handle spice but not
obnoxious levels of spies.
Not the level that hurts your tongue.
- [Will] 50, have you ever
tried cooking a new dish,
and how did it turn out?
- I tried cooking pierogi,
I think they're called.
Potato dumplings that you often find
in Ukrainian and Polish cuisines.
And they went okay.
I found them delicious,
but when I showed my polish friend,
she said I'd done them wrong.
- [Will] Sixth topic,
family and relationships
small talk questions.
Question 51, do you have any siblings
and what's your
relationship with them like?
- I do.
I have a younger brother called George.
He's four and a half
years younger than me,
and we have a fantastic relationship.
I consider him a good friend.
- [Will] 52, what's your family like
and what do you enjoy most
about spending time with them?
- My family is small.
My mom, my dad, my
brother, my husband and me.
And what I love about
spending time with them
is that we just do not stop laughing.
- [Will] 53, do you have
any nieces or nephews
and what do you enjoy doing with them?
- Ah.
- [Will] Such a hard question.
- I have got a niece or nephew
that is due to be born in April,
so I'm hopefully gonna be an aunt.
I'm so excited.
Haven't met them yet,
but if they are watching
this in the future,
I'm so excited to meet you.
- [Will] 54, are you in
a relationship or married
and how did you meet your partner?
- Yes, I am married to my husband, Will,
who is doing a very good job
of reading out these questions to me.
- [Will] Hi, everyone.
- And we met at Young Farmers' Clubs,
which is a very British
rural teenager social club,
which is just as cool as it sounds.
But if you get a husband out of it,
it's totally worth going to.
- [Will] 55, do you have any children
and what do you enjoy
most about being a parent?
- I don't have any children
so I can't really answer that question,
but I hope to have them
at some point one day.
- [Will] 56, what's
one challenge you faced
in a past relationship and
how did you overcome it?
- Being unsuitable for
each other and leaving.
- [Will] 57, what's one
piece of relationship advice
you'd give to someone
in a new relationship?
- Infatuation is very
different to long lasting love,
but you can enjoy both
stages with each other
in different ways.
- [Will] 58, have you
ever been on a memorable
or interesting date and what happened?
- Once I went on a date with a guy
and he asked me what I
wanted to drink and I said,
"Please, can I have a gin and tonic?"
And the barman said, "normal or slimline?"
And the guy looked me up and
down and said, "slimline."
And it wasn't a joke.
He was weird.
- [Will] 59, do you have a best friend
and what's one thing you love about them?
- I have two best friends and
I love them in different ways.
I've got my friend, Ellie.
I have loads of history with her.
We've known each other since
we were born basically.
And my friend Felicity is
someone I see sporadically.
But when we get together,
it's like no time has passed at all.
- [Will] 60, what's one
memorable family holiday
or trip you've taken together?
- So growing up,
my grandparents had a little apartment
in the south of Portugal.
They used to hibernate there
in the winter and play golf.
And we went there every
summer as a family.
And I hadn't been back
there for seven years,
and I went back last year with
my husband and my parents,
and it was amazing to be in
my childhood holiday location
and to have my husband.
I felt like a child and
an adult all at once.
It was a crazy, crazy experience.
- [Will] Seventh topic, current
events small talk questions.
Question 61, have you been following
any interesting news stories lately,
and what are your thoughts on them?
- One big news story in the UK recently
was about a woman that went
missing called Nicola Bulley,
and I found that really, really scary
and fascinating to watch at the same time.
- [Will] 62, what's your opinion
on the current political
climate or social issues?
- Oh, well that's a big question.
Dire.
- [Will] 63, have you
tried any new technology
or gadgets recently and
what's your review of them?
- I have been playing around with ChatGPT,
and it has been scary and
useful all at the same time.
- [Will] 64, what's one
recent scientific discovery
or breakthrough that
caught your attention?
- Definitely the development
of artificial intelligence.
I feel that we are at a turning point.
- [Will] 65, have you been
following any sports news,
and what teams or athletes do you support?
- Not really.
I mean, the Six Nations is going on
and my husband talks a lot about it,
but I can't say that sport
really interests me too much.
- [Will] 66, what's your opinion
on the latest celebrity gossip or news?
- I used to follow a lot of
celebrity gossip and news.
I just don't find it
as interesting anymore.
But I do really like
seeing beautiful dresses
on the red carpet.
- [Will] 67, what's your take
on the current state of
the economy or job market?
- I'm really worried about
the economy at the moment.
We have huge inflation.
Food is really expensive.
Fuel is really expensive.
It costs a lot to heat your home.
In the job market, I've heard
rumours that people are taking
a little bit more control
and not accepting as low pay,
and I'm really for that.
- [Will] 68, have you discovered
any interesting books,
podcasts, or other media lately
and what did you like about them?
- There are two podcasts that
I've been enjoying recently,
and they are by two British newspapers
that are leaning to
the left and the right,
so I get both sides of
the same story really.
One is Stories of our
times by The Sunday Times.
The other is Today in
Focus by The Guardian.
And it's really interesting
to hear them both cover
the same story but in
slightly different ways.
- [Will] 69, what's your
opinion on climate change
and what actions do you think
we can take to combat it?
- I feel frustrated by climate change
because there are these huge corporations
making so much of a negative impact
that sometimes as one human
I feel quite insignificant.
But I'm really, really making an effort
to take more control over what I can do
to improve climate change.
- [Will] 70, have you been following
any recent cultural trends or movements,
and what's your take on them?
- I have been interested in the Anti-Work
or Anti-Work Movement.
I like using Reddit,
and I've seen some things
on that Reddit sub-forum
and I find them really interesting
that people are suddenly
sticking it to the man.
- [Will] Eighth topic,
personal small talk questions.
Question 71, where did you
grow up, and what was it like?
- I grew up in a tiny
village in Bedfordshire,
and it was a very happy childhood.
Very rural, in the countryside,
lots of playing in the garden.
- [Will] 72, what's one childhood memory
that stands out to you, and why?
- I remember waking up,
it must have been my
seventh birthday I think,
and my parents had put a
trampoline in the garden.
And I kid you not,
I spent every waking
hour on that trampoline.
I absolutely loved it.
- [Will] 73, what was
your relationship like
with your sibling when
you were both growing up?
- Well, it was funny
because I was five
years older than George.
That's a big gap when
one is two and one is six
or when one is 10 and one is 14.
So we weren't so close as children.
It's only now we are adults
that we are really close.
- [Will] 74, what's the best thing
that's ever happened to you
and how did it make you feel?
- Getting married.
I just felt high on life.
I was so unbelievably happy.
I got to marry the man of my dreams
and be surrounded by everyone I loved.
And it was just after COVID,
so it was the first time
I'd seen so many people
in over two years.
- [Will] 75, what's one challenge
or obstacle you faced in your life
and how did you overcome it?
- I was really ill as a teenager.
From the age of 14 to 16,
I had glandular fever
and then a weird post-viral
chronic fatigue thing,
and it wiped me out,
and it was a rubbish time
and I was very depressed.
It's such a blur that I don't
even know how I overcame it.
I just know that I had a lot
of support from my family.
- [Will] 76, do you
have any personal goals
or aspirations that
you're working towards?
- Oh, a big goal is to have a happy family
with a couple of children.
- [Will] 77, what's one
thing you're proud of
or accomplished recently outside of work?
- I've made some pretty big
charity donations this year
that I am personally
very proud of, I think.
- [Will] 78, who's one
person that's influenced
or inspired you and how have
they impacted your life?
- My dad because he's so supportive,
so kind, so encouraging,
and that's how I hope to be.
- [Will] 79, what's one thing you've done
for someone else recently
and how did it make you feel?
- I helped someone very close with me
achieve something they've
wanted to do for a long time,
and it made me feel really good.
And that's all I can say.
- [Will] 80, what's one
thing you've learned in life
that's helped you grow or
become a better person?
- Not everyone is going to
like you, and that is okay.
- [Will] Ninth topic,
technology small talk questions.
Question 81, what's one
technology or gadget
you can't live without, and why?
- Oh, it has to be my phone.
So much of what I do is done on my phone.
- [Will] 82, have you tried any new apps,
software, or devices recently
and what's your review of them?
- I've started wearing an Apple Watch,
and I've found it really good,
although the battery life is terrible.
- [Will] 83, do you prefer Apple
or Android products, and why?
- I prefer Apple products.
I think they are really
user-friendly, and unfortunately,
I love the way they all
connect with each other.
- [Will] 84, have you
ever built or customised
a computer or device
and how did it turn out?
- No, I've never done that.
I would be interested in learning though.
- [Will] 85, what's one recent
technological advancement
or development that you find interesting?
- AI, definitely artificial intelligence.
I feel like we're on the
cusp of something amazing.
This is the worst it's ever going to be.
It's only going to get better,
and I feel you have to
keep up or get left behind.
- [Will] 86, have you
tried virtual reality
or augmented reality, and
what's your experience like?
- I have, very briefly at an event,
and I thought it was amazing.
I'd love to explore it more.
- [Will] 87, what's one useful
app or tool you use regularly
and how does it help you?
- I use an app to track
my menstrual cycle,
and it helps me understand
why I'm feeling rubbish some days.
- [Will] 88, do you think
technology has more positive
or negative effects on our lives, and why?
- I would say in the grand
scheme of things, positive.
There are lots of negative parts,
but definitely for medical
advancements, positive.
- [Will] 89, what's
one technological issue
or challenge that you
wish could be solved?
- My internet connection, please.
I can't believe it's 2023,
and in rural parts of the UK,
you still can't get
solid, reliable internet.
- [Will] 90, do you have
any tips or recommendations
for staying safe and secure online?
- Don't trust anyone.
There are so many scammers.
If it sounds too good to
be true, it probably is.
- [Will] 10th topic, lifestyle
small talk questions.
Question 91, what's your
typical daily routine
and how do you make the most of your time?
- We normally wake up at around 6:30.
I nearly always have
porridge for breakfast,
lunch between midday and one,
and dinner between six and eight.
That's a bit random.
And I make the most of my time
by trying to get as much done
in the morning as possible.
- [Will] 92, do you prefer
to stay in or go out,
and what do you enjoy doing
during your free time?
- Oh, I like a balance of both.
I end up getting really
stale if I stay in too much.
I love going out of the weekends
and staying in during the week.
- [Will] 93, what's one activity or hobby
you find most relaxing
or stress relieving?
- I don't know if it's a
hobby, it's an activity,
but taking a bath, and
especially a bath with a view.
I have a bath near a window,
and sometimes there
are sheep in the field,
and it's just lovely.
- [Will] 94, do you have
any daily rituals or habits
that you swear by?
- I have a coffee in bed every
morning, and I love that.
I love that little 20-minute
period of waking up,
having a coffee.
I know lots of people say
you shouldn't have it
first thing in the morning,
but it works for me, and
it makes me feel good.
- [Will] 95, what do you
typically have for lunch?
- I normally have soup in the winter
or a salad in the summer.
- [Will] 96, what's one way
you like to stay active or healthy,
and how has it benefited you?
- Well, we love walking our dog,
so we walk in for at
least an hour every day.
I also have a stationary
bike and a treadmill,
which is great for winter
because I don't have to
go outside when it's cold.
- [Will] 97, do you have
any guilty pleasures
and what do you enjoy about them?
- I love a glass of wine.
I love a Lindor Truffle
every now and again.
- [Will] 98, what's one way
you like to spend a lazy day
or relax after a long week?
- I love collapsing on
the sofa with my husband,
my dog, and my cat, and
watching a predictable movie.
- [Will] 99, what's one
activity or practise you do
to de-stress or unwind?
- I like to listen to audiobooks,
so I might put one on
whilst I'm in the bath.
- [Will] 100, what's one
thing that brings you joy
or fulfilment in life and why?
- There is so many things.
Teaching is one of them.
My husband is another.
My family.
Yeah, that's an impossible
question to end on.
Did you see how even when
it was a closed question,
we'd add something onto
the end to make it open?
I couldn't just say yes or no.
If you really want to
improve your English,
download the e-book that
goes with this lesson.
The link is in the description box.
Don't forget to connect with
me on all of my social media.
I've got my Instagram, my Facebook,
and my website where I have
my free pronunciation tool
where you can click on phonemes
and hear me pronounce those phonemes
and the words that contain those phonemes.
You can also check out all of my courses.
I've got lots of different challenges
and also my B1 course, my B2 course,
and my C1 course is coming
out very soon in May.
I will see you soon for
another lesson, mwah!