Hi. I'm Ronnie, and thank you for watching
my videos. I'm here to give you a wonderful
video about pronunciation-yeah, I said it
right-and also spelling. So it's, like, you
watch one video, and you get two bonus videos
in one. I love these. It's, like, Boxing Day
sale or something. So, Rosie, thank you for
helping me with this, for pointing this out
to me. Love you, girl. Wow. Check this out.
I'm pretty excited about this. We have a lot
of words in English, like I said the first
time. Watch. Okay? And we spell it, W-A-T-C-H.
So if you're first learning this crazy language
called English, our little brains are, like,
okay, we have to say "wa", okay? W-A-T-C-H.
I am watching this video. And that's pretty
hard. I'm going to catch your next video,
Ronnie. I have to get a match to light this
candle. And this hopefully is going to be a
lot easier for you because I've got something
that's super amazingly, fantastically, wonderful,
groundbreaking. In all of these words, here,
we don't have to say the "t". So you're trying to
say "wa-tuh-chuh", "wa-tuh-chuh", "wa-tuh-chuh".
I am... But people don't say that. Guess what?
The "t" is silent. So it's, like, "watch".
Hold on. Hold on. Hold on. Okay. So "cat-tuh-chuh"
becomes "catch". I'm going to catch a ball.
You're going to light something for a candle,
you're going to light a match. You take the
"t" out, and you don't even worry about that
little guy there. The "t", he's off, man.
He's out of here. He's just, like, "See you
later, C-H. You guys do the job." Match. Snatch.
Snatch means to grab something quickly. It
also means "vagina" in slang, so of course
we have to include
"snatch" on the board. No "t".
"Stitch", we don't say "stih-tuh-chuh". "Stitch"
means you take a needle and a thread, and
you sew something. So I have to stitch-not
"stih-tuh-chuh", my shirt. "Bitch", and you
can say that word, okay? Don't worry, I'm
going to teach you about the other word "beach"
later, but feel free. We don't say "bit-tuh-chuh".
"Hey, you're such a bit-tuh-chuh, Ronnie."
Huh, thank you, baby. "Bitch".
"Fetch". Do you have a dog or a person? "Fetch"
means I throw something, and you go get it
and bring it back to me. Now, I have a dog,
and he... I don't know what's wrong. I think
he's broken, actually, because ever since he
was a puppy, I would throw something, like,
"Go fetch", and he'd run and get it. And I'm
waiting, I'm like, "Bring it back. Come on."
And he's like, "No." Puts up his little paw
and goes away. I'm like, "Dude, now I have
to go and find where you put the ball." So,
"fetch" means you throw something, and then
magically someone returns it to you, unless
you're my dog, and then he's like, "Ha-ha.
Go get it yourself,
Ronnie." So, "fetch".
"Scotch".
Truth be told, I don't really like scotch that
much. I'll drink it because I like whiskey.
I prefer Irish whiskey, but scotch, we don't say
scotch. I am scotches. I like scotch whiskey.
It's just scotch. It's easier. And "witch",
the kind with the hat, right? And the broom
and the nose, because most people have brooms
and noses. "Witch", we don't need to say the
"t". So, as I was researching this, and I
thought, "Whoa, super cool. Oh my goodness,
it's so rad we don't need to say the 't'."
Then I thought about spelling, like, "Uh-oh.
How do people know, because we put the "t",
because the "t" is silent, oh no, how are
people going to know when they write, when
they're learning English, if we put a "t"
or we don't put a "t" if we don't say it?" So
then I learned a rule. I hate rules. Because
there are always exceptions to
them. But this one's okay so far.
So, this is our game. Okay? If we have a short
vowel sound-okay?-a short vowel sound means
the vowel does not say its own name. So, in
English, this letter is "a". We don't say
"sn-a-ge". Look at your "sn-a-ge". Okay? This
is a short vowel sound, makes an "a" sound,
so we say "snatch". All of these vowels, here,
are short vowel sounds, so they say "a", "a",
"a", "i", "i", "a", "aw", and "i". If they
were long vowel sounds, they'd say "a", "a",
"a", "i", "i", "e", "o", and "i", so we don't...
We don't say "w-i-ch". Look at the "w-i-ch"
over there. She's so wonderful. So, if it's
a short vowel sound, we have to put the "t",
but we don't say it. Okay? And this is why
I like this rule. I love this rule. Usually,
in English, it's like if it's a short vowel
sound, you do this; if it's a long vowel sound,
you do this. But this rule is easier because
we're like... Guess what? If it's not short,
then we just put a "ch". And when I tell you that
something's not short, I mean it can be a long
vowel and a consonant. So, the vowels in English,
"a", "e", "i", "o", "u"... "a", "e", "i", "o",
"u". Now, when I've said them, I'm saying them
in the long vowel sound, and the consonants are
everything that's not a vowel. So, "b", "c", "d",
"f", "g", "h", "j", "k". All of those guys that
are not vowels are consonants. So, check this
out. We have... Consonant, consonant. Uh-oh,
we have two vowels here. We don't say "b", "e",
"a", "ch". We want to, maybe some people do,
but this is actually "beach". So, this makes a
long vowel sound because we're saying the "e",
we're saying "beach". So, because it makes a
long vowel sound, we're only going to put a "ch",
we're not going to put "th". Consonant, consonant.
Consonants are easy. Same thing with this,
"reach". Okay? If you have problems with the long
vowels and the short vowels or when we have two
vowels together, check out my videos on that.
I've got a really cool technique about how to
say these words because we just say one vowel, not
two. "Roach", "peach", this is a double "e" sound
again, "poach", and "approach". Let's go through
what these words mean. So, "torch". If you have
a phone, sometimes you want a light, and sometimes
it says "flashlight", but in British English it
says "torch". So, "torch" is something that gives
you light. It can be, like, something that you
shine, or it can be fire that you carry around.
But, I mean, most of you are not out hunting
dragons at nighttime, so we don't really use
torches as much, but it's a British word for
"flashlight", so you could have one of those on
your phone. "Lunch". Do you know "lunch"? It's
the thing between breakfast and dinner? It's a
meal. "Beach". Okay? "Bitch". Yes. No "t". Don't
say the "t". So, "bitch", "beach". Make the "e"
long, here. And this word is rhymed. "Reach".
If I reach, it means I'm trying to extend to get
something. Let me reach you. Okay? "Roach". Oh,
two meanings for this one. If you guys like
smoking marijuana, when you get to the end of
your little marijuana, there's a tiny, tiny piece
left. You're like, hmm. You don't want to burn
your finger. Some people eat it, but this is
called a "roach". It's also short for the dirty
little buggers called "cockroaches". So, I don't
know, I guess people don't like saying "cock" all
the time, so instead of "cockroaches", we just
say "roaches". Like, oh, I've got "roaches".
Better than saying I've got "cockroaches".
So, there's no "t". "Poach". Two meanings.
One is if I cook something in boiling water,
I'm poaching it. So, I can poach an egg,
I can poach fish. "Poaching" as a verb is also
when you illegally hunt and kill animals. So,
people are poachers where they go into areas
and kill animals. They kill lions and stuff.
Bad poachers, but no "t". And this word,
"approach". "Approach" means I get nearer
to you, so I'm approaching the camera. So, I
hope that you've learned two things today. One,
"if" is a "tch". I hope you learned five things,
but if it's a "tch", we don't say the "t"
pronunciation. Okay? And the second thing is
about our spelling. If it's a short vowel sound,
we put a "tch". If it's not a short vowel
sound, you're just going to write a "ch".
"Ch". Stay tuned for more wonderful pronunciation,
spelling, vocabulary, grammar tips from me. I'm
Ronnie, and I'm going to get some lunch. Yeah,
by the beach. Mm-hmm. With my bitch. Mm-hmm.