1: I'm going to make some exercises
before breakfast tomorrow.
2: Oh, you mean you're going to do some exercises?
1: Right. Thanks. And after that,
I’m going to do a quick meal.
2: Well, you make a meal, so that's incorrect!
1: Oh okay! After eating, I'll
probably… make the cleaning in my room.
2: Hmm, you will DO the cleaning, not make.
1: So confusing! Now I’m going to DO a phone call
2: You make a phone call, not do!
"Hello, everyone! I’m Kate and this
is English Lessons with Kate channel. Today
we're going to talk about the most common
mistakes in English. Let's go!"
Mistake #1: 'Make' vs. 'Do'
"Make" and "do" are both action words in English.
They can be tricky for people learning English
because sometimes they are used in similar ways.
"Do" is often used when talking about work, jobs,
or tasks. For example. Do your homework. I need to
do the laundry. She does a lot of work every day.
Actions that are regular
or routine often use "do."
For example. I do the dishes every
evening. He does the shopping on Saturdays.
"Make" is used when we
create or produce something.
For example: She made a cake for my birthday.
They are making a documentary about wildlife.
When an action results in a specific
outcome, we use "make". Make a
decision. Make a mistake. Make a promise.
Let’s move on to the next mistake which my
students make all the time.
Mistake #2: Hair vs Hairs
1. Your hairs are so long! "How did you grow….?”
2. Hair, not hairs. Actually,
you should say 'Your hair is so long.'
1. But why? You have so many hair?...
2. You cannot say – MANY
hair. Hair is uncountable.
What?
When we talk
about all the hair on someone's head, we just
say "hair". "Your hair is long." Short hair,
curly hair, straight hair. BUT If we are talking
about a few pieces of hair, then we say "hairs".
Like, "There are some hairs on your shirt."
So, "Your hairs are so long!" is not right.
It should be "Your hair is so long!"
Now let’s talk about pronunciation
mistakes. Mistake #3: Silent Letters
Another common pronunciation mistake is:
Pronouncing Silent Letters
1 - I need to cut these apples.
Give me a knife please.
2 -Sorry, what?
1 -A knife
2 - Oh, you mean a knife. The k is silent.
1 -Yes, a knife
2 - Now I'm going to.... Knead the dough.
1 - What? It's correct to say nead the dough...
2 – Yeah, to knead the dough
The letter K before N is not
pronounced. Like in such words
as – knock, knight, knees, know and so on.
What about this word? How would you read it? It’s
not salmon, it’s salmon. Mispronouncing ‘Salmon’
is also a very popular mistake. In this case,
we kept the silent 'l'. The same rule is
for the words – calm, almond, palm, half.
Mistake #4: Confusing ‘V’ and ‘W’
This one's tricky for many of my
students! vent vs. went , veer vs. weer ,
vow vs. wow Can you hear the difference? The
difference lies in the position of your teeth
and lips. When you pronounce V sound, you bite
your bottom lip with your upper teeth. When you
pronounce W sound, you make your lips round [w].
It’s very important to work on your pronunciation.
And now I want to show you guys an amazing app for
improving your pronunciation: ELSA speak,
which is the sponsor of today's video.
Elsa Speak is a unique English app that uses
innovative artificial intelligence technology.
This app pinpoints your mistakes in English
pronunciation. You speak into the app,
it recognizes your voice and gives you feedback
on how to pronounce words correctly. Let me show
you guys how it works. I chose the
advanced level. Going to the store.
Going to the store.
The best part is that it gives you a score
based on how close you sound to a native speaker.
Ice-cream or Vatermelon? Let's intentionally
make a mistake. Ice-cream or Vatermelon?
You see guys. I pronounced some sounds
wrong. If you mispronounced any sounds,
you can click on them and listen to the
correct way they should be pronounced.
I really love this app because you
can learn anywhere and anytime. It helps
improve your pronunciation and vocabulary,
and you get better at speaking English. Now go
ahead and download it right now for free and get
7 days of pro membership for free. The link is
in the description and in the pinned comment.
ELSA Speak offers over 1,600 lessons and more
than 40 topics to practice. The app has real
life topics that range from business topics like
Everyday Office Conversation, Job Interview,
Business Travel, Sales meetings, to
casual everyday topics like Movies,
Food and Drink, Education and Entertainment.
I also have an exclusive discount for you guys, to
get 40% off of one-year membership and an amazing
85% off of the lifetime membership. The link is
in the description and in the pinned comment.
Give it a try and let me know if you like it.
Let’s move on to the next common
mistake. Pronouncing ‘Colonel’
‘This word’ may look like 'col-o-nel'
but surprise! It's 'KER-nel'. English
borrowed words from various languages.
The word "colonel" originates from French.
In the word "colonel," we don't say the
"o" or the second "l". We say an "r" sound,
even though it's not in the word.
An odd one, but now you know!
Mistake #6: Mispronouncing 'th'
Well guys, how would you read this word?
It’s not zing and it’s not ding but THING. We put
the tongue against the upper teeth and blowing
out. Thing. I hear that mistake very often.
What about this word? It's not 'zat' or 'dat'
but 'that', /ð/ with the tongue against the
upper teeth. We make a voiced sound /ð/.
Mistake #7: Mispronouncing ‘Comfortable’
While the word looks like it should be
'com-for-ta-ble', the common and more
natural pronunciation is "kʌmf-t'-b'l"
This is a very common pronunciation
mistake. After a long day, I love
sitting in my comfortable chair to relax.
Mistake #8: ‘Dessert’ vs ‘Desert’
What do you call this? Is it a desert
or a dessert? This is a dessert. A sweet food
that you eat after the main part of a meal.
And this is a desert. A large, dry area of
land with very few plants and little rainfall.
Have you ever made this mistake? If
you have, let me know in the comments.
Mistake #9: ‘Borrow’ vs ‘Lend’
English learners often confuse
these two words. “Can I lend your book?’
This is a classic mistake! Remember,
'borrow' means you take something,
and 'lend' means you give something."
"Can I BORROW your book?"
- "I'll LEND you my book."
Mistake #10: ‘Effect’ vs. ‘Affect’
They sound similar. Easy to confuse,
but here's a clue: 'A' for action, so 'affect'
is usually the verb. On the other hand,
'effect' is the end result or outcome." For
example, have you ever heard about domino effect?
One domino falls, and it makes the others fall
too. That's the effect. If you take out a domino,
it will affect how the remaining dominoes
fall, possibly stopping the chain reaction.
Mistake #11: ‘Your’ vs. ‘You’re’
This mistake deals with spelling
and writing. 'You’re' is a contraction
of 'you are'. Apostrophes often indicate
that something is missing. You’re a
student. You’re the smartest student.
'Your' is all about possession. Your
goal is to write English words correctly.
It's your choice to understand the difference.
Mistake #12: 'Then' vs. 'Than'
This is a common spelling mistake. "‘Then’ relates
to time, while ‘than’ is used for comparisons.
She’s taller THAN her brother. We’re comparing.
I’ll call you THEN. We’re talking about time.
Thank you for watching this video! I hope you
enjoyed it! If you want more enriching content,
you can send me a Superthanks! It motivates
me a lot to create new videos for you.
Did you make any of the mistakes I talked about
today? Please let me know in the comments below.
Remember, everyone, even native speakers make
mistakes. So don’t be discouraged by a few errors.
If you enjoyed this lesson, make sure
to hit the like button and subscribe for
more videos like this! Until next
time, keep practicing! See you!