Hi
there. Why am
I
wearing this?
Well, today
let's talk about
how cities
around the world
are
transforming
their streets
to
accommodate greater
numbers of
cyclists,
people on bikes.
The
hope is that
this
makes it a safer
and more
enjoyable
way to travel.
Just
imagine if your daily
journey
to work
could help
improve
your health,
reduce your
carbon footprint,
and
either bring
you
closer to nature
so that
you can
hear the
birds singing
or help
you take in the
vibrant
culture
of a big city.
So today
I'm talking about
the
boom in cycling.
Apparently
in London, bike
use is
up by 20%
in the
last few years.
And new
cycle lanes, that's
roads
and pathways
built
specifically for
bicycles,
are a
big part
of this.
Another
European city that I
love to
visit, Amsterdam.
I like
Amsterdam, I
love
its atmosphere.
But what's
really noticeable
to
someone like me
from
the UK when
I visit
Amsterdam,
the huge
numbers of cyclists.
My
memories of Amsterdam
include
nearly being run over
by cyclists on
several
occasions.
British
people forget
to look
for cyclists
when
crossing the road
because
we're just not used
to
seeing that many.
And I'm
sure the
Amsterdam
cyclists
curse
British tourists like
me for
those near misses.
But
today let's
look at
cycling
and at
whether it
might
be the solution
to some of our
environmental
problems.
There's
some great vocabulary
in this
podcast
for English
language
learners.
And if you
listen right to
the end
of the podcast,
I'll
talk about
a
brilliant idea
that
might make
cycling
safe, popular,
and
accessible everywhere,
not just
in the big cities
and at
no extra cost.
Listen
to the end
to hear
that one.
Before I
get onto that,
please
help Adept English.
Subscribe
to our channel on
Spotify,
on YouTube,
on YouTube
Podcasts, or on
Apple
Podcasts,
wherever you
listen,
basically.
Subscribing
helps Adept
English
get more listeners.
It means
more people can
benefit
from what we do.
So please
hit that Notify
button
and Subscribe.
It's a
no-cost way of
supporting
Adept English.
People say to
us all
the time,
"Your
content is really good.
I'm
surprised you don't have
more
listeners."
We think
that too.
So
please help us out.
Thank you
for doing that.
So
vocabulary first of all,
the
words cycle,
bicycle,
and bike
all mean
the same thing,
that
two-wheeled vehicle that
most of
us learn to ride
as children.
And the
verbs for
this
topic are similar.
We
probably wouldn't talk
about
bicycling,
but we
would talk about
cycling
or biking.
So
that's the verb
to bike,
B I K E.
Both
forms are used.
And you'll
have heard me talk
in
previous podcasts
about
the move towards
electric
vehicles or EVs.
This is
most Western
governments'
response
to the
requirement to go
carbon
neutral.
I've
talked in previous
podcasts
also about
how the
current design of
electric
vehicles
isn't going to
serve
people's needs.
And
neither is there
infrastructure
to supply
the electricity
and the
charging
points
that we need.
Infrastructure,
I N F R A S T R U C T U R E.
That means
services, things
like
electricity and roads.
With
imposed deadlines in the
next
few years,
it's really
difficult to see
how
we're going to
arrive at
net zero.
And there
are other issues.
We're going to
struggle
to get away
from the
use of plastic,
P L A S T I C.
It's a big
by-product of the
petrochemical
industry,
but
it's one that we
absolutely
rely on.
Medical
supplies,
household
items,
the
interior of your car and
food
packaging.
What
would we do
without
plastic?
So we're
still reliant on
fossil
fuels for many things.
But
imagine a future where
our
streets are filled
with the
gentle hum of
bicycles
instead of cars,
much cleaner
air, for
one thing.
If more
and more of us are
going to be
living in cities
much
closer together,
cycling
could be the solution
to our
transport problems.
Could
more of our
journeys
be done by bike?
Once
you've bought a bike,
it's
very cheap to run.
There's
no fuel needed,
except for the
effort
you put in,
the
calories that
you burn
cycling.
As long
as the air is
relatively
clean,
cycling
is good for your
health
and your
level of
fitness.
So back to
those statistics.
Cycling in
London is up by
20%
since 2019.
And it's
estimated that 1.26
million
journeys
are
made by bike
every
day in London.
1.26
million! That's a lot!
And
apparently the
number
of trips by car,
journeys
by car, has fallen
drastically in
the
same period.
And in
fact, the number of
journeys
by bike
has
quadrupled.
That means
it's gone up, it's
increased
by four times.
The
reasons for the
popularity of
cycling
are easy to see.
You've the
choice to drive,
but in London,
that
just means
sitting
in traffic
for long
periods of time,
very
frustrating.
The
roads in London are
extremely
congested
and
increasingly restricted.
There's the
congestion
charge to pay,
and
fewer and fewer of
London's
roads are
available
to cars.
Getting
anywhere in London by
car is
unsatisfactory.
I do
drive in London
sometimes
when I go
to
visit my daughter,
but it's not a
pleasant
experience
and I do
try to avoid it and
go on
the tube instead.
And
public transport, the
London
Underground,
for instance,
the
tube that I
just
mentioned,
that is
still the most
efficient
way to travel
around
London, but there are
strikes
and problems
with
certain tube lines.
So it's
understandable
that people prefer
to be
above ground, getting
their exercise
on
their way to work.
If you have a
busy
London life,
then
getting your exercise in
at the
same time
as your
commute to work,
well, that
just makes sense.
You're
'killing two
birds
with one stone'.
That
just means you're
'solving two
problems
with one action'.
Here, the need
to
commute to work
and the
need to get your
daily
exercise.
So while
the number of
journeys
by bike
in
London is rising,
they still
only represent 5%
of
journeys made each day.
Compare
that with the Danish
capital,
Copenhagen,
where
that figure
is
closer to 49%.
Half of
journeys
are made
by bike.
And another
way of measuring
the popularity
of
something like cycling -
how many
bike trips are made
per
person per day
as an average?
Despite the
increase
I'm describing,
the number
of bike trips per
person
per day in London
is still
only 0.14.
Compare
that to Amsterdam,
the
location of my near
misses with
people on bikes.
Well, in
Amsterdam, the
number of bike
trips
per person
per day
is 0.9.
That's
really high, isn't it?
It means
that on average,
nearly
every single
person in
Amsterdam
makes a one
bike
trip per day.
The
problems with cycling?
Well,
the obvious ones -
it's much
more practical
where
the land is
relatively
flat.
If you
live in a
place
with steep hills,
cycling is
only practical if
you're
very fit.
Or maybe
the other
way to
look at it,
the
population of such a
place
could become a fit
by being
made to cycle more.
People
aren't going to like
that
though, are they?
And
cycling to work is fine
if you
have somewhere to
shower
and get changed.
People who
must dress smart
for their work
may have
more of a
problem
with cycling.
'Cycle
helmet hair' is a
problem,
I can tell you!
But more
seriously,
the number
one problem with
cycling is
of course safety.
That's
S A F E T Y.
The
increase in
cycling
in London
has only come
alongside
a big increase
in the
number of
cycle
lanes available.
Cycle
lanes or cycle paths
are pathways
specifically
for bikes.
London's roads
are
simply too busy
for it to
be safe cycling.
It's
dangerous for cyclists
to mix with
ordinary traffic.
And even
if you eventually
ban
most of the cars,
taxis,
buses, and vans
delivering
goods to shops
are
still going
to be
necessary.
These
vehicles pose a threat
to the
safety of
cyclists
of course.
So
continuing to build cycle
lanes,
cycle paths
is
essential if we want to
see
cycling in London
as part of
the solution to
some of our
environmental
problems
and our
transport problems.
Outside big
cities
like London,
how
practical is cycling as a
mode of
transport?
Well,
there are
certain
local journeys
that I
could make by
bike if
I needed to.
And it
would probably
increase my
level of fitness.
However,
the town I live in
has
hills, it's not flat.
There's one
particular
one on the road
back up
to my house
that's
very steep.
It makes
me puff and pant.
That
means I get
very out
of breath
when I'm
cycling up there.
So a
greater level
of
fitness is required
where
there are hills and
that might
be an obstacle.
There's
also a lack of cycle
lanes
outside of the capital.
There are
some, but they're
not
consistent.
And
most of the time,
cyclists
are expected to ride
on the roads
alongside
the traffic.
There just
isn't the money to
build cycle
lanes everywhere.
So
people are naturally
concerned
about safety.
And
indeed, my son
is just
15 years old.
And only at
Christmas,
one of his friends
had a
serious accident when
he was
knocked off
his bike
by a car.
He had to
be hospitalised.
Fortunately,
the
friend
is better now,
but he was
very lucky not to
be more
seriously injured.
Cycling
on roads
carries a
big risk.
One
obvious solution to the
lack of
cycle lanes
outside of
the big cities,
cycling
on the pavement.
That's
'pavement',
P A V E M E N T.
That's
the pathway at the
side of
the road
intended
for people on foot,
or 'pedestrians'
as we
call them.
P E D E S T R I A N S,
'pedestrians'.
Currently
the situation in
the UK,
at worst,
it would
be a £30
fine on
the spot.
But actually,
most of
the time,
the police
'turn a blind eye'
to cycling
on the pavement,
meaning
'they ignore it'.
The
pavements around where I
live are
generally empty.
There
are hardly
any
pedestrians.
If
necessary to
make
this safer,
you could
increase the fines
for
dangerous cycling
and make
it a rule that
cyclists
on the pavement
give way
to pedestrians.
And
cyclists would be
responsible
for judging
whether or
not it's safe to
ride on
the pavement.
Clearly
there are situations
where
it isn't.
Outside of
the big cities in
normal
towns and villages,
there
simply isn't the money
to build cycle
lanes
everywhere.
But
there are already
pavements
everywhere.
Relaxing
the rules to allow
cyclists
outside
of the capital
to cycle
on the pavement
could be
a solution
without
endangering
pedestrians or
people
on foot.
And it
would make a
massive
difference.
I think
that could work.
What do
you think?
Do you
cycle to work?
enjoy cycling?
Or is it
something that you
would
never do?
Let us know.
Enough
for now.
Have a
lovely day.
Speak to
you again soon.
Goodbye.