How many times have you
shared an opinion in English,
but halfway through your words weren't
really coming together as smoothly
as you wanted?
Maybe you found yourself saying too
much or searching for the right words,
trying to wrap up your thoughts.
This might happen, for example,
when a coworker asks for your
opinion in a meeting and again,
you have a difficult time explaining
why you have a certain perspective
or perhaps a friend shares her thoughts
about a movie you just saw. And again,
you're not really sure how
to put your ideas into place.
If that sounds familiar to you,
here's what I want you to know.
It's not at all because your
English isn't good enough.
It's simply because you don't have
the right connectors in place.
Words like because.
So that and due to these
connectors improve your flow and
help your ideas to feel
structured rather than scattered.
They also help you explain your reasoning,
which makes your opinion stronger
and more engaging. Ultimately,
this helps you sound
confident and professional.
Instead of hesitant or
unsure of your own opinions.
I want you to think about it for a moment.
When you hear someone confidently
explain why they believe something,
doesn't it make their
opinion more persuasive?
That's exactly what we're going to work
on today. By the end of this lesson,
you'll have the best professional
connectors to explain your reasoning
smoothly.
You'll also have a simple structure to
make your opinions sound polished and
professional in English. Ultimately,
you'll have more confidence in sharing
your thoughts without hesitation or
over-explaining. Now,
I want you to stick with me because at
the end I do have a challenge for you so
you can put all of these strategies
together and start using the right
connectors to get started.
Let's talk about how to structure your
opinion so that it's clear, logical,
and easy to follow.
English speakers naturally use a
three part structure when we're
expressing an opinion. The first step
is to clearly state your opinion.
This is where you introduce your
perspective in a direct confident
way. Most of the time you're going to
hear this with a sentence starter like I
believe, I think I would say,
and I feel following that immediate
statement of your perspective.
Step two is to explain why, and this
is where the connectors come in.
Strong opinions should be
supported by clear reasoning and
connectors help you explain
the why behind your statement.
So again, this would include
words such as because since,
and due to however, we're going to
learn many more in this lesson today.
Before we get there, let's
talk about the third step in a.
Clear logical opinion,
wrap it up with a
conclusion or a question.
Doing this makes your opinion
feel complete or finished.
You can do this by reinforcing your
point or inviting further discussion.
For example, after stating your opinion
and why you have it, you might say,
that's why I think this is a good
solution, or what do you think?
Before we get into our
professional connectors,
I want to give you two examples of
this step-by-step process in action.
We're gonna look at a social
example and a professional,
so let's imagine in a
social setting I might say,
I think the new wicked movie was great
because the actors did justice to the
roles and didn't stray from
the original characters.
What did you think about it? I
have my opinion, my reasoning,
and a way to reinforce or invite
discussion on that opinion.
And now let's look at
a professional option.
I believe we should adjust the project
timeline since the current deadlines
don't give us enough time for quality
control. What's your take on this?
When you structure your opinion in
English using this three-step process
and when you include your reason why
you have that particular opinion,
your ideas are more clear
and more persuasive.
Now of course, simply following
this structure isn't enough.
The connectors you choose are going
to determine how natural and confident
you sound.
So let's go deeper into the best
professional connectors you can use
to explain your opinions
clearly in English.
We're going to explore three categories
of connectors today and we'll start with
the most important explaining why you
think something or what happened as
a result. We need this because when
you're expressing your opinion,
you're not just saying what you think,
you're answering an
important question why,
and this is where our connectors come in.
So let's start with cause
or the reason why you have a
particular belief or opinion.
In English we have several
go-to words for this.
The first is the most common
because which means for this reason.
Next on this list is sense and
we use this when the reason for
an opinion is already
pretty clear or obvious.
Now similar to the word
because we can also use due to
it's very similar in meaning
but slightly more formal.
And here's one more that has a very
similar meaning just like due to
we can use because of these
two function in the same way
grammatically however of these
two due to is more formal
and because of is used more
often in everyday conversation.
Now I've got one more in this
list, but before I go there,
I know you might be thinking Annemarie,
it sounds like you've just given me a
list of words that all have very similar
meaning. And you're right,
English speakers love variety.
We like to use different
vocabulary and sentence structures.
This allows us to have more than
one way to express what we think.
Now you don't have to start
using all of these today.
My recommendation is learn one or
two connectors that are new to you.
Start incorporating them into your
conversations and your writing and
then once you're comfortable
you can add a couple more.
Now the last one on this
particular list is the word As
we use this when we're emphasizing
the result of a situation,
let's take a look at how these
work. In real conversations,
I want you to imagine you're
talking about your company,
the place where you
work, and you might say,
I like this company because
the people are friendly.
Or maybe you're making weekend
plans and you could say,
since the sun is shining,
let's go to the park.
Remember we talked about using sense to
highlight that the reason for something
is already clear and obvious.
It is clear and obvious to everyone
that the sun is shining and it's a good
reason to go to the park.
If you needed to explain why
you were late to a meeting,
you might say I was late due to traffic.
And when letting someone know
why an event was canceled,
you could say the meeting was
canceled because of the storm.
And here's one more using
as as our local coffee shop
has closed, we have to drive
two miles away for good coffee.
Before we move on to our next category,
I wanna talk about something that is
grammatically important when we're using
the words due to and because
of these are always followed
by a noun like traffic, the storm,
the delay for example,
I cannot say I was late
due to it was raining.
That doesn't work for us.
Instead you would say,
I was late because it was raining.
This is a simple but important difference.
Now, at the start of this section,
I highlighted that we're looking at
words that help us explain why or
what happened,
so let's take a look at a few more
connectors that help us express the what
happened, what was the
result of something.
For that we use words like so,
and this helps us to show a
consequence or an outcome.
We might also use witches.
Why this explains a reason at the
beginning or the end of a sentence.
Let's take a look at a few examples.
Let's say that you studied really hard
for some exams and you want to highlight
the result. You might say,
I studied hard so I
passed all three exams.
Or maybe your team just had a really
successful meeting and in telling someone
else about it, you might
say the meeting went well,
which is why we got the project. Now,
before we move on to our
second category of connectors,
I want to give you a
challenge to practice.
I want you to think about
something that you did recently.
Maybe you just started to learn English,
maybe you changed jobs or
maybe you moved to a new city.
How would you explain why? For example,
you might start with I started
learning English because,
or since I wanted to improve
my communication skills I,
or due to my work environment,
I decided to take a moment to
finish those example sentences.
As always, you can also share them
with me in the comments below.
Now that we've covered
connectors for cause and result,
let's move on to purpose.
To further explain the
why behind your decisions.
Just like expressing what you think.
When you share a thought or a
decision that you've already made,
you're not just talking
about what you did,
you might also need to
explain why you did it.
And for that we use purpose connectors.
I want to share with you three great
ways to express why you did something.
The first is in order to,
this is more formal and allows
you to emphasize your intention.
Now a more informal everyday
conversational version of in order to
is simply using the word to, and I'll
share an example with you in a moment.
The third in this category is so that,
and this focuses on the
ultimate desired response.
Here's what all of these would sound
like in real conversational examples.
Let's start with evaluating why you
started to learn English for work.
You might say,
I'm taking these lessons in order
to communicate better at work.
Again, using in order to
is a more formal version.
You might also say, I joined this
course to improve my speaking skills,
or I'm studying English
so that I can work abroad.
Again, in that example,
we're emphasizing the ultimate
goal or desire that you have. Now,
I want to pause here for a
moment because in category one,
focusing on cause and results we had,
so as a connector and here
when talking about purpose,
we had so that what's the difference?
Let's take a look at two
example sentences to help.
The first is I went by
car so that I could take
more luggage to the hotel with
so that we're highlighting the
purpose for making that decision.
What pros and cons did we evaluate
in order to come to that decision?
We could also say,
I went by car so I was able to
take more luggage to the hotel.
Here we're emphasizing
the ultimate result.
It might not have been a factor
in the original decision,
but it was a positive result. In the end,
one is about what you intended to do
and the other is about what happened in
the end. So now let's do
a quick practice again.
I want you to think about a
decision that you've made recently.
Maybe you changed jobs or signed
up for a new English class.
I want you to try
finishing these sentences.
I started learning English
two or I changed careers
so that and now what if you need to
give more than one reason for your
opinion?
That's where our next category of
connectors comes in because sometimes one
reason isn't enough.
Maybe you love your neighborhood where
you live and there are multiple reasons
why. Or maybe you think a
decision at work is a great idea,
but there's more than one benefit
that you want to highlight.
For clear organized speech,
we use connectors to add more
details and here's how we
can do that. The first,
another reason is this
allows us to add a separate
second reason to support a
decision or an opinion we can also
use, plus, this is a bit more casual,
quite often used in everyday
speech similar to plus is using
also very neutral and commonly used.
And a fourth option is on top of that.
This adds emphasis and may be
used to highlight a surprising
detail. Now again, let's take a
look at all of these in action.
Let's say that someone asks you,
do you like your new neighborhood?
And you might say, I love
my new neighborhood because
it's so close to work.
On top of that my friends live there
and there are many great restaurants
nearby.
Or imagine you're trying to explain why
you support a particular company policy.
You might say this new work
from home policy is great
for those who prefer to work at
different times of the day. Also,
it helps employees save money on
commuting. And here's one more.
Let's say that you're giving feedback
to someone on a new cafe that you tried.
You might say, I love this new
cafe, the coffee's excellent,
plus they have delicious pastries. Now,
one important thing to keep in mind
about using on top of that or another
reason is both of these can
only be used at the beginning
of a sentence. And once again,
let's do a bit of practice.
I want you to think of something
that you really enjoy or support.
It could be your job, a
new hobby, a policy change,
or even a favorite restaurant.
How would you give two reasons for
your particular opinion? You could try.
I love because and plus or one reason I
support is a, another reason is,
and now let's do a quick recap.
Today we did quite a few things.
We started with a three step
structure to ensure that you can share
a clear, well organized
opinion in English.
Then we learned a variety of connectors
for cause and result explaining why
something happened. Next,
we moved on to purpose connectors
showing why you did something,
and finally we learned how to add
extra reasons to strengthen an opinion.
So now I want you to put
all of this into practice.
Here's my challenge for you. I want
you to think about this question.
Why did you choose to learn
English? In your answer,
I want you to try to use at least
two connectors from today's lesson.
You might begin with,
I started learning English because
or since I wanted to improve my
communication skills or I'm
learning English. So that,
and another reason is as always
you can share your answers and
your questions with me in
the comments below. Also,
if you found this lesson helpful
to you, I would love to know,
give this lesson a thumbs up here
on YouTube and while you're at it,
make sure you subscribe so you never
miss one of my Confident English lessons.
Thank you so much for joining me and I
look forward to seeing you next time.