In today's lesson we're going to study a scene from a movie
and you're going to learn so much about pronunciation.
We're really going to focus on
smoothness in American English,
especially vowel to vowel links and how using these same kind
of links and smoothness in your own speech will help you sound
so natural and American.
Linking two words with a single sound.
Also the way we drop syllables in American English
like how families becomes fam-lies, two syllables.
There's so much to learn about
smoothness
and linking in American English.
You're going to get perfect pronunciation on some common two-word
phrases like ‘used to’ becoming ‘used tə’ and wanted a becoming ‘wɔntɪd ə’.
So stick with me, I am so excited for you to learn these tips and tricks about
American English pronunciation.
First here's the scene we'll study.
Lola said you asked about her potato mashers.
Your kid is super dope. And I was thinking I used to help out families
in my neighborhood, like if
parents wanted a night out,
I would stay with their kids or like even
watch their house, and I was wondering if
like you and Lola have a situation like
that with someone who I need to kill.
No.
Let's do the analysis.
Lola said you asked about her potato mashers.
An interesting first sentence let's look at our stressed words.
The name, the proper noun Lola, Lola.
That's got that up down shape of stress,
Lola. That smooth gliding in American English, we don't really have jumps
or skips for the most part. It's generally smooth gliding from
sound to sound, syllable to syllable,
word to word.
Lola said yes.
you asked about her potato mashers.
Lola said you asked about. A little bit
of that up down pitch change on asked,
our verb. Lola said you asked about
her potato mashers. So all of those
words gliding together smoothly with no breaks.
Lola said you asked about her potato mashers.
So, the word Lola, this name ends in the schwa sound
and the schwa goes right into the S of said.
So, if you want to practice linking,
you could say ‘ə said, ə said’. So you can
link that ending schwa into the word said with no break as if it was the same word.
ə said, ə said. Lola said, ə said, Lola said.
I'm Rachel and I've been teaching the American accent on YouTube for over 15 years.
Try the accent training yourself. Go to Rachel english.com/free to get my free course,
The Top Three Ways to Master the American accent.
Lola said--
Lola said you asked about her potato mashers.
Said you asked about her, said you asked about her.
These are all a little bit lower in volume
and energy than Lola, potato.
Lola said you asked about her,
said you asked about her.
It's a little quieter and it's very fast, isn't it?
Very fast. Said you asked about her,
said you asked about her.
Said you asked about her—
Said you asked about her. There are a couple different ways that we may
pronounce D plus the word you.
Said-ju, it's very common to
make a J sound, I don't really hear that,
said you said. The D is vibrating in the vocal cords and then it goes right into
the U diphthong for the word you. Said you, said you, said you,
said you, said you, said you, said you asked.
Now we have an U vowel or the second half of the U diphthong linking into
another vowel.
ae as in asked. The ED ending here makes a T,
and linking vowel to vowel is sometimes
the hardest one to do smoothly.
You-asked. So, in this case it can help
you to feel like you're going through
a W consonant which is a glide consonant, that can help you connect these smoothly.
You asked,  you asked, you asked.
You asked—
This lesson was recently released in
my Academy with audio to train with,
you will hear me reference training with that material in this video.
Watching the analysis video and then training with the soundboard,
speaking out loud in slow motion to help you hear the up down shape of stress.
I'm just so tired.
Then at regular pace over and over—
Can really help you smooth out your speech simplify your mouth movements
and get a more relaxed and natural a American placement in sound.
If you feel you could benefit from more ease in speaking American English,
please check out  Rachelsenglishacademy.com.
We have a great training program that's helped thousands of students
improve their American accent and speak with less effort and more confidence.
Now, you may notice she's not saying asked. She's saying asked.
What is happening? This many consonants in a row especially unvoiced
can be tricky so it's pretty common to drop the middle one,
and then you get asked, asked, asked instead of asked, asked, asked.
It really simplifies it. You asked, you asked, you asked.
So that W to connect, low and volume in pitch, very smooth and dropping that K.
You asked.
You asked—
about her potato mashers.
Her potato masher, about her potato masher. About her. Asked about.
So, the ending T of asked links into the beginning sound the schwa of about asked ə,
asked ə, asked about, asked about, this T is pronounced as a stop T,
about her, about her, about her, about her. So that little tiny lift there, that little lift in
energy, is what signifies the stop T. Another way to pronounce these two words,
about her, about her, that would be a flap T
no H, that's another common pronunciation.
In fact, it's maybe even more common    than stop T with it H.
About her, about [flap].
Do you hear that flap? About her. But here
it's about her, about her, about her.
About her—
potato mashers.
Potato mashers. Potato. So, a lot more pitch change here than we had in this
little one for asked.
Pota, ey. Don't be afraid to hit
more extreme up and downs as you're practicing
your English. This may be exactly what your English needs.
Pota-to. So notice we have two different T's here.
This first one is a true T, that's because
it starts a stressed syllable,
starts a stressed syllable. And the second one is a flap T, potato.
Also we have two letters O,
but two different pronunciations. The
first one is a schwa, pə, pə, and the
second one is an O diphthong. Ou, ou. Ou-t-r. So, the letters don't always make the
same sounds.
This word is good for noticing that. Two letters O but two different pronunciations.
Two letters T,
but two different pronunciations.
Potato--
Potato mashers.
Potato mashers. Her voice is very soft. mashers
this is the a vowel. Mashers. First syllable
stress, a little bit of that up down shape.
Mashers.
Your kid is—
Your kid is. Your kid is. And then a break.
So he's not linking everything together quite the same way she is.
He's putting more stress into this sentence.
He wants it to be really
known to her that he means it. Your kid is.
Your kid is. The D and kid links right into
the next word. The T continues right into the K, no breaks here.
No breaks until the end of is. Your kid is.
Your kid is—
I love how we can really hear that D  linking into the ih vowel. Kid is [flap], kid is.
kid is—
super dope.
And the ending S of the word is a Z sound. Now, if he had linked these together,
Z linking into S, that's usually going to turn the Z into an S.
But he put a break here, so we have a Z and then an S. Super-dope.
super dope.
Super dope. So we have a stressed
syllable then unstressed. Super. So,
the unstressed syllable is this.
Quiet. Not much to it. The stress
syllable is su. Louder, up-down shape of
stress. We need this contrast. Su, super,
super dope. Uhhuh, super dope.
Super dope.
The letter U makes the U vowel here, super.
And the letter O makes the OH diphthong, dope,
just like the ending sound of potato, oh, oh.
super dope.
and I was thinking—
And, a little break, breaking
up his thought groups. I was thinking. Again, no linking there, so ‘and’
doesn't link in. And, the pitch going up at the end shows that he's going to continue
with his thought. And. Now, the word and if you look that up in the dictionary
you'll see ae. You'll see ae as in bat,
N and D. But this ae,
it's not pure when it's followed by N. So it's
not A, that's like cat. A, and. But it's ænd,
ænd, or in this case, ænd, ænd. So see if you can
imitate that A, it's more relaxed and it goes into
sort of, you could think of it as the UH as in
butter or the schwa sound, ænd before the N, ænd.
And—
I was thinking.
I was thinking. What do you notice
about the intonation, the melody there?
I was thinking. Again it goes up a little bit at the end to show he's not done,
he's about to say what he was thinking. Was is unstressed, I and think both
stressed with that up down shape and the whole thing links together really smoothly.
I was thinking—
The word ‘was’, you can think
of that wəz, wəz. It's fast,
it's unstressed. The vowel UH reduces to the schwa. wəz, wəz, I was, I was.
So I is clear, was is unclear. I was, I was, I was. Now I know this transition
from Z into TH can be tricky.
I was—
I was thinking.
Was thinking. So this TH is unvoiced, that means the tongue tip has to come
through the teeth.
For the word was, I wəz. My teeth are more or less together and the back of the
tongue tip is
touching the very backs of the teeth. So, inside the mouth here, the tongue tip,
and outside the mouth here. But it's a little movement. It's not sticking way,
way far out for this. It's just the very tip and the air should flow freely there.
You might want to slowly go back and forth really thinking about both
positions and just notice what change is
happening in the tongue.
Z. It's not that big of a change. It moves
up and out of the teeth just a little bit.
I was thinking—
I used to help out families in my neighborhood,
I used to help out families in my neighborhood. Okay, so what are our stress
words here?
We have I, and this time rather than going down or up and down it's sort of going
down and up. I used
to help out families in my neighborhood. So,
all of those stress syllables are going down
and up because again he's going to continue on with his thoughts.
So we have this upward aiming pitch. I used to help out families.
And again all this links together pretty smoothly.
No abrupt stop or skips in the melody. It all glides.
I used to help out families in my neighborhood,
I-U, I-U. So, smoothly linking together those two diphthongs. The I diphthong,
I-U. I-U, I-U, I-U.
I used—
to help out.
I used to help out. When we have
used, which is the U vowel Z-D,
and it's followed by the word to, this
happens a lot, this is a common phrase,
something happens.
I used to help out—
The pronunciation changes. So the Z
changes to an S, the D gets dropped
and the S links into the T and usually this vowel reduces like it does here. Instead of to it's tə.
So, used to is almost always pronounced.
Used to, used to. You know what, I realized,
I’ve said U vowel, I meant U diphthong, let
me rewrite that down there. U, I-U. I used to,
I used to, I used to, I used to. You say it enough times it stops sounding like
three words, right?
If you feels like one word. That's what we
want, that smooth connection. I used to,
I used to, I used to.
I used to—
help out families.
I used to help out families. So, a little bit of up down shape on helping out.
Help. Out. This is a phrasal verb. Two parts to it. Help and out.
Help out, help out. The P releases into the
O diphthong, so it's not help out but it's
help out. You can think of the p is
connecting in help out, help out, help out.
There shouldn't be a stop there. Now, here there's a little stop because of the stop T.
Why? When the next word begins with a consonant, usually a t in this case is
pronounced as a stop T.
So, it's not help out, but it's help out, out. It's not dropped. Out, out.
It's this abrupt stop that signals. It's this abrupt stop that signals the T.
Help out families. Help out families.
Help out families—
Families, families, families. Now, you might notice this looks like it should be fa-mi-les.
Family. Three syllables.
It's much more common to pronounce it as two syllables and that's what he's doing.
Fam-lies,
lies. This ending s is a Z. Families, families. So don't make that three syllables.
Simplify it.
Families—
in my neighborhood.
In my neighborhood, in my neighborhood. In my, said so quickly.
In my, in my, in my, in my, in my, in my, in my, in my. How quickly can you
say those two words linking them together? In my, in my, in my, in my, in my.
This contrast of very, very short words and
syllables and longer
syllables is important for clarity.
In my neighborhood—
In my neighborhood, in my neigh, stressed syllable, neighborhood, borhood, borhood,
borhood. Last two syllables not stressed, the pitch is just going up, from this
dip for the stress. Borhood, borhood, borhood, borhood. This letter O is the
schwa, neighborhood.
In my neighborhood—
In my neighborhood,  in my neighborhood. It's really fast.
Neigh is the only syllable that has some length.
In my neighborhood—
Like—
Like, like. Filler word said pretty flatly
here. Little bit of up down shape. Like, like, like.
like,
And he does release the K,
kk, kk, we hear that sound.
Like,
if parents wanted a night out.
If parents wanted a night out. If
parents, if parents wanted a. So,
we have up down shape of stress there. Wanted a night out. And then also on the
word night out,
the phrase night out. Night out and again he makes
his pitch go up and down. Sorry, down then up,
so he can continue his thought. He signals with that intonation that he's going to keep
going.
The word if said so fast. Up here we're talking about how ‘in my’ is so fast,
the word if, honestly all I really hear is the F consonant. F, parents, f, f, f, f parents,
F parents, f parents,
if parents—
wanted a—
If parents wanted a, wanted a, wanted a, wanted a. What do you notice about this T
and wanted?
It gets dropped, doesn't it? Wanted a, wanted a, wanted a. There are a couple
different vowels
you can give this. AH and father, AH and law, UH and butters also pretty common
though you
might not see that in the dictionary. Wanted a, I think I tend to use this one the most.
If parents want a. So here, the ED ending we studied before a case where the ED
ending was a T and the word ‘asked’. Here the ED ending is an extra syllable,
so it's a vowel sound and a consonant sound. Id,
id, wanid, wanid a, and then that D links
right into the schwa, for a, wanted a,
wanted a, wanted a, wanted a, wanted a. Just like used to, used to, used to, used to,
up here. There a lot of cases where it's a super common two-word phrase
or three-word phrase and it gets reduced and simplified.
If parents wanted a--
night out,
Let's look at the two-word phrase night out. Two T's at the end, how are they pronounced?
Night out,
Night out, night out [flap],
that's a flap T. To me it sounds like
a D, depending on your native language,
it might sound like an R, but that's the flap
T. And we use the flap T to link words between
vowel or diphthong sounds. So the word night in IPA would be written N consonant, I diphthong,
night, and then the word out is with the AU
diphthong. Out. So here's a diphthong, here's
a diphthong. The T between is a flap. Night out. Now, the ending T here, he does do a true T release.
He could have even linked it in, night out I,
night out I. But he separates it. Night
out, Night out.
Night out,
I would—
I would, I would. Little break. He's breaking this up quite a bit. I would,
I would. One word is stressed. It's I. The next word not stressed. It just smoothly
falls down from the peak of stress for I.
I would. Would, would. Simple. I would.
I would—
stay with their kids.
Stay with her kids, stay with their kids. So
‘stay with’ there said quickly and it's pretty
flat in pitch. Stay with their kids. Now he's
listing things. Things that he would do. So when
we list things, everything goes up in intonation at the end until the last part of the list. So,
stay with her kids, stay with their, stay with
their, stay with their, stay with their. That's
all sort of that unstressed, less clear feeling, isn't it? And it all links together.
Here we have two different th's, we can link those together with a single unvoiced TH,
with there, with there, with their, with their, with their, with their, with their,
stay with their, stay with their, stay with their kids.
Stay with their kids—
or like,
The word ‘or’, he reduces it.
schwa R said so fast, linked into the word ‘like’. This is all really flat. And it's lower in
volume,  lower in pitch. It's again a little bit of a filler word. Or like, or like, or like,
or like, or like, or like. See if you can get that same low open quality. Or like, or like, or like.
Or like,
or like even watch their house.
Even watch their house. So, again he's still
listing things. Even watch their house.
So, it's still going up, he's not done with
his thought on what he's going to offer.
Now, let's look at this word ‘even’. It's not stressed.
even watch—
I basically don't even hear very much
of the word. I sort of hear the E vowel,
I sort of hear the N consonant but it's
really reduced. It's not said very clearly.
It's crazy but in American English, we simply don't say every single word clearly.
We say some less clear and that provides contrast to the more clear and we
like having those two different kinds. That's what makes it clear. Even watch.
Even watch—
Even watch their house.
Watch their house. So the word there like
even, it's unstressed. It doesn't have an up
down melody or down up ,it's just kind
of flat in this case it's connecting these two, and it's not pronounced there but it's their.
watch their house.
Their house, their house. So fast, there, there, there, there, there.
I don't even need to bring my tongue tip through the teeth for that TH, there,
there, there. I just touch it on the backs
of the teeth. Their, their, their. That
way I can make the word super, super short. So, it's not their, it's their, their.
their house.
It kind of stops sounding like the word, doesn't it? Their, their. Sometimes when you
isolate these unstressed words by themselves, it sounds like it can't possibly
be the right pronunciation because it's so unclear, and yet
it is. Their, their, their house.
their house.
And—
And. Little bit of a break there, full
pronunciation and it's really common to reduce that but since he's breaking it out into its own
thought group, he's fully pronouncing it. And.
And—
I was wondering if—
I was wondering if, I was wondering if,
I was wondering if. Teeny tiny little lift here, but if you'll notice we have four words here.
I was wondering if. And only one of them has a stress syllable, wondering if, I was. So,
I was just going up and during if, just going
down from that one peak of stress.
It's one smooth up down shape of the voice. Uhuh, uhuh,
I was one wondering if, I was wondering if. Very smooth and connected.
I was wondering if—
you and Lola have—
You and Lola have. He
must feel very shy here because he's putting all of these breaks in.
You and, Lola have. Little bit of a break here and look at this word and.
Here we said he fully pronounced it, and here he totally doesn't. And, and, you and,
you and. The word and becomes and, and, you and. Link that in smoothly with you. You and.
You and Lola have—
You and, you and Lola have. Have, we still
get all of those sounds but it's still lower,
flatter, not as long not as loud still has an
unstressed feeling. Lola have, uhhuh, Lola have.
Lola have—
situation like that.
And then he does another break. I don't
even hear the UH sound really. Uh, uh,
uh. Although grammatically, it would be there, uh, situation. He must be saying it so, so quickly,
and linking it into the S, that it, just didn't
really get picked up by the mic, a situation.
Situation—
Situation, situation.
So this word has primary stress on a and
secondary, a little bit of up down on sit, situ.
The TU here is making a CHU, si-chu-way.
You might feel here linking these two sounds
that you're making a W to glide them smoothly. Situation. T-I-O-N ending here is SH schwa N,
shu, shun, situation.
Situation—
a situation like that.
A situation like that,
like that, like that. Do you hear the difference? They're both getting quieter at the end of the
phrase but like is flatter, like that. That
up down shape of stress on our vowel,
that, and then he does do a light
true T release because again,
he's breaking it up from the next part of
the sentence. He's not linking it together.
like that—
with someone,
With someone, with someone, with someone.
A little bit more up down on with. With someone, but overall still pretty flat,
we have an unvoiced TH here, and then an S sound with someone. Now, it would be
pretty common to drop the TH and just replace it with an S, with someone,
with someone, with someone, were you there with someone. But here, he doesn't.
He is making a quick little light TH with someone.
With someone, before he continues, with someone.
with someone—
I wouldn't think of this as being some, but more like some.
Fast with schwa, some, some, someone, someone.
with someone—
who I need to kill.
Making a joke here. He wants to be
the person who takes care of Lola.
who I need to kill.
Who I need to kill. Now here, no breaks, this is all, all five of these words linking
together smoothly. Who I need to kill. Who I need to, who I need. One stress word
there, it's our verb. To kill, and another verb, uhuhuh. So those five words,
two up down shapes of stress, the rest is either leading up to one
peak or coming down. Who I, who I.
Who ends in oo, I diphthong, who I,
it might help to think of going through a
W. Who I. That can help you link smoothly.
who I need to kill.
Who I need to, who I need to. So, it's pretty common when one word that ends in D
is linking into the word to, to reduce that to, to just the schwa and link it onto the D.
Need to, need to, need to, need to, need to kill, need to kill.
This L is a dark L, it comes after the vowel in the syllable, kill.
That's made with the back part of the tongue, not the tip the tip should not lift
here.
Kill. Who I need to kill. So many things are happening but slow it down break it up,
practice it in slow motion first, simplify, simplify, and after you've done it in slow
motion many, many times and it's starting to feel more natural then bring it up to
regular pace. So that you can keep everything you simplified like dropping
the D in need, like changing the vowel in to. The smooth link of who and I. It's really about
saying it out loud, playing it and saying it over and over. Who I need to kill, who I need to kill.
Who I need to kill.
Let's listen to the whole conversation one more time.
Lola said you asked about her potato mashers.
Your kid is super dope. And, I was thinking, I used to help out families in my neighborhood,
like, if parents wanted a night out,
I would stay with their kids or like,
even watch their house, and I was wondering if you and Lola
have a situation like that with someone, who I need to kill.
I hope you've enjoyed this video, I absolutely love teaching about the stress
and music of spoken American English.
Keep your learning going now with this video and don't forget to subscribe
with notifications on, I absolutely love being your English teacher.
That's it and thanks so much for using Rachel's English.