today
I'm going back to the UK
and you are coming with me
so let's travel and learn some English
[Music]
all right
we've arrived in London
got my coffee
got my suitcase
going to go to the center now and find my uncle
let's go
it's lovely British summertime
i'm with my uncle Lee
we're going to go get the tube
and explore London
all right here we are queens station
heading into the tube
i'm tapping my card and
walking through the barriers
the tube has arrived
we're getting on
now we're getting off
all right just coming out of the tube
and going onto the escalator
this is an escalator
please hold the handrail
this is a handrail
a police car with a flashing sirens
restaurant
a little girl in a pink hoodie
is chasing a pigeon and giggling
but the pigeon flew away
all right guys
the London Eye
the famous London Eye
this is called a carousel
you're riding the horses
and you spin round and round
and a bit of classic Britishness for you
fish and chips
love it
all right we are walking
by the famous River Thames
this is the River Thames
and the sun has come out to grace us
look how beautiful it is, London
there we have Big Ben
okay okay and if I flip the camera around
there we got the London Eye
these are pods or capsules
and this right here is a spiral staircase
street lamp
ice cream truck
and these people are waiting in a queue
a long queue
it's a gazebo
gazebo
photo booth
the London Dungeon
these are black cabs
cab is another word for taxi
so right now walking over
what's the name of the bridge?
Westminster Bridge
and that is the Houses of Parliament
where all the politicians hang out and chat [ __ ]
we got some massive seagulls up here
this is Big Ben
not the clock tower but the bell inside
the clock tower is called Elizabeth Tower
the lady in the pink dress
is talking to a policeman
that's a double-decker bus
i love it
busy busy busy around here
there's a helicopter flying past
that's the Union Jack flag
at top the Westminster Palace
all right guys we have a red telephone box
i can
Oh no i can't open the door
it's locked
no one's home
right now we are walking to
Notting Hill via Portobello Road
and we're going to try find
where Hugh Grant had the
famous scene at the bookshop
in Notting Hill
so let's see if we can find it
you can see to my right hand side
we have a canal
there are some ducks swimming on the canal
there's graffiti on the wall
all right these are called narrow boats
one two three four ducks
they are perched on the edge of the canal
a male duck is called a drake
just like Drake the artist
all right check out what we have just spotted
this is a phone box turned cash machine
so come here and we're going to learn some English
i'm taking out my credit card or debit card
i'm inserting it into the slot
it says "Please enter your PIN."
So I'm going to type my PIN
if I can remember it
i'm going to withdraw 20 quid
in England we say quid
that means pounds
and this is a cash machine or an ATM
i'm taking my card putting it in my wallet
and there we go look at that
£20 British pounds
lovely
that is 20 quid
here we have some street art
now we are walking on Portobello Road
still not found Hugh Grant's bookshop yet
so more to come
we stopped in the deli for a quick snack
this is an aisle
these are tins and these are jars
uncle Lee is going to pay
this is a till
right that there is a market
with some market stalls
and here we have one of the
most famous bakeries in England
Gregs
all right this is a pharmacy
in the UK we say chemist
behind me the oldest cinema in London
all right we found it
the Notting Hill bookshop is where
they filmed the film Notting Hill
should we go inside
let's go in
[Music]
wow look at these donuts
yeah look unreal
jammy dodger
Gordon Jamsy
that's sick look at that the colorful houses
we call these terrace houses
which are houses built in
a row and joined together
so right now we're just cutting it a bit late
but we're going to head to King's Cross station
and go back to my hometown
let's go
can you guess where we're going?
just arrived at King's Cross
and going to find our train
but first let's look for the
Harry Potter 9 and 3/4 platform
that's where the people are queuing up
there it is
all right let's go in the shop
backpack no worries
can I film in here is that all right
nice one man
harry Potter t-shirt
harry Potter mugs
harry Potter
hello
all right we got the robes
Gryffindor robe ones
hoodies
mugs
key rings
scarves
who needs to queue when you can see that there
all right that was cool
seen the Harry Potter shop
now time to get the train
we have the departure board
these are where you get your tickets
ticket machines
these are the barriers
all right this is where you scan your ticket
got my ticket here and we go through the barriers
right here we are on the train platforms
walking to our train
we made it
but there we have the clock
the train is on my right
we are walking to our carriage
getting on the train p
lease mind the gap
[Music]
let's go we have arrived in York
we are home
wagging his tail
i love you
hello fella
oh sweet
look who we have here Lenny
say hello Lenny
hello can you speak some English
he's still learning
i am feeling very jet-lagged
very tired from all my travels
but there's one feeling I
want to leave you guys with
and this feeling is serene
it means peaceful and calm
as today was a travel episode
where is your dream destination
where would you love to travel
to in the future and why
let me know in the comments i'm curious to know
and I will respond to every single one of you
as always thank you for watching
much love
peace
see you soon