So, you might or might
not know this, but I
am a private teacher,
so if you're struggling
with things in English,
I have online private
lessons, englishwithronnie.com,
and I'll help
you anything you need
in English; pronunciation,
vocabulary, crazy
things like this.
This is for one of my
students, Braino, this is for you.
A lot of the times in
our classes, students
have specific questions,
like, "Bronnie, what's
the difference between
'as long as' and 'as far as'?"
And I go, "Oh, god,
that's a good question.
Let me check..."
Whoa, there's a lot to explain about this
one, so I'll make a video about it for you.
But if you have
questions like this, I'm sure
they come up all the
time, I'll help you answer
those, and I'll walk you through
what each of these crazy things mean.
So, this lesson is to help you with "as
long as" versus "as far as", "as long as".
We use this for a
period of time, so we can
say, you can stay
here-period of time-as long
as you like, or you can stay
here for as long as you want.
So, I'm telling you that this
is a period of time or duration.
I can't say, you can stay
here as far as you like.
That doesn't make sense.
So, for this one,
we're talking about a
period of time, we
have to say "as long as".
Next one.
This is kind of fun.
Do you guys hate
conditionals, like "if" or "when"?
Huh.
So, we can substitute conditionals,
and we can use "as long as".
As long as you pay,
you can eat here.
I can substitute "as
long as" in this sentence
for "if", so I could
say, hey, if you pay,
you can eat here.
Now, another cool
thing about this sentence,
because I have a
little star here, is I can
also reverse the
order of the sentence.
I can definitely say, hey, guess what, you
can eat here-comma-as long as, or you can
substitute "if" you pay.
So, this is a
conditional, right?
If you don't pay, guess
what, you can't eat here.
But as long as you do this,
then you have permission.
So, this is a requirement.
As long as you give me
money, I will give you lessons.
If you give me money,
I will give you lessons.
It's like a trade.
We also talk about length
when we're comparing something.
My coat is as long as his.
So, as long as makes sense, we
talk about the length of something.
Long means length.
Length means how
long something is.
When you measure things, right?
What's the length of something?
And also, we can use "since",
and this one we can change, too.
As long as you're
here, let's drink.
It's just another way of saying
since you're here, let's drink.
Or because of the reason
why you're here, woo, let's drink.
Now, I can switch this.
I can say, "Let's
drink as long as you're
here", but we have to
be careful because this
one can change its meaning.
So, since you're
here, let's drink.
Since you're here, let's drink.
Let's drink since or
because you're here.
Because of your very presence.
It is just inspired me to drink.
Maybe that's a good thing.
I don't know.
So, if you see an
asterisk or a star beside
these sentences, it
means that we can change
the order of the sentence.
And it's cool.
It's just fun.
Woo.
Look at how much fun we're
having with grammar today.
Yes.
Someone hold me back.
As far as...
This one's fun.
This shows the extent of
your knowledge or your...
I guess your appear...
Not appears.
Opinion.
But we'll get to that one.
So, as far as I can
see, you have three kids.
You might have more
kids, but I don't know.
And we can use
verbs like "see" or "tell".
As far as I can tell,
it's going to rain.
Yeah, there's clouds.
As far as I can see,
it's going to rain.
As far as I know...
So, I'm telling
you that I know...
I don't know everything;
I know a little bit.
It's like a limit.
Okay?
It's perfect as far as I know.
So this is an example of
how I've inverted the sentence.
I can say, "As far as
I know, it's perfect."
Or "It's perfect
as far as I know."
It doesn't change the
meaning of the sentence.
As far as I can tell,
it's going to rain.
I can say, "Oh, it's
going to rain as far
as I can tell, but I'm
not a weather person,
so don't ask."
Distance.
Now, these ones
we cannot switch.
Okay?
Don't...
Do not change the order
of this sentence, please.
And this is telling us kind of our
limitations on something; our limits.
"We will travel
as far as we can."
But then we're just, like,
done, going to sleep now.
"The grass grew
as far as the fence."
So that means up to the limit of
the fence, there is no more grass.
So we're giving it a
distance and a limit.
"I ran as far as
the school, yeah!"
And then I died, because
I'm not good at running.
And the last one, we use this a lot, "As
far as I'm concerned, you did a great job."
I can also invert this, "You did a
great job, as far as I'm concerned."
Or, oh, yeah, "You're a
horrible person, as far as I know.
As far as I know,
you're a horrible person."
So again, we can switch those.
And this is only giving
someone your opinion.
It's kind of weird
because we have "far" and
"long", and they might
be the same in your
languages, but I
hope this helps.
I hope you can
work some things out.
And as far as I know,
these are all the examples
that I've got to give
you for this lesson.
EnglishWithRonnie.com if you want
to have private online classes with me.
As far as I know,
I'm out of time.
I got to go.
I'm...
Yeah.
Bye.