Hey everybody!
Welcome back to my YouTube channel.
My name's Ariannita la Gringa and
today I'm here at the dentist,
and I'm going to get my teeth cleaned.
In this video, I will show you the process
of how to book an appointment,
how to get your teeth cleaned,
and I will also talk with a dentist.
Let's start the video!
But to go to the dentist, you
have to make an appointment.
I already made an appointment,
and I have to check in over there
at the front desk so they know I've arrived.
Hi, good morning.
-Good morning, how are you?
Good, how are you? I'm here for my appointment.
Okay. And what time was your appointment?
-9:00.
And what's your last name?
-Dziadkowiec
And then is it Arianna?
-Yes.
Um, I have some paperwork
for you to fill out for me.
If you could just take a few
minutes to fill that out,
and then they'll call you back shortly.
-Thank you so much.
You're welcome.
I just checked in for my appointment,
and now I have to fill out some paperwork.
On this form, it asks me my medical history,
like if I've been sick within the past 2 weeks,
whether I have any allergies or
any of my past medical history.
And now I'm ready for my appointment, so I have
to return this paperwork to the front desk.
Hi, I just finished filling out my paperwork.
-Great, thank you so much.
Go ahead and have a seat, and Carolina will call
you back shortly.
-Okay, thank you.
You're welcome.
Right now I'm in the waiting area,
and before the hygienist calls my name and
gets me, do you know some dental vocabulary?
What's this?
This is a tooth.
Tooth.
And if it's plural, what do you call it?
These are teeth.
Teeth.
And what's this?
That's my tongue.
Tongue.
What are these?
These are gums.
Gums.
If I want to get straight teeth,
what can I put in my mouth?
You can get braces.
Braces.
Arianna, are you ready?
-Yes.
Let's go.
Let's go to room number four.
-Okay.
Carolina is a dental hygienist, and she
helps out the dentist by cleaning my teeth.
She will clean my teeth today,
and we are in a small room,
and this is where we will get my teeth cleaned.
Are there any changes in your medical history at
all, or do you have any pain or sensitivity today?
I don't have any changes in my medical history,
but I do have some sensitivity in my bottom tooth.
Before getting my teeth cleaned,
I will get an x-ray of my teeth.
This is basically just a picture of my teeth.
Come with me uh to take your x-rays.
-Okay.
Right now I'm in the x-ray room where
Carolina will take a picture of my teeth.
So why do they take X-rays of teeth?
Well, they take x-rays to see if you have
any cavities or any holes in your teeth,
or if you also have an infection.
This is the vest for protection.
Then you can turn around.
I'm going to put this up, and then
you're going to bite over here,
and then this is going to spin around, okay.
Here's some glasses for you.
Then a vest.
So I'm going to take some measurements
for your gums to see how they are doing, okay.
-Okay.
Open.
What are you putting in my mouth,
and what do you use those things for?
This is a mirror, well I can look in your mouth,
and this is a probe, and we are
going to measure the gums with this.
Do you normally use an electric brush or a manual?
-A manual.
And how often do you floss?
-I usually floss after I eat,
so in the morning, afternoon, and in the evening.
We're going to start the cleaning now.
I'm going to use cavitron and suction.
-What's a suction?
So the suction is like a little vacuum that is
going to suction your saliva
and all the water that is coming out from here.
I'm going to start the polishing part.
I have a prophy paste and a polisher.
Now the dental hygienist will floss
in between my teeth with dental floss.
We are going to do fluoride.
What flavors do you want?
I have mint, bubble gum, and caramel.
-Can I get mint, please?
So there are some restrictions for fluoride.
You can drink water right after,
you have to wait 30 minutes to eat something,
then avoid coffee, tea, and alcohol for today.
The hygienist just finished cleaning my teeth,
and now she will go get the dentist
who will just do a physical exam.
By the way, Carolina is from
Ecuador and she speaks Spanish,
so if you feel more comfortable speaking Spanish,
come over here to Pearce Dental Group
and get your teeth cleaned by her or one of their
many dental hygienists that speak Spanish here.
Hi, can you tell me a little
bit about this machine?
-Yeah, this is a 3D scanner, so
we don't do impressions anymore.
That's old technology.
We use this primarily for diagnostics.
If you wanted to do something like bleach
trays or retainers, we can make it out of this,
but this is a permanent model and
it'll be stored in the cloud for you.
All right, so this is just showing your teeth,
and we can show the upper teeth by themselves,
we can show the lower teeth by themselves,
and we can also show how hard
you're hitting on your teeth.
So the red is bad, green is good, and we
call the front teeth the anterior teeth,
and the back teeth are posterior teeth.
Little dental terminology for you.
And this is called occlusion.
Right now I'm here with a dentist.
Are you going to check my teeth?
-Today we're gonna do a check-up and
an examination and cleaning today.
We're gonna look for cavities, gum disease,
talk about things like whitening our teeth.
If you have any problems, we can
address any problems like that.
So we're checking for signs of
cavities or gum inflammation.
We're looking at your gum tissues to check
and make sure there's no soft tissue cancers.
We do a cancer screening,
so we're having a thorough check just
to make sure we have optimum health.
Okay. All right.
And could you raise your tongue
in the roof of the mouth?
Good.
And bite again. Great.
So overall your teeth are very healthy.
We have a couple cavities on the upper left.
We have a small chip in the front
tooth, which we can discuss.
Also, if you're interested in ways to
help brighten your color of your teeth,
we can talk about that today.
There's lots of different ways to whiten your
teeth and have a great smile
that you're really proud of.
But overall, you're very healthy.
It looks like you've had braces in the past.
-Yes.
The alignment of your teeth is very
good, and that's great for longevity.
How can you tell if I have a cavity?
Sometimes a cavity will appear to be a
different color, like a gray or a brown,
darker color in the mouth, but
sometimes you can't see them.
That's why we take x-rays.
So x-rays are necessary to
make sure that we don't look
over any potential problems that
we can't see with our own eyes.
But also our patient can tell us.
Sometimes a patient may say they
have temperature sensitivity,
hot and cold sensitivity, chewing sensitivity,
and sometimes a tooth just kind of aches and
throbs, and that might be something different.
So there's different types of pain or
sensitivities that can tell us a little bit more.
And you also said I have a chip in my tooth.
I've noticed it too.
Um, how can I get that fixed?
There's options for fixing chipped front teeth.
The most conservative option
there is a product called bonding,
and bonding is—think of it like something that
adheres to the tooth that's the shade of your
natural tooth—and so that's why we might want
to whiten our teeth first, so we can up the
color a little bit and then match an improved
color if that's something you're interested in.
And why do patients normally
come here to the dentist?
What is the most typical issue they
have, and why do they come here?
What we have found is patients who come to
the dentist on a routine basis every 6 months,
over the lifetime, have fewer
problems with their teeth.
The most common thing that we see are normal
six-month type of checkups
for cleanings and x-rays.
But another common type of appointment is an
emergency appointment when a tooth is broken,
or a tooth has discomfort, or there might be
swelling, something like wisdom teeth coming in.
So there's a lot of things that can
happen that might signal that you
might need to see the dentist,
but the best bet is to go on a routine basis
so that you can avoid those types of problems.
What do you normally
specialize in besides checkups?
A general dentist, which is what we do typically,
are like cleanings, fillings, root canals, crowns.
But in our office, we have
lots of different doctors,
and we have specialists in our office too.
So we do things like Invisalign, cosmetic
dentistry, dental implants, wisdom teeth.
People also can come in here and
have our oral surgeon and go to
sleep and get their wisdom teeth taken
out while they're taking a little nap.
We do a little bit of everything here.
And why are people scared to go to the dentist?
I think the most common things that
make going to the dentist fearful is
it could be expensive, especially if we
don't do the preventive type of care.
Dental pain is very intense, or it can be,
but we have things that can help with that,
like numbing agents that help deaden
the teeth while we can work on them,
and also certain medications can help too.
So our patients have a really good
experience when they come to our office,
so we make sure that there are answers
for it, keeping them out of pain,
and also for financial arrangements
to help them afford treatment better.
Thank you so much, Dr. Pearce,
for having this interview with
me and teaching me a little bit
about cavities and everything.
And if you want to get your teeth cleaned,
come here to Pearce Dental
Group to get your teeth cleaned.
Thank you so much.
Hi, what's your name, and can you tell
me what you're holding in your hand?
Hi, I'm Dr. Tara, and I'm holding
what's called a typodont, and I use
it to educate patients so that they know what
I'm talking about when I'm talking dentistry.
And can you tell me like the
names of different teeth?
Sure. So we have the back
teeth, which are called molars.
The teeth between the front teeth and the
back teeth, which are called premolars.
We have canines.
And then we have central incisors
and laterals just on the outsides.
So right now you're holding
a toothbrush in your hand.
Can you tell me the best way to brush your teeth?
Some of the best ways is to take the brush and
go along the gum line at a 45-degree angle.
You wanna be able to massage the
teeth and your gums at the same time.
I personally like an electric
toothbrush better than a manual
toothbrush because it takes the
guesswork out of how to brush.
But if you want to use a manual
toothbrush, you go along the gum lines.
You want to be brushing at least about
2 minutes, and what that allows you to
do is to get all the areas of the mouth and be
really comfortable and get a really good clean.
And then should I brush, floss,
and then mouthwash, or what's the—?
Everyone always asks this question.
The goal is for you to brush and floss.
Which order you do it in doesn't really matter.
Studies show that you get the exact same result.
I personally floss first and then I brush,
but I know plenty of people who do the
opposite and they have great oral hygiene.
Mouthwash is optional.
You definitely can optimize and use mouthwash
if you want to, but you don't have to.
Thank you so much.
-You're welcome.
Hi, I just got my teeth cleaned.
-Hi, awesome.
I can get your scheduled back for
your treatment with Dr. Pearce,
and I can also collect your
payment for today's visit.
Would you like to pay with
insurance or credit card?
-With insurance.
I have my insurance card right here.
-Perfect, thank you.
Let me enter that in the system.
Okay, everybody, that's all for today's video.
It's very important to go to the dentist
because—because today it turned out I
have three cavities, and I have to
come back to the dentist in 2 weeks.
I hope you guys enjoyed the video.
Go ahead and give me a like, subscribe,
and I'll see you guys next week.
Bye.