Hello, lovely students, and welcome back to
English with Lucy.
If you know these 15 business English
phrases, your professional English is
amazing, no question!
These are 15 advanced professional phrases!
As always, I've created a free PDF that
you can download, and I've included 15
bonus business English phrases as an
extra boost to your vocabulary!
I've also included an interactive
vocabulary exercise to test you on what
you've learnt.
If you'd like to download that PDF, just
click on the link in the description box
or scan that little QR code there.
Enter your name and your email address,
and the PDF will arrive directly in your inbox.
After that you've joined my PDF club, you
will automatically receive my free weekly
lesson PDFs alongside all of my news,
course updates and offers.
It's a free service, and you can
unsubscribe at any time.
There are 15 professional English phrases
in total.
I want to know how many you know out of 15?
Let me know in the comments, and let me
know which ones were new to you.
Okay, let's get down to business.
Phrase number 1, 'touch base,' 'touch base.'
'To touch base' means to make contact with
someone, usually to share updates or information.
We usually say 'base' with a bit more
energy, 'touch base.'
You might also hear people say 'check in'
or 'catch up,' which have similar meanings.
For example—'Let's touch base next week
to discuss the progress of
the marketing campaign.'
Moving on to phrase 2, 'get the ball rolling'.
'Get the ball rolling'.
When you 'get the ball rolling', you start
or initiate something, like
a project or a meeting.
This phrase comes from the idea of
pushing a ball to start it moving.
Another similar phrase is 'kick off'.
An example for 'get the ball rolling'—'I've
scheduled a team meeting for Monday to
get the ball rolling on the new product launch'.
Next up, phrase 3, 'on the same page,'
'on the same page.'
Being 'on the same page' means that
everyone agrees and understands a
situation in the same way.
'Before we move forward, we need to get on
the same page and figure out the next steps.'
Phrase 4, this is a good one.
'In the loop,' 'in the loop.'
Informed about what is going on.
We normally stress the word 'loop,' 'in the loop.'
The opposite phrase is 'out of the loop,'
meaning someone isn't fully informed.
An example—'I'll send a weekly update
email to keep all stakeholders in the loop.'
Or—'I've been feeling a bit out of the
loop ever since I got back from maternity leave.'
And number 5, we have 'win-win.'
'Win-win.'
Business professionals love to use this phrase!
'A win-win situation' is one that benefits
everyone involved.
We say both syllables clearly, but the
main stress is on the second 'win.'
'Win-win.'
An example—'If we collaborate with their
team, it could be a win-win for both companies.'
Now, you get a bonus point if you can
come up with the opposite of 'win-win.'
No trick questions here.
We do say a 'lose-lose,' I promise.
Phrase 6 is 'think out of the box.'
'Think out of the box,' or
'think outside of the box.'
'To think out of the box' is to think
creatively and innovatively, coming up
with entirely new solutions.
If someone tells you 'to think out of the
box,' they are basically saying—think creatively.
You will also hear people shorten 'out of
the' to /ˈaʊtə ðə/ or /ˈaʊt̬ə ðə/.
That's in fast speech.
As I mentioned, we also say 'think outside
the box' or 'think outside of the box.'
They're both very common, just choose the
one you like best.
An example—'We really need to think
outside the box if we're going to beat
our competitors on this.'
Lucky number 7 is 'bottom line.'
'Bottom line.'
'The bottom line' has two main meanings in
business contexts.
First, it refers to the essential point
or final outcome.
It's the most important part of the
matter, the deciding factor.
This could be meeting a deadline,
satisfying customer needs, or achieving a
specific goal.
For example—'The bottom line is that we
need to ensure customer satisfaction
above all else.'
In addition to this more general meaning,
'the bottom line' also has a specific
financial definition.
In a business English setting, your
'bottom line' can refer to the final
financial outcome, whether it's a profit
or a loss, after all expenses and
revenues have been accounted for.
An example—'Our bottom line has improved
since implementing the new cost-saving measures.'
For phrase 8, we have 'action point.'
'Action point.'
'An action point' is a task that needs to
be completed, usually assigned during a meeting.
Stress 'action.'
You might also hear 'action item,' which
has the same meaning.
An example—'Let's review the action
points from last week's meeting.'
Phrase 9, 'learning curve.'
'Learning curve.'
'The learning curve' is the time it takes
to learn a new skill or understand a new process.
We often use the strong collocation—
'steep learning curve' to talk about
something that's quite difficult to learn.
For example—'We went through a steep
learning curve when switching to the new
software but it was worth it in the end.'
Number 10, 'game plan.'
'Game plan.'
Notice how there's no pause between the
two words and I blend the 'm' and 'p' together.
'Game plan.'
'A game plan' is a strategy or plan for
achieving a goal.
And this phrase likely comes from sports
where teams have a strategic plan for winning.
For example—'Let's develop a game plan
for expanding into international markets.'
Phrase 11, 'to give the green light.'
'To give the green light.'
When someone 'gives the green light,' they
approve or give permission for something
to happen.
The emphasis is on 'green light,' which
comes from traffic signals where green
means go.
You might also hear the verb 'to green-light
something,' which has a similar meaning.
An example—'Once the budget is approved,
we'll give the green light to start the project.'
At 12, we have 'at stake,' 'at stake.'
If something is 'at stake,' it means it's
at risk or there's something to be lost
or gained, and it often implies high
importance or urgency.
For example—'There's a lot at stake with
this big client pitch, so let's bring our
A-game!'
'A-game' is another great expression,
meaning giving your best performance or effort.
Moving on to 13, 'pain point,' 'pain point.'
'A pain point' is a problem or challenge
that a customer or business is facing,
but the emphasis is on pain.
Identifying 'pain points' helps businesses
create solutions that customers need.
For example—'Our new service addresses a
major pain point for small business owners.'
Our penultimate phrase—phrase 14—is 'up
to speed,' 'up to speed.'
When you're 'up to speed,' it means you
have the latest information and are fully
informed about a particular topic or situation.
We often use this phrase with 'on' to
specify the subject.
For example—'I need to get up to speed on
the new project guidelines.'
Once you're comfortable with this usage,
you'll also often hear it combined with
verbs like 'get' or 'be.'
For example—'Let's schedule a call to get
the new team members up to speed on the project.'
And finally, our last one, number 15, we
have 'ballpark figure.'
'Ballpark figure.'
I remember being so confused when I heard
this for the first time.
'A ballpark figure' is a rough estimate,
not an exact number.
'Ballpark' likely comes from baseball
stadiums, implying a large general area.
For example—'Can you give me a ballpark
figure for the cost of the event?'
And there you have it: 15 essential, quite
advanced business English phrases to help
you sound professional. How many did you
know? Let me know in the comments! You can
practice using these in your work
conversations and emails, and you'll sound
like a seasoned pro in no time.
Also, this is the first time I'm
mentioning it on this channel, but in the
next few months, I will release my new
Professional English Programme, Level 2.
This caters to the B2 level of English in
a professional context.
If you would like to sign up to the
waiting list, I have added a link in the
description box, or you can scan the QR
code right here.
This means that you'll be the first to
know about all updates on the release of
this Programme.
I've also left a link to Level 1, which
you could take now, and then you could do
Level 2 later.
Don't forget to download the free PDF for
this lesson, where you have 15 bonus phrases.
I will see you soon for the next one.
Muah!