Hi there, it's Ronnie, going to teach
you a lesson about using the past tense.
A lot of people struggle
with the past tense
because there's so many
verbs, there's irregular
verbs, there's regular verbs, "ed" verbs,
and a lot of the times when we're focused
too much on the
conjugation of verbs, we kind
of forget to use other
ways to actually use
the past in regular
conversations, which is
my goal with you, to
help you speak naturally
so you don't sound like a person
that doesn't speak English very well.
I want you to sound as natural as you can,
and this is a really interesting thing that
I've been thinking about for a while is how
we use the past tense in kind of a strange
way.
So, this is a grammar-based lesson on using
the past, but there's some cool connections
here.
Let's look at our
sentences, first of all.
The blue sentences are
written in present tense.
I would say, "He
is such an asshole."
Because our verb is "is",
we know this is present tense.
And "such an asshole"
means they're not
really cool, not a really
good person, okay?
But if we wanted to make it past, we
would say, "He was such an asshole."
So, again, simple past,
we're changing "is" to "was".
And, hopefully, through
this, when I'm giving
you these examples,
you're thinking, "Wow,
why would I say 'He
was such an asshole'?"
Okay?
Let's look at number two.
We always go to the park
and make fun of rollerbladers.
Do you know what this means
to make fun of someone?
Ha-ha.
If you make fun of
someone, it means that
you take delight or joy
in weird things about
people.
So...
Or bad things.
Let's say that someone's
wearing some weird
clothes, or someone
falls someplace, or they're
doing something that
you think is weird, you
would make fun of
them, like, "Oh, that's
weird.
Ha-ha.
That's weird you do that."
This is how bullying starts.
So, you can make fun of
rollerbladers, that's fine.
We always go to the park
and make fun of rollerbladers.
This sentence is in simple present, because
we have "always" and we have the verb "go".
If I wanted to make
that past, I would say,
"We would always go
to the park and make fun
of rollerbladers."
This past tense of
the verb "will", "would",
the auxiliary verb, is
indicating to me that
it's something that we did in
the past as kind of a hobby.
It's my hobby to do that.
We can talk about people's jobs.
I can say, "Oh, yeah, yeah,
yeah, I know, I know, Kelly.
She is an undertaker."
So, when we talk about people's occupations
or their jobs, we use the verb "to be", and
again in the past, "Oh, yeah,
yeah, she was an undertaker."
So, why would we use the past
tense to speak about people like this?
What's happening?
There are two reasons.
One of them is maybe the person
has died, or the person's dead to you.
Maybe the person you're
speaking to is talking
about an ex-boyfriend
or an ex-girlfriend
or an ex-friend.
So, if I'm having a
conversation with someone
and they said, "Oh my
god, Kevin was such
an asshole", hmm, this has two things
that are going to happen in my brain.
Either Kevin's dead, or we no longer talk
to Kevin, and he's still an asshole, maybe,
but the relationship with
the speaker has changed.
Let's look at this example.
"Oh, we would always go to the
park and make fun of rollerbladers."
We're reminiscing or
thinking about things in
the past that we would
do with this person.
Maybe this is a good thing
about a past relationship.
"Oh, my ex and I, you know, we broke up, we
would always go to the park, it was great."
So, when people are
using the past tense to
speak about someone,
those are the two reasons.
"She was an undertaker."
Now, she could be
retired, or she could be
dead, or, you know,
your ex-girlfriend could
have been into that stuff
and been an undertaker.
Another thing that we
use in English to talk
about habits, like "would",
is we use "used to".
"Oh, you know what?
You know, we used
to go to the cemetery."
So, I'm talking about
things that we did habitually,
things that we did
together on a regular basis.
And in English, again, I
use the simple present.
We go to the graveyard.
This tells me...
And by the way, "graveyard"
and "cemetery", not very different.
Oh, hey, Trevor.
What are you doing there, buddy?
He's the keeper of the
graveyard and the cemetery.
We go to the graveyard,
something you do on a regular basis.
Every Tuesday, we go to
the cemetery and we run.
Or every Friday, we go to the
graveyard and we check out the birds.
We go birdwatching in the
cemetery, see some crows.
But if people are using
the past tense, you're
going to have to be
careful, especially if
the person's dead.
It's very important to
read your audience.
If someone's like, "Oh, okay,
um, tell me about your family.
Okay, tell me about your dad.
Uh, yeah, he was really cool."
Uh-oh, he was cool.
What happened to him?
Is he not cool anymore?
No.
He's probably dead.
So be very careful with this.
You don't want to trigger
someone or make them
feel depressed or sad
about what's happened.
We also have some
very interesting vocabulary
that could be confusing
if you didn't know
how to talk about
dead people, not exes.
"Exes", by the way, means
past boyfriends or girlfriends.
We just say "exes".
It's my ex.
You could say "someone passed away"
or "someone passed", and you think...
Did they pass a test?
Did they pass you on the street?
No.
This means that they're dead.
So these are some different
phrases that people use.
It's kind of rude to say,
"Oh yeah, he's dead."
Like, whoa.
Okay?
So, people try and
use more polite phrases.
You might hear someone say,
"Oh yeah, we lost him last year."
You lost him?
Well, did you find him?
Where did he go?
Is he okay?
If someone says, "We lost someone",
again, that means that the person's dead.
More formally, "She's
no longer with us."
And then you think,
well, where is she?
Is she with someone else?
No.
If someone's no longer with
us, again, it means they're dead.
We have some slang.
It's okay to joke with
your friends, but make
sure your friends aren't
going through a death
when you're doing this.
First word is
"croaked", like a frog.
I don't know why.
Frogs croak.
It's the sound that
frogs make, by the way.
So, "Oh yeah, the old
man croaked yesterday."
He's a frog?
No.
Just means he died.
Here's a really common one.
"He kicked the bucket."
Oh.
Well, I don't know why
that represents death.
I've got some homework, or
you've got some homework.
In the comments, look
these expressions up
and tell me why in
English we say "he kicked
the bucket", because he's dead.
Right?
So, if he's dead, you can't
kick a bucket, figure this out.
And there's one,
"He dropped dead."
This has the suggestion
that the person died
suddenly, like, oh
yeah, he was just jogging
and he dropped dead.
It's really strange the
amount of people who
are really fit, really
healthy, and they're
jogging and they die.
Yeah, don't jog.
Run fast or walk, but just don't
jog, because you might pass out.
And that's another thing.
"Pass out", be careful,
and "pass away".
You don't say, "Oh yeah, my
grandmother passed out last night."
"Pass out" means you
lose consciousness,
but "passed away"
means that you died, so...
I know English is
difficult, I know we've
got these phrasal
verbs, but one thing that's
really important when
you're speaking to people,
pay attention and try
and use the past tense
naturally using expressions like "he was",
"we would always do this", "we used to" to
talk about habits, and
make sure that when
you're listening to
people, if they're using
the person in the past
tense, that you focus
on why they're doing
this, like, oh, okay,
I remember Ronnie's
lesson, it's either an
ex or a dead person,
so be careful, but have
fun.
And for your homework,
check out these expressions,
and don't forget to visit
your local graveyard.
I'll be there, too, with
Trevor, yeah, we'll
be hanging out, you
know, taking autographs
and stuff, and maybe you can give me
some popsicles when you're there, but...
Or money, you know.
I'm Ronnie, and I hope that
all your days are wonderful.
Yeah.