- Hello, lovely students and welcome back
to English with Lucy. Before we start today's
lesson, I've got a question for you. Can you
understand what I'm saying and I really hope
you said yes because I often read comments
on my videos saying things like I can understand
you perfectly but I can't understand my coworkers.
Or why can I understand you but I have to
watch British series and films with subtitles.
Well, in today's lesson I'm going to explain
why you have so much difficulty understanding
native speakers and I'll give you some tips
to help you overcome these challenges. Now,
before we get started, don't forget to download
today's PDF. It's a free PDF that comes with
today's lesson. It's going to give you a detailed
explanation of each of today's points as well
as a quiz to test your understanding. We'll
also mark out some key vocabulary, so you
get a little vocab bonus there. If you would
like to download that free PDF, all you've
got to do is click on the link in the description
box. You enter your name and your email address.
You sign up to my mailing list and then the
PDF arrives directly in your inbox. And after
that you've joined the PDF club. You will
automatically receive my free weekly lesson
PDFs along with all of my other news course
offers and updates. It's a free service you
can unsubscribe at any time. Okay, let's get
started with the lesson. Tip number one, understand
that spoken English is different from textbook
or school English. This is a really important
concept to understand is going to help you
so much. Now, simply put the English that
native speakers use in everyday life is generally
very different to the English that you learn
at school. I'm talking about casual everyday
type English that you'd use in daily conversations.
Now, I'll admit it when I speak in my YouTube
and course videos, I do speak at a slightly
slower pace. I choose my words carefully and
I make sure that my register is suitable for
English learners. I want you to be able to
understand each word I say. But most native
speakers you meet on the street will not necessarily
have the same mindset. Or they might not be
as able to change their register to adapt
to learners of English. Take my mother for
example. Many years ago I had a Spanish boyfriend
who didn't speak English and watching my mother
try to talk to him was pretty hilarious. She
was using idioms, phrasal verbs, dropping
her Ts, messing around with the pronunciation
and the poor guy stood no chance for a number
of reasons and not just when it comes to understanding
my mother. Here are some examples of how spoken
English and textbook English might differ
from a grammar standpoint. There are certain
tenses and grammatical structures that are
far more commonly used in written English
than they are in spoken English, like the
passive voice which is a grammatical construction
used to emphasise the action or object rather
than the subject or doer. It's often preferred
in academic writing formal reports and professional
documents. For example, the decision was made
by the committee. Sticking on the topic of
grammar you may have been taught that you
shouldn't end sentences with prepositions.
Well I'm here to tell you that native speakers
do it all the time. It might be confusing
to hear a random preposition at the end of
a sentence, but trust me, it's really common.
Like in this example, who are you going with?
It honestly sounds way too proper to say With
whom are you going? Obviously, if you say
it without the accent with whom are you going
it sounds slightly less proper but it sounds
old fashioned at best. Another example, it
sounds way more natural to say she didn't
know who to give the gift to rather than the
textbook English version she didn't know to
whom to give the gift. I also want to point
out that we tend to bend other rules a bit
when speaking. For example, you might hear
someone say I haven't got any money which
is common in spoken British English. While
in school you're most likely taught to say
I don't have any money. Another example of
this is in the expression can't believe it,
where we drop the subject and utilise the
contraction of cannot. Obviously, you are
taught in school to always include a subject
like I cannot believe it but that doesn't
always happen in conversation. Tip number
two. Get feedback from trained, qualified
professionals. If you are serious about truly
mastering English there really is no better
way than one-on-one sessions with a qualified
professional. Trying to progress without feedback
is really bloody hard. There's no better place
to do this than LanguaTalk which is a company
that I think is so awesome. I decided to become
a part of it. So technically I'm sponsoring
myself here. LanguaTalk is an online language
tutor platform with incredibly high quality
teachers. Across all the languages they only
accept around 10% of applicants, but for English
it's much lower. Their standards are that
high. I'm currently using it to learn Italian.
My husband will uses it to learn Spanish and
you can join us and learn English there. The
teachers are top notch. Now, a little incentive.
I will give you $10 in lesson credit if you
sign up and take your first lesson after watching
this video. So as well as being able to log
in, look through all the teacher's profile
videos, book a 30 minute trial lesson for
free. You can also claim $10 towards lessons
by messaging their support team with the code
EWL10. This is valid for anyone signing up
from today onwards. The link is in the description
box. Have a look, have a browse, and find
your perfect fit for a tutor. Tip number three,
native speakers don't articulate. This is
the topic of connected speech. So one of the
things I'm sure you'll pick up on while listening
to British content or in conversations with
your LanguaTalk tutor or native English speaking
friends, is that we love to squish our words
together and get information out as quickly
and efficiently as possible, and this is known
as connected speech which refers to the way
words are linked together in natural fluent
speech. Now, there are several key aspects
of connected speech that you need to be aware
of. And I'm not going to go too deep into
this right now but I want you to be aware
of certain features you will definitely hear
in spoken British English. We'll start with
elision. Elision is the omission or leaving
out of certain sounds and speech often to
make pronunciation more efficient and fluid.
In British English, the most common example
is the dropping of the final t sound in words
like not, but and what. For example, I don't
know, might be pronounced as I don' know,
no t sound to be found there. Assimilation.
Assimilation occurs when a sound changes to
become more like a neighbouring sound. In
British English this often happens with the
t and d sounds when followed by a y sound
t and y often sounds like ch and d and y often
sounds like j. For example. Got you, go'chew.
Would you, wou'jew? Now, this one is really
fun. The intrusive r. In British English an
r sound is sometimes inserted between two
vow sounds to make the transition smoother
and this is particularly common in non-erotic
accents such as received pronunciation or
modern received pronunciation, my accent.
For example, law and order may be pronounced
as law-r-and order. I've inserted an Ur R
sound that isn't meant to be there but I've
put it there because it's easier for me. Now
as well as the intrusive r we also have the
linking r, and this is really similar but
it occurs when a word ending in the letter
r is followed by a word beginning with a vowel
sound. In non-erotic accents the r is pronounced
to connect the two words. For example far
away may be pronounced as fa-raway, fa-raway.
Far on its own no r sound, but when followed
by a word starting with a vowel sound fa-raway,
it's just natural to put it in there. And
let's look at weak forms. In connected speech,
certain words are often pronounced with a
reduced or weak form. And this is particularly
common with function words such as prepositions
articles and auxiliary verbs. For example,
two may be pronounced as t and and maybe pronounced
as n. So. That was a very quick overview.
We do have more videos on connected speech.
It is actually one of my favourite topics.
Understanding how frequently connected speech
is used will go a long way in improving your
comprehension skills. Let's move on to tip
four contractions and unique language features.
I feel like contractions go hand in hand with
connected speech. Contractions as I have talked
about in previous videos refer to the shortening
of words by combining two or more words, there
are sometimes triplets in there, together.
This process involves emitting certain letters
and replacing them with an apostrophe. In
spoken English native speakers pretty much
always use contractions. For example, we don't
say, I am from England. We say I'm from England,
I'm is the contraction there. Here are some
common contractions, but please be sure to
download today's PDF to see a full list. As
I said before, the link is in the description
box. We have, I'm, you're, we're, they're,
he's, she's, it's, I've, you've, we've, they've,
I'll, you'll, we'll, they'll, can't, didn't,
won't, coulda, woulda, shoulda let's, there's,
that's, I could go on forever about contractions
and maybe I should let me know if you want
a focused video on contractions. Now we also
have informal contractions which combine two
or more words into shorter words but they
are quite informal and they're used in very
casual conversations like in this sentence.
I hafta go to the shops if you wanna come
rather than I have to go to the shops if you
want to come. These kinds of informal contractions
are extremely popular and tend to cause a
lot of confusion for English learners so the
more familiar you become with them, the quicker
your listening skills will improve. Here we
have some very common ones like usta, kinda,
lotsa, coulda, Ida, sheeda, how'dja, and what'dja.
Final tip, learn idioms and slang. If you
want to understand native speakers this is
unavoidable. As English learners I'm sure
you were taught to speak in a very direct
form of English to say exactly what you mean.
But unfortunately native speakers don't often
speak in such a way. We tend to use a lot
of slang and idioms because it adds colour
and character to what we're trying to say
and I'm sure you do the same in your native
language. I know I said that connected speech
is one of my favourite things to teach, but
I actually think that idioms and slang is
too, I can't decide, so I won't. I'll just
enjoy them both. Slang and idioms are often
used to express ideas or emotions in a more
creative and nuanced way than standard direct
English but this also tends to make it challenging
for English learners to understand. Here are
some very common slang terms that you will
most likely encounter in daily conversation.
Grub. Food, particularly pub food or unhealthy
food food that fills you. Lurgy. An unspecified
mild illness or feeling unwell. It's like
a general call or I've got some sort of lurgy.
Dab hand. If you're a dab hand at something
you are skilled or proficient at something.
Fit, this is used to mean attractive rather
than just physically fit which which it means
a normal English and slang English. If I say
you are so fit, it means you are so attractive.
We also have merry or tipsy meaning slightly
drunk while wasted or pissed signifies being
heavily intoxicated. Be careful because pissed
in British English means heavily drunk and
pissed in American English means angry. In
British English we tend to say pissed off,
a phrasal verb. One of my favourites, I use
this all the time, knackered, if you are knackered,
you are extremely tired. I also like to say
chuffed. Ah, which means very happy or pleased
or kind of smug and satisfied. I'm chuffed
with my exam result. Okay, I have put loads
more idioms and slang phrases in the pdf,
so don't forget to download that. If you enjoy
learning about slang and idioms let me know
and I can make a dedicated video for you.
It's something I enjoy teaching, so if you
like it and I like it, I mean we should get
together and and make a video. Right, that's
it from me. That's it for today's lesson.
I really hope these tips help you. Again,
don't forget about the PDF. The link is there.
It's designed to help you and don't forget
about that offer on LanguaTalk. It really
is an awesome platform. Otherwise, I wouldn't
have become a part of it. Use that code for
your discount. Just send it to the support
team after enrolling in your first lesson.
If you weren't aware, we have recently launched
our B1 B2 and C1 programmes. Please don't
forget to check those out if you're looking
to take your English really, really seriously.
And I will see you soon for another lesson.
Bye.