(bright upbeat music)
- Okay, so let's start off
by talking about your work.
Do you work or do you study?
- I'm currently working,
I finished my studies two years ago,
so I'm currently working as a pharmacist.
- And where do you currently work?
- I currently work in Dublin.
I came in Dublin a few months ago.
I worked previous in
Romania from where I am.
- And why did you choose that career?
- Well, I think my mother
has some influences on me.
She's an assistant and she always
thought that pharmacy will suck me
and it's a easy job
and, or respected jobs.
So she kind of pushed me to do pharmacy.
So I chose pharmacy in the end.
- And do you enjoy your job?
- I do now.
When I was in Romania, I
didn't like it that much.
But now in Ireland the system is different
and I feel more appreciated for my work.
So it starts to grow on me.
- Good.
So now let's talk about your hometown.
So where are you from?
- I am from a small town in Romania,
so I grew up in a really small town
and then I moved to a
larger city near to my town
and it's called Negresti.
So it's difficult for
foreigners to pronounce it.
- And do you like your hometown?
- I didn't like it when I was a child.
I like it now because it's a small town,
a small community where
you can raise your children
with no problems with no bad influences.
So it's a good place where you can grow up
and be a decent person.
- How often do you visit your hometown?
- Now that I'm living in Ireland
probably I will visit
once or twice a year.
But when I lived in
the other city in Iasi,
I went to Negresti maybe twice a month.
- And how do you think your
hometown could be improved?
- Well, because it's a small community,
maybe just improve the job offers,
try to raise the local economy.
Most of the people that are living there
are farmers or they are
working in construction.
So maybe just improved that
part and they can live better.
- Now let's talk about your childhood.
Did you have a nice childhood?
- Yes, I did.
Like I said, it was small community,
so my parents knew every
neighbors that we had.
They weren't afraid to leave me with kids
on the street just to play
or let me out in the night
to going with my friends to have some fun.
So it was nice.
- What is your first memory?
- My first memory is a funny one.
I was two years and a half and
I run from my grandparents'
house to go to Kinnegad
where my aunt was going.
So I missed her so much
that I ran out of the house
and come back with her a few hours later.
- And when you were a child,
what did you want to be when you grew up?
- I only loved medicine,
pharmacy science in general.
So I knew I would be a biology teacher
or doctor or pharmacist,
something that related
with the science part.
- And what hobbies did
you have as a child?
- I tried a lot of hobbies.
I tried singing.
I tried sports.
I did actually karate.
I did a lot of them, but I never found one
that it suits me 100%.
So I don't think I have a hobby.
- All right.
That's the end of part one.
We're gonna move on to part two now.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna show you
a cue card with a topic on it.
You should read the cue card
and you will have one
minute to prepare an answer.
After that one minute,
I'll let you know when
the one minute is up
and you should speak about the topic
on the cue card for up to two minutes.
Is that okay?
All right.
Here's the cue cards.
I'll start the stop watch.
(bright upbeat music)
- Please speak for up to two minutes.
- So I'm going to talk
about my first computer
that I got when I was like
eight or 10 years old.
Back then we didn't have
an internet connection,
so it was pretty easy to use it,
especially for a kid that did
some computer science in school.
So basically I used it
only for basic games
that I already had
pre-installed on my system
or listen to music or movies
that I borrowed from my friends.
It wasn't hard for me to
learn a computer science
on that one because with the
develop of the technology
we got also a computer or
internet connection in our house.
So practically I started to grew up
on the same time with the technology.
So now the main benefits
that I'm getting from that
are me knowing to use and
discover more utilities
of the computer, new programs.
I can manage to solve my own problems
with the computer hardware or software.
I also don't have any
difficulties when it comes
to work to solve a problem
with my system at work.
Also I think because we
as a generation grew up
with a computer in our houses,
we got a lot of advantages of this because
nowadays everyone is depending on
a smart device or a computer.
So that helped a lot and I even start--
(laughs)
- So that's the end of part two.
And we're gonna move on to part three.
All right.
So we've been talking about technology
and we're gonna continue to talk about
technology for a little bit.
And we're going to talk about technology
as it relates to education.
So the first question is,
"Do you think someone can learn a language
using an online course?"
- Yeah, I just did that.
It's not like I learned a
language, a new language.
But an online course can help as much
as a face to face teacher can help you
if it's a good course and it
has enough explanation on it,
they can help you a lot
to get the information
that you are missing.
So, for example if we are
speaking about a vocabulary course
for a beginner, a good course
will provide the learner
the basic words, the basic grammar
and everything that they have to know
in the beginning of
learning that language.
- And should schools use more
technology in the classroom?
- I think so because children nowadays use
their smart mobiles and
smart devices all the times.
So they are very familiar with technology
and schools should really
improve their classrooms.
I don't know about Ireland in general,
but in Romania we didn't have
computers in our classrooms.
We had only one with computers
and the rest were all old books.
So every new information that
we got it came from books
and not an actual technology piece or
let's say we are studying biology,
it's easier to study
something that you can see 3D
like we Taylor Graham's
than seeing him in book.
- And do you think one day
AI Artificial Intelligence
will replace teachers in the classroom?
- No, I don't think that because a teacher
can come with some experience in the back,
can come with more than
Artificial Intelligence can bring.
It's a personal experience
that a student can correlate
with the lesson and remember
that particular story
from the teacher's
experience and correlate it
with what he learned.
So I don't think a computer could do that
even though it's programmed to be like
an Artificial Intelligence.
I don't think it will accomplish that.
- Now let's talk about
technology and society.
So has technology improved
how we communicate
with each other?
- It has.
If we are speaking about
smartphones for example,
now we can.
Not only can call each other.
We can text in a few seconds.
We can video call.
We can use the internet
connection to see each other
from big distances like
I am with my family.
The smart device that I'm
using is helped me a lot
to keeping in touch with them.
- And why are some people now reducing
the amount of time they
spend on electronic devices?
- I think at some point we got overwhelmed
by the technology around us.
And now people are trying to realize that
the social connection
that are between people
are starting to fade.
So they are trying to
restart a real connection
between people and give up a
little bit of social internet
and actually doing some socialization.
(laughs)
- Okay, good.
Well done.
That's it over.
You can breathe now.
You can relax and you
ended up with socialization
at the end.
(laughs)
All right, good.
So now I am gonna give you some advice.
And I'm basing this
advice on the fact that
you've done the test three times now.
You got a band six the
first time in speaking,
then you got seven and then you got eight
in speaking before.
So you're continually improving.
And what we want to do
with you is to make sure
that next time you do the test
that you absolutely want 100%
are going to get at least
the score that you need.
Because as a pharmacist
you need a band seven.
What you're struggling a little bit
with writing at the minute,
but sometimes students will
focus so much on writing
and let's say they're at a band seven
for speaking and they'll
focus so much on writing
and they forget or they
just are a little bit
complacent when it comes to speaking.
So what we're gonna.
The advice I'm gonna give
you now is to make sure
that you would never fall below a seven
and to make sure that you get there.
So first of all, I'm
gonna go through each part
and then I'm gonna go through
the four marking criteria.
So you did something in part
one which is very common
where you were a little bit
nervous in the beginning.
So when we're talking about work,
you were a little bit more hesitant,
shorter answers, and
that is totally normal.
And most examiners will
expect that because
part one is important but it is designed
to let you ease into the
test and to let you warm up.
So that's why they ask
you questions about work,
about your hometown, about your home
which you know, are quite easy questions
to try and get you warmed up.
- And as you went through
when you were talking about your hometown
and more when you're talking
about your childhood,
you were talking far more fluently.
You were developing your answers.
It was more relaxed.
So when you're talking about work,
it was like not robotic but,
when you're talking about
hometown and childhood
is like talking to a
friend all by yourself.
If you and I were in a coffee
shop when I was saying,
"Did you have a nice childhood?"
you're like, "Yeah, I did."
And just talking naturally.
And that was great to see.
So part one was really good.
The examiners would never
listen to your first few answers
that were a little bit,
let's say there were a
little bit short fluency,
a little bit hesitant.
They would never base their score
on those first few answers.
So some people watching now,
we'd be like, "Oh, she
gave one short answer."
She gets a band six like that's not
how the examiners think or how
the marking criteria thinks.
The examiner will base
their score on the totality,
your total performance.
Not on one short answer or one answer
where you hesitated for example.
So for part one and the length was good.
You really eased into it.
Your fluency was excellent.
Some nice vocabulary in there,
some grammatical errors.
But we'll talk about
that when we talk about
the four marking criteria.
I think part two was the
area that you struggled
with a little bit compared
to the other parts
cause there was a lot of pausing,
a lot of hesitation.
So your fluency wasn't as good in part two
as it was in part one and part three.
I'll tell you why I think but
it's always good to hear from the student.
Why did you think that you
were struggling or did you.
You didn't do a bad job by the way.
It's just in comparison
to the other parts,
there was more audible
pauses and like, "uh, uh."
- Yeah, I've noticed that myself.
Maybe because I try to.
I forgot about some ideas
that I had in my head
and I tried to see if I got
all those thoughts on the card.
I know I don't have to
speak about all of them.
They are just guidelines.
But at some point I felt stuck
and didn't know what to say.
So maybe that's why with the long pauses.
- So the audible pauses
are normally caused
by one of two things.
One is linguistic, related to
grammar related to vocabulary.
So you're tryna think of the
correct word for example.
The other one is related to ideas.
People tryna think of content,
basically things to say.
Was it linguistic?
Were you trying to think
of the correct vocabulary
and grammar or was it just ideas?
- Ideas.
So the examiner will
also notice that because
if you are constantly
stopping because you're trying
to think of the correct verb
tense or trying to think
of the correct vocabulary,
that's a signal to the examiner
that you have a problem
with the English language.
If you're just pausing
because you're just tryna
think of the next thing to say,
that's not really a problem
with the English language.
It's more of a problem with the subject.
And so the examiner should
take that into account.
But one of the things that
I noticed that you did,
which normally causes a drop in fluency
related to content is you
listed a lot of things.
So you're like.
So for example it could be,
"I went to the shop when I got bananas,
an Apple and cheese and
cereal" and you're tryna
think of the next thing and the next thing
and the next thing.
It's much easier just to
pick one of those things.
So you're talking about
software versus hardware
and go a little bit deeper into that
until at a story related to
that or example related to that.
Because I think a lot of
people go through part two
and they're just like okay,
"I need to talk about this,
let's list a lot of things with that."
Then this, list a lot of things.
And then you run out of time
or run out of things to say.
So I think when you're
doing the real test,
don't be afraid to go
very deep into one thing
and especially pick one thing
that you're comfortable talking about.
Like, for example, "When
I was a little girl
I got Windows 2000" or something like that
and how the changes that it
made were blah, blah, blah.
" And I really learned a lot
about programming through that."
So that's much better than,
"We had Windows and we
had Adobe and we had this
and we had this and we had this."
You see what I mean?
- Yeah.
- It just makes it easier
for you to be more fluent.
So I think that's the
only in terms of fluency
and coherence, that's
the only area of concern
that I would have.
- You weren't like, your
fluency wasn't terrible.
But well just making sure that
you would never go below a seven.
And if that topic sounds
like something you know
a lot about it but if
you've got another topic
that you don't like, that could
turn into a problem for you.
And part two is such
a big part of the test
that if you get a topic
you are uncomfortable with
plus you're tryna think of content
that can really drag
down your fluency scores.
So that would be my main bit of advice
to go deep on a few things
you feel comfortable
talking about rather than
trying to list everything.
- Now I got it.
- And examples and stories are great.
Like the story you told about
when you're a little girl
running after your auntie,
you're very fluent because
you're just talking naturally
and it's much easier to talk
about something you know
than to try and think of something
completely abstract and
to list lots of things.
- But overall I thought it was good
cause you got to the two minutes
and that most people don't
get to the two minutes.
And speaking in a foreign
language for two minutes
it's not easy.
For part three I think
you did really well.
For part three you had no
problems with any of the questions
and a lot of the questions
like for example,
"Will AI replace teachers?"
"Why are some people reducing their time
on their electronic?"
Those are difficult questions
and the examiners will.
If they think that you
are seven or band eight
or a band nine, they'll
ask you more and more
difficult questions to see
if they can stretch you
and really test you.
So if you get difficult questions,
that's a good thing.
Be happy.
If they ask you really simple questions
then you might have a problem
but you coped very well
with those questions.
- I liked the way that you
answered the questions,
gave an explanation, gave
an example to help you
fully answer, fully develop the question.
So part three, you finished very strongly.
And then the test,
don't be afraid to keep
going in part three
or you should keep going apart three
because people often feel tired
and they just want it to be over
so they get very short
answers for part three.
Often people do that subconsciously
as well cause they're just
like, "Oh, I'm sick of this."
But you did a really
good job on development.
Development is the most
important thing I think.
Apart from the four marking criteria,
development in part three
is the most important thing
and you did a good job
with that so, well done.
Let's talk about four marking criteria.
Your strongest area is pronunciation.
Like many Romanian students,
the clarity of what you're
saying is very good.
I can understand 100%
of what you're saying,
any ILT examiner would
be able to understand
a 100% of what you're saying.
So that means that you would be getting
at least a band seven for pronunciation.
Plus you have very good use of intonation,
sentence stress, word
stress, connected speech,
all these higher level
pronunciation features,
you've very good command of those.
Which means you would get more than
a seven for pronunciation.
So when you combine the examiner
can understand everything.
Plus you're using those higher
level pronunciation features.
So that's probably why you
got a band eight the last time
because you can't get a
band eight without using
the higher level pronunciation features.
For fluency and coherence,
your coherence is very
good because you answered
every question properly.
You stuck to the answering the question
rather than going off topic
and you fully developed your question.
So for part one, you don't
need to give very long answers.
You gave a few answers
that were quite short
at the beginning, but the rest were fine.
At part two, you talked for two minutes,
so that was fine.
And part of three, you
fully developed your answers
by answering the question,
explaining, giving examples.
So that was good to see.
Fluency was very good in part one.
Quite good and part three,
dropped a little bit in part two.
But we've already talked about that,
how to get around that.
And I would encourage you,
don't be complacent about speaking
(murmurs)
practice part two, because
part two seems to be
the area that you need to.
The only area that you
really need to worry about--
- It depends on the subjects so maybe
I should do more subjects
with various teams.
- Yeah.
- And have an answer about and some ideas.
- A pint of sweat is better
than a drop of tears.
So you wanna do the hard work
and during your preparation
make it as difficult as possible.
So the test day is a breeze
and it's no big deal for you.
So that would be my only concern.
Your fluency is very
good and it's at least
at a band seven level.
But as I said before, if you
got a topic that you know
nothing about and they're
gonna ask you about
the same topic in general in part three
so it's like, you said before you got
they're asking you about history
and you don't know anything about history
or you don't know very
little about history.
So that could cause
fluency problems because
you don't have a problem
with the language,
but you might have a
problem with the content
you're tryna think of of those things.
But in general it's very rare.
I don't think you would ever get a topic
that you know nothing about.
Like history is something that
you know a little bit about.
You know of what the World War I was
and or the World War II.
They're not testing your
knowledge of the World War II
or the World War I,
they're talking about
whether you can talk about
a range of topics.
And your vocabulary is quite good.
You have a really nice
range of vocabulary.
I asked you about many different topics.
You have no problem talking
about all of those topics.
So that.
Because I was asking
about a range of topics
and you have topics
specific vocabulary related
to all of those and
that would indicate that
you have a very wide ranging vocabulary
because if you asked
someone about five or six
different topics and
they have topics specific
vocabulary about all of those,
that means that you could talk about
pretty much any general topic.
So that was very good.
Collocations are something
that work on for you.
When you're listening to
English and reading English,
notice collocations underline them,
put them in a book and work
trying practice them,
review them and use them.
Collocations is one of the
areas that tells an examiner
the difference between
somebody at a band six,
band seven level and a band
eight, band nine level.
Cause if you listen to
native English speakers
they will use collocations
just intuitively
without even thinking about it.
Whereas someone at a band
six, band seven level
will know the words.
They might have a very
wide ranging vocabulary
but they might not be able
to put those words together
which would make little
mistakes with that.
I'm not too worried about
your vocabulary though.
Just be careful with
collocations but in the test
don't be thinking
'collocations, collocations'
(laughs)
cause that will affect your fluency.
Cause there's a balance between
fluency and vocabulary and grammar.
The more you think about
vocabulary and grammar
normally the lower your fluency.
Just be confident that that
I think your vocabulary
is good enough to get
a band seven at least.
And the one area that I
would be concerned about
is small grammatical errors and
you seem to have two things.
One would be, you seem to
be translating sometimes.
So that's probably because of the way
I would guess that you learned English
through translation rather than learning
it through communication.
The other problem is
little fossilized errors.
Fossilized errors or errors that you make
and you've no idea that
you are making them.
So common fossilized errors or things like
articles and prepositions,
they don't affect.
You didn't make article
mistakes by the way,
but you made some preposition mistakes.
They don't affect communication.
So if you're in Dublin and you're in a bar
and you're talking to your boyfriend,
he won't correct you if you
say, 'of' instead of 'in.'
It was a preposition cause
he understands exactly
what you're saying.
So that means that you never pick up
on the mistake that you're making
and you make it again and again and again
and again and it becomes
hardwired natural into your brain.
A good way of of getting around
that is to record yourself
and listen to it.
So I think the best advice
that I could give you
would be get part two questions.
Look at them, prepare them for one minute,
record on your phone and then listen back.
Because that's gonna help your fluency.
It's gonna help part two,
but it will also help you
pick up on these little
grammatical errors that you're making.
You're not making any
serious grammatical errors
and you're not making them
like every single sentence
because if you were, there's
no way that you would have
got to band seven and a band eight
the last two times that you did it.
And I'm not really concerned
that you'll get a band six
or a band 6.5, but we wanna
make absolutely 100% sure.
These little errors that
you're making with grammar
are also present in your writing.
So I think working on them is gonna help
both your speaking and your writing.
So we wanna make your preparation
as efficient as possible.
So I think doing that in
combination with the reading
and the listening and the
writing that we suggested
for you is gonna really help you.
Any questions about the speaking test
or any question about the
advice that I gave you?
- Not now but I will think about it.
- I think you should be really confident.
And if you take those steps,
I think you'll get at least a band seven
and if not, repeat the band
eight that you got last time.
So well done.
- That's good to hear.
- Alright, good.
(bright upbeat music)