Oh, hush, my dear, it's been a difficult year
And terrors don't prey on innocent victims
Trust me, darlin', trust me, darlin'
It's been a loveless year, I'm a man of three fears
Integrity, faith and crocodile tears
Trust me, darlin', trust me, darlin'
So look me in the eyes, tell me what you see
Perfect paradise tearing at the seams
I wish I could escape it, I don't wanna fake it
I wish I could erase it, make your heart believe
But I'm a bad liar, bad liar
Now you know, now you know
I'm a bad liar, bad liar
Now you know, you're free to go
All my dreams never mean one thing
Does happiness lie in a diamond ring?
Oh, I've been askin' for
Oh, I've been askin' for problems
Problems, problems
I wage my war on the world inside
take my gun to the enemy's side
Oh, I've been askin' for (trust me, darlin')
Oh, I've been askin' for (trust me, darlin') for problems
Problems, problems
So look me in the eyes, tell me what you see
Perfect paradise tearing at the seams
I wish I could escape it, I don't wanna fake it
I wish I could erase it, make your heart believe
But I'm a bad liar, bad liar
Now you know, now you know
I'm a bad liar, bad liar
Now you know, you're free to go
I can't breathe, I can't be
I can't be what you want me to be
Believe me this one time
Believe me
I'm a bad liar, bad liar
Now you know, now you know
Now you know, you're free to go
Oh-oh-oh
Oh Please believe me
Please believe me
Thank you so much for watching. I hope that you enjoyed this new cover
This song has been requested a lot and both me and David just fell in love with it
We kept hearing it on the radio and everywhere we went and it was just meant to be.
Don't forget to leave me a comment to let me know what you think
Continue to request the songs that you wish to hear me cover and it might be the one that you wish for that will be
the next one
Some of you might have noticed the difference of sound in the piano
It's because I'm playing on my own grand piano that I received as a birthday gift from amazing amazing angel Alan.
I'm so happy that so many of you have signed up to support my music on patreon.
Special thank you to my angels...
Don't forget to subscribe. If you're new on my channel. Give me your happy thump and I see you on my next upload