I know what you mean; that does look
good. Oh, hi. James from engVid. E and I
were just discussing: "That looks pretty
healthy." And today, I'm going to talk
about collocations for health or a
healthy diet. Let me explain quickly
what that means so we can go to the
board. Collocation — "c-o" means "with"
or "together", and "location" — come
together — "location" is a place. So,
"collocation" means words that are
usually situated together; they come
together. Right? So, if you see one, you
will probably see the other word. So,
I'm going to give you five collocations
about a healthy diet.
Let us not confuse "diet". A lot of
people think "diet", like the keto diet,
or the vegetarian diet. "Diet"
originally means — and I mean it here —
it is a.  the regular foods that you
eat; that is your diet. It's not cutting
down calories, so I'm not talking about
not eating to get nice, and skinny, and
slim. I'm just saying: "What do you
usually eat?" For instance, cats have a
"carnivore diet" — they eat mostly meat;
that's their diet. They're not trying to
get skinny for summer season. Right? So,
that's what I'm talking about a "healthy
diet": What do you usually eat? So,
let's go to the board and take a look at
this healthy diet.
Look at this. Interesting. Very
interesting. Let's start off with: What
does it mean to have a healthy diet?
Well, I think a "healthy diet" is a
"balanced diet". And what does that
mean? Generally put, without — and I
don't mean any insult — extremes, if
you're a "carnivore diet", it means
mostly meat all the time; and if you are
a "vegan", it means no animal products
whatsoever. Right? Those are, I would
say, on the ends of it. The "balanced
diet" would be in between, where for the
average person, because let's face it,
I'm in North America — you may be in
Saudi Arabia, you may be in Asia, you
may be in Russia — the foods that are
available to you are going to be
different than when they are available
everywhere else.
So, a "balanced diet" is keeping fruits;
vegetables; carbohydrates, like potatoes
and rice; and balanced with protein,
whatever that may be — cheese, it could
be fish or meat. Okay? So, a "balanced
diet" is having a healthy balance that's
not too much of one, so not too many
fruits and vegetables only. And that
would be, like, "vegan" for most people.
Right? Or having only meat, and that
would be for a "carnivore diet" for
other people. So, we're saying keeping a
healthy balance; making sure you have a
bit of everything, because our bodies
require certain nutrients — right? — and
we can get them most efficiently and
easily from different sources. Okay, so
now I've said that. That's what your
"balanced diet" is.
And what E and I noticed is that we have
"protein" in the form of fish, and we
have "carbohydrates" — because, yes,
vegetables have carbohydrates, or
commonly called in North America
"carbs". You will not see many people
talk about the "carbohydrates" in these
foods; they talk about "carbs". That is
your energy. Actually, "protein" and
"carbs" can both be used for energy in
different ways, but "carbs", they mean
not meat sources. Okay? So, keep in mind
that "carbs" can be vegetables, but they
can also be starches, which would be
rice and potatoes. I don't have rice or
potatoes here, but it is balanced. Half
the plate is protein; half the plate is
carbs. And the collocation here is: a
"balanced diet". So, if you say: "I have
a balanced diet", people know you have
equal carbs, equal protein.
Now, let's talk about.  Well, we know
animals live all year long. You know?
Humans don't live from — some humans
seem to — May; and then in November,
they disappear. It's like: "Where did
the humans go?" They all died, but they
come back in May. Animals tend to live
all year long, so we don't talk about
"seasonal animals". You're not going to
hear someone go: "The seasonal animal,
this" — no. Bears may sleep, but they
still live. Bees go to sleep; some go to
sleep, but they still live. But some of
our fruits and vegetables, they die. In
the winter in Canada and United States,
it's too cold for apples to be on trees;
they just die, and they come back in
May. But depending on where you live in
the world, at different seasons,
different foods are naturally available
to you. So, this collocation list I'm
giving you is not about just being
healthy for yourself, but you might say
it's also healthy for your environment.
Many scientists and people noticed that
seasonal fruits actually are better for
you because they're ready to eat now;
they're not frozen, and they don't add
salt and make them wait, you know, so
you can eat them six months later. So,
getting them in the season means they
have maximum nutrition, which is good
for you. So, "seasonal fruits and
vegetables" are good things to have.
Okay?
What's the best way of doing that? So,
this is one collocation: "seasonal
fruit" or "seasonal vegetable". The best
way to get "seasonal fruits" or
"seasonal vegetables" is.  Guess what?
They have to be "locally sourced".
There's your fourth collocation.
"Locally sourced" means it grows in the
area that you live. I am very, very
lucky and fortunate. And I know this,
because I live in North America, and I
can get a pineapple in December. I can
get watermelon in December. I can have
starfish or starfruit in December. In
the countries these places come from,
they have them that season, and no more.
But we have everything brought to us; we
don't have everything locally sourced.
So, if you're very lucky, and you can
have grapes, milk, chicken, and pears,
and apples and they're all grown around
you — that's the best way to get your
food. See on my fish? My fish comes from
Lake Ontario. If you see the eyes —
yeah, that water is poisonous. I don't
think this is a good fish to eat, but
it's locally sourced. I found it in Lake
Ontario, and it's dead for sure. So, as
we're going through, we want to have a
balanced diet. Okay? We want it made up
of seasonal fruits and vegetables. We
really want it locally sourced; in your
area. So, if you're at Italy, eat
Italian grapes, get Italian cheese. Oh,
God, Italian food; I'm so hungry now.
Anyway, I'm sorry, back to the work.
Yes, so.  now, what do we call these
green things? Because the tomatoes,
which are interesting — they're a fruit
not a vegetable. Please, please go on
the internet right now because I know
some of you are like: "He doesn't know
what he's talking about." Please check
it out. "Seed-bearing fruit". Tomatoes
have seeds. Told you. So, a cucumber
is.  "What!?" I'm blowing your mind.
Extra information. So, anyway, "leafy
greens" are like spinach — I love
arugula — arugula. Everybody's like:
"James is very snobby; he likes arugula,
not lettuce." Love arugula. Spinach,
arugula, collard greens, heads of
lettuce, just normal lettuce — these are
called "leafy greens". We usually use
them as salads, on your hamburgers. Hmm?
Yeah, on your hamburgers, too. Okay.
These are "leafy greens" — they are good
for helping with digestion. Okay? So,
you want to have those with your salads
or whatever you want to cook it with,
because collard greens are pretty good
by themselves.
And another thing about a healthy diet
is you want it "freshly prepared".
McDonald's says it's freshly prepared,
but what they mean is: "Made six months
ago, brought to the McDonald's close to
you. Cooked — put in the microwave for
another three minutes", and it's freshly
given to you. "Freshly prepared" means
literally you go out, cut that tomato
down. Well, not exactly, but close
enough. Cut it down, cut it up, put it
on your plate — "freshly prepared". Or
when you're cooking.  I don't cook
until you come. You come to my house,
you sit down, and say: "I'm hungry." I
go: "Okay, now I cook." I make it there
when you're there. I don't go in the
freezer, defrost it, and microwave it.
Cool?
So, now I've given you five collocations
for a very healthy lifestyle, and it
will show your depth of English
knowledge when you say.  God, if you
came to, with this.  Here's my fake
world accent: "So, I would like to have
some food. Yeah. And it must be freshly
prepared. You know? I like
freshly-prepared foods, yes. Locally
sourced. I hear Ontario has very good
food. Yeah?" They'd be like: -"Bravo.
That's absolutely brilliant. Yes,
locally sourced. And you know that
Ontario has great seasonal fruits and
vegetables. Don't try the fish, of
course." They'd be impressed, even if
you have a strong accent because that is
a very excellent use of the English
language. It's very specific, and it
shows you understand; not just in your
own language, but in ours. We usually
call that "intelligence". So, I've gone
through my collocations for you. Why
don't we go through a test to see if
you've learned them? And see if you can
master the language and sound like an
expert traveller English. (snaps)
Okay, so I'm about to ask you something
very important. Something I've never
asked you to do before, and that's to
make a promise. But I'm not going to say
"promise"; that's not strong enough. I
need a vow. A "vow" is a very strong
promise. If you vow to do something, you
must do it. Imagine you had a sword and
there was a village behind you, and
you're the only one with a sword and the
dragon's coming — and you vow to protect
them. That means to every little girl
and boy crying, behind you, like: "I vow
to protect you!" It's: "I will die
before I break this promise". In the
modern age, a vow is so strong that we
make people get married to it. You vow
to stay with this person till death. And
if you don't, they take half your stuff.
That's serious. Forget the sword. Half
your stuff.
Okay, so I want you to make a vow — now
you're like: "No, James! No!" —about
leading a healthy lifestyle. But before
you do, I just want to tell you I made a
mistake. I made a mistake. I'm sorry. I
am for real. I forgot to say: "lean
meat". "Lean meat". What is "lean meat"?
"Lean meat" is food, or actually it's
animal meat that doesn't have a lot of
fat. The example I can give you is
chicken. A chicken breast, which is the
breast of the chicken, is usually called
"white meat" and it has very little fat
on it. In fact, it's.  doesn't cook as
well because there's not enough fat to
absorb the flavour. It's good for you,
but it's not as flavourful as a leg or a
thigh, which has more fat to absorb
seasoning. That's why in a lot of
indigenous foods, or a lot of native
foods through certain areas, they will
use leg meat more than breast meat
because it gets more flavour. Okay? But
flavour comes fat. So, to be healthy,
you want to eat leaner meat.
Now, you'll see I have: "fish" and a
question mark. Well, remember I said:
"chicken"? What? So, "lean meat" is
usually considered parts of meat that
doesn't have a lot of fat; and they
usually talk about chicken, beef, and
pork. I am going to raise the argument
that fish is a lean meat. Why? Well,
it's an animal like the other ones and
it bleeds like the other ones; and just
like the other ones, when it's alive
it's an animal, when it's dead it's.
you say: "fish". And I go: "It's a type
of meat", just like we're meat when we
die. Believe it or not, you're just
meat. So, my idea: Fish is lean meat.
Now, because you will run into people
who are native speakers and they'll hear
you say: "Fish is lean meat", some of
them will go: "No, it's fish. Fish is
fish; meat is meat." They can make that
distinction. In your head, you can go:
"Yeah, stupid. Yes, you're correct. But
I know the truth." So, fish can be
considered a type of lean meat in my
little definition, but go by the strict
one when you talk to native speakers and
whatnot. Okay?
Now, let's go to the board and continue
with our vow. So, now you're going to
make a vow for not only learning English
with me or learning English, but to lead
a healthy lifestyle. So, here I want you
to put your name. So: "I", let's say:
"I, Bobby", "I, Anna", "I", whatever,
"will lead a healthy lifestyle to keep
both myself and the planet healthy".
Because you are a good person and you
want to do what's right. So, that,
you're going to do that. Let's look at
the collocations we learned and how they
can best fit into the rest of our vow,
so we can keep our promise. We have to
know what the promise is.
So, next sentence is: "Therefore, I will
only eat __________ food." That's: "food
close to me". Now, that doesn't mean: Go
in your refrigerator and grab a beer,
and some chicken wings. That's close to
you, but that's not what we mean. What
do I mean? That's right, local food.
"Locally-sourced". So, go to your local
farmer and ask them: "Do they have eggs?
Cheeses? Lean meat?" and they probably
won't have fish, but that's okay. But
you can get lean chicken. All right?
"Locally-sourced foods" — things you can
find close to you. In Italy, they have
some of the best grapes, wines, cheeses,
pastas — they don't need to go nowhere
else; it's paradise there. Great food. I
love it there. Anyway.
Next. What's the next one? "I won't eat
a lot of meat, but if I do, it will be
__________" — not having much fat on it.
No, not Mr. E. Okay? You can't eat Mr.
E. He needs to come.  he works for a
living; he's got to be on the board.
What did I just say? "lean meat", right?
Because it doesn't have a lot of fat, so
it's better for your heart. What about
this one? "I will eat a lot of
__________ at lunch and dinner." Now,
I've put "salad" to help you out. "leafy
vegetables". When we talk about leafy
vegetables, we talk about spinach. Ah,
sorry. I'm jumping ahead of myself. I
don't mean "leafy vegetables". You're
going to go: "No, James, that's not. "
Shh. Don't tell anybody yet. "leafy
greens", because they are green — like
spinach, romaine, romaine lettuce,
spinach, lettuce, or arugula, which I
love. I'm looking and thinking about all
of these things, but "leafy greens". And
those are usually in your salads. When
you have a Caesar salad, or a
Mediterranean salad — they're leafy
greens.
Now, what about this one? "I will only
eat __________" something. And this is
important for helping the planet because
when you get things brought in at
different times of the year, when you
shouldn't have them, we have to use
ships and airplanes, and that pollutes
the planet, so.  Oh my gosh, I sound
like a tree-hugger. I'm not. Trust me.
But what do we do? We're going to eat
something in the season, so "seasonal
fruits and vegetables". Right? So, in
Canada, we really shouldn't be having
pineapple in January. We've got that
much snow. When I say: "that much" — I'm
not the tallest guy in the world, I'm
not that tall, but the snow comes up to
here. There is no room for pineapples.
Okay? You got to go to the Bahamas, man.
Anyway, but we get it in January,
because that's where we live.
Now, finally: "I will eat a __________"
something.  And I told you when you have
something that's, you know, like weights
— the scales of justice — they must be
balanced. A "balanced diet". And
remember what I mean "diet" here, I
don't mean; You're going to try and lose
10 pounds before the prom to fit into
your nice dress, or you want to look
good on the beach. I'm talking about
your regular foods. So, what you eat for
breakfast, lunch, dinner, all year long
for the last 10 years is your "natural
diet". Hope you did well on the quiz.
You know, we have a better, bigger,
badder, better one at engVid, but before
I get to that, let's give you your
bonus.
We talked about the good; now we're
going to talk about the bad and the
ugly. Because when you're not doing this
and using these collocations to talk
about a healthy lifestyle, you may be
using these other ones. Okay? Now,
"processed foods". This is a really
interesting one, because people at
McDonald's might say their food's not
that processed. I say they're lying. But
they might say: "No, no, it's actual
100% beef." Now, here's the key, because
this is from the Food and Drug
Administration from the United States of
America, and what they say is this —
this is paraphrased, but basically: "Any
food that has a process applied to
change its natural state is called
'processed'." So, even if the beef is
from a cow, that's not its natural
state.
Have you ever seen a cow burger? You
know, it's got, like, ground beef. It
goes: "Woo." It doesn't go: "Moo",
because it's cut up. "Woo". And you just
take pieces off and eat it? No. You have
to take that meat, and then do something
with it. And sometimes you add a little
salt, some pepper, some — "num, num,
num, num, num, num" — secret ingredients
that we don't know. You know, things to
keep it stay longer and fresher. You
know what I'm saying? So, that's not its
natural state anymore; that's called a
"processed food". So, if you take an
apple, you might say: "Well, James, I'm
smart. They wash the apples." Does it
look like it came off the tree? Yes.
That's its natural state. That's not it.
Applesauce — processed food; apple juice
— processed food. Apple that's been
cleaned — you lucky bastard; someone
cleaned it for you. It's its natural
state. Okay? Now, that is anything
that's packaged, usually packaged
because they cut it up and do something
with it. That's not just its natural
state. So, think of hamburger versus
steak, think of applesauces versus an
apple, and you can follow it from there.
When they change it from.  you can look
at it and say: "I know what this food
was before I took it." Okay? If you
don't.  if you can't recognize it, then
it's a processed food.
Next: "fatty food". Do you remember we
talked about "lean meat", and that's why
I had to talk about this one? "Fatty
foods" aren't good for your heart,
because they contain a lot of extra fat
that your body cannot process. So, if
you eat a lot of fattening foods —
sausages.  My heart's: "Bl, bl, th,
th". You know, lots of cheesy pizza.
"Bl, bl, th, th". Come on, come on,
baby. Come on. Come on! Come on! That's
not good for you. So, if you say: "My
diet is high in fatty foods and
processed foods", you're probably going
to see the doctor and the undertaker —
I'm not talking the wrestler — sooner
than you would like. All right? So, you
want to eliminate those.
Now, for the homework. I got to separate
this here. Okay. Homework is this. This
is for your own good. So, you're only
going to get five points each. Yup. So,
when it's good, you get nothing. Okay?
This one's a joke. So, in case you don't
know, I'm telling a joke here before you
start telling people. But if you get it
that actually.  If you get the joke and
you put: "hahaha" because you get it —
you don't get five points; you get a
million points. If you just write the
answer, and you don't find out why it's
funny — stay with five because you got
no sense of humour.
So, the first one is: "The fish is
__________; I stole it from my friend's
dinner plate." It's funny. You get it?
It's right there. It's right there.
Whatever. Okay. Question number two: "I
eat a __________ with a mix of lean meat
and seasonal vegetables." Cool? Well,
that's what I got for you today. I hope
you keep your vow, because that means
you will stay around longer so we can
work together, or I can keep my vow to
help you learn English. Okay?
So, I'm going to get going. But before I
go, please make sure you stop by www
"eng" as in English, "vid" as in
video.com, to get the larger quiz to
this. And also, I've been saying it
recently, and I think I'll keep saying
it, because I think it's true: If you're
still listening to my voice now, you
like this video, because there's nothing
more and you're still waiting for
something, so press "Like" please. And
outside of that, if you've been watching
this, and it's like your third, fourth,
fifth video — subscribe, because I think
you want what I have to offer. And the
most efficient way to get it to you is
to subscribe, press the bell, and you'll
be notified the next time one of my
videos comes out. So, you won't be one
of those people, because I see it all
the time: "Teacher, where have you been?
We don't see you", and I'm like: "I come
out. You don't look till three months
later. But it's there." Don't be one of
those people; hit the bell. Anyway, I
gotta get going. You have a great day
and I will talk to you soon.
Locally-sourcing my dinner tonight; I'm
going to order some pizza. (laughs) I'm
so funny. No, you're not. No, you're
not.