(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(STUMBLES)
-Mum, my shoelaces.
-You can do it.
-Please.
-OK.
Two bunny ears,
loop around and pull together.
(SIGHS)
-Got it?
-I don't want to be here.
James!
I want you to pick an artwork
you like and tell me about it.
Art is a wonderful thing,
and I want to enjoy it with you. OK?
OK.
(DELICATE, LIGHT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
Wow!
-What do you see?
-Come.
-Sit here.
-OK.
(BUGLE BLOWS FAINTLY)
(MEN ROAR FAINTLY)
(MILITARISTIC INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
Before you towers
a terrifying scene of war -
thousands of horses' hooves
break the grassy ground
in a cavalry charge!
(HOOVES BEAT, MEN ROAR)
Soldiers sporting blood-red uniforms
ride with valour
in a fearless resolve to attack!
Some blow military bugles,
others raise their voice
in a war cry.
Mighty silver blades
are exalted above their heads.
Leading up front, a commander,
on a mighty white stallion.
The beast's eyes
were wide and ferocious,
every muscle and vein
pulsing through its skin.
The commander rides the steed high,
his face blazing with heroism,
but still in his eyes,
a glimmer of fear,
for at the front line,
survival is not guaranteed.
(LAUGHS JOYOUSLY)
(AUDIENCE MEMBER WHISTLES)
I'm so proud of you!
Can you describe that one to us
over there?
(DELICATE, LIGHT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)