EAST JERUSALEM
We're on the grounds of Al Aqsa.
It's one of the holiest
places in the Islamic religion.
And so, we've come here, today on
one of the holiest nights of Ramadan.
The crowds are huge.
So, if anything happens,
it could potentially be very
dangerous to the people that are here.
It's night-time prayers
for Palestinian Muslims.
And this year, Israeli forces
showed up unannounced.
If we pray until dawn,
we will be obeying God's command.
So, you can see that there's
Israeli police actually inside,
in the grounds of Al Aqsa.
That's what triggered the protests.
And that's what triggered the anger today.
If your only sacrifice for Al Aqsa
is getting arrested or suffering,
that's worth it for defending it.
Palestinians feel like they're
being pushed out of East Jerusalem,
the city they see as the capital
of a future Palestinian state.
They say Israel is upping its efforts
to redraw the borders of the city.
But Israel claims it belongs to them
despite the United Nations
saying that it's an occupation,
illegal under international law.
The Israeli police have been arresting
loads of Palestinian children.
The Palestinians are retaliating
because so many young men
have been taken away by the police.
Stop! Stop!
Stop! Hold him!
People just came here to worship,
and you're giving them shit!
Fuck you all!
Do what you want.
Come and arrest me!
How old are you?
-15 years old.
-15 years old? Why are they taking you?
God is great!
Why do you think they took him?
Why?
They want to keep the young people away.
They want to remove all
young people, one by one.
As Ramadan continued,
Palestinians in East Jerusalem faced
stun grenades, arrests, and water cannons,
some of the worst violence seen in years.
Go away! Go away!
They sprayed us with water.
We were walking and not doing anything.
They're dogs and animals.
Come on, move. Don't scream.
Don't ever forget this.
Don't you ever forget what they did.
East Jerusalem is important to
Jews, Muslims, and Christians.
It's also the site of the
sacred Jewish Temple Mount.
But most of the people who live in
this part of the city are Palestinians.
That's been slowly changing
since Israel captured the area in 1967
and started moving in settlers.
Jewish people now make up
around 40 percent of the population.
And in 2018,
Israel was emboldened by President Trump.
He moved the US Embassy
into East Jerusalem from Tel Aviv.
It outraged Palestinians
but was celebrated by right-wing Israelis.
It is time…
to officially recognize Jerusalem…
as the capital of Israel.
At the heart of the fight
over East Jerusalem
is the neighborhood of Sheikh Jarrah,
home mostly to Palestinian families,
some who came here in 1956
after being displaced by Israel when
the state was created eight years earlier.
Israel claims Jews
historically owned this land.
Now, there's a lawsuit to forcibly
evict some Palestinian residents
making its way through the courts.
Even if you capture, kill,
and destroy our homes,
you won't defeat our resolve!
Protesters have been turning up
since the issue reached
the Supreme Court this year.
We will take our freedom!
The Zionist organizations seized the
first house five months after the war.
The first house they seized
back in November 1967
belonged to the Shanti family.
Muna Al Kurd and her relatives
are one of 28 families fighting
in court to keep their homes.
Believe me, no person from
the neighborhood will leave
until they drag us out
at the last moment.
We want to live! This is our house!
This is our land!
Other Palestinians are already being
replaced by right-wing Israeli settlers.
What's happening?
Go away!
Hey! Hey!
Don't touch me.
We don't want any trouble.
What happened exactly?
Some young Palestinian boys and girls
were standing there,
then that guy attacked them with a stick.
Look at it in his hand.
They are thieves.
They are not just here.
They live in my house!
-They are in your house?
-Yes, they are.
Come, let me show you.
This house was given to my grandmother
because she was a refugee
from Haifa in 1948.
-This house.
-This one?
It was built by my father in 2000
because he got married and had children,
so he needed more space.
After my father finished building the house,
we were never allowed to live there.
The judge came and sealed it permanently.
He kept it sealed on the pretense
that it was built without a permit.
-Who lives in it now?
-Settlers. Young men, not families.
You live in that house?
-They live here.
-And they live in this one?
Exactly.
Both my father and my mother
worked and saved to build this house.
It was built with blood, sweat, and tears.
And then the Israeli court
issued a decree
allowing settlers to live in it.
It's true that this house
was built without a permit
and received two demolition orders.
So, why would they allow
Israeli settlers to live in it
and not me, the Palestinian?
What sort of a democracy is this?
How do you feel when you see him?
Oppressed.
Disturbed.
It's annoying and exhausting.
I don't cry because I'm weak.
Never.
Believe me.
I swear.
But I cry because we are not dealing
with a just state.
This is an occupation.
This is our land.
I was born, raised, and have lived here.
How can someone come and take it?
How does that make any sense?
What's happening is a violation
of international law.
This is a war crime.
Forced eviction is a war crime.
Hello.
-Hello. Hi.
-Hi, how are you?
-Thank God. Still alive.
-Yeah.
You're a difficult man to get hold of.
Yeah, I generally don't interview,
but given the circumstances
and the bad press that's out there…
decided that we need to
do some damage control.
Jacob Fauci is an American Israeli.
He became infamous after Muna
confronted him and the video went viral.
Jacob, you know this is not your house!
Yes, but if I go, you don't go back.
So, what's the problem?
Why are you yelling at me?
I didn't do this.
You are stealing my house.
And if I don't steal it,
someone else is going to steal it.
No! No one--
No one is allowed to steal it, Jacob!
He's been living in an additional
part of Muna's house for over ten years
after being recruited
by a US-based company
called Nahalat Shimon International
which owns the property under Israeli law.
How did you end up here?
It's a long story.
Basically, I needed to
move from where I was.
And my friend was very very
active in this neighborhood.
And he said you can stay
here for the time being.
Do you pay rent?
I have an arrangement
with the owners of the house.
I don't wanna get into personal
arrangements and rents and things.
But yes, I'm a tenant here. I'm not--
I have no ownership over this property.
-You're from Brooklyn?
-No, I'm from New York.
-From Long Island.
-From New York.
What right do you have to live here?
The right I have is that the owner
of the house wants me to live here.
And he wants there to be Jews
living in his house. And he wants--
And I got chosen--
For whatever reason, it ended up being me.
-We as a--
-So, why do you live here?
Because I live here.
Because it's important.
And because not too many
people want to live here.
And it's important to strengthen
this neighborhood to make sure that
this neighborhood is not
lost in any future peace deal.
No, no to occupation.
Occupation will disappear!
This is not their ancestral land.
They've not been here for generations.
They came here in 1956 because
they had nowhere else to be.
And somebody illegally put them here.
Whatever they're accusing me of is…
is no different from what they're doing
and what they did.
So, your position here is a political
position to keep Palestinians out of it?
Not to keep Palestinians out of it,
to keep Jews in it.
And therefore keep the
Palestinians who were here out of it.
No-- That's not--
No.
That's a--
That's a necessary evil.
Whatever the situation is,
and that's what I was trying
to explain in that viral video,
they're not coming back here.
This part of the house, for sure, is lost.
The second part of the house,
unless there is some major miracle,
is going to be lost.
And they're not coming back in here.
So, whether I'm here,
whether I'm not here,
whether it's me,
whether it's someone else,
whether it's a monkey,
whether it's a giraffe,
they're not coming
back into this house ever.
I understand why they're angry at me.
I understand why they dislike me.
But I did not do this to them.
I'm not doing this to them.
And, as I said, if I leave,
I'll be replaced immediately.
And I venture to think that whoever
comes here is not going to be as…
easy-going as I am.
I've been instructed
to disperse the crowd.
Jacob's Nahalat Shimon International's
unyielding stance
is being challenged both inside
the neighborhood and in court.
Where lawyers representing
the families argue
it's illegal under international law
to displace anyone from occupied land.
They're also arguing that
there's a double standard.
Israel allows Jews
to return to their homeland,
but not Palestinians.
-Go over there!
-It's okay.
-I don't want to cause a problem.
-You're in my way.
-I just want to ask you, "Why?"
-Talk to me in Hebrew.
-Over there. Go.
-I just--
I wanna ask you why
you have taken the man.
Nahalat Shimon International did not
respond to our request for comment.
Across the street from Muna's home
is a house that belonged to a family
pushed out in the last round of evictions.
We found Abu Ayman Al Ghawi alone
sitting outside his old house.
So, you used to live in
this house across the road.
What happened?
They kicked us out
on the street in an hour.
They destroyed the doors and beat us,
our children, and women.
They forcefully threw us out.
Were you given any help,
any money, a place to stay?
What sort of support did you get?
They didn't give us any assistance.
They didn't give us a flat or rent.
Imagine, we have lived
here under this tree
outside our flat for seven months.
So, what happened to all your
belongings that were in the house?
They took all the
furniture and dumped it.
We don't know where
they took the furniture.
We left with only the
clothes we were wearing.
I was in my pajamas,
and my wife left without slippers.
How long exactly have
you lived in this house?
I was born here in 1962.
STOP OUR HOMES
Jerusalem is our right,
not the settlers'.
The settlers came from
America, Russia, and Germany.
They don't have more of
a right to live here than me.
I was born here, and my blood
and tears are in this house.
SHEIKH JARRAH
Arieh King, a right-wing activist,
who was appointed East Jerusalem's
Deputy Mayors last year,
says the right belongs
to the Jewish people.
When we are Jews
in the States, in Australia,
in England, in Jerusalem,
we're facing towards one place.
Haram al-Sharif.
Mount-- Temple Mount.
-I mean, that's religion.
-Of course.
Talking about a religion
when you're talking about people
and the land and where they live,
is it relevant?
Absolutely!
So, you can't really justify ownership
over religion when there are
so many different types of Arabs.
Of course not.
But I'm just explaining what we are--
The way that we see Jerusalem,
it's a different way than any other…
religion.
As a Jew, you can live
everywhere in the world,
you can be the most orthodox Jew,
if you don't live in Jerusalem,
you cannot…
keep the entire commitment of God.
Do you want to see a Sheikh Jarrah…
that is…
Jewish?
Of course.
Without Arabs?
I want to see Jews, yes.
As the neighborhood
waits on the eviction appeal,
support for the families is growing.
This is our land!
Police are getting more aggressive.
As it's getting closer, the smell
is getting really really strong.
We can see everybody just ran inside.
Because they don't want
to be sprayed with that.
It smells like sewage.
Close it. Close it.
One night, police even raided
a Palestinian resident's house…
for playing loud music.
Tell him to turn off the music!
It's my house.
-What are you doing?
-Come here. Come on!
-Let me take him.
-Take him.
Why? Tell him to turn the music off.
-I want to go inside.
-Come on, move!
Move away!
Close the door completely.
Don't open the door.
Stay away from her!
It's our house.
There is music here.
Move!
Son of a bitch, go outside!
Get out!
On another night,
police detained Muna's younger brother
and held him for hours when
he was trying to go home.
He lives here!
Why are you pushing me?
Calm down.
Now do you know where he is?
We don't know,
but we're going to check
to see if he's at the police headquarters.
You're the one who arrested my brother!
May God not bless you! May God break
your arms, you animal! Son of a bitch!
As Ramadan neared its end,
Palestinians flocked to Al Aqsa Mosque.
And the Israeli police
once again stormed in.
ISRAEL POLICE VIA STORYFUL
Hundreds of people were injured.
But many medics were
prevented from entering.
We've been outside for a while.
They wouldn't let us in.
We've now made it into the grounds.
There are the remnants of
stun grenades everywhere.
East Jerusalem is at the heart
of the Palestine-Israel conflict.
And right now…
it's exploded.
Come inside! Come inside!
The Palestinians are taking
refuge inside the Aqsa Mosque.
God is great!
While Palestinians barricaded
themselves in the mosque,
close by, right-wing Israelis,
including Arieh King,
celebrated the date Israel
captured Jerusalem in 1967.
A lot is happening right now.
Al Aqsa, what you call Jerusalem Day,
Sheikh Jarrah.
Do you think that
this is a very delicate moment?
It's a delicate moment like many
other moments that we have here.
And we've passed many moments like that…
and we'll pass this also.
What do you want to see in the end?
What would make you happy?
To see the temple built…
at the temple mark where
there is the Dome of the Rock.
In the holy of holiness…
we believe,
and we trust God,
and we believe God,
So, we trust that it will happen.
And we need to do everything
to ensure it happens in our days.
2021-05-13
THURSDAY 14:27:16
In retaliation, for the
storming of the Al Aqsa,
Hamas, the Palestinian
militant group that governs Gaza,
fired on Israel.
At least 13 civilians had been killed,
including two children.
GAZA CITY
Israel responded with a
disproportionate show of force
leveling apartment
buildings and newsrooms.
In one of the most densely
populated places on earth,
to escape is impossible.
Israel has closed off the
crossing into the blockaded strip.
So far, over 200 Palestinians have
been killed, including 61 children.
When the bombing stops
and the international
community is no longer watching,
Muna will still be fighting,
including Israel's Supreme Court.
The residents of Sheikh Jarrah say
court cases like this
happen on a monthly basis.
But they still say despite the
amount of times they've been here,
they have no faith in the justice system.
They say it's their land,
and we say that it's not their land.
In the coming weeks,
the courts will make a decision on the
cases of 28 families appealing eviction.
If they lose, they'll be left homeless.
When you sat inside there,
as a Palestinian in an Israeli court,
do you feel the same as them?
Do you feel equal to them?
I feel that even my most basic right,
having an Arabic translator,
was not given to me.
In the end, we're dealing with
a system of settlers.
They don't want us
Palestinians to stay in our land.
They want to make Jerusalem
the unified capital of Israel
and they want to do an ethnic cleansing
of all the Palestinians in Jerusalem.
We will not give our homes to them.
No way!
I always say that I would
chain myself to the house.
I won't leave.
They'd better come and drag me out of it.