[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪
>> Jimmy: WHAT HAPPENED?
>> THAT'S HOW YOU GOT TO GET IT,
J.
>> Jimmy: CAN YOU HELP ME --
>> I GOT YOU.
>> Jimmy: YEAH, I NEED HELP.
>> BULLY BULLY BULLY.
>> Jimmy: I KNOW YOU PLAYED
BASKETBALL AS A YOUNG MAN.
[ LAUGHTER AND APPLAUSE ]
>> LOOK AT THAT, LOOK AT THAT,
LOOK AT THAT.
LOOK AT THAT HAIR.
>> Jimmy: IS THE JERRY CURL AN
ASSET OR DISADVANTAGE WHEN
YOU'RE PLAYING BASKETBALL?
>> THAT'S HOW I GET MY SHOT OFF.
WIPE THE HANDS.
IT'S THAT JERRY CURL.
I HAD A CALIFORNIA CURL.
>> Jimmy: OH, IS THAT RIGHT?
>> ALL MY CURLSTERS BACK THERE.
I CALL THEM CURLSTERS.
THAT IS A CALIFORNIA CURL.
WHAT IT IS, I GET THE SMALL
ROLLERS IN THE FRONT AND THE BIG
ROLLERS IN THE BACK.
FROM THE SIDE I LOOK LIKE A
Z-28.
[ LAUGHTER ]
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Jimmy: IT WORKS.
[ RIM SHOT ]
>> YOU GOT TO LeBRON HIM.
>> Jimmy: I DO.
>> YOU GOT TO BE PHYSICAL.
YOU KNOW HOW A WHEN BRON JUST --
YEAH.
>> Jimmy: YEAH.
>> LET'S GO, LET'S GO!
>> Jimmy: IS LeBRON A FRIEND OF
YOURS?
>> YES, I LOVE LeBRON.
>> Jimmy: HAS HE BEEN TO YOUR
HOUSE, FOR INSTANCE?
>> HE HAS NOT, NO.
>> Jimmy: HE HAS NOT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> HE'S STILL A FRIEND.
I HAD EVERYBODY ELSE, THOUGH.
>> Jimmy: WHO'S BEEN TO YOUR
HOUSE OF BASKETBALL FAME?
>> I DO MY PARTIES, MAN.
>> Jimmy: UH-HUH.
>> SO I DID -- I DID A PARTY FOR
THE WHOLE OLYMPIC BASKETBALL
TEAM.
>> Jimmy: UH-HUH.
>> EVERYBODY CAME EXCEPT DeANDRE
JORDAN AND HARRISON BARNES.
EVERYBODY ELSE.
KLAY THOMPSON, MELO.
THEY ALL COME TO THE CRIB.
>> Jimmy: UH-HUH.
>> I DO WHAT WE CALL CONTRAST
PARTIES.
>> Jimmy: WHAT IS THAT?
>> THERE'S ALWAYS A CONTRAST.
I HAVE THE WHOLE OLYMPIC
BASKETBALL TEAM, BUT I HAD DAVID
BLAINE SHOW UP.
AND DID MAGIC.
>> Jimmy: MAGIC, OH, NICE.
>> I DON'T KNOW IF YOU'VE EVER
SEEN HIM.
HE'S JUST, LOOK AT THAT, IT'S
RIGHT THERE.
PULLING STUFF OUT OF PEOPLE'S
FACES.
I WAS LIKE, IT'S CRAZY.
BUT IT'S SOMETHING ABOUT BLACK
PEOPLE AND MAGIC.
IF THE MAGIC IS TOO GOOD, WE GET
SCARED.
[ LAUGHTER ]
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
AM I RIGHT?
BECAUSE HE DID SOMETHING AND
KEVIN DURANT WENT, UH-UH, MAN,
HOLD ON.
[ LAUGHTER ]
HE SAID, MAN, THAT'S SORCERY,
MAN, THAT'S SORCERY.
AM I RIGHT?
I WAS GOING TO SAY, AM I RIGHT,
BROTHER?
THERE ARE NO BROTHERS.
>> Jimmy: YEAH, NO.
>> I'LL HAVE TO SIGN A
COMPLAINT.
NO, BUT YEAH.
SO I LIKE DOING THE CONTRAST.
BUT WE HAD --
>> Jimmy: THAT'S A GREAT IDEA.
>> I GOT THE CHANCE TO GET THE
INSIDE SCOOP.
KYRIE IRVING CAME.
AND THIS WAS JUST BEFORE HE LEFT
TO GO TO BOSTON.
BUT I DID HIS BIRTHDAY PARTY AT
MY CRIB.
>> Jimmy: YOU DID?
>> WE ALWAYS DO A CONTRAST, DO A
CONTRAST.
I HAD HIM COME.
AND I HAD A MARIACHI BAND.
[ LAUGHTER ]
AND HE LITERALLY WENT LIKE, YO,
REALLY, ARE YOU SERIOUS?
MARIACHI BAND?
I SAID, WAIT TILL YOU SEE WHAT
IT DOES TO THE PARTY.
MARIACHI BANDS ARE SIGNIFICANT
BECAUSE THE PERSON WHO DOES THE
MARIACHI IS THE GUY WHO HANDLES
MY GROUNDS AT THE HOUSE.
ONE DAY HE WAS OUT THERE DOING
SOME STUFF.
AND I HEARD HIM SINGING.
AND I WAS LIKE, MAN, YOU DO
MARIA
MARIACHI?
YES.
MAN, REALLY?
I DO CONTRAST PARTIES, WOULD YOU
COME?
I HAD DENZEL COMING ON.
>> Jimmy: UH-HUH.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
WAIT, YOU MEAN DENZEL
WASHINGTON?
>> DENZEL WASHINGTON.
>> Jimmy: OKAY, ALL RIGHT.
>> I'M BEING TOO COOL.
I HAD D.!
>> Jimmy: D. CAME.
>> DENZEL WASHINGTON HAD COME
BEFORE.
MANNY, I WANT YOU TO BRING YOUR
MARIACHI BAND AND PERFORM FOR
DENZEL WASHINGTON.
MIND YOU, I NEVER HEARD HIM.
HE SHOWS UP WITH 100 MARIACHI
PEOPLE.
LIKE THE DANCERS, THE HORNS,
EVERYTHING.
DENZEL'S SITTING AT THE TABLE.
I SAID, DENZEL, WE GOT MARIACHI
BAND.
HE SAYS, OH, MARIACHI, ALL
RIGHT, OKAY.
OKAY, ALL RIGHT, MARIACHI.
[ LAUGHTER ]
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
ALL RIGHT, OKAY.
SO THE MARIACHI BAND, THEY'RE
GREAT.
SO I'M TELLING -- SO AS KYRIE IS
STANDING, I SAID THIS MARIACHI
BAND WAS IN FRONT OF DENZEL,
IT'S GOING TO BE HOT.
HE'S SITTING THERE STILL
DOUBTING.
THERE'S MANNY COMES TO THE TOP
OF THE STAIRS, FULL REGALIA.
♪ GUADALAJARA, GUADALAJARA ♪
AND THE WHOLE PLACE WENT UP IN
FLAMES.
>> Jimmy: THEY LOVED IT?
>> YEAH.
BAM BAM BAM GOING CRAZY.
THEN I HAD -- I HAVE A SECRET
WEAPON.
>> Jimmy: WHAT IS IT?
>> IN THE MARIACHI BAND.
HIS NAME IS LUIS.
LUIS IS ABOUT THIS TALL AND LUIS
COMES OUT, MR. JAMIE, IS IT OKAY
IF I SING SOMETHING IN ENGLAND?
I SAID, OF COURSE.
AND HE BROKE OUT.
♪ AT LAST ♪
♪ MY LOVE ♪
AND THE PLACE WENT CRAZY.
>> Jimmy: A MARIACHI VERSION OF
"AT LAST"?
>> YES, EXACTLY.
[ SPEAKING SPANISH ]
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Jimmy: ONE MORE QUESTION
ABOUT THEM.
THEN AFTER THEY HAD THIS AMAZING
PERFORMANCE, ON MONDAY AFTER THE
PARTY, AND THOSE GUYS ARE NOW
BACK OUT IN THE YARD RAKING
LEAVES, WAS IT WEIRD?
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> OH MY GOD.
THAT'S MY FAMILY.
IT'S -- YEAH.
>> Jimmy: YEAH.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> GOT TO WORK THAT PART OUT.
TO BE HONEST WITH YOU, WE DID A
MOVIE CALLED "ALL-STAR WEEKEND."
WHERE IT'S ABOUT -- I DIRECTED
MY FIRST DURING THE COURSE
TORTTORT
IAL -- FIRST DIRECTORIAL DEBUT.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
BUT IT'S ABOUT TWO GUYS.
IT'S CALLED "ALL-STAR WEEKEND."
TWO GUYS, ONE LOVES STEPH CURRY,
THE OTHER LOVES LeBRON JAMES.
THEY'RE TRYING TO GET TO THE
ALL-STAR GAME.
BUT I CALLED ALL OF MY FRIENDS
TO COME PLAY.
SO I CALLED ROBERT DOWNEY JR.
YES, YES, LET IT OUT.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
I CALLED ROBERT DOWNEY JR.,
WOULD YOU COME BE IN THE MOVIE,
JUST GIVE ME FOUR HOURS.
THE ONLY CATCH IS YOU HAVE TO
PLAY A MEXICAN.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Jimmy: WHAT?
>> AND HE WAS LIKE -- AND I WAS
LIKE, COULD YOU PLAY A MEXICAN?
HE SAID, DUDE, HEERMS THE DEAL,
SURE, OF COURSE.
OF COURSE, WHY NOT, SURE, OF
COURSE, PLAY THE MEXICAN.
SO HE PLAYS A MEXICAN.
>> Jimmy: HE DOES?
>> I PLAY MYSELF AND -- I PLAY A
RACIST WHITE COP.
>> Jimmy: OH.
>> GERARD BUTLER PLAYS A
RUSSIAN.
>> Jimmy: UH-HUH.
>> WHO LOVES GYMNASTICS JUST AS
MUCH AS WE LOVE BASKETBALL.
BENICIO DEL TORO PLAYS A TATTOO
ARTIST/DR. PHIL.
WE GOT EVERYBODY IN IT.
BUT HERE'S WHAT I WAS TRYING TO
GET TO.
MANNY.
>> Jimmy: YEAH?
>> WROTE THE SONG.
>> Jimmy: WHAT?
>> THAT ROBERT DOWNEY JR. USES.
THERE'S A SCENE WHERE ROBERT
DOWNEY JR. PULLS -- MAN.
WHEN ROBERT DOWNEY JR. PULLS
GUNS.
I SAY, MANNY, I WANT TO SAY
"DEATH IS COMING AND YOU CAN'T
HIDE" BUT I WANT TO SING IT, YOU
KNOW, IN SPANISH.
>> Jimmy: I THINK THEY CALL IT
SPANISH, YEAH.
>> THANKS.
IN SPANISH.
[ LAUGHTER ]
SO HE WROTE THE SONG.
[ SINGING IN SPANISH ]
THEN HE PULLS THE GUNS.
>> Jimmy: THE TALENT HAS SPREAD
TO YOUR YARD, IT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
>> SO MANNY HAS A PUBLISHING
COMPANY.
>> Jimmy: I LOVE IT.
GOOD JOB, MANNY, WELL DONE.