Hi. My name is Ronnie, and I'd like to
share a little story with you. So, nice;
story time with Ronnie. I lived four
years in Japan — beautiful country,
wonderful people, good mountains — and
one thing that really shocked me was the
job-interview process, and the amount of
information that people were asked and
give in job interviews.
So, for example, in Japan, I remember on
resumes, people had to give their
picture, their age, maybe their marital
status. And I found this to be very
strange, because in Canada and in North
America, this just can't.  just don't
give your picture. Because I'm sure that
people will judge you on your appearance
in a job interview. Even just looking at
your resume, like: "Well, this one's
gorgeous — let's hire him." You can't do
that. And we have really strict laws
about this in North America, so I'm here
to walk you through some.
You have to be aware that there are many
questions that the interviewer cannot
ask you; based on race, age, gender,
appearance. There's also the problem
that you have to know enough not to talk
about them yourself. So, for example, if
you're a new mother — congratulations,
you just had a baby — and you're going
for a job interview, don't mention the
baby. Okay? It's not illegal to say that
you don't have a baby or say you have a
baby, but it's just a very dodgy subject
to talk about at a job interview. It
makes you look very unprofessional.
You're there to talk about your job, and
you getting a new job; not about your
newborn baby. So, you have to watch out
for professionalism.
If you get involved in talking about
things that are or can be seen as
discriminatory, not a good situation.
You have to watch out for legal issues.
And you have to be aware that the
standards in North America might be very
different from your country. They could
be similar, but they could be very
different. So, pay attention, make sure
you know the game before you run it.
Mm-hmm. Run the race. Practice.
So, discrimination based upon gender.
"What do you identify as?" They're not
allowed to ask your sex. "Who do you
live with?" Again, trying to determine
your gender can be caused as
discrimination or can be looked at as
discrimination. "How are you related to
the people you work with?" Again, it
seems that these questions are leading
to: "What's your gender?" which, again,
is discrimination. They cannot
discriminate against you based on you're
a male, you're a female, you're.
choose to identify with whatever you
choose. It's just wrong.
Also, they cannot discriminate against
you based on appearance. As I mentioned
to you in Japan, and I know in Korea as
well, you put a picture on your resume.
And I know people are sitting there,
going: "Nah, this one. Nah. Oh, this
one's cute. Let's hire her. Whoa, look
at this guy's eyes. Let's hire him." You
cannot do this. Appearance. You're not
allowed to talk about how much you
weigh, your height; unless it is very,
very specific to the job. If you're
going for a job for the tallest person
in the world, they can ask you your
height. But if it's a general question,
if you have to meet some height
requirement, they can ask you: "Do you
measure up to six-two?" or "Are you
taller than three point five?" if it's
required for the job. It's very
important to stress that. "Do you have
any disabilities?" If this is brought
up, again, it can be seen as
discrimination. "Are you pregnant?"
Never, ever ask a woman if she's
pregnant. Okay? I don't care what social
situation you're in, but especially in a
job interview — again, it can be seen as
discrimination.
We have age discrimination. So,
depending on how old or young someone
is, they could be denied a job; again,
unless it's a legal requirement. In
Canada, if you're under 18 years of.
of age, you cannot work in a bar
legally, so they can ask you: -"Are you
of legal age to work in Canada in a
bar?" -"Yes." That's perfect. They can't
ask you specifically how old you are.
"When's your birthday?" No. "What year
were you born? What year did you
graduate?" If they know what year you
graduated, and they're good in math,
they're going to know your age. Maybe
they are concerned about someone being
too old for a job, or too young for a
job, which is that way. "When did you
get your first job?" Mathematically,
they can figure out how old you are. So,
these questions — very, very dangerous.
Be careful.
As far as availability goes, your
schedule; scheduling. So, they're not
allowed to ask you if you can work on
evenings or weekends. That seems
strange. Why? Because this gets into
religion and your marital status. "Do
you have children?" They can't ask you
that. It doesn't matter what religion
you are, you can't talk about that; it's
not their business. Working at night,
working evenings, working in weekends
can kind of determine your religion.
Marital status — married, single,
divorced, widowed — none of their
business; not allowed to give that
information.
And this is a huge one: "Are you
planning to have a family?" I know, in
Japan, if you were planning to have a
family or you were pregnant, they would
not hire some people because they
thought that they weren't loyal to the
company; they would just work there for
a little bit, get pregnant and leave.
Also, when I was in Japan about 10 years
ago, when women actually were pregnant
and had children, some companies didn't
allow them to work anymore. Oh, hello.
In North America, this is very, very
wrong. They cannot do that to you.
Another big thing is your ability to
work. "Do you have a work visa?" Okay?
They can ask you that. But they can't
ask you about your citizenship or your
background, your parents. They can't ask
you to see a birth certificate because
where you were born has nothing to do
with you getting a job. They can't ask
you to see citizenship papers. They can
ask you for a work visa or work permit,
because that's the law, but they can't
ask you about anything about your
family. Oh, it says: "Why do you speak
French?" Hmm. Why do you want to know if
I speak French? This has to do with
discrimination on a citizenship level.
It's not your business why I speak
French, unless of course, you are
applying for a job as a French-English
translator or a French teacher. Hmm.
Maybe this is an appropriate question to
ask.
So, I highly suggest that you know, with
the back of your hand — that's an
expression — what things are okay to be
talked about in a job interview, even on
your part. Because if you start going
off: "Oh yeah, you know, I was born here
and. " Oh, you've given them too much
information. So, please be careful. But
good luck out there. You can get this
job. Just know your rights.