hey guys welcome to lingua marina let's
talk about
english students least favorite tense
which is present perfect
because it is so confusing i was taught
at school that present perfect is a past
tense which is not because if we look at
its name it says
present perfect which means that yes
we're talking about our actions in the
past
but their result is still here with us
in the present this is why it's present
perfect it's
a present tense and it's really
important not to mix it up with the past
tense
it's really important to use it in the
right way so today we're gonna talk
about
present perfect one of the most
important things to remember about
present perfect is that we don't really
care
when exactly something happened
for example i say i've lost my keys i
don't really care if i lost them
yesterday i don't really care if i lost
them a week ago
i care about the result i've lost my
keys and i can't
get into my house this is the result and
so it doesn't matter when exactly
the action happened it matters that the
result is still here
it's my present i can't get into my
house
the way we form this tense is that we
use either have
or has i have you have
they have we have it she
he has after that we use
our verb in the third form
and here please pay attention we have
regular verbs
where the third form is the same as
second and is easily formed
by adding ed play played played stop
stop
stopped and we have irregular verbs that
you have to learn
run run run
bring broad broad rise rose risen
so we use the third form and please
remember that some regular verbs
actually change the way they're written
so for example
say sad sad we get rid of y in the
second and third form
and we add i d study
studied studied so just pay attention to
the spelling of those words so we have
has or have
we have a verb in the third form and if
it's a regular verb we add ed
if it's irregular verb we just learn the
third form
and very often we have
a word that tells us that we have to use
present perfect ever never since already
yet
remember what i told you we don't really
care
about the exact timing of an action so
whenever you have
a year ago in 1990
in march 2015 that means that you would
probably need to use past simple because
again in present perfect
we don't care about the exact
point at time we don't care about the
exact day or exact year
we just care about the result so i have
never eaten pizza in my life
okay the result if i try pizza it's
gonna be something new for me
i've never eaten a taco i've been to
great britain once
that means if i go now it wouldn't be a
new country for me
but it doesn't really matter whether
i've been in great britain in
2015 or 2020 in this case would use past
simple sim i've been to italy many times
also when you are taking your toefl test
when you're taking your ielts test or
whatever
test that you're taking please do not
contract your verbs
don't say i've been there don't write
i've been there
please say and write i have been there
this is formal academic english
and this is what's required from you
when you're taking a formal test when
you're writing a formal essay
of course when you're chatting to your
friends to your classmates when you're
recording a video on youtube or
watching my videos you're free to
comment below oh my god i was scared by
this slip
when you're commenting on this video you
can totally contract
uh your verbs and say i've been there
i've enjoyed this video so much i've
learned so much from this video marina
you're an amazing teacher
you are being too modest so feel free to
contact
below this video but please don't use
contractions
when you are taking an academic test the
negative form
in this tense is formed by adding not i
have
not done this i have not seen this
before
or if you want to make it shorter you
can say i haven't done this before i
haven't seen this before
when you're forming a question in
present perfect this half
goes into the beginning of the sentence
have you ever been to the united states
if you want to add wh question your wh
word comes first
who what when whatever what have you
done today
this wh comes first and then you have
your have or
has and then you have your verb or how
many times have you been to the uk
again your question comes first then you
have has
a have and then you have your verb it is
really important to learn the word
order because when you are speaking to a
native speaker
and when your intonation isn't right
when your word order is not right
people might not understand you at all
because when you are talking to native
speakers
they are used to talking to other native
speakers and
it might be a little hard for them to
understand you if you have an accent or
if you're mixing up word order
this is why whenever you're learning
something please make sure you're
learning everything
accent word order pronunciation that's
really important in any language
okay when do we use present perfect we
use present perfect
to talk about actions that started in
the past or happened in the past
and still have effect on our present
i've lost my keys i can't enter the
house
they've missed the bus that means they
will be late
i've already eaten means i'm not hungry
so we don't care about
when exactly the action happened we care
about the result
in present i've lost my money i've lost
my club and now i've lost my guests
we also use present perfect when we talk
about our life experiences
i've been to the uk i've studied in
germany
i've done this so many times before when
you talk about your experiences
about things you've done before you use
present perfect
i've never driven before also if you
have an unfinished
time word for example this year this
week
today and want to talk about actions
that have happened
in the period that is still ongoing you
use present perfect
let me give you a couple of examples
we've already
prepared our car twice this year
oh my god and there might be another
repair coming up
you've already done so many things today
you've accomplished so much during this
day and you
still have time to do something else
you've already slept
for five hours today stop sleeping come
on
time to work so whenever we have this
ongoing time stamp
we use present perfect i've already seen
someone cry today
also quick difference between present
perfect and past simple
if you say i worked here for five years
that means you're still working here
that means you're
no longer working here you see the
subtle difference
in using of tenses makes everything
completely different and gives a
completely different context to a person
you're talking to
and let me give you a quick exercise he
hungry in 1990
which tense would you use here
another example he
hungry two times
so in the first example you have past
simple
because it has a time stamp 1990. he
visited hungary in 1990 but in the
second sentence you don't have a
timestamp
you just have a number of times he has
visited hungary so
he has visited hungary two times
guys if you like how i teach you tenses
i have a whole course
on english language tenses it's really
detailed really
interactive with a lot of exercises
because once you got information about
tenses you really need to practice them
it has a lot of additional materials for
you to practice to learn to print out
and
put on your desk only for you guys
because you're watching this video and
you're watching up to the very end
you're getting an exclusive from a code
to take
my course with a discount the link and
the promo code will be below
thank you guys so much for watching this
video i'll see you on my course
where i will talk about other english
language tenses
and explain them in more details with a
lot of exercises so looking forward to
seeing you there
please subscribe to this channel if
you're learning english and haven't
subscribed yet
because this is one of the mistakes
you're making in your english language
like this video if you enjoy this
content i will see you very soon
bye