I'm Gill at www.engvid.com and today's lesson
is on seven time expressions, okay?
Seven different ways of using the word "time"
with slightly different meanings, okay?
So, let's have a look.
So, the first one is "on time".
If you're on time, that means you're exactly
on - arriving at the time agreed.
If you're coming for an 11:00 meeting, you
arrive at 11:00.
It's what we call "on the dot".
On the dot, meaning the dot on the clock.
So, you can say, "The train left on time",
on the timetable for the train, the train
is supposed to leave at 12:00 and it does
leave exactly at 12:00.
So, on time is exactly on the dot, okay?
Not before, not after, but exactly on time.
Okay.
Right.
Next one, "in time".
So, just by changing the preposition from
"on" to "in", "in time".
So, here's an example sentence: Don't worry,
we'll be in time to catch the train.
So, you're going to catch a train.
Somebody is worried you're going to be late,
you will miss the train.
But someone else says, "No, it's okay.
I know how long it takes to get to the station.
We will be in time to catch the train."
So, that means you will arrive at the station
a number of minutes before the train is due
to leave.
So, comfortably, a number of minutes where
you're not having to run because you think
you're going to miss it.
So, we'll be in time, don't worry.
Okay.
And then, moving on from that one, "in good
time" means you have even more time, lots
of time.
So, we arrived in good time for the coach
trip.
If you're going on coach trip for the day,
a day trip into the countryside or something,
you have to arrive at the departure place
by, say, 12:00.
If you arrive at 11:30, that's a whole half
hour before the coach leaves.
So, you could say that's in good time.
It means "plenty of time".
Plenty of time.
You can arrive, you have half an hour, you
can relax, okay?
So, that's in good time.
And then the other - going back the other
way again.
"Just in time".
We caught the train just in time before it
left.
So, that's very close to the departure time.
So, the departure time.
The time that it's scheduled to leave.
Just in time.
So maybe the train is due to leave at 12:00
and you got in at one minute to 12:00, so
it's that close.
Just in time.
Okay.
So, that's like about a minute before.
This one, "only just in time", is even less
than that.
So, "We were only just in time to catch the
train."
If you're only just in time, maybe it was
ten seconds before the train left, or five
seconds, very, very close to leaving.
You know, the guy was blowing the whistle
and the doors were slamming or the doors were
closing.
Only just in time, it means you nearly missed
it, okay?
So, you're probably out of breath and you
sit down and you think, "Oh, oh, we made it
only just in time."
Okay.
And then this one, "in the meantime" is when
you have some time to fill in before something
else happens.
So, you've gone to see a film for example,
and you're at the cinema.
But the film doesn't start for another hour.
So, "We have an hour before the film starts",
so what do you do for an hour?
"So, in the meantime", while we're waiting,
in that hour that we have to spare, what shall
we do?
"Shall we go for coffee?"
So, in the meantime is something you do to
fill in the time while you're waiting for
something else, okay?
And then finally in this first half of the
lesson, "it's about time", or you can make
it a question, "isn't it about time?" is when
you think something is overdue.
So, if something is overdue, you've been waiting
for something and it hasn't happened and you
think, "Oh, it's about time that happened."
Or, "Isn't it about time that happened?
We've been waiting now, a long time."
So, the sort of thing you might say at work,
for example, if you've worked for a company
for ten years and maybe you've never had a
pay raise.
That's a bit extreme, ten years without a
pay raise, but anyway, this is just an example.
So, you could say, "I think it's about time
I got a pay raise."
This is in the past tense.
You wouldn't say, "It's about time I get a
pay raise."
It's about time I got a pay rise, because
it's a kind of conditional thing.
You haven't got a pay rise, so it's about
time I got a pay rise.
It's almost a kind of subjunctive form, okay.
And then you can turn that into - you can
add a question about the pay rise and you
think, "Isn't it about time I got a promotion,
too?
After ten years?"
So, that's using it as a statement, "I think
it's about time I got a pay rise."
And then you can use the question form, "And
isn't it about time I got a promotion, too?"
Okay.
So, that's seven different time expressions.
And in the second half of the lesson, we have
a little test where you can fill in the gaps
in some sentences.
Okay, so let's have a look at these sentences,
which have gaps for all the time expressions,
okay.
So, the first one: To avoid stress, I made
sure that I arrived ____ ____ _____ for the
interview.
I'll go through them first, then we'll go
back over it.
We were ___ ____ ____ ____ for the coach.
The project was completed ___ _______, right
on schedule.
Isn't it __ __ something was done about that
empty building?
If we don't arrive at the theatre __ ___ for
the start, they won't let us in.
My friend will be in two hours, so ___ ___
_____ I'll do some homework - sorry, housework,
not homework.
Do some cleaning around the house, okay?
And finally: We thought we'd be late, but
we arrived __ ___ ____ to see the start of
the film.
Okay, so there are seven sentences there and
we have seven time expressions to fit in,
one of each.
So, let's have a look.
So, you're going for an interview, which is
stressful anyway.
So, to avoid stress, I made sure that I arrived
__ ___ _____ for the interview.
So, the idea here is that you have plenty
of time, okay?
Not just a minute before the interview begins,
but lots, lots of time so that you can relax
a little bit.
So, which one is that?
I made sure that I arrived __ ___ ____.
The number of words, of course, gives you
a clue.
So, in - something - time.
So, not just "in time".
You could say that.
I made sure that I arrived in time for the
interview, but everybody tries to do that.
If you want a little bit of extra time to
be able to sit down and relax, what's the
other word?
In good time.
Okay.
In good time for the interview.
Plenty of time to spare, okay.
Right, next one: We were - now, we have four
words here - for the coach.
So, a coach is setting off on a day trip or
something, and this situation, you nearly
missed it.
You nearly missed the coach.
So, another two seconds and the driver would
not have seen you and let you onto the coach.
He probably had already closed the doors and
then, at the last moment, he saw you and opened
the doors and let you onto the coach.
So, it was very, very close to missing the
coach.
So, we were - so, "time" comes here.
Can you remember the other words? "in time",
you were in time, we were ___ ___ in time.
So, "only", only just in time.
We were only just in time for the coach.
Okay.
Right.
Next one: The project was completed __ _____,
right on schedule.
So, this means the same as "right on schedule",
on the dot.
The date it was meant to be completed, that
was the date it was completed.
So, it was completed - so, we have "time"
here, which is the preposition that you put
with it when it's on the dot?
Well, this gives you a clue.
"On schedule", "on the dot", on time.
Okay, exactly, precisely, Okay, good.
So, then we have a question.
Isn't it __ ___ something was done about that
empty building?
There's an empty building.
Maybe it's been empty for ten years or more
and it's in bad condition, probably.
It's boarded up, it looks terrible.
You wish somebody would do something about
it.
Open it up and use it, renovate it, do something
nice with it.
So, you're asking, isn't it __ ___.
So, "time" goes there, and what's the other
word that goes with it when you're asking
this question?
Isn't it about time?
Isn't it about time something was - subjunctive
- done about that empty building?
It's terrible, the way it's just been left.
Okay, good.
Next one, "If we don't arrive at the theatre
__ ____ for the start," the start of the play,
"they won't let us in."
In some theatres, if you're not there, they
close the doors.
They don't let you into the performance space,
the auditorium, because you will disturb other
people and disturb the performers as well.
So, sometimes they won't let people in if
they're late.
So, if we don't arrive at the theatre __ ____,
so this would be "time".
So, you have to be there before the start
time.
So, what preposition goes here?
If we don't arrive at the theatre in time,
in time for the start, they won't let us in.
Okay.
Right, next one: My friend will be here - you're
at home, expecting your friend - my friend
will be here in two hours.
You have two whole hours.
Are you going to just sit there and wait for
two hours?
No, so hopefully not, unless you want to meditate.
That's useful, it's always good to use the
time somehow in a constructive way, even if
it's meditating.
That's good.
Or sleeping, maybe?
As long as you're using it for something and
not just wasting time, okay?
My friend will be here in two hours, so __
__ _____, I'll do some housework.
So, that's a very useful thing to do while
you're waiting.
So, what do we put in here?
When you're filling in some time by doing
something else while you're waiting, so we
have a word here that ends with "time", but
it's a longer word.
Do you remember that one, beginning with "m"?
Meantime, okay.
So, that's "meantime".
So, in the meantime, I'll do some housework.
Okay.
And then finally, "We thought we'd be late,
but we arrived __ __ _____ to see the start
of the film".
So, you thought you were going to be late,
but you weren't.
You were very close to being late, though.
So, this is that one where you're very close
to being late, but maybe with one minute to
spare, you get into your seats and then the
film starts.
So, we arrived ___ ____ time.
That's "in time", what's the word here?
We arrived just in time.
Okay?
We had "only just in time" there, which is
even closer to being late.
This wasn't quite as close to being late.
Just in time to see the start of the film.
Okay, so I hope that was helpful.
So, also, if you would like to go the website
www.engvid.com , there is a quiz to test you
a little bit further on this subject.
So, thank you very much for watching and see
you again soon.
Bye for now!