i'm elise i'm frank
that's a terrible name it's the only one
i've got
maybe we can find you another okay
today we're learning english with the
tourists
a british woman elise clifton award
played by angelina jolie
is being followed by british police
through downtown paris
because they are searching for alexander
pierce
who is her criminal lover stay on his
face
his face
do you think it's alexander peers i
think everybody's pissed
in the following scene elise receives a
letter from alexander
giving her some instructions to throw
off the police
then we'll see a scene where elise meets
frank depello who is played by johnny
depp
but before we get into today's lesson
and in case you're new here i want to
let you know
that every week we make three brand new
lessons
just for you to help you learn fast
english
without getting lost without missing the
jokes and without subtitles
just like jiwoo who says that they have
learned so much new vocabulary and
our lessons are really fun so make sure
you hit that subscribe button and the
bell down below
that way you won't miss a single one of
our new lessons
[Music]
elise you have no reason to trust me
anymore
but give me a chance to explain myself i
know the police are watching you
we have to throw them off the trail
board the 822
at the gaudillon pick someone my height
and build
and make them believe it is me
burn this letter it is important you
follow my instructions precisely
i love you alexander
[Music]
save that letter go in now save that
letter
[Music]
protect the ashes take them to the van
i'll send you someone
elise you have no reason to trust me
anymore
but give me a chance to explain myself
we use the collocation to give someone
the chance to do something
to say that we give someone an
opportunity to do something
give me a chance to redeem myself no
matter what you do her parents will
still be gone
your mistakes can never be undone we use
the word chance with many different
collocations
you could jump at the chance to do
something meaning you quickly take
advantage of the opportunity or accept
it with a lot of enthusiasm
i'll generate false currency transaction
reports out the wazoo
as well as the necessary w2gs
i know a couple casino managers who will
jump at the chance to report
false losses it's a win-win for everyone
alexander the mysterious man who got the
letter wants to explain himself
if you say for example let me explain
myself
or i want to explain myself it's because
you want to tell someone why you did
something that made them upset
or feel angry example i didn't mean to
make you upset
let me explain myself
i know the police are watching you we
have to throw them off the trail
he says we have to throw them off the
trail
what do you think this means confuse
kill
chase
[Music]
if you throw someone off the trail you
confuse them by giving them false
information
we often simply say to throw someone off
to mean to confuse someone
and why'd you ask them what time it was
uh throw them off and
what kind of drug dealer asks a cop what
time it is when he's got a briefcase
full of pot right
we should hire you in our fluent with
friends course
we'll teach you important expressions
just like this one to help you avoid
making mistakes
of course in addition to understanding
thousands of words that we use in our
everyday speech
understanding far-speaking natives our
pronunciation
and of course laughing along with all
the jokes
so you can try that right now with our
free three-part master class
just click up here or down in the
description box below to learn more and
sign up now board the 8 22
at the gal de to board means to get on a
bus
plane train etc in order to travel
somewhere
having just handed his son a breakup
cactus
michael finally boarded the boat for his
three-month sojourn to stare at the
ocean floor
here the 822 simply refers to the train
that arrives at the train station
at 8 22. pick someone my height and
build
and make them believe it is me he is
instructing her to
pick someone meaning to choose someone
of his height
and build height is how tall you are
build is the shape and size of someone's
body
example he has an athletic and muscular
build
[Music]
pick someone my height and build and
make them believe it is me
true
i'm sorry what fall
you mind me smoking it's not a real
cigarette what
it's electronic it delivers the same
amount of nicotine but the
smoke is water vapor yeah what
led light
that's somewhat disappointing
would you rather have me smoking for
real i would rather you be a man who did
exactly as he pleased
what brings you to venice you read spy
novels
i'm a mysterious woman on a train you
tell me what my story is
okay um
i think you'd be a
diplomatic attache or maybe
a girl from east germany whose father's
been kidnapped
and they're blackmailing you into
stealing something for them
is there a man in my life
i have to wait and see
invite me to dinner frank what
would you like to have dinner
women don't like questions
join me for dinner too demanding
join me for dinner another question
i'm having dinner if you'd care to join
me
[Music]
remind me smoking it's not a real
cigarette we usually use the word
mind in questions or in negative
statements to
ask for permission or to say that
something doesn't annoy us
frank here could have asked do you mind
if i smoke
but he used a shortened form mind me
smoking
hey do you mind if i get in there go
ahead
very nice to meet you jay now if you
wouldn't mind
mr jackson i'm happy to let you use my
phone
we can also say never mind to tell
someone
not to worry about something because
it's not important
should i ask where you've been
never mind we're long past that i
suppose
it's not a real cigarette what it's
electronic
it delivers the same amount of nicotine
but the smoke is water vapor
yeah what
led light
that's somewhat disappointing we say
something
is disappointing when it's not as good
as you hoped or expected
as she says later she'd rather see him
smoking a real
cigarette than a fake one somewhat
means a little bit
city of brotherly love turns out we uh
we know some folks there
and they told us that your tenure as a
police officer ended somewhat uh
dramatically would you rather have me
smoking for real
if you do something for real you
actually do it as opposed to pretending
to do it
example are the kids fighting each other
for real or are they just playing around
in a more slang way people also use this
to ask someone if
or say that they're telling the truth as
in this example she can lift 100 times
her own weight
for real what the hell am i supposed to
do with this
i would rather you be a man who did
exactly as he pleased
if you say that you would rather do
something you mean that you prefer to do
that and not something else
we often contract this with the pronoun
as in i'd rather have dinner at a
restaurant than go to the cinema
i'd rather spend thanksgiving at your
house than with my sister
things you find at the beach for us i
had seagull
to make a negative sentence we used the
collocation
i'd rather you didn't do something this
class
sounds like da bomb i'd rather you
didn't attend if you're not going to
take it seriously
what brings you to venice we use the
verb
bring in this way to ask why someone is
in a particular place
what brings are you i heard you were
under investigation by internal affairs
didn't want to miss that
you tell me what my story is
okay um
i think you'd be a
diplomatic attache an attache
is a person who works in an embassy
usually in a specialized area
or maybe a girl from east germany
whose father's been kidnapped and
they're blackmailing you into stealing
something for them
if someone is kidnapped a criminal takes
that person somewhere illegally by
force often in order to get money for
returning them
yeah we never kidnapped you yeah you did
we didn't yeah you abducted me
yeah you brought me back blackmail is
another crime which is when
someone tries to get money from someone
or make them do something by threatening
to tell other people their secrets
well if you want that tape back i got to
get something in return
are you blackmailing me i don't have any
money hitchcock
i'm still paying my uncle's funeral
bills frank says
she is being blackmailed into stealing
something
here the preposition into indicates what
they're forcing her to do
just remember i have got dirt on each of
you and i am not afraid to spill it
barney you can't blackmail us into lying
to nora
really lily is there a man in my life
i have to wait and see let's take a look
at the connected speech in this sentence
which is how fluent speakers cut and
connect their words
have to is shortened to haveta
and wait and see reduces to wait and see
that is the t isn't fully articulated
and
and is just an
have to wait and see
join me for dinner too demanding
we usually say demanding to say
something requires a lot of attention or
effort like i have a demanding job
in this context however she means the
way he invited her sounds too
forceful or you could also say he won't
take no for an answer
i made a commitment to bernadette into
your family and
i've got a hell of a lot of nerve coming
in here and demanding that we postpone
this thing
well message heard and understood
mission cancelled thank you
if you're a fan of angelina jolie then i
highly recommend you check out this
lesson we made with her
and brad pitt you can click up here or
down in the description box below to
watch it straight after this lesson
elise you have no reason to trust me
anymore
but give me a chance to explain myself
why does he want a chance to explain
himself
he's talking about the details of the
plan he did something that made her
angry
he's telling her about his life
i know the police are watching you we
have to throw them off the trail
board the 822 at the gaudeleon
pick someone my height and build and
make them believe it is me
burn this letter it is important you
follow my instructions precisely
i love you alexander
what's the main purpose he's writing to
her
he wants to meet her he wants to throw
the police off
he wants to break up with her
[Applause]
[Music]
that's from there
save that letter go in now save that
letter
[Music]
pick someone my heist and build and make
them believe it is me
true
i'm sorry what fall
remind me smoking it's not a real
cigarette what
it's electronic it delivers the same
amount of nicotine but the
smoke is water vapor yeah what
led light
that's somewhat disappointing
would you rather have me smoking for
real i would rather you be a man who did
exactly as he pleased
what brings you to venice
read spy novels i'm a mysterious woman
on a train
you tell me what my story is
okay um
i think you'd be a
diplomatic attache or maybe
a girl from east germany whose father's
been kidnapped
and they're blackmailing you into
stealing something for them
is there a man in my life
i have to wait and see
invite me to dinner frank what
would you like to have dinner
women don't like questions
i'm having dinner
if you'd care to join me
you know step right up five shots five
dollars
[Music]
go on again