So you want to learn how to sound like
you're from Birmingham, ay?
Well, I'm sure I can help with that.
Follow me. And no fighting!
Right let's keep this quick. If you want
to be a Peaky Blinder, you're gonna have to
sound like one.
So listen very carefully, I will say it only
once.
But if you want you can replay the video
to make sure you've
learnt everything but I will say it only once!
Right.
Let's start with the vowels. Very, very
important vowel in the Birmingham accent is the 'U'. We don't say 'but,'
'cut'.  We say put, but and cut.
It's an UH sound.
Like a monkey. Don't be tempted to say
'under'.
Is that clear? Good. Listen to this
example:
"Arthur, shut up."
Shut up.
Shut up. Good let's carry on.
Now let's talk about diphthongs, right? So
you'll notice
in a word like this: game. The 'a'
moves. It goes like this:
A-E. Game. Name. Fame.
It's a lot less of an A-E
and it's more of an I-E so it's actually
more like you're going from an
I to an E rather than an A to an
E. Listen to the difference: name
name. Let's move on. So in words where in RP you might say this sound: 'oh.'
In Birmingham we say 'ow'.
'ow'. It's wider. It's actually a lot closer
to London. So instead of saying float we say
float. Can you see how i'm going from a
wide: Aah Ooh
Aah. It's like Ah. Aah Ooh. Float.
Boat. No. Listen to the difference
again:
Float. Float. Have a look at this example:
"He knows better words. Right, Pol?"
He knows. Oh. Alright let's move on:
'I' sound. Now, in RP you might say things
like: quit, fit, bit. However in Birmingham we
say: quit, bit, fit. Do you see how I'm making an
IH sound rather than an EH. It's a lot
more forward. Bit. It's closer to an E.
It's closer to E then anything else,
really.
It's in the nose. Alright? Quit.
Bit. Fit. Listen to this example:
"Whose duty it is."
Whose duty it is. It is. It is.
Moving on. In RP you would say words
like:
Bath, grass and pass. So that
'A' becomes an 'Ah'. However
in Birmingham we say bath, path
grass. Fast, past.
Alright? It's an 'A' sound rather than an
'Ah'. So in RP when you would say 'ah',
replace it with an 'A' like you're about to
say apple.
Alright? A-pple.
And finally, the vowel sound 'Y'. When words end in a 'Y',
like funny, money or...
I can't think of another word. Penny!
Thick Birmingham accents will pronounce the 'Y'
as an 'uy'. Penny. Money. It's like a diphthong at the end
it's like you've put a 'U' in it.
You're saying: money, penny.
Move your tongue from laying flat to
moving upwards and it'll block the
passage of air a little bit to help you
go money.
Just listen to this:
"Tommy!"
It's complex but i'm sure with practice you'll get there.
Alright let's move on
to consonants.
Birmingham like a lot of accents in the
UK is non-rhotic. Now,
non-rhotic means you don't pronounce the 'R' if it comes after a vowel.
So for example the word 'first',
'first'. It's actually closer to what we
call a schwa.
Which is a neutral sound that requires
nothing going on in your mouth it's an
uh uh. So words like 'first',
is open. It's an open sound:
'first'.
It's not 'first'. It's not 'first', alright?
'First', it's open, 'first'.
When you get words that end
in 'er',  like mother, father, however.
Instead of going 'uh' we actually release
it into more of an, 'ah'.
sound. Like you would say apple. Mother,
father, however.
And there's one more thing you need to know about the letter 'r'.
in a Birmingham accent, alright?
If an 'r' is followed by a vowel, so
if a vowel comes after an 'r',
a lot of the time people from Birmingham
will roll the 'r',
give it a bit of a tap. Now this might
seem strange in an accent from the
British Isles, but I promise you I'm
telling the truth.
I wouldn't say roll your 'r's on every
single 'r', you'll sound a bit ridiculous.
It wavers between being 'rrr' and just a tap.
For example, listen to that! For example.
I don't really say
'for example' you can if you want but if
you're proper Brummie:
'for example '.
So these 'r's need to have a bit of a tap and the way we do a tap is
our tongue, the tip of our tongue taps on what we call the alveol-
on what we call the alveolar-
it's very hard to say.
The alveolar ridge, alright?
So, tip of your tongue that's your alveolar. So your teeth are there, and that bit of skin,
above your teeth, that's the alveolar
ridge. So you want
up there, alright? So, alright.
It's like you're saying a 'd.'  It's like you're
saying 'd'.
Alright.
Okay so we've got that little bit of a
tap, alright? Now let's hear some examples from the boss:
"Alright boys, you're all here."
You're all here. It's not 'you're. all. here."
Birmingham is a tricky one to understand
because we do link our words quite a bit, alright?
You're all here.
You're all here.  It's not you're. all. here.
You're all here, alright? Notice that
that tapped 'r',  you're all here.
Sorry.
"Do anything to embarrass her,"
To embarrass her.
To embarrass. Embarrass.
Notice it's not a proper embarrass it's
just a little tap, alright?
Embarrass. It's like a little... It's like you're saying 'embaddess."
Last example:
"Your cousins, your horses,"
And that example leads me very well onto my next consonant which is 'H'.
And very often in Birmingham we drop
our 'H's, so we don't say them, alright?
So, notice in, 'your horses,"
we don't say your horses we say
your horses.
Almost like the word horse starts with
an 'O'. Okay final consonant the letter 't'.
You'll notice that 't's in the birmingham accent
are quite delicate
so for example if I said the words to you:
put.
Put. You'll notice that the 't' is quite
weak. Put. Bit. Bet.
It's like the the the teeth don't quite
close, in a way.
But. Bet. You know we actually make the
't' more with our tongue
rather than closing our teeth together
which is what a lot of people do.
So, but, pet, bit, bit.
There's a little gap in my teeth, alright?
And I'm tapping the alveolar ridge.
Bit. It's like it's a breathy 't'. Breathy.
It's kind of unvoiced, alright? Bit.
It's like you're whispering the end of
the word, okay?
Here's a very good example:
"Similar to the one described in that report,"
In that report.
It's like a whisper at the end of the
word. In that report.
Now let's talk about the tone, alright?
The tone.  Now in Birmingham we do tend to go down
at the end of our words quite a bit. So
most of our sentences
in Birmingham do end on a down, alright?
so we'll finish our sentence and end it on a down.
Okay I think I've taught you all I know
so, we're gonna do a practice sentence, alright?
Let's see how you do.
Our practice sentence goes like this:
This place is now under new management. By order of the
Peaky Blinders.
Let's go through it. This place
This, remember our 'Ih' sound when we've got an 'I',
This place. Place. Remember, place.
This place is now under
new management, alright? Pretty much the same. Under new management.
By order of, see how we link those words:
order of. Order of. With the little tapped. By order of the
Peaky Blinders. Have a go at practicing
that every now and again you should be
alright. Thank you very much for
joining me, I hope this has been useful
if you enjoyed this video then press
the button that
says subscribe and  I'll be back soon
with another video.
Not me obviously it'll be the
other lady that
runs this Youtube channel. But it's
been a pleasure
and just remember there are lots of
accents in the UK
and Birmingham is only one of them. But
it's wonderful. Birmingham is a city that
extends far beyond the Peaky Blinders.
It is a vibrant, lively and down-to-earth
city.
So if you're ever in the UK, pay it a visit!
Tata!
(Take a shot for how many times I say 'alright' in this video."