The 1997 film Titanic is one of the most successful and iconic movies ever
Produced it stars Leonardo DiCaprio and Kate Winslet as members of different social classes
Who fall in love aboard the ship during its ill-fated voyage
It is absolutely full of vocabulary. You can use to sound more sophisticated and polite for this lesson
We've chosen two scenes in the first one Jack joins the first-class passengers for dinner after having rescued Rose
Having a completely different philosophy about life
The lack of compatibility between him and the rest of the dinner guests becomes strikingly obvious and make for a very interesting
And somewhat humorous conversation then in perhaps the most iconic scene from the film
Jack and Rose share a moment on the front of the ship
Unfortunately, we cannot include the full two scenes here on YouTube. You can enjoy the lesson without watching the original clips
however
I recommend that you watch them first by cleaning up at the top then come back here for the lesson if you're ready
Then let's climb aboard the Titanic
Tell us of the accommodations in steerage. Mr. Dawson, I hear they're quite good on this ship
Jack here has been momentarily invited to share dinner in first-class
Perhaps you could join us for dinner tomorrow evening
He comes from the steerage which in a passenger ship is the part of a ship providing the cheapest
Accommodation for passengers in the past. This is where immigrants would sleep when traveling to a faraway place
When we say accommodations, we mean a place for someone to stay temporarily
For example when you're in another city
You might need to find accommodations to stay the night on the Titanic
The passengers accommodations are the room where he or she stayed
Example the price for the holiday includes flights and accommodations
the university provides free accommodations for first-year students
Then the woman says I hear they're quite good
when we say I hear we're basically saying I know about something because someone has told me about it and
We use it to introduce a subject that we want to talk about with someone
So Barney, I hear you and Nora had a fun time at laser tag. I don't know what you heard that it was a disaster
This is different from the common expression. I hear you, which means I understand what you're saying
Like I said, we will love you back until late. I hear ya. Mrs. Dunphy you could trust me
Jack answers the question about the state of the steerage in the following way the best I've seen man hardly any rats
Ma'am is short for madam and is a word we use to address a woman in a polite and respectful way
Go back and turn the heaters on in our rooms. I'd like a cup of tea when I return
Hardly any rats means almost no rats or very few rats
Example there is hardly any traffic
This is a comical response which gives us an idea of what you could expect in the steerage area of a ship. For example
Rats wouldn't be anything out of the ordinary
Hey, so I know you're watching this because you're passionate about English fluency and making the learning journey fun and meaningful
And so I wanted to let you know that for just the next few days
It's super fluency week in order to celebrate hitting 1 million
Subscribers here on learn English with TV series and to thank you for all of your support for all of our lessons
we wanted to give you a really huge opportunity over the next year to take your English fluency to the next level with a
55 percent discount on our premium course fluent with friends just like Julian who says that it's unbelievable
How much better he can understand natives now?
Wouldn't you just love if this time next year you could confidently
Comprehend all your favorite movies and series even without subtitles in English
Well to learn more about the course and sign up
Simply click up at the top or down in the description below and remember to get your fifty five percent off
just use the coupon code a million at checkout and
Hurry, because this offer is only available for a few more days
I look forward to seeing you inside the fluency circle. Now, let's get back to the Titanic
It was of some assistance to my fiance
We're going to analyze this utterance from a connected speech point of view try saying this utterance
Did you say it like this he was of some assistance
if you didn't you probably put stress on the words was and of
Resulting in he was of some assistance
These are structure words meaning you don't put stress on them another feature
You might have missed is the linking between was and of was of some was of some assistance
Another reminder is that the F in of is actually pronounced moon if you pronounce it as in
You will say off
Amy I was off by a factor of
10,000 in the following two examples of is linked with the S consonant from the word before
Months of my life glass of milk. I put 10 months of my life into this place a
glass of milk or something to wash that down with
It turns out that mr. Dawson is quite a fine artist. He was kind enough to show me some of his work today
We used this phrase to be kind enough to do something to express our gratitude for an action
Someone did we only say this in formal situations?
Example he was kind enough to hold the door open for us in the following example
We hear this phrase used together with other similar polite sophisticated vocabulary
Like the words ma'am as we've seen and pardon me which equals to excuse me
Two champagnes, please, sir
Pardon me young man. Would you be kind enough to order me a whiskey sour yes, ma'am. I can miss
Frozen I differ somewhat in a definition to find out
Not to impugn your work, sir
Somewhat means to some degree
For example, you could say that the Titanic is a large ship and this is a small one
Then this one would be a somewhat big ship meaning not as small as this one, but not as big as the Titanic you
Seem somewhat familiar if I threatened you before
I'll make a point of avoiding familiarity with pirates
Not to impugn your work, sir
Impugn means to criticize a person's character intentions, etc
By suggesting that someone is not honest and should not be trusted
This is not a very common word outside of formal settings nowadays
Yoshiko free don't dare impugn me honor boy. I
Agreed to go free but it was you to specify we're nowhere
So every single week we make fun lessons like this one to help you
understand fast speaking natives without getting lost without missing the jokes and without
Subtitles just like Victoria who said that our videos are helping her on her journey to become an English teacher
And we can help you on your journey to English fluency as well
all you have to do is hit that subscribe button and the bell down below so you don't miss any of our new lessons and
Where exactly do you live? Mr. Dorsen?
Well right now my address is the RMS Titanic
After that, I'm on God's good humour
Here he means that he doesn't have anything planned after being on the ship
This is not a fixed expression
But rather a creative way, he uses to say that he's at peace with letting circumstances or her God direct where his life goes
And how is it you have means to travel I work my way from place to place
You know tramp steamers and such
If you have the means to do something you have the financial resources to do something in other words
You have the money for it example. I don't have the means to travel right now, but I'm going to start saving up a
Tramp steamer is a type of ship
He uses an interesting term when he says he's worked on tramp steamers and such
Here and such means and similar things. It is also common nowadays to hear and whatnot
I've gotta go back to work defending our nation against terrorists and whatnot
somebody
But I want my ticket on Titanic here at a lucky hand at poker a very lucky hand
In the context of card games your hand is the group of cards that you've received or you get dealt
Two deal cards means to distribute the cards among the players
Later in the scene Jack uses this expression
He never know what hand are gonna get dealt next in this case. He's speaking metaphorically to say that in life
Sometimes you have luck and sometimes you don't
He did win his ticket to the Titanic on a bet by playing poker. Sorry mama funk goolah
'du you bet I'm sorry. You're not gonna see your mom again for a long time
Cuz we're going to America
Now say
Did you say it like leo or the lucky hand at poker
But I want my ticket on Titanic here at a lucky hand at poker at like all prepositions
Most of the time is reduced to its weak form listen carefully
I'll meet you tomorrow at 10:00 at the office in Leo's phrase at is followed by a which is another word
Which you need to articulate with very little or no emphasis at all
So you say it like this out of lucky hand?
What are you doing at a high-school dance?
This came at a bad time for George senior
one day at a time penny
One day at a time Oh life is a game of luck a real man makes his own luck
To make one's own luck means to rely on one's skill ability and perseverance to capitalize on
Opportunity rather than relying solely on luck itself
Example she's a successful businesswoman who's made her own luck. And you find that sort of rootless existence
appealing to you
Literally roots are the part of a plant that grows underground
Figuratively speaking. A person's roots are his home work relationships, etc
We can use the phrase to put down roots, which means to do the things necessary for a stable life
Getting married buying a house having children
But Jack's life is different as he doesn't seem to have nor want a place to call home
So that's why the woman says he has a rootless existence. Of course, she's being very rude here
appealing means pleasing or
Attractive having qualities that people like if you find something appealing or something is appealing to you
It means that you like that thing
Example her singing is very appealing to me. I find her singing very appealing
Well, yes, ma'am, I do
I mean, I've got everything I need right here with me. I've got air in my lungs and a few blank sheets of paper
Jack is saying here. His needs to be happy are very simple. He just needs oxygen and paper to draw as he is an artist
Jack I want you to draw me like one of your french girls
Wearing this all right
Wearing only this
I
Mean I love waking up in the morning not knowing what's gonna happen or who I'm gonna meet
Where I'm gonna wind up
Wind up it means to arrive or end up in a specified state situation
Or place without planning it the past form of this phrase a verb is wound up
Psychologically speaking. It's perfectly normal to wind up with someone like your parents
Next to my mom will probably wind up with someone who loves my brother more than me
Can you think of an example where you could apply this phrasal verb to something that happened in your own life?
For example, I didn't expect to move to Barcelona. I just wound up here after teaching English and Galicia Spain
Just the other night
I was sleeping under a bridge and now here I am on the grandest ship in the world having champagne with you fine people
Rand is an adjective that means impressive especially because of size importance, etc
This is perhaps why the famous Canyon in Arizona is named the Grand Canyon at?
The time of his existence the Titanic was said to be the grandest ship in history. I
Figured life's a gift and I don't intend on wasting it
To intend on doing something is to plan or want to do something
This is the verb form of the phrase to have the intention of doing something
You can say intend on doing something or to do something
And then I intend to return here tomorrow
I intend to free my father. I hope you wanted to see it. I can't let you do that by them
Hey, are you a Leonardo DiCaprio fan?
Well, then I highly recommend you check out this new playlist that features all the lessons that we've made with him
You can watch that after you finish this lesson by clicking up at the top or down in the description below
You'll learn to take life as it comes at you boy you go count
To make each day count
If you take something as it comes you deal with it in the moment rather than planning for it
This is again another way in which he expresses that he's happy to accept life as it is
To make something count means to ensure that the maximum benefit is obtained
Example you'll only have one opportunity to impress the interviewer
So you better make a count if you make each day count you live each day to the fullest
I changed my mind
This is a very common expression that we use to say we have changed our decision plan or opinion about something
Hey Mike. Yeah, I changed my mind. I don't want to do this
Then as Jack instructs rose on what to do he says
Keep your eyes closed
To peek is to look at something briefly or to look at someone or something secretly especially from a hidden place
Jack here. Simply doesn't want her to open her eyes just at that moment
Did you fly in an airplane today?
Yes, I did
No peeking did we pot roast for dinner tonight?
Yes
Then although the phrases hold on to and hold on look similar
They mean different things
When you hold on to something you make your hold or grip tighter so that you do not drop it
Or do not fall as there on the edge of the ship
She needs to hold on to the railing. So she doesn't fall on the other hand
Hold on by itself is simply a phrasal verb. That means wait
Example, hold on. I will help you once I get off the phone
Also, don't forget that you can test your English by watching the clip a final time without subtitles and answering some quiz questions by
clicking the link in the description now, it's time to go beyond the classroom and
Live your English. Oh, yeah