In this English lesson,
I wanted to help you
learn the English phrase,
to wear out your welcome.
When you wear out your welcome,
it means you're visiting someone
and you've stayed longer
than they wanted you to stay.
Here's a good example.
If I was to visit my
sister, and if she said,
"Hey, you can stay two nights."
And if I stayed for a whole week or two,
I would definitely be
wearing out my welcome.
So when you wear out your welcome,
it means you go somewhere
and you stay too long
or you eat too much food or
you do something that means
that changes the situation
and you're no longer welcome there.
It's not good to wear out your
welcome at someone's house.
By the way, this phrase
came from Aleksey Konkov.
Thank you so much for
talking about this phrase
in the comments in a
video a couple days ago.
I realized that I hadn't taught it yet.
The next phrase I want to teach you today
is the phrase wear and tear.
In English, when something
has a lot of wear and tear,
it means it's getting old.
We usually use this to
talk about something
like a machine or an
appliance or a device.
So your phone can have
a lot of wear and tear.
If you drop your phone a lot
and if you use it for two or three years,
it starts to get scuffed on the corner.
Maybe the glass on the front
is cracked a little bit.
It has a lot of wear and tear.
When humans use machines
or devices or appliances
or any of those kinds of things,
they usually have a lot
of wear and tear on them.
They start to wear out a
little bit after awhile.
There's a phrasal verb that
kind of means the same thing.
So it's not good,
but it's just part of how
the world works, isn't it?
So to review.
When you wear out your welcome,
it means you go somewhere
and you either stay too long
or you eat too much food or
you do something that makes it
so you're not welcome there anymore.
It's not a good thing.
And when something has
a lot of wear and tear,
it means that it is starting to look old.
Maybe it's scuffed.
Maybe it's rusty.
Maybe it's even a little bit broken.
I know my one van is starting
to show a lot of wear and tear
because we've been using it for so long.
Anyways, let's look at a
comment from a previous video.
This comment is from Ricardo,
and Ricardo says,
"All us adventurers are
used to running risks.
"What would life be like without risks?
"Honestly, I don't know, but
for sure, pretty boring."
And my response was this.
"Sometimes you have to take a risk."
So a few of you mentioned that
in the last lesson, in the comments,
a few of you mentioned
that sometimes in life,
it's good to take risks.
Sometimes in life, taking
a risk can be exciting.
Maybe you want to start a business
and you're not sure you
want to take the risk.
Sometimes it's good to take the risk.
Sometimes it's good to
try something brand new
just to see if it will
work, and I would agree.
I took a risk a long time
ago making a YouTube channel.
I think it was a good idea.
Anyways, I want to talk a little bit about
the phrase wear and tear
because this piece of equipment here,
this piece of farm equipment behind me,
you'll notice if I bring
the camera down here,
I'm not sure if you can see it,
you'll notice that tire is
supposed to be straight,
but it's sitting like that.
If we look at the tire on the other side,
this is a manure spreader by the way,
you'll notice, I'm gonna
spin you around really fast,
sorry about that.
You'll notice that this
tire is nice and straight.
So this manure spreader
has been experiencing
a lot of wear and tear.
It is quite old.
By the way, we use this
to spread composted manure
onto the flower beds.
You'll notice it's quite rusty.
It actually sometimes has
Wasps or Hornets living in it,
but it's definitely seen better days.
There's another fun
English phrase for you.
And somehow, I'm going to
have to get this tire fixed.
Luckily Jen's dad is really
good at fixing things.
Sometimes he comes down and helps me,
but hey, it's the nature of farming.
Sometimes things break.
Anyway, it's Bob the Canadian here.
Hope you're having a good day.
Thanks for watching this little lesson.