"Shall I compare thee to a
summer's day? Thou art more
lovely and more temperate."
So, you may have heard that
before somewhere; it may sound
rather familiar. So, you may
know that it's by Shakespeare,
the English poet and playwright.
So, today, we have a lesson on
some slightly old-fashioned
English language, but I've had a
few requests to cover this
topic, so I'm responding to
those requests. And this is for
native English speakers, as well
as for people who are learning
English, people who usually
watch my channel to learn
English or improve their
English. But I think native
speakers of English will also
find this useful if you're
interested in, for example,
poetry and older styles of
English language and literature.
So.  So, today's lesson, then,
is about what I call the archaic
second-person singular form,
which is: "thee", "thou", "thy",
and "thine", and "thyself" is
another form of it. So, these
words tend to appear in poetry.
Okay. So, I'm just going to show
you some text here.
Okay, so here we have the words,
we've got: "thou", "thee",
"thy", "thine", and "thyself.
And you can see that the modern
equivalent is just: "you",
"you", "your", "your" or
"yours", and "yourself". So, it
depends whether it's the subject
of the sentence, or the object,
or the possessive, or the
reflexive. So, I'll explain that
as we go along.
So, with "thou", like in the
quotation I began with: "Thou
art more lovely and more
temperate", it means: "You are
more lovely." So, "you", "thou"
- they are the subject of that
statement. "You are", "thou
art". Okay.
So, also to say that these
words, oh, a few 100 years ago,
at the time of Shakespeare and
before a bit before Shakespeare
as well, and after Shakespeare,
writers and speakers, also
people were using these words in
conversation, too. It was just
the usual form. I'll explain a
bit more about that on.  In the
next section. So, that's "thou"
is the subject. Thou art more
lovely. You are more lovely."
And then when it's the object,
it changes to "thee", so: "Shall
I compare thee to a summer's
day?" means: "Shall I compare
you to a summer's day?" So,
that's the object. Okay.
And then "thy" is the
possessive; so that means your,
what belongs to you. Okay. You
could say: "Thy.  Thy face, thy
beautiful face", something like
that. "Your face, your beautiful
face", that kind of thing. Okay.
And then "thine" is an
alternative. It depends
sometimes. If the next word
begins with a vowel: "Thine
eyes", for example, you wouldn't
say: "Thy eyes". "Thy eyes", it
sounds a bit ugly because
there's a break between "thy
eyes". So: "Thine eyes", it sort
of flows better. "Thine eyes are
shining" or whatever; meaning:
"Your eyes". So, that's the
possessive; belonging to you.
And then the reflexive:
"thyself" meaning "yourself".
You could say.  If you look in
a mirror, you see yourself, so
in this older form, you might
say: "Thou seest thyself in the
mirror", something like that.
"You see yourself in the
mirror." Okay. So, that's the
general overview of these words.
So, if we just carry on, just to
explain a little bit more about
them. So, these are all the
second-person singular, archaic
form; the old-fashioned style of
English from around the time of
Shakespeare, as I said. And it's
often found in poetry and also
in Shakespeare's plays, and
older writings in general; old
editions of the Bible, for
example. And it's the old sort
of informal, familiar form.
Whereas when in the past when
people said: "You" that was sort
of more formal and respectful,
which is still the case in a lot
of other languages all over the
world, but I'm just using here
examples from French and German.
In French, "tu" is the familiar
form of "you". And "du" in
German is the familiar form of
"you".
So, this familiar form, although
it's not used in English
anymore, or only in poetry or
for particular purposes, it's
still used in a lot of other
languages; French and German,
for example. And it's to do with
how well you know somebody. If
you want to be.  You know. If
it's a friend or a family
member, you might use "tu" or
"du". If it's somebody you want
to show more respect and you
don't know them so well, you're
being more formal, you would use
a different form in that
language. So, there we are.
So, just to move on from there.
Here we are with some quotations
so that you can see how these
words are used in particular
quotations. So, here we have:
"Thou art as wise as thou art
beautiful." This is from
Shakespeare. If you want to find
out where exactly it's from,
rather than me telling you, I
think you might find it quite a
nice bit of research you can do.
If you just Google this
quotation, I'm sure you will
find where it comes from. And it
might be quite fun to do that
for you, rather than me just
tell you where it comes from.
You know it's from Shakespeare,
but where? Is it from a play? Is
it from a poem? Well, I think
Google will help you to find
out. So: "Thou art".
You can see also the verb. We.
In modern English, we would say:
"You are as wise as you are
beautiful", but the verb also
usually changes that goes with
"thou" and I'll explain a little
bit more about that later on in
the video. Okay.
And then here's another
Shakespeare quotation: "I pray
thee, gentle mortal, sing
again." So: "I pray you, or I
beg you, I ask you: Please sing
again. Because I like your
singing, so please; I pray you.
I pray thee, sing again. That
sounded nice, so please sing
again." So.  Okay.
And then this: This sounds very
similar to what I was quoting at
the beginning; I wonder if it
comes from the same poem,
perhaps. Summer is mentioned
again. "Shall I compare thee to
a summers day?" So, this line
says: "But thy, eternal summer,
shall not fade." So, this is the
possessive now, but: "Your
eternal summer shall not fade."
Okay? So: "Thy eternal summer."
I just wonder why it's not:
"Thine eternal summer", because
it doesn't fit the rule I've
mentioned earlier, but then
Shakespeare did what he felt
like, so it sounds okay to me.
"Thy eternal summer."
Okay. And then we have another
poet here, John Donne. And in
something he wrote, which again,
you can find if you Google it:
"My face in thine eye; thine in
mine appears." So, this does
follow that rule. He's saying:
"Thine eye", not "Thy eye". "Thy
eye" sounds a bit odd. So, what
he's saying is: "These two
people who are looking at each
other, they can see their own
reflection in the other person's
eye, like in a mirror." So, he
says: "My face in thine eye, and
your.  Your.  My face in your
eye, and your face in my eye. We
can see each other in.
Reflected in each other's eyes,
like in a mirror." That's what
he's saying, in that poem. "My
face in thine eye; thine in mine
appears." Okay.
Then we have a Greek
philosopher, Plato. So, this is
obviously a quote, a translation
into English. So: "Do thine own
work and know thyself." So: "Do
your own work and know
yourself." So, I suppose that
means just: "Do. Do your own
thing, and understand yourself
through what you do. It's part
of your identity." So, again,
we've got that rule: "thine own
work", not "thy own work".
Whoever translated it chose to
use that form: "thine own".
Okay?
Then we have some Shakespeare
again: "Hamlet". Well, that
gives you a big clue as where it
comes from, if you've heard of a
play called Hamlet. So: "Hamlet,
thou hast thy father much
offended. Hamlet, you have your
father much offended." Meaning:
"Hamlet, you have offended your
father very much." The word
order is a bit strange, because
it's poetic. But "thou hast" you
can see again. "Hast" - the verb
ending changes. It's not "have",
"you have", "thou hast". So, as
I say, we'll.  I'll explain
that later on. Okay, so Hamlet
has offended his father. Or
rather, I think, not his real
father, but his stepfather or
his uncle. He's both, really,
for various complicated reasons,
which I won't go into.
So, here's our quotation that we
started with: "Shall I compare
thee to a summer's day? Thou art
more lovely and more temperate."
So, "thee" and "you are", "thou
art." We've got the different
verb ending again.
Okay, and then we have Shelley
who was quite a bit later than
Shakespeare, sort of early 19th
century, but then poets did tend
to keep using "thee" and "thou"
a lot more because it kind of
goes with the poetic style. So,
in poetry, you might find it a
lot, you know, coming more up to
date in time, because it's a
poetic tradition in a way. So,
let's see what we have here.
Now, this is Shelley writing or
speaking to a bird, a skylark.
So, it's a bird high up in the
sky, singing, making an amazing
sound, and he's writing a poem
to the bird. So, he says: "Hail
to thee, blithe spirit." So:
"Hail to you." Or, you know:
"Hello." He's saying: "Hello,
hello. Hello, you up there. Hail
to thee, blithe spirit".
"Blithe" means "happy". Happy
spirit, because the bird is
flying around, singing, sounding
very happy.
"Bird, thou never wert. Bird,
you never were." So, here we've
got the past tense of the ver
"to be", which is usually "wa
" or "were". But here, with "th
u", it changes again. "Thou wer
"Bird thou never wert, That from
Heaven, or near it, Pourest thy
" or "Thou never wert". So, the
e's another verb ending that cha
full heart." So, he's saying
"This bird is pouring its hear
ges. Okay? So, he's saying: "Yo
were never really a bird." He
hinks this bird is so spe
ial; it's very different fro
other birds.
out." So: "Pourest thy ful
heart - you pour your ful
heart." So, you can see, again
"to pour" is to pour ou
something from your heart or t
pour.  In a literal sense, "t
pour a liquid" like pouring
cup of tea from a tea pot, tha
sort of thing, or pouring wate
from a jug. So: "pour" an
"pourest". "Thou pourest th
heart, thy full heart in profus
strains of unpremeditated art.
So, meaning the sounds, th
strains, the music from th
bird. "Unpremeditated" meanin
sort of unplanned; it's jus
spontaneous. The bird is jus
singing spontaneously an
pouring out its heart in a ver
happy mood, apparently. Okay, s
we have several examples, we'v
got "thee", and "thou", an
"thy". So, that's a good exampl
using three of the forms
Okay, so now just to explain a
little bit about the verb
endings, and I've just given a
few different verbs here to show
how the form works. So, the verb
"to know": "I know, you know, he
knows, she knows". For "thou",
it's "thou knowest" or "thou
know'st". Offered you get this
apostrophe to show there's a
missing letter: "know'st". And,
in poetry, that's quite
important because the rhythm of
the poetry matters; the number
of syllables in a line. And
sometimes the poet just wants
one syllable, rather than two,
so they can choose between "thou
knowest" and "thou know'st". So,
two syllables with "knowest" and
one syllable with "know'st". And
that choice is often made
because of the rhythm or the
meter of the line to make sure
it's not one beat too much or
one beat too few. Okay.
So, then the verb "to go":
"They'll goest". So, often, it's
an "s-t", that goes on the end
of the verb. So, then: "to
make": "thou makest". Or "thou
mak'st" if you just want one
syllable, "mak'st", like that.
And then the verb "to be": "thou
art" because it's an irregular
verb. "I am, you are, he is, she
is," but "thou art". So.  Or it
could be: "Thou beest, thou
beest". It's not.  It's not
meaning: "You're a beast." It's
not the same spelling, anyway.
"Thou beest, thou beest, beest".
And then the past tense, also:
"I was, you were, he was, she
was, thou wast" in the past. Or
another alternative: "Thou
wert", which is closer to
"were". "You were, thou wert".
And "thou wast" is closer to "I
was, I was, thou wast". So, it's
closer to that. Okay?
And then "to have": "thou hast".
"Thou".  And then the past:
"Thou hadst". A bit difficult to
pronounce. So, "had". "I had in
the past. You had, we had, they
had, thou hadst", so the "s-t"
does come up a lot. Okay.
"To do": "I do, you do. He does.
She does. Thou dost" or "Thou
doest. Doest". And then in the
past: "I did, you did, he did."
It's all "did", but: "Thou
didst, didst". Okay.
And then "can": "Thou canst".
"Could": "Thou couldst". "May":
"Thou mayest" or "Thou mayst" if
you want just one syllable
instead of two. "Should": "Thou
shouldst". "Would": "Thou
wouldst". "Shall": "Thou shalt".
Okay. And "will": "Thou wilt".
And "must": "Thou must". And
there, there's no change at all.
No change to the verb. Okay?
There's always one exception at
least. Right. So, I hope that's
all clear.
And then we have a bit of
information about how this form
is still used even in a very
modern way. In films, for
example. So, in Star Wars in The
Empire Strikes Back, Darth Vader
says: "What is thy bidding, my
master?" So: "What is your
bidding?" Meaning: "What do you
want me to do? What are my
orders for today?" That sort of
thing. "What is thy bidding, my
master? What? What must I do?
What do you want me to do?"
Okay? So, if you're a Star Wars
fan, that's probably a very
familiar line.
And then also in some regional
dialects in the UK, Lancashire,
and Yorkshire, up in the north,
and also in the west, more
further south. But in the west
these are used still. So, some
people might say: "Sit thee
down", meaning: "Sit yourself
down. Sit. " Or: "Sit you
down." I've heard people say:
"Sit you down, sit you down, sit
thee down. I'll get thee a cup
of tea", something like that.
"Sit thee down."
And then people also say: "Thou
knows, thou knows", which is.
Means: "You know", or "Thou
knowest" as we had earlier with
the verb ending: "Thou knowest".
Some people, mostly in the
north, I think: "Thou knows,
thou knows". Or they might
pronounce it: "Thou knows, thou
knows" because they have some
different vowel sounds.
So, I hope that's been a useful
explanation, whether you're a
native English speaker, who's
perhaps never quite been sure of
homw these words work. Sometimes
you get people using them, but
they use the wrong form or they
don't put the right ending on
the verb because they're not
really clear on how it works
grammatically. So, I hope this
helps to see, if you're.  If
you're actually writing poetry
yourself, you might want to use
it in the correct way. Okay.
So, that's.  That's the.
That's the lesson. And there is
a quiz. If you'd like to do the
quiz just to test your knowledge
on this, do go to www.engvid.com
for the quiz. And you might also
like to look out for my several
videos I've already made on
poetry, sometimes looking at a
particular poem, and analyzing
it. So, do look out for my other
poetry videos. And so that's it,
really. So, I will see thee
again soon I hope and take care.
And all the best with the quiz.
Bye for now, then. Bye.