In this English lesson
I wanted to help you
learn the English phrase, I've had it!
Now simply used, this simply means
that you have had something.
If someone says, have you had pizza?
You could say I've had it and I liked it.
But we also use this phrase
to describe a situation,
when you want something to stop.
It's been raining a lot here lately,
you can maybe see some
puddles on the ground there
and I've had it.
I've had it with all the
rain we've been having.
That means that I wish it would stop.
Sometimes I use this phrase
in the classroom too.
When students are talking
too much, I can say, hey,
I've had it with all of the talking there
in the back of the room, please stop.
So, in English when you say I've had it,
it means you want something to stop.
I've certainly had it with all this rain.
It's just way too wet out
here, it's gotta stop soon
or it's not going to be a
very nice rest of the fall.
The second phrase I wanted to
teach you today is the phrase
to have it out with someone.
When you have it out with someone,
it means that you're annoyed
with someone about something
and maybe they're annoyed
with you about something,
and eventually you argue about it
or you discuss it strongly
would be a good word.
When you have it out with someone,
it usually means that there's
a little bit of arguing,
maybe some yelling involved as well.
Maybe my sister is doing
something regularly that annoys me
and I don't want to say anything,
but eventually I want
to have it out with her.
I'm going to tell her what
she's doing that's annoying me,
and we're going to have
a conversation about it.
And hopefully after we argue
and fight a little bit,
we come to a resolution.
By the way, I don't really
actually fight with my sisters
they're very nice people,
and that was just an example.
Anyways, to review when
you say I've had it,
it simply means that you
are done with something,
you want something to stop.
My example was that I've
had it with all this rain
I hope it stops soon.
And then when you have
it out with someone,
it means that you argue with
them, you fight with them.
You talk about whatever the two of you
have been disagreeing about,
you just have it out with them
and then hopefully you resolve it.
Hey, let's look at a comment
from a previous video.
This comment is from Mat,
and the comment is this.
Oscar thinking, I can't be bothered
to say hello to everyone.
This is from the video
a couple of days ago,
where Oscar was kind of grouchy
and sitting on the picnic table.
My response, he's like that sometimes
when I'm out with the camera.
He does the same thing
whenever someone has a camera
and tries to take a picture of him.
He does not like the camera at all.
So Oscar is a unique dog.
He, well, maybe there's
other dogs like this as well,
but he certainly does
not enjoy the camera.
The camera when I bring
out my video camera,
when any of my kids try
to take a picture of him,
he usually tries to hide or he goes away
or he acts a little bit grouchy.
Now, the other day he was acting that way
because Jen was on her way to market.
And he knows when Jen is leaving,
and that makes him really really sad,
Hey, it's Thanksgiving
weekend here in Canada.
I'm actually filming this
video, let me spin you around.
video on a Saturday afternoon.
I'm filming it a little bit early
because I wanna spend some
time with family later today
and later this weekend.
And I just wanted to show
you some of the bouquets
that Jen has for sale
out here on the wagon.
You can see that they
are all nicely designed
using fall colors.
Fall colors are any colors that are dark
are burgundies and other types of colors.
And you can see, we put
these little flags up to try
and attract people to pull
in and to buy some flowers.
Sales have been pretty good this weekend,
but they could be better.
Hopefully they get better
over the next little while
as the rest of this afternoon goes by.
Anyways thanks for watching,
happy Thanksgiving.
It's Thanksgiving day here,
October 11th, Monday, October 11th.
The day you're watching this
is probably Thanksgiving
day here in Canada.
I'm thankful for all of you.
Thanks for watching, have a great day.
Bye.