In this English lesson,
I'm going to tell you a lie.
I'm going to tell you two stories.
One of the stories that I tell you,
one of the stories will be true,
and the other story will be a lie.
But I'm not going to tell
you which one is which.
You will need to guess.
So listen to both stories and
maybe in the comments below,
let me know which story you think is true,
and which story you think is a lie.
And then tomorrow, I will
publish another video,
just a short video, where I
tell you which story was true,
and which story was a lie.
Let's get started.
(upbeat music continues)
Story number one, "The Pet Puppy."
One day when I was about 10 years old,
my parents told me that
we would be getting
a new puppy soon.
Our dog Prince, was getting old
and they thought it would
be good to get a new dog
while Prince was still around,
so that the new puppy could
learn how to behave from him.
My sister begged them to get a poodle,
but my parents said that
wouldn't be a good breed of dog
for a farm.
And that we'd be getting
a dog from the neighbors,
because it was free and both its parents
were good farm dogs.
My sister and I were really excited.
And we got a special
place ready in the barn
for the new puppy.
We put some straw in a big cardboard box
and got a couple old
bowls from the kitchen
for water and food.
We even got to go to the
pet store with our mom,
to buy a bag of puppy chow.
A couple of days later,
we went to the neighbor's
farm to pick out our puppy.
Their dog had, had a litter of seven pups
and we would have first choice.
We were excited.
The puppies were about 10 weeks
old and they were so cute.
They were play fighting with each other
and yipping and barking.
Some were black and white,
some were brown and white,
and one was completely black.
My sister wanted the smallest one,
a small brown and white puppy
who was sitting in the corner,
far from the rest of the litter.
He looked scared and lonely.
I wanted the black puppy,
who was the biggest and most aggressive,
just fighting with all of
its brothers and sisters.
For some reason, my mom and
dad agreed with my sister
and a few moments later,
we were riding home in the car
with the small brown and
white scared little puppy,
sitting on my sister's lap.
When we got home, we
put the dog in the box
and my sister played with
it for the next few hours.
She loved the dog from
the moment she saw it.
And it was clear that the
dog liked her a lot too.
At the dinner table that night,
we talked about names for the dog.
I suggested Brutus, as I
thought it sounded like a cool,
tough name.
My sister liked the name King,
because our older dog was named Prince.
My parents said that we could decide.
I liked her idea.
And so we named the dog King.
King grew quickly and soon
learned to do all the same things
that Prince did.
He helped to bring in the cows at night.
He barked when strangers came to the farm.
He chased cats a lot.
Although, that wasn't
really one of his jobs,
but he sure seemed to like it.
King lived a long and
happy life on the farm.
And it became clear over the years,
that King was my sister's dog.
As you probably know, dogs
usually only have one real owner,
even if they live with a
whole family of humans.
And he seemed to have chosen my sister.
I was good with that.
I'm not really a dog person anyways.
(upbeat music continues)
Story number two, "The Pet Spider."
Once when I was a kid, I
found a spider in my bedroom.
It was a small brown spider,
and I thought it was cute.
It had spun a web up in
the corner of the ceiling
and was sitting in the middle of it.
I got a small jar with a lid from my mom
and I used the lid to flick
the spider off its web
into the jar and then
quickly screwed on the lid.
When my dad came in for lunch,
I showed him the spider
in the jar and he told me
I should find a bigger jar
and put some small holes
in the lid so the spider
would have fresh air.
My mom told me that I should
catch flies in the kitchen
and put them in the jar
for the spider to eat.
I'm not sure if she was excited
that I had a pet spider,
but she was certainly excited
that I would be ridding the
kitchen of flies each day.
I rummaged around in the
cupboard below the sink
and found a large glass jar with a lid.
I went outside and found some stones,
some small sticks and
some blades of grass,
and put them in the jar.
I wanted the jar to be nice
and cozy for my spider,
so it would be happy.
And I thought it would like
the stones, sticks and grass.
I asked to borrow my
dad's hammer and a nail
and punched some holes in the lid.
I also filled an old bottle cap with water
and slowly lowered it to
the bottom of the jar,
without spilling any of the water.
I then carefully transferred
the spider from the smaller jar
to the bigger jar and screwed the lid on.
I wasn't sure where to
put the jar in my room.
I didn't know if spiders
liked light or dark,
but seeing the web up in the dark corner,
I assumed they liked the dark.
So I put the jar on my
bookshelf, far from the window.
I named my spider Rick.
And every day I would check
to see if he had spun a web.
I would catch flies and put
them in the jar for Rick to eat.
Unfortunately, Rick
never made a spiderweb,
so he never caught and
ate any of the flies.
When I watched him, he
would just sit in one spot.
I would never see him move.
But he was always in a
different place when I looked,
so I knew he was still alive.
A couple of days after catching Rick,
I went to the library and
borrowed a book about spiders.
In the book it said that
spiders didn't make great pets.
And that the best thing for
them is to be in the wild.
I was sad, but I knew
I had to let Rick go.
I carefully took the lid off
the jar and set it on the floor
in the corner of my room.
A few flies flew out,
but Rick just sat on his favorite stick.
I decided to let him be.
After all, he usually only moved
when no one was watching him.
The next day, Rick was gone.
He never came back.
I thought maybe he would
return in a day or two
to his web in the
ceiling, but he never did.
And although I was sad that he was gone,
I was also happy because he was free.
Well, do you think you know the answer?
Do you know which story was a
lie and which story was true?
Please let me know in the comments below.
And remember, in about 24
hours, in about a day or so,
I'll put out another video,
where I tell you which story was true
and which one was a lie.
I hope you enjoyed learning
English through story,
with this video.
Remember, if this is your first time here,
please click that red
Subscribe button over there.
And give me a Thumbs Up,
if this video helped you learn
just a little bit more English.
And if you wanna learn a bit more
about secrets, lies and the truth,
I do have a couple more
lessons you could watch.
(upbeat music ending)