hey everyone i'm alex thanks for clicking and
welcome to this lesson on 30 common imperatives
that you can use in your daily life so for this
video i wanted to focus on the short phrases we
hear everywhere so these are phrases you will
hear at the bank at the grocery store in your
own home in movies on television anywhere you
can think of we use these short brief imperatives
now before i begin i want to mention this is
different than the 30 phrasal verb commands
video that i made in the past if you enjoy this
video and you want to hear some other imperatives
some other commands that you can use in english
but which are a little more challenging because
they have an idiomatic element to it check out the
link attached to this video for 30 phrasal verb
commands this is 30 imperatives for daily life
there will be very little idiomatic language in
this it's very clear what each word means okay so
let's start let's do it let's go ah those are two
of the first imperatives so let's do it why not
let's go so you know what this means if you're
leaving on a trip someone will say come on let's
go or let's do it do you guys want to go for lunch
yeah let's do it so let's is like let us it's
inviting everyone right it's making a suggestion
to let's do it let's go let's leave um
let's make this happen next come here
now this obviously you can use in a lot of
different contexts specifically with children
or with people in your daily life other
adults other teenagers other 20 somethings
so you can say hey come here right you're
there i want you to come this way so come here
next if you're at a restaurant the person
who you meet at this at the entrance to the
restaurant or the server might say follow me it
means like come with me now they might also say
come this way please or come right this way
you can you don't have to say come in this
situation necessarily you could say come this
way or come right this way but you can also say
or you might also hear this way
please the implication is follow me
or write this way which means come this way
come follow me all right so next time you're
at a restaurant and you hear right this way you
won't feel confused right or you hear this way
please or follow me you will know what it means
it means come in this direction with me next
keep doing what you're doing okay so if someone is
working on something and they're doing a good job
on it you want to encourage them or you want them
to continue in the same manner in the same way
you can say yeah just keep doing what you're
doing okay next keep going this means again
continue just continue moving forward keep going
so this could be you know you're telling a person
if who is driving and you're in the passenger
seat and they say do i turn left do i turn right
and you say no no keep going keep going
okay like continue driving straight okay
next wait okay so wait this just means stop where
you are and you can say wait here uh wait there
you might hear this in a doctor's office or
a dentist's office probably with a please
at the end of it or at the beginning of
it so please wait here wait here please
uh please wait over there okay or please wait
you know in that room next hold it okay so hold
it has i put an asterisk because it has a couple
of different contexts one hold it can mean whoa
stop wait hold it i don't understand what's
going on or i'm confused or ah what you said
is really like shocking to me or interesting
and you say whoa whoa hold it wait stop okay
now hold it can also mean literally like here hold
this hold that means like if you have a phone and
you say oh hold on a sec i need to do something
and you can say can you hold this for a second
hold this hold it or hold the elevator this means
like you know the person is coming and they might
say hold the elevator and say okay i'm going to
hold the elevator for the person next stay still
stand still
don't move stay right there these are
all different ways to say don't move
okay so like stay still maybe you're in a
situation where you're on safari and you're
trying to see an animal or you're in a forest and
you see a bird and you don't want the bird to fly
away so you tell your friend who's with you
you're you have a camera you say stand still
stay still don't move you will scare the bird away
i want to get a good picture or stay right there
okay so you're telling people commanding people to
just stop moving in this situation next try again
why don't you try again okay or try one
more time so maybe you're sending an email
and for some reason the email bounces back or the
email doesn't you know doesn't get sent properly
you might tell your friend something is wrong with
the wi-fi just try again maybe it will work now
try one more time you can also say stop
right there so this is similar to again
don't move but if someone's coming your way
you say whoa whoa whoa stop right there okay
next uh how about try it right so you can you
can tell someone who you know there's a new
food or something and you just want to want
to tell them to sample it you can say try it
why not right it might be good you might like it
you can also use try it to talk about activities
try it help me help is a very useful imperative
right so if you're carrying something heavy
can you help me or help me please all right
or help him help her if you're a teacher
you could say to one student oh you're
done uh vanessa help him please or
help katie please right so you hear this all
the time help that person help her help me
give it to me give it to her give it to him so
this means pass what you have to someone else
so maybe i need a pencil and you say okay you have
a pencil okay give it to me give it to me right
it's my turn or it's i'm next i need what you
have give it to me please or please give it to me
okay next click tap or scroll so this is on your
phone um on your laptop on your desktop computer
uh depending on if it's touch or not right you
can say click here oh click there uh tap here
uh scroll there okay so uh scroll you can also use
you know scroll left scroll right scroll up scroll
down um another one is swipe right so swipe is i
don't have it written here but it's a bonus s w
i p e swipe right swipe right swipe
left etc so in the middle we have
be quiet right so you want people to turn
down the volume in the room be quiet stop that
stop it right uh so this is some something
that i say to my children very frequently
um if they are misbehaving or if they are fighting
or arguing with each other like girls stop that
stop it okay so a very common uh imperative
that you might hear and in addition to stop that
and say uh don't do that okay or don't do it so
here you're trying to discourage people from doing
something don't do that right stop walking up the
stairs you're well they probably don't understand
you maybe if they're a year and a half old
they're a baby all right don't do that stop that
okay very common be careful it's like
you're walking somewhere and maybe the road
is not very steady is not very stable and you
know this road and you know this sidewalk that
you're walking with your friend you
tell your friend hey be careful here
okay so be careful means pay attention which is
next right pay attention focus your attention look
around identify any danger around you right so
pay attention don't lose your focus next we have
ask him ask her ask them ask your teacher right
so why don't you ask that person if you are in a
theme park right or you're in a grocery store
and you don't know where something is you say
hey where is that big monster ride or whatever
roller coaster that i'm looking for and you see
someone who works in the park and say excuse
me where is that your friend will tell you oh
ask him he knows he knows where that is or maybe
she knows where that is right so ask very useful
next let go let go of that let go of it let go
means to release something so something is like
you know clenched in your hand or you're holding
something and the person someone else will say
let go let go of it let go of that right so you're
holding something and your friend wants it someone
in your family wants it and they say come on
let go let go of that let go of it leave it okay
so this means don't touch it um you can say leave
it here leave it there leave it on the table all
right so you can have a bottle say uh just leave
it there or if a friend comes to your house
and they're carrying a big bag and they say oh
where can i put this and you say uh just leave
it there put it in the corner right so leave it
in the corner and speaking of put it's right here
put right so put is the act of like transporting
the object into the place leave just means like
let it rest in that area okay so leave it put it
here put it there etc now the little difference
the grammatical difference between leave it and
put it leave it can stand on its own you can
say just leave it don't touch it you can also say
leave it here leave it there etc put it you can't
just say put it you have to tell the person where
to put it right so put it here put it there put it
on the top shelf wherever it may be so those were
30 everyday imperatives that you can hear in daily
life that you can use now in daily life let's
review them one more time you guys listen and
repeat to practice the pronunciation and to
get this you know into your long-term memory
watch this video a few days from now too and
it'll stick better so let's try let's do it
let's go
come here
follow me
this way please
right this way
keep doing what you're doing
keep going wait here
hold it
stay still
stand still
don't move stay right there be quiet
stop that don't do that hey
there's an airplane flying over
be quiet we're just gonna wait for it to fly by
is it gonna listen to me if i say like be quiet
come on quiet okay so stop that okay go all
right don't do that listen and repeat be careful
pay attention
ask him
let go of that
leave it here
put it there
try one more time
stop right there
try it
help him
give it to me
click here okay perfect now if you'd like
to test your understanding of this material
please go to ingvid.com and check out
the quiz that is attached to the video so
click on that invid link go to ingvid.com
click on those answers it's all multiple
choice and let me know how you do on the quiz
and if you want to see more videos from me
of course you can keep going to ingovid.com
or you can check me out on youtube
where don't forget to subscribe to my channel
click the like button share this with everyone
you know and uh tell them how awesome this
was so till next time thanks for clicking