Hello! Welcome to the very first video
training lesson for the imitation technique.
Thank you so much for signing up!
I know you are going to love this training.
Now, imitating something is
similar to copying something.
Usually, imitating is copying actions or words so
this technique is all about copying
something that a native speaker is
saying, exactly.
It teaches you to listen to the sounds and patterns of English and trains you to make those same
sounds yourself. You're training your mouth
with your ears.
So you're listening to the sounds and you're not training your mouth with your eyes by reading and
guessing the pronunciation of words, you
are training your mouth with your ears.
By practising with this technique, you'll
reduce your accent and pronunciation
problems more quickly and become a
clearer and more confident English
speaker. Now, there are three steps that
you'll need to remember when you're
using the imitation technique. First,
you'll need to listen to me and read the
text at the same time. So when I talk on
this video you'll see the words come up
at the bottom of the screen. In the text,
the important stress has been marked so
you'll be able to hear the stresses in
my expression and read them as well.
Then, it will be your turn! So you're going to
hear me read each sentence again but
there will be a pause after each one and
this is where you'll need to copy
exactly what I've said.
Listen for my pronunciation,
the stress, the pause, the intonation and
then you'll need to copy it exactly.
You can do this step as many times as you
need to before you move on to step
number three. Then the bigger challenge
is for you to shadow me, which is to copy
everything that I'm saying again but
this time you won't have any text on the
screen, you're just listening to the
words that I'm saying.
Now it might be a little bit tricky, especially the first time, because you'll be listening to me
and speaking at the same time! So it
might take you a few times to get
comfortable doing it. And remember that
you might not understand everything
that's being said as I'm saying it, but
that's not the point of this training.
We're not testing your understanding of
English. We're testing and practising
your pronunciation and speaking skills.
So if you don't understand it, don't worry!
But do it again and again and
again until the sounds that you are
making sound very similar to the ones
that I'm making in the video.
And that's it! The imitation technique is simple yet so effective.
If you practise this technique regularly, soon you'll sound
more natural, more confident and more
relaxed when you're speaking English.
Let's try it!
I love to travel to different countries,
I love meeting new people and tasting
different foods (that's my favorite part!)
To date, I think I've visited about twenty-two
different countries but there are so
many more places on my list.
Almost every person that I know, who has a decent
income, does some sort of travel every year,
usually overseas. to a different
country. In my opinion, travelling overseas
and to different countries makes us more
accepting of each other's differences
and teaches us respect for different
cultures, traditions and beliefs.
It also helps me to tell some pretty interesting
stories about my adventures.
I love talking to people about places they've
visited and things that they've seen in
the world,. I think it's because I can
easily relate to them and it's easy for
me to share my stories and experiences
with them. Plus, I love getting
recommendations about places to visit. It
helps me to plan where my next holiday
is going to be.
Okay, now for step number
two. You're going to imitate exactly what
I say - the pronunciation, the stress, the
pause. And there will be a pause after
each sentence that will let you do that.
Ready?
I love to travel to different countries
I love meeting new people and tasting
different foods
(that's my favorite part!)
To date, I think I have visited about
twenty-two different countries
but there are so many more places on my
list.
Almost every person that I know,
who has a decent income,
does some sort of travel every year,
usually overseas, to a different country.
In my opinion, travelling overseas and to different
countries
makes us more accepting of each
other's differences
and teaches us
respect for different cultures,
traditions and beliefs.
It also helps me to
tell some pretty interesting stories
about my adventures.
I love talking to people about places
they've visited
and things that they have seen in the world.
I think it's because I can easily relate to them and
that's easy for me to share my stories
and experiences with them.
Plus, I love getting recommendations
about places to visit.
It helps me to plan where my next
holiday is going to be.
This is step three, where you're going to
shadow exactly what I've said,
as I'm saying it. So you'll be listening to me
and speaking at the same time.
Remember, it might take you a couple of goes to
get this right but that's OK! Ready?
I love to travel to different countries.
I love meeting new people and tasting
different foods (that's my favorite part).
To date, I think I've visited about twenty-two
different countries but there are so
many more places on my list.
Almost every person that I know, who has a decent
income, does some sort of travel every
year, usually overseas to a different
country. In my opinion, travelling overseas
and to different countries makes us more
accepting of each other's differences
and teaches us respect for different
cultures, traditions and beliefs.
It also helps me to tell some pretty interesting
stories about my adventures!
I love talking to people about places they've
visited and things that they've seen in
the world. I think it's because I can
easily relate to them and it's easy for
me to share my stories and experiences
with them. Plus, I love getting
recommendations about places to visit. It
helps me to plan where my next holiday
is going to be.
So that's it! Tomorrow I'm going to send
you a new lesson to practise with!
If you're watching this on YouTube and you
haven't signed up on my website yet, you
will need to do that to get the next
lesson for tomorrow.
So you need to write your email address
on my website www.mmmenglish.com/signup
So, then come and join us! We've
got four more lessons to get through.
See you tomorrow!