please welcome three-year-old James
mr. mayor how are you more to grab a
seat so
you're the mayor at three years old plus
what are your duties as the mayor oh I
shake everybody's hands my pants are
black that's look man I wore my black
pants because they said that the mayor
was gonna wear black pants so I said I
better wear my black pants and look we
both got on black shoes black laces let
me ask you something James what's the
best thing that's happened to you since
you've been mayor oh my brother was a
mere boy
how does your brother 30 no 26
all do you ever
okay can you come up here
how are you sir come on
he got black shoes on like menu this is
a black shoe day what you you've been
the mayor Oh
yeah James James told us you have been
the mayor twice do you give your brother
any tips on how to be mayor yeah like
what
when you shake people things to shake
them with the right and when you talk to
them you looking them in the eyes
wow that's pretty good man so mr. Harvey
yes sir I tell you something really
quick because oh oh you what I keep
unlike people that's good you know what
I think James I think a lot of people
like you too
how do you get to be mater somebody
shakes up this bucket or a hat to be
mare
kind of like what the Republicans are
doing now huh
Donald Trump European food Oh
bouncer I had to do that now fellas
funny to me it's just a joke relax I
don't kill him huh Oh buddy
don't interrupt me when I'm talking
mr. Harvey yes sir um you're the bestest
mother in the world
hey James I love you oh you're very
respectful you call me mr. Harvey you're
only three I Love You Man