Hi everyone! Welcome back to another
mmmEnglish lesson.
I'm in London at the moment and I decided to contact
another English teacher who has a channel on Youtube!
You might know her.  It's Lucy from English with Lucy!
We are going to meet together on camera
so that you can learn a little bit more
about how to introduce yourself in English!
Hello! Hi! It's so nice to meet you!
Lovely to finally meet you.
How are you?
I'm well, how are you?
I'm good thank you. How are you?
How are you finding London?
So far it has been incredible, like I've been, you know,
working really hard but also having lots of fun as well.
It's just the weather that's not quite my cup of tea!
It's not great! It's a bit grey at the moment.
It's a little bit grey and a little bit drizzly,
a little bit cold for me!
I've spent a few days up in Scotland as well,
which was even colder, so I guess now..
What's it like in Australia?
At the moment we're just going into summer
so it's starting to get warm.
I'm envious!
I'm looking forward to getting back there actually.
Do you live near the beach?
I do, yeah! I live in Melbourne right near the beach. Yeah.
And how long are you going to stay here for?
Probably just another few days actually
so I've been here for about two weeks already.
Do you miss home?
Not really! It's nice to get out and explore
and see new things and meet lots of new
people, like yourself! So yeah.
Yeah I love travelling.
Do you? So where have you been traveling recently?
Well, I used to live in Spain. I got to see quite a lot
of Spain. I haven't been traveling recently.
I did go on a holiday to Spain this summer
but I'm looking to move abroad very soon!
Really?
I'm looking to go back to Spain very, very soon.
I would love to visit Spain! I've never been.
Haven't you? No.
Have you been to many other countries?
I have been.  Yeah I've travelled quite a lot.
I've been to Greece, so you know, warm, beautiful
beaches, lovely in summer - that kind of thing.
I went to Greece this summer! I went to Kefalonia,
one of the islands.
It is such a gorgeous part of the world.
The food! And the food!
It's like a mix of Greek and Italian food together,
just my two favorites!
The European summer is lovely.
It's a shame about the winter!
I know! I'll make sure that I'm back here
for the summer next time!
And you need to visit Spain!
Yes!
Spain is my favourite country in the world!
Yes, I know! It's been on my list for many years.
And the food there - if you like like the Greek food,
then you're going to love Spanish food!
I'm a bit tired of eating Spanish food in restaurants
anywhere else in the world except in Spain.
It's just not the same! It's not the same!
And I'm looking forward to having my first proper
'siesta' as well!
Have you never had one before? We need to correct that
Not officially, no.
So, I've seen on your channel that you quite like cooking.
Yes.
How did you get into that?
Well to be honest, I learnt a lot of it
from my my fiancé, Shah.
So he is an excellent cook and I guess when you
get in a relationship with someone,
you have to kind of 'up the ante' a bit
so he was a really good cook and I needed to
impress him with my skills!
Well, cooking for one just, it's not same, is it?
Actually, I'm awful at cooking for one.
I always make about six meals worth
and then I have to end up freezing it,
which is kind of helpful
but I'm not good at cooking for one.
Well I recently moved back with my parents
for a short while before moving on to another country
and the best part of it is is being able to cook
for three other people
I thought you were going to say that you
the best part about it is you get like home-cooked meals
every night!
No! I make them myself!
You do it yourself?
Yeah! That's like my sort of agreement.
You can have me here, and I'll cook for you!
What's your specialty?
Well I did travel in Italy a little bit.
Actually, I didn't go to Italy, I went to Palermo in Sicily!
And they taught me how to make a mean risotto!
But I really like experimenting, so I kind of ask my
dad and my brother because they're the most
appreciative: "What do you fancy?" And then I try and
do it but with a twist!
So, if they want Mexican, then I'll do some sort of..
I like to invent!
We're quite opposite in that sense,
I'm very much like a find a really good recipe
and make the recipe.
See I like to find a couple of recipes,
take inspiration from them and then rewrite it myself!
That sounds interesting and very exciting!
So, what's your number one recipe then?
I love cooking Thai food actually!
I do love a Thai green curry!
Yeah.
But I find it hard to find a good paste.
Well I make all of my pastes myself!
So, that's why mine are so good! But yeah, it's
all about the paste, right? So you cook that first,
then you deal with the rest of it.
So, you must have lived in quite a few countries then?
I have, I've definitely travelled and visited a few
I've only lived in.  I was born in Australia
and I've lived most of my life in Australia
but I have spent some time living in Vietnam
and also in Malaysia.
I've never been to Asia at all!
Haven't you?
In fact, I have only ever left Europe twice.
Once was to go to Jamaica
and once was to go to Grenada
Oh, really? You're a Caribbean kind of girl.
I've lived in, just in Spain. I lived in Madrid
and I lived in Seville.
Beautiful part of the world!
And London and the countryside in England.
I'm from Bedfordshire.
What's the countryside like?
So green that sometimes when I get off the train,
I have to put my sunglasses on because it hurts my eyes!
It's beautiful! Lovely in spring and summer.
Autumn is stunning
because you get all of the fall of the leaves.
Yeah.
And winter's nice. It does snow, occasionally.
Where I'm from it's quite flat, but if you go further,
quite flat but if you go further,
further afield you can go down hills and everything.
Yeah.
But I'm looking to live in some other countries, soon!
Not sure!
That's one of the things that I love most about teaching
and meeting new people is there are so many
opportunities to, you know, travel and go to
different places, and places that you never really
expected to go either!
Yeah! I mean, it's journey, isn't it? You just end up
doing things that you never, ever imagined
and meeting lots of random people.. like you!
Exactly!
Running into you in London!
Okay Emma! Well, I would love to show you
my neighborhood so why don't we go grab a coffee?
Yeah I'd love to have a little bit of a walk around.
That sounds great! Let's do it!
And have a chat? Continue chatting?
Okay!
Well, i hope you enjoyed that video about introducing
yourself to someone that you've never
met before!
So there was lots of small talk and
conversation topics that you can use
when you first meet someone! So if you
would like to continue the conversation
with Lucy and I, she has another video on
her YouTube channel: English with Lucy
You can find the link underneath this
video and in that video we're going to
be talking about our jobs and what we do!
...