- You said something in an interview,
that I don't even know
if you knew that I knew,
they were asking you about,
"When are you gonna do black characters?
"You're gonna be blackety-black-black
and be black-black.
[Michael chuckles]
"And that's what you're gonna do."
And you actually said, "No,
I want to do characters."
[lo-fi music]
I've known this young man
since he had the tank top and the.
- Cornrows.
- Aw, man.
- [Interviewer] And how long ago was that?
- Ten, twelve, fifteen?
- Somethin' like that.
- [Interviewer] Wow.
- Yeah, at least like,
over a decade for sure.
- Over a decade.
- Yeah, yeah, I was probably like,
in my late teens like, maybe 19.
- Yeah, late teens, so it was like,
that was a while.
I'll tell you one specific
thing when not even,
[clears throat] I don't
know if you remember this,
when you came to L.A.,
there was thing called.
The Basketball, what was it, the.
- The NBA E League.
- It was the E League back
then, back then, yeah.
- But it was really a league
for people who weren't athletic,
who were in movies who
wanted to look good.
[Michael chuckles]
. you know, on the court.
You know, 'cause their girlfriends
was coming and watching.
And then he shows up,
and you understand why his
name is Michael Jordan.
[Michael laughs]
And he did a move on some actor.
He did a move, the actor lost him,
the actor ended up in the parking lot.
[Michael laughs]
And he was just killin' everybody
and it was just amazing to watch.
I think they complained about you.
It was like, "No, we don't. "
"He's too athletic."
"This doesn't go with my narrative."
- [laughs] But yeah,
I think the E League was probably
one of the first times we started to meet.
- But you know what I'll say about you,
is that nothin's really changed.
It's like, you know,
you filled out, most definitely. [laughs]
- No, I was skinny when
I got to L.A., man.
- Look how you --
Oh, see what you did?
See what you did?
When I gon' to touch you,
you say "Aye. "
- Nah, it was one of those things,
I guess coming from Jersey,
you know, moving to L.A. like most,
trying to you know,
follow the dream,
you know, grind,
hopefully become successful as
an actor and stuff like that
and you would find these
little groups and cliques
you know, of people that would hang out,
and somehow I just kinda,
you know, finessed my way in to like,
you know, on the court, I said,
"All right, well, I know
I can hoop, so like,
"At least we can figure this out."
- And the girls was,
"Oh! Who's the guy over?"
- Nah, it was.
- Which really made them want to
kick you out of the league.
[Michael laughs]
- But nah, but Jamie was
one of the, you know,
the first people that I met in Los Angeles
that really kind of
took me under his wing,
and gave advice and you know,
he saw what I was trying to do,
and he wanted to, you know, protect me
from some of the pitfalls and obstacles
you know, that are out in L.A.,
and you know, you wanted to,
always wanted to, you know, make sure I.
- Yeah, because living in L.A. is.
Living in L.A. is an interesting thing
because it is a place
of plastic, what I feel,
but there's also a place where artists go,
and I feel like seeing you,
there was more to you than
just, I think just surface.
Now, I don't know what I or
any of my homies were reading,
but there was a special quality about you
that was like, huh.
It's interesting,
and even everything
that we watched you do,
there was a certain type of,
it's weird to say this,
the "It" thing, or the integrity,
or if it was a younger verb,
this wasn't around then -- the swag.
- Oh.  [laughs]
- I'll say this:
The ingredients of what it
is in being a movie star
along with the type of material
that you were about to
get into as an actor.
Because I do think that
there are two sides,
I think there's celebrity
and then there's the actor.
But you gave me the energy
that you wanted both,
that you wanted whatever
you were doing to be.
- I just wanted to compete.
- Oh, i'mma tell you.
You wanted to compete,
and here was the thing,
it was interesting,
to take the competition,
but also you said
something in an interview
that I don't even know
if you knew that I knew,
they were asking you about,
"When are you gonna do black characters?
"You're gonna be blackety-black-black
and be black-black.
[Michael chuckles]
"And that's what you're gonna do."
And you actually said,
"No, I want to do characters.
I don't want to be in --"
You remember that?
- Yeah.
- What was that?
- I can't remember the interview,
but it was kind of like,
the way I've thought
about it was just like,
there's always a bias somewhere,
it's human nature, right?
So even with writers, you know,
there's not a lot of, you
know, successful black writers
that are writing, you know,
write like, for the, you know, big movies,
and at the time, you know,
there wasn't really that.
There wasn't enough material
out there being written for us
that wasn't very stereotypical.
- [Jamie] Right.
- I've been blessed with my career
to play some stereotypical characters
that lasted the test of time
that just was bigger than that box
that they tried to put me in, you know,
"The Wire", "Friday Night
Lights", stuff like that,
the characters --
- And talking about the "The Wire",
because I believe in the interview
[clears throat] you did reference to that,
but talk about the
significance of "The Wire".
- I mean, "The Wire" for me was at a time
where you know, Wallace.
You know, corner boy, you know,
but he was the heartbeat of season one,
he was the heartbeat of that
show, everybody loved him.
So when he died, it hurt everyone.
- It hurt all of us.
- [Michael] David Simon, you know,
he knocked on the trailer door,
but you know, you never wanna
get that knock on the trailer,
'cause you know, because you know,
you know what I'm saying?
When you get scripts,
when you're on a show where nobody's safe,
you always try to skim through --
- Oh man, it just seems.
"Do I die today?"
- Exactly, so Wallace was
one of those characters
that everybody watched,
everybody in Hollywood watched,
all the right people, the
casting directors, the producers,
you know what I'm saying,
the studio execs, you know.
So when the right people
that are gonna eventually see
your name come across
their desk, you know,
when it comes to different
jobs and roles, you know,
it helps that they're
a fan of certain things
and Wallace was one of those characters
that really did that for me.
But my mentality behind it all was like,
"I wanna play the roles that --"
Brad Pitt's one of my favorite actors,
you know, Leonardo DiCaprio's
one of my favorites,
Tom Hanks, Giovanni Ribisi,
you know what I'm saying,
Edward Norton, these are
cats that I really enjoy,
you, Will, Denzel, obviously,
you know what I'm saying,
the Mount Rushmore of actors,
but I would hate seeing,
I'd be in an audition, you know,
for the role of the year,
you know what I'm saying,
that's not one of those
stereotypical characters
and you would see
everybody from, you know,
ages 40 down to 17 going
out for this one role
and then everybody's
sitting in the audition room
looking at each other
like, afraid to speak,
and you know, it's like
this whole pitted tension,
and my way around that was just like,
"Look, man, I wanna play
roles that are people.
"Of course, me with the skin that I have,
"The person that I am,
stepping into that character,
"I'm gonna make it inherently black,
"That's what it's gonna be."
So I told my agents and everybody,
"Look, I wanna go out for every role
"that's written for you
know, like, a Caucasian man,
"I want those roles, because
when I take that role,
"I'm gonna make it me.
"You know what, but it's just people,
"It's just characters."
- And why did you feel --
[clears throat] I guess I'm saying,
I understand that, but
what gave you that edge?
What made you think that way?
Did you just see all this
clutter and you just said,
"I don't want to be in that box"?
- It was just one of those
things that were like,
how do you.
Reverse engineering the problem.
- Right.
- You know what I'm saying, like it was.
You know, I started thinking back like,
why I never saw a lot of your generation
at each other's premieres.
- Right, oh!
- [Michael] You know
what I'm saying, like,
"Oh, I've never seen this person
at that person's premiere,
"Or that person at that person's --"
Like, damn, why is that?
You know what I mean?
Like what's the subtext there?
- Yeah, like why aren't they
supporting or why isn't --
- And if they are, why can't I see that?
You get what I'm saying?
And then I started thinking
about my own circumstances
with other actors that are my generation,
and you see 'em out
and people won't speak.
They won't say "What's up?"
'cause at the time, it was competition.
and I couldn't be friendly
with my competition,
"Oh, he got that role that I wanted."
So it was a subtext, but I was like,
"Man, there's more material
out there for all of us
"Outside of that one project,
that one role a year,
"Which has really started to
spark the production company."
The desire to create
material, create content,
you know, then that wouldn't be an issue,
and I enjoy seeing somebody's strengths
and trying to help them succeed
and get the things they want.
- And Michael, it's tough to look at you,
coming in all good looking.
[Michael laughs]
That starts a lot of cantankerousness.
We even talked about that,
I even told you about that.
- Yeah, you did.
- I said "You're so nice,"
which is rare, 'cause you.
To be this high in your career,
you know, a little bit of.
Most people get a little
[beep] sprinkled on that
a little bit, you know?
Some people have a little pocket of [beep]
and they sprinkle it on
themself once they ascend,
you know, they start
talking through people.
You don't do that, which makes it.
Which makes people even.
Maybe it makes it even
tougher that you are nice,
but I tell you what,
the fact that you have
that way of thinking,
that you want to relieve that tension
is amazing and.
- I just feel like there's room, man.
I just feel like there's
room, you know, like --
- [Jamie] But you understand that, though.
You understand that when,
and I would say this,
you know, I would tell this to you,
I said "Hey, keep moving.
"Don't worry about all of those things
"and all of those people
"and all of those things
"that are trying to get you distracted
"because you've got something special."
And I say, even coming
along with "Just Mercy",
but going back to like,
your narrative in "Fruitvale Station",
is that something that you.
'Cause now we're looking back,
but is that something that when
you took that type of movie,
was that on purpose?
Meaning like, a narrative for us?
For our culture?
For black -- ?
- Yeah, that was my first
real intentional move
where I had a choice.
'Cause you know people think
'cause you're an actor,
all these roles, you know,
that you're doing, that,
"Oh, I had like, 10 choices
and I decided to do that one."
It's like, nah, that's the one I booked!
So that's the one I did!
- [Jamie] Right, right.
- But I think that was the
first one that I really.
- [Jamie] And Ryan Coogler.
- And that was beyond, above me,
you know what I'm saying?
That's the universe
putting people together
the way it just worked out,
because Ryan just so happened
to be coming fresh out of USC film school,
you know, kind of his senior project,
you know what I'm saying,
this script that he wrote with me in mind,
that I didn't know at the time,
I was coming back from South Africa,
I had just finished shooting
this movie called "Chronicle".
And I was like,
"Man, I wanna do a --"
I was at a crossroads,
I said I wanted to do an independent film,
I wanted to do something
that could show I can act,
and I wanna know,
I wanna answer this question myself,
I wanna be able to be a leading man.
You know what I'm saying,
I wanna know if I.
If that's where I fall.
'Cause I know you could
be extremely talented
and not open big movies.
You know what I'm saying?
But I wanted to know where I stood,
where I fell.
But then also,
Trayvon Martin's shooting had happened --
- That affected you.
- A month prior, before that.
And I just remember being frustrated,
you know, going online at the time,
it might have been on BlackPlanet,
I don't know what it was, but --
- BlackPlanet!
I still have an account!
- MySpace or something like that,
it was something that was like,
I remember just writing posts, you know,
of how I felt as a black man
or whatever, at the time,
and deleting it, you know what I'm saying,
like, man, I don't even know what to say,
I can't say that, I was too angry,
I said, "I don't know --
"How do I express myself?"
And I felt frustrated.
So when "Fruitvale", you know,
it was called "Fruitvale" at the time,
when "Fruitvale" came along,
I read it and I was in tears,
and I was like, "Man, this is it.
"This is my way to tell
people how I'm feeling,
"to express myself on
hopefully, you know --"
We never knew what the
movie was going to be,
it was like, you know,
we shot it for $900,000
and some duct tape.
- Wow. [laughs]
- We barely got it made.
And I could see if I could
carry a film, you know,
so it checked off all the boxes.
So you know, I met Ryan,
20 minutes into conversation,
just talking with this
brother, I was like,
"Oh, man, this is my guy!"
Like if we would've went to school,
if we would've grew up together,
he would've been one
of my closest friends,
he would've been one of my best friends,
so we just saw a kinship in one another,
and he told me, "Look, Mike," you know,
"I think you're wildly talented,
"Let's go show the world.
"Let's go do this."
You know what I mean?
"Let's go tell this story,
"I think it's important, let's get it."
And we both was like, "All
right, let's go, let's do it."
- That's great, man, and you know.
- [Michael] And we did.
- And you know what, I
tell you all the time,
when I went and saw that movie,
I took some guys with me, man,
that are very, very tough,
know what I'm saying,
very like, you know, macho,
and then when we watched you
capture us in that performance,
I heard sniffles from these guys
and I know it wasn't --
They didn't have a cold!
[Michael chuckles]
I'm saying, they was like,
they were broken down with that.
And you know what's interesting about you?
And I'll say this --
I think swag matches swag,
because you and Ryan have
this sort of coolness
about you guys,
like I think that was.
That really was the stars lining up.
- Yeah, and you know, to find
a director who understood me,
spoke my language, you
know what I'm saying,
same age, liked the same things,
like, our shorthand was incredible,
you know, we had limited time,
we only had the shoot --
and we shot in twenty-one
days, I wanna say,
it was a quick shoot,
and we maximized every take, man,
and I think our relationship
and being able to speak
to one another quickly
and get it really lent itself to that.
And then he brought up "Creed"
before we'd even shot one frame.
He was pitching "Creed"
to MGM before we even
started shooting day one
of "Fruitvale Station".
Yeah, and it was like,
"All right, come on, let's do it!"
You know what I mean,
so it was the way things
started to line up,
and then right after "Creed", you know,
"Black Panther" came into the mix.
- Slow down, young man, slow
down, you just can't go in
and reference "Creed"
and "Black Panther", man,
Like, you can't go in and go,
"Oh, this is 'Creed' and
this is 'Black Panther',
biggest movie in the world right now,"
You can't do that!
First of all, "Creed",
what that did,
what I believe that did,
I always looked to love Jones as
a template for me and my
generation who loved Jones,
it was just like,
"Wow, that's black love,
that's universal love."
Anybody that watched said it.
And "Creed",
I was like, "Oh my goodness.
This is so amazing,
the love that you.
That love story alone
with the iconic person
that you were playing was. "
Speak about that just for a second.
- Nah, it was cool,
it was like one of those things where,
you know, obviously you're
coming from the world of "Rocky",
you know, that franchise and Apollo Creed,
I never transformed my body before,
I wanted to, you know,
I was gonna challenge that
I wanted to kinda like,
I wanted to see,
yo, you look at, you know,
Sly and Carl Weathers,
you know what I'm saying,
and you know, there were chiseled, man.
- Yeah, especially Carl, yeah.
Carl's like,
"Come on, bro!
"Tap now."
- And I was like,
"Man, that's impressive,
"I wanna know if I can do that."
You know, so, we put the time in the gym.
- And then you got the body right.
You didn't do it like me,
like, I have a spank on right now.
[Michael laughs]
You didn't spank it out.
This is all spank.
Those are muscles.
[elastic band slaps]
Spanks.
- Nah, it was one of those things
where it was just kinda like,
I knew what we were following,
I knew we'd get all the
comparisons to like,
you know, what "Rocky" was,
and we wanted to distinguish
us as our own franchise
and our own story.
You know, Ryan came up with
that entire idea and pitched it
and we finally got everybody on board
and we went out and I think
we executed in a big way
you know, while paying
homage to what Sly built
in the whole "Rocky" world,
we wanted to distinguish,
you know what I'm saying,
what it would be like
told through our lens,
and that's what we wanted to do,
so when "Black Panther"
came along, that was,
you know, Killmonger was another narrative
that we wanted to push and
that was a big one, you know,
so our relationship is
very unique, very special.
- Well, from "Fruitvale Station",
a small movie that won our hearts
and then to go to the
biggest movie in the world
in "Black Panther" playing Killmonger,
still having the same narrative
that we could feed off of it now,
"Just Mercy", I have to say
is, I say it all the time,
we are so appreciative of you
in keeping that narrative alive.
- They convicted an innocent man.
I was always taught to fight for
the people who need the help the most.
- You don't know what it is down here.
They ain't got to have no evidence.
- How many of you all were
with Walter that morning?
- You ain't quitting, is you?
- No, sir.
- In front of and behind the camera,
you were absolutely amazing.
Talk about the birth of "Just Mercy",
how'd that come about?
- It was, you know, my agent
kind of brought this up,
it was booked to me and was like,
this is something that I want you to read
and figure out if it's something you think
you could wrap your head around.
And I was a little bit embarrassed,
once I started to find
out more information
about who Bryan Stevenson was,
'cause I was like, why
don't I know this guy?
Why isn't he more of a household name?
Why isn't his work, is incredible,
and what he's doing is
exactly what is the remedy
to my frustrations as a young black man,
dealing with all these
issues of police brutality
and mass incarceration of
unfair citizens on death row
and the whole situation, so it was.
I got a chance to watch his TED Talk,
listen to him speak,
a chance to meet him a few times,
and I was blown away,
I was intimidated actually,
because he's much more.
I thought he was much better
of a person than I was,
so I was like,
man, I gotta get my life --
I gotta do better.
I gotta try harder,
'cause this guy dedicated
his life to a cause
and he's continued to beat
that drum roll of justice,
so that all happened, and you know,
so I met him, signed on to do it,
you know, I think he was
feeling me out to see if
I was worthy enough to play him.
- I'm sure he was absolutely happy
that Michael B. Jordan was playing him.
Bryan Stevenson's a lawyer who.
Explain --
- Bryan Stevenson's a
lawyer who started the EJI,
Equal Justice Initiative,
who fights for wrongly accused
and unfair sentenced
black and brown people
for poor disfavor,
you know, people that have been condemned,
he works to get them exonerated
and he fights for just the writing
of a racially-biased judicial system.
- Right.
- So I had the honor of playing him.
So anyway, that got that together,
me and Destin Cretton,
director of "Short Term 12",
a friend of Ryan's,
we started cracking together a script,
trying to develop the stories
out of this huge memoir,
it was so many and so much material
and I'm trying to figure out
how do we make this into a two-hour film?
So we start to pull stories
and work on it over the next couple years,
this is about, you know, three
to four years in the making,
and then we started to
get down to studios,
who's gonna distribute this thing,
Warner Brothers stepped
up in a really big way,
we started thinking about cast,
the case of Walter McMillan,
what the movie's kind of based around
and being in a position
as one of the producers,
you know, I felt.
I knew what would knock it out of the park
somebody, you know, who screamed his name,
was you know, it was you, you know,
my mentor and big brother,
somebody who I consider
on the Mount Rushmore,
one of the GOAT's in the game,
along with Brie Larson, you know,
Rob Morgan and O'Shea Jackson
and Karan Kendrick and Tim Blake Nelson,
many other talented
cast that came together
to help make this thing come about.
The movie is.
I'm really, really proud
of, you know, in a lot ways,
it was one of the first
films under Warner Brothers'
adopted the inclusion rider,
along with my production company.
We helped write the inclusion rider
that all of Warner media
actually hires under,
so all their companies
under their umbrella
uses are inclusion act, as well.
So everybody knew this
story was very important
from the studio to the director, clearly,
all the way down to the P.A.'s,
it was a production that
was a very diverse crew
and everybody knew how important it was,
so everybody went the extra mile
to make sure the story was right.
- Well, I was absolutely
honored and humbled
to get that call to play
this character, man,
and I thank you again, like,
our personal conversation is basically,
you've given me opportunities to have
my artistic integrity back and in tact,
and to hear the story of
this Walter McMillan person
who was wrongly accused of.
In Alabama, coming from
his job as a tree-poping,
owning, chopping down trees,
he's wrongly accused of killing someone
in a city that he'd never been in
and just so a matter of fact,
they put him in jail and
they put him on death row.
I thought that, "wow, I'm in,"
we both speaked on this,
because it's so necessary
and even today,
even though this was 30 years ago,
1986 or '87, whenever it was,
those types of things are still going on,
like, there's a case in Texas
and so many other places
and I just thought I was in with both feet
and then putting Walter McMillan,
putting the skin on him,
having a father who had
been to jail himself
for $25 worth of illegal substance,
I drew upon that.
I remember when we had
to shoot those scenes
in the jail cell,
on how I felt when they
were putting cuffs on me,
and I'm a person of perception.
I don't like the perception
of seeing anybody in jail
but I knew those.
Just like, getting the
cuffs on really put me
in the mindset of like,
"Wow, this person's life
is put upside down."
His family, everybody's affected
and then all of a sudden,
an angel of a person,
Bryan Stevenson, played by you,
it was just magical on set.
It's such a necessary story
and I applaud you for
bringing that to everybody.
- I appreciate it.
I think it's important, you know,
it's a movie that will take
you through a range of emotions
and hopefully you end up feeling,
you know, walking out of the theater
when you get finished watching it,
that you wanna feel like
you wanna be a part of the solution,
I want this to inspire conversation
and to provoke thought and to.
Sometimes the criminal justice system is
such a big issue that it
almost paralyzes a person
to not wanting to do anything
you know, it's just like,
"What can I do to affect this big thing,
so I'm just going to do nothing,"
and I think that's the
wrong perspective to have.
You can do something.
You know, voting is extremely important,
to educate yourself,
what prosecutors in your local community,
who are they, you know?
What policies are being
put in place, you know?
All the information's at your fingertips,
you just gotta do a
little bit of inquiring
about certain things just
so you can be knowledgeable,
so you can learn how your
vote can directly affect
your circumstances and your environment.
So yeah, there's a million things,
you go on to EJI.org,
Bryan Stevenson is
setting up this, you know,
a lot of actionable things on his website
that you can do if you
feel some move to do so,
but I heard you say it a million times,
the things that we go online about,
the things that we talk about,
all these issues,
all these injustices that are happening
that we go on social media
and we have these rants
and we have these revolutions
and we're emotionally reacting.
And then we get distracted,
and 30 minutes later,
we're on to the next thing and the next,
whatever it is, you know,
all the things that we're talking about,
you know, Bryan Stevenson is
actively fighting everyday.
So, you know, I think this
is a all hands on deck,
as you say, this is a --
Everybody needs to get involved
and do whatever they
can to see this movie.
You know, outside of the movie,
it's what it represents.
- Yeah, but it, absolutely,
people need to see it
because it's special.
And I wanna jump into this
one particular situation
when you embody Bryan Stevenson
absolutely incredibly,
but the scene in the courtroom,
I talk about this all
the time specifically,
because I think this is so important,
the scene of you in the courtroom,
this wonderful speech
that I watched you craft
and it was so important,
why was.
You've said in interviews
that that speech,
you looked in the script
and you went straight to that speech like,
this is the most important thing
and I absolutely agree with you.
Talk of that.
- I think because the.
You know, as an actor,
you'd look through a script
and there's certain scenes
that you just circle,
that's like, "okay, I can't
wait to get that one."
It was a pivotal moment in the movie,
it was a pivotal moment
in Walter McMillan's case,
everything was kind of
resting on this argument,
and I wanted to get it right so bad.
I think it's important because.
It really goes into the human condition,
it really goes into how we're viewed,
it goes into the perception
that people have on people of color,
people that look like us.
And then we can't be a fair system,
we can't be a system
that calls ourselves just
if we treat people that
are rich and guilty
different than if you're
poor and innocent.
- Wow.
- So Bryan Stevenson is
very good at being reserved,
at being methodical,
at being strategic,
but in this one scene,
you saw him kind of
take all of his strategy
and kind of just ball it into one,
and it ultimately helped,
helped get Walter McMillan's
case a return, so.
- That, to me, that speech was amazing,
and I'm just gonna tell you as a fan,
watching you walk that speech down,
oh, you finished that speech,
and what you didn't see behind you was.
The extras in this courtroom
gave you a standing ovation.
I went to congratulate you,
it was like, as we say in church,
you had the holy ghost,
you had the spirit,
and you walked out.
Oh, I texted you and told you
that it was an amazing performance,
the people in the fourth row are weeping,
and then.
and then all of a sudden,
the movie is being seen by
people for the first time,
in the biggest way,
at the Toronto Film Festival,
which is, I mean, for
those of you watching,
that's like our Superbowl in a sense,
and I whispered to you, I said,
"Hey, man, you gon' be
surprised when people see this,
on how they react."
And we walked out on that stage
after the movie had just
been seen in Toronto,
and when you walked out,
they're giving you a standing ovation.
How'd that make you feel?
- Yeah, humbled, man, honored, honestly.
You know, we put so much into this movie,
we put so much into making it,
we knew how important it was
but you never really know exactly
how people are going to react to it,
so when you see people
appreciate the work.
And one of the biggest
things I took away from that
was the Q&A we had after,
the questions people were asking was,
"What could I do?"
"How do I make a difference?"
"Where do I sign up?"
"What's going on?"
"I feel some type of way,"
and that confirmed that we had something
that was gonna make people think
and make people start
having conversations,
so, you know, the voice of
the people is very powerful.
The people that spoke,
and there's a phrase that goes back to,
you know, the beginning of time,
so you know, we collectively
get together about something
and then we want to see a change,
we can demand it,
so hopefully they feel passionate
about the subject enough
that they want to demand
some type of change.
- That's great.
I'm gonna call you Santa Claus, brother,
because you have given us a gift,
everybody go out and see "Just Mercy",
I'm happy to be a part of it,
in January.
- Open out wide.
"Just Mercy".
- Boss.
- Boss?
- Yeah, I had to.
[Jamie laughs]
I just had to.
I'm still [laughing drowns out Michael]
[Michael laughs]