hey guys welcome to lingua marina today
we're going to talk about things that
native speakers don't say and you
might say them and i might say them just
because they sound natural in our
language and they are okay in our native
language and so what we do we translate
them from our language into english and
they make either no sense to native
speakers or they just sound wrong in
order to avoid this problem you need to
learn how to think in english but that's
a different topic for a different video
today i'm just gonna highlight things
that you should pay attention to because
you might have been using them in a
wrong way let's dive into those things
first of all there are some nouns in
english that don't have plural form but
they mean a lot of things let me go back
a little bit there are some nouns that
are regular and they have regular plural
forms like battery
many batteries
or remote control a lot of remote
controls iphone iphones microphone
microphones cat cats like easy right but
there are some nouns that are
uncountable pretty easy as well milk
information water evidence that's okay
like we understand that information
means a lot of different pieces of data
and you can't really count information
you can't really count milk and it's
pretty obvious because when we talk
about water you can just say one two
three water you need glasses of water or
you need bottles of water and this is
what you can count but there are some
trickier nouns like for example fruit
you think i can count fruit if i have
five apples that should probably mean
five fruits and this is what happens in
my own language in russian we have a
plural for fruit and we say fruits well
we say fructi in russian anyways and let
me give you some other examples and the
only way out here is to memorize them
furniture rain homework research
equipment evidence luggage money
information work wine and there are
other words as well so the only way out
learn them remember that they don't have
a plural form let me give you some
examples they drank a lot of wine last
night i drink a lot of wine they had a
huge amount of evidence to prove his
alibi we need a massive amount of
evidence before making that leap not
much research was done on this matter
i've done some research the next mistake
that we make is using the wrong order of
adjectives in a sentence just listen
i am wearing a checkered cotton blouse i
am wearing a cotton checkered blouse
basically both of these sentences are
correct but the second sounds a little
like ah and you're like it doesn't sound
natural because
normally you would say checkered cotton
it's just again another thing that you
need to remember because every adjective
has its own place in a sentence in case
you have a lot of adjectives so the
first one would be opinion unusual
lovely or beautiful for example the
second would be size big small tall the
third will be physical quality thin
rough untidy the fourth would be shape
round square rectangular the fifth will
be age
young old youthful the sixth will be
color blue red pink or as in my case
checkered oh by the way checkered is
basically what you see
the seventh origin dutch japanese
turkish number eight material metal wood
plastic or cotton and you see it comes
later so it's checkered cotton not
cotton checkered
type general purpose four-sided u-shape
tent purpose cleaning hammering cooking
again this might sound too complicated
but the more you practice you just i've
never learned this this is the first
time i see it and if you show it to the
most native speakers they'll be like
what what are you showing me i've never
seen this table before this is the first
time i see it when making this video but
the thing is because i listen to the
language every single day i read a lot
in the language yes cotton checkered
sounds a little weird to me and i would
say checkered cotton so just develop
your inner ear to hear those things by
the way if you're looking for courses to
take in english and you're looking for
ways to surround you with the english
language my company and i my company is
language trip.com we have created a
course called intermediate to advanced
so this is basically for people who are
stuck
on their intermediate level and who want
this next step who want to surround
themselves with english to start feeling
those things to start understanding that
something sounds off something doesn't
sound right this course is full of
classes it has my classes as well it has
classes from
other amazing teachers but the most
amazing thing about this course is that
we actually match you and we put you in
different pairs with people from all
over the world so you can practice
english and practice what you've learned
and we give you interactive tasks so you
basically you have a study buddy you
have someone to practice english with
every single day and this course lasts
for 30 days you will have things to do
every single day yes you can take breaks
but every day is interactive every day
you have something new you would need
around 30 minutes a day maybe an hour a
day to be fully present in the course to
take the classes to make your homework
but interacting with studybuddy you can
do it whenever you want you basically
install an app there is a chat and you
just chat with a person from a different
country or maybe from a different city
we have batches every single month but
for the upcoming batch we have amazing
prices we have two iphones we have study
abroad trips we have different language
courses that we're gonna give out for
free we basically have over a hundred
prizes so we're basically gonna rate
students who take this course based on
how fast they accomplish their homework
how active they are and the most active
win the prizes the link will be down
below alongside with my special promo
code use it to get a discount and this
has been one of my favorite courses this
has been one of the favorite courses by
our students because over 10 000
students have already taken this course
and i'm super excited that we're adding
this interactive feature to it where you
can actually find a study buddy so the
link is down below i'm looking forward
to seeing you in our next cohort of
intermediate to advanced in 30 days
course the next mistake that we make is
agreeing with negatives so when you say
i didn't really like the restaurant as a
russian i am urged to say me too i
didn't like the restaurant as well right
but this is wrong
when you're agreeing with the negative
sentence you have to say me neither i
didn't like the restaurant me neither me
neither or another phrase i could use
neither did i neither did i so if
somebody says i don't like the sound
don't say me too say me neither or
neither do i a lot of people in the us
would also ask you do you mind if i sit
here and the correct answer here would
be no no i don't mind but again as a
russian as a foreigner i'm always
tempted to say yes like do you mind if i
sit here oh yes yes because what i mean
by this is yes yes please sit down so
ideally you just say the right word and
it's no do you mind if i sit here no i
don't mind
but if you're urged to say yes and if
you said yes and you realized you made
this mistake it happens to me all the
time somebody says do you mind if i use
your computer and i say yes and be like
so you do mine anyway yes yes please use
my computer so just add this second
sentence to clarify what you mean but
just remember that when somebody asks
you do you mind if you don't mind that
you say no i don't mind please use my
computer no i don't mind please sit at
the table no i don't mind please
subscribe to this channel and like this
video now let's look at the sentence i
want to go to usa first there is an
obvious mistake for me at least usa is
always used with the the usa because usa
is an acronym and it stands for the
united states of america so we have
states here the united states of america
the united arab emirates so whenever
it's a
complicated structure to describe one
country we use the the united kingdom
but canada australia all countries that
just have their name they don't require
the with my country russia for example
you can say russia and then you don't
need the but you can also say the
russian federation and once you have
this federation then you have your the
and this rule applies not only to
countries but also for instance to
mountains and mountain ranges for
example with names like everest elbrus
we don't use any article but if we're
talking about the alps this is actually
a mountain range and we use that and
another thing i wanted to note about
this sentence it's not actually a
mistake but a lot of people would say i
live in the us nobody really says usa i
live in the states is another way to say
it uh but i haven't heard a lot of
people use the usa you see these are
small things that you learn either from
this video or by practicing english
every single day or listening to
audiobooks watching netflix shows taking
intermediate to advanced in 30 days
language course with a link down below
and using my promo code this is the only
way to kind of memorize those things
because i don't really expect you to
print out this table with how you should
position adjectives in your sentence
like who who does that yes i would print
it out and i would just look at it from
time to time when i have a question but
i wouldn't really memorize which
adjective comes after which thank you
guys so much for watching this video up
to the very end if you're not yet
subscribed to this channel hit the red
button down below and i will see you
very soon in my next videos bye