When you hear the word networking.
I know you know exactly what that means.
Networking means meeting new
people, starting conversations,
and even engaging in small talk.
If you're someone who's naturally
shy and introverted, like I am,
that can sound like the nightmare
scenario. Not only that,
but networking in English
may be a challenge.
You're never sure of the right questions
to ask or how to best follow the
conversation. Plus at the end of the day,
what you really want is meaningful,
engaging conversation.
So when there are opportunities
for you to network in English,
you might turn them down, but
here's the problem. You know,
that networking can lead
to amazing opportunities.
It can lead to new career
connections, job promotions,
positions at a new company, new clients,
and even lifelong friendships.
So as an international English speaker,
who struggles with networking in English,
how can you muster up the
motivation needed to engage in those
opportunities and do it
with confidence in English,
maybe even enjoy it. I'm Annemarie
with Speak Confident English.
Everything I do here is designed to
help you get the confidence you want for
your life and work in English in
this Confident English lesson today,
I'm going to share with you six
powerful and instantly effective tips to
help you network in English so that
you can meet new people easily.
Even if you're an
introvert or naturally shy.
[Inaudible].
Tip number one, prepare in advance.
Do you ever think that some people
seem to love networking and they
seem to do it easily? It's like they
don't even have to think about it.
They can just jump into a group of
people and start conversations and make
connections without
even thinking about it.
If you've ever had that
thought you're right,
networking does come more
easily to some than others.
Research indicates that introverts
need more time to think and process
information.
We can be easily overwhelmed
by noise crowds and
increased stimuli, which leads to anxiety.
And as our anxiety increases,
it makes it more difficult for us to
think clearly or be in the moment.
As the author of the introvert
advantage explains an introvert's
brain actually works
harder to process events,
thoughts, feelings, and interactions.
There is literally a longer
neuro pathway for information to
travel as a result.
It's no surprise that introverts
often need or prefer to
have time to think before
they speak or in responding to
questions.
And that's exactly why preparing
in advance is effective when you're
getting ready to go to a
networking event in English. Well,
the first thing you can do is
consider what kind of event it is.
Is it a formalized professional
networking event, or is it a dinner party?
What kinds of people might
you be meeting at that event?
And then prepare the questions that
you would like to ask in advance.
Have a list of three, four or
five questions that, you know,
you can use with almost anyone you meet.
This is something I often do anytime
I know I'll be meeting new people.
I always have a list of
questions prepared to use.
Another way to prepare in advance
is to plan to limit your time
there.
If networking is a challenge
and it drains your energy don't
plan to spend hours at an event,
if you don't need to give yourself
a limited amount of time that you
will be at the event and fully
engaged during that time.
And then when you're ready,
you can leave. When, you know,
in advance that you're only going
to be there for a short time.
It can help you get and keep
the motivation you need to be
present and start those
conversations successfully.
Tip number two is change your
mindset as someone who is interested
in personal growth,
I'm sure that you've already implemented
this strategy in many other areas of
your life.
So you know how effective it can be rather
than views small talk and networking
as a necessary evil,
you can shift your mindset just a
bit and think of it as an opportunity
to engage in meaningful
conversation or develop meaningful
relationships. On top of that,
instead of going into an event,
thinking this is going to take forever
and I'm going to be so tired when I'm
finished again, you can shift
that mindset just a bit to:
I can be positive and engaging
for one hour at this event.
And instead of thinking, I
never know what to say or ask.
You can shift your mindset to,
I only need two or three
questions to get others talking.
And that is the perfect opportunity
for me to introduce tip number three,
use your secret weapon as an
introvert and ask questions.
Introverts are natural question askers,
and you can use this to your advantage
when you don't want to be in the
spotlight or you don't know what to
say, let others do all the talking.
And here's an effective way to do that
when you're preparing your questions in
advance,
avoid focusing on questions that
have a simple yes or no answer,
for example, are you having a
good time or do you like the food?
Those questions can
have a simple yes or no.
And that immediately shuts
down the conversation.
Instead in your preparation
focus on questions that require
detailed answers.
We call these open questions in English
and they're easy to identify because
they start with question words,
such as who, what, when, where,
why, how, how many, how
long, how often and so on.
Here are just a few examples
of fantastic open questions.
What's been the highlight
of your year so far?
What project are you working on right now?
What exciting opportunities are
on the horizon for your team?
How did you get into your profession?
What challenges do you think the
industry is facing right now,
before I move on to tip number four,
there's one added benefit of
asking these open questions.
They naturally make you more interesting.
I know that sounds a little bit strange,
but individuals who are
effective at asking questions are
interesting people to talk
to. If you don't believe me,
I recommend that you check out my lesson
titled how to be cool and interesting
in English. What you
discover might surprise you.
And now tip number four,
find common areas of interest
as you ask your great open
ended questions, listen
carefully. As you do that,
you'll quickly identify
common areas of interest.
And this is what can lead to
more meaningful conversation and
lasting relationships.
A great way to show someone
that you're listening carefully.
And you've identified an
area of common interest.
Something that you want to talk more
about is to reflect back to them.
What you've heard, what that means
is repeating what you heard them say.
And turning that into a
question. For example,
maybe you're at a social networking
event with everyone in the company.
While you're chatting with
one of your colleagues.
You hear her say that she's been
really struggling with how to implement
all these new policies and rules around
the budget this year to show that you
heard her and that you have
found something of interest
that you want to keep
talking. You could say,
you mentioned that it's been a real
struggle to implement some of these new
policies. So how's it going?
Have you been successful and where
do you still have some challenges?
Do you see how I did that?
I repeated what I heard and I used
it to continue the conversation.
Here are some other ways you can do
that. Oh, you play tennis. So do I,
where do you like to play? I love cooking
too. What's your favorite cuisine?
I heard you say you're into hiking.
Where do you usually go on the weekends?
And that leads me into tip number five,
which is make it easy to
participate in the conversation.
If you've planned your
questions in advance,
then make sure that you're
also ready to answer those same
questions. Have you ever noticed
that when you ask a question,
most people will answer and
then say, and what about you?
Where do you like to hike on the
weekends? Or where do you play tennis?
And that is the evolution of
turn-taking in a conversation.
Every good conversation has
back and forth where everyone
participates. So when you're
following tip number one,
and you're preparing your
questions in advance,
make sure that you're selecting questions,
that you're also ready and
willing to answer. So for example,
if you're going to ask the question,
what have you been working on lately?
Be sure to take time,
to also prepare your own answer to
that question so that you feel well
prepared and ready to go. And finally,
our last tip for networking in English
so that it's easy to meet other people.
Even if you're an introvert is be genuine.
It is absolutely okay if
you're not comfortable when
networking and it's also
okay, to be honest about it,
you might be surprised to discover
how many people feel the same way.
For example,
if you're meeting peers at
an international conference
and you have no idea how
to start a conversation,
and it feels a little awkward
to just introduce yourself,
you could say something like, I'm
not great at breaking the ice, but.
or I'm not great at
breaking the ice, so.
I'm not great at breaking the ice. So
I'll just introduce myself. I'm Annemarie,
I'm an English coach and an entrepreneur.
How about you? And another example,
I'm not even going to pretend
that I have a fancy ice breaker,
so I'll just introduce
myself. Hi, I'm Annemarie,
and I'm a marketing specialist
and you are your genuine honesty
in those moments can put other
nervous networkers at ease
and help open the flow to conversation
more quickly. And with that,
you have six powerful tips to
network in English and meet other
people more easily. Even if
you're shy. Before we finish,
I want to give you a chance to
put some of this into practice.
I'm going to share with you
three different situations.
And I want you to use these
as an opportunity to think
about how you would begin
a conversation.
How would you use this as an opportunity
to network with someone as you review
these situations, you
can share your example,
answers with me in the comments
below situation. Number one,
you're attending a trade show and
your dream company has a booth.
You would love to find out more about
working with that company and what the
possibilities might be.
How would you initiate the conversation
with someone working at that booth
situation? Number two,
you're sitting next to someone
in your industry at a conference.
What would you say to start a
conversation and situation? Number three,
you're at a networking in a room
full of potential customers.
How would you start a conversation with
one of them review the tips I've shared
with you here and share your
answers with me as always,
if you found this lesson useful
to you, I would love to know.
And you can tell me in
one very simple way,
you can give this lesson a
thumbs up here on YouTube.
And while you're doing that,
subscribe to this channel.
So you never miss one of my
competent English lessons.
Thank you so much for joining me. And
I look forward to seeing you next time.