Hi Everyone! I'm Arnel and today we're going to
look at the past simple and the present perfect
In today's lesson there are six
steps and I'm gonna use a pyramid.
We're going to start with the most obvious
difference - the grammatical structure, then
everything else is about finished and unfinished
- not finished. Finished or unfinished time,
life experiences, actions and that last one -
connections to the present. The larger parts
of the pyramid are pretty simple. It's that
top part of the pyramid, in my experience,
that students find the most confusing. Don't
worry, I'm going to give you lots of examples.
Let's start with the base - grammatical
structure. verb 1 verb 2 and verb 3.
We form the past simple: subject plus verb 2,
and the present perfect: subject have has plus
verb 3. Verb three is the past participle.
For example, I ate a sandwich for lunch.
I've eaten three sandwiches today.
I'll keep the grammatical structures highlighted
for you.Has or Have? It depends on your subject.
Take a look. Use Has when your subject is
HE, SHE or IT. Finished or Unfinished - time
I have a clock. My morning is from 7 to
12. That's my morning. I worked very hard
this morning. I've worked very hard this morning.
Notice the contraction. When you're speaking,
contract. So what's the difference between
these two sentences? I worked very hard this
morning. Now it's three o'clock. The morning
is finished - use past simple. I've worked very
hard this morning. Now it's 11, the morning isn't
finished. It's unfinished - use present perfect
I have the month of February and I'm in the
middle. Which sentence is correct? February
was a successful month. February
has been a successful month
The second one. February isn't over. I'm in the
middle, we're in the middle of February now.
imagine now it's March. Then I could
say: February was a successful month.
Okay look at this chart. Here you can see
there's a lot of vocabulary we can use to show
finished and unfinished time. With finish
time, we have dates, years in the past.
Things like yesterday, last week. For unfinished
time, we have things that are still happening now.
Today, this week, or even so
far, recently, things like that.
Yesterday I went to the beach with my sister
and we had a picnic. Yesterday, finished,
past simple. Sue called me three hours ago.
Past simple, three hours ago, finished time.
I've had a headache all afternoon. It's only
four o'clock, the afternoon isn't finished.
2021 has been a challenging year. It's only
November. 2021 isn't finished yet, right?
Hello future viewers! If you're watching
this video and it's not 2021, you need to say
2021 was a challenging year.
Common mistake: Last month
we have visited Lake Como.
Last month is finished. Last month we visited
Lake Como. Okay let's move on to life experiences.
Have you ever been to Canada? Have you ever
broken a bone? Have you ever messaged the
wrong person? I've been to Canada once.
I've never broken a bone, and yeah I've
messaged the wrong person five or six times.
We use a present perfect with life experiences
because your life isn't finished
yet. You're still alive.
The question: Have you ever. ? is really
common. Have you ever been to Mount Rushmore?
Do I care about the "when"? No I don't care.
You don't care. This lady doesn't care.
I went there two years ago, it was great, I took
loads of pictures. Did you go with your family?
No, it was actually a business
trip. You can see the rest of
the conversation is in the past simple because
I've established a specific time - a specific
finish time, two years ago. Now the "when"
is important. Finished / unfinished actions.
Okay I have two sentences. I knew Lynn for
one year. I've known Lynn for one year.
We know the first one is past simple
because of the grammatical structure
and the second one is present
perfect because of that grammar.
But, when you're studying, you really don't
want to isolate the grammar. Without context,
no sentence really makes sense. Morning
Al! I knew Lynn for three years!
We need some context, it's more
natural. I knew Lynn for one year
back in high school. We were good
friend,s but her family moved away.
Past simple, I've given you a bit more
context _ back in high school. I've
only known Lynn for one year. We work
together but we're not really close.
Here, present perfect because we still work
together. I've given you a bit more information.
We can't talk about these two tenses
without looking at for and since. So
let's do a mini For and Since review. For
plus duration, since plus starting point.
What does that mean? For plus duration: for
ten years, four eight months, for five hours.
Since plus starting point. When did
something start? From when? since 2011,
since March. Those are my starting
points. I've lived here for 10 years.
I've had a bad shoulder since summer. For and
Since are really common with the present perfect
because they show us that something is
continuing up to now. I still live here.
My shoulder still hurts. Can we use For and
Since with the past simple? We can use FOR.
My grandparents were married for 60 years. I
lived there for 10 years. We don't use Since
with the past simple because Since means something
is continuing up to now. I lived here since 2011.
But! I've met thousands of students since I
started teaching. I've met - present perfect.
I'm still teaching now, great. Since I
started? What? Since plus past simple?
In this sentence here, Since plus I started, is
my starting point. I'm not saying my starting
is continuing up to the present. Let me give you
the same sentence, but I'll change things around
a little bit. I've met thousands of people since
2010. Same information, I'm just using different
vocabulary. To summarize: Don't use the past
simple with since if you're trying to express
up to now. Use since plus past simple if that
past simple time was your starting point. Let's
move on to that last part - connections to
the present. A connection to the present.
Oh man, Kevin has already booked the meeting room.
The police have taped off the
path I use to walk to work.
Both of these past actions have an impact on
my present. How do I know that? Because without
these actions, my life wouldn't be different now.
Now I can't book the meeting room. Thanks Kevin!
Now I need to walk the long way to work.
So there's a connection to the present.
Does anyone here speak Russian?
Kyle's been to Russia loads of times.
Notice my contraction. Let's ask him. Maybe he
can help us. We see the present perfect a lot
in the news because past actions impact us now,
right? New Covid restrictions have complicated
plans to reopen air travel between the US and
the UK. Teachers have expressed concerns over
recent cyber bullying cases. Okay, let's
get a little bit more conversational.
I've sprained my ankle, so
I can't go on a skiing trip.
I've received some bad news from my
doctor. I really don't know how to feel.
We're out of coffee pods. Don't
worry, I've already ordered some.
Because of my sprained ankle, now I can't go
on that skiing trip. Because of the bad news,
now I don't know how I feel. I ordered coffee
pods, now you can relax. But, Americans usually
don't use the present perfect when we have this
past to present connection. If something's done,
it's done. So I could say: I sprained my
ankle, I received some bad news, I already
ordered some. Keep that difference in mind when
you're listening to podcasts or watching movies.
Okay are you ready for a big review?
Both tenses have different grammatical
structures. Verb 2 for past simple.
Have/Has plus verb three, past
participle - for the present perfect
It's all about something that is finished
or unfinished - time. Finished: I drank three
cups of coffee yesterday. Unfinished:
I've drunk three cups of coffee today.
Life experiences. Finished: My grandma went to over
50 countries. Unfortunately, she's not alive now.
Unfinished: She's been to over 50
countries. She's still alive. Actions.
Finished: I lived there for 20 years. Unfinished:
I have lived here for 20 years. Connection to
the present: You don't need to cook. I've just
ordered a large pizza. This is correct, but many
times, Americans prefer to use the past simple .
You don't need to cook. I just ordered a pizza.
Well done. I know there was a lot
of information in today's lesson,
so leave me a comment down below, and I
can't wait to see you soon. Thank you. Bye!