Hi, I'm Ronnie. I have a YouTube channel.
You're watching it, but you need to
subscribe to it. EnglishLessons4U.
Hit that subscribe button, do it,
do it now or I'm not going to teach you... okay,
I'll teach you anyways. But subscribe and sign up.
It'll be great, you'll love it. No, you will.
I'm going to teach you phrasal verbs, and phrasal
verbs are essential. A lot of people kind of get
off track and they start to study idioms. Wow,
idioms are kind of old, in my opinion, and not
very useful. But, one thing that is essential
for you to understand and learn in English are
these crazy phrasal verbs. What is a phrasal verb,
you ask? You did, I heard you! A phrasal verb
has a verb + a preposition. So, prepositions
are things like "up, on, down, around". So,
if you have a verb and a preposition together,
magically these are called phrasal verbs. And
they're very confusing. A lot of people have
problems with them, because one phrasal verb can
have many meanings, but I'm here to make it easy
for you and teach you about something you probably
do every day. It's called your morning routine.
I don't know about you, but I have to wake up
in the morning. Some of you have to wake up in
the afternoon or at night, depending on your
work schedule or if you work. So, the first
thing that happens. Most treacherously and most
terribly is, "My alarm goes off". In the past,
I could also say, "My alarm went off", maybe
at 7:00. If you wanted to be very specific,
you could say 7:00am. But because most people
wake up in the morning, you don't need to say
"am". Most people understand you're waking up
in the morning. If you work a night shift or,
I don't know, you're a vampire, you could also
say, "Oh, my alarm went off at 7:00pm". That's
cool, but usually we don't need to specify or
we don't need to say "am", because most people
understand it's the morning time. And this is also
very illogical, crazy in English. An alarm goes
off. But in reality, it goes on. Because it makes
a noise. So, in English, we just like to have a
giggle and make it difficult. So, we have to say,
"My alarm goes off". It means my alarm sounds or
makes a noise. And then, I turn off the alarm that
went off. Don't get it? Don't worry about that.
So, my alarm goes off at 7:00. What do I do next?
I wake up. That means I open my eyes and I - Oh
God, why isn't is Saturday? Why do I have to wake
up? Why was I born? Then, to actually physically
leave your bed, you're going to say "get up". So,
maybe you are good at getting out of bed, but I'm
not. So, my alarm goes off at 7:00, but I actually
get up, which means I leave my beautiful, warm,
luscious bed, at 7:30. What are you doing for half
an hour, Ronnie? Yes, I am trying to make time
stop so I can sleep longer, but it never works.
And then I try to figure out all the problems of
the world and solve some English problems, but
yeah. 7:30 comes again and I have to get up.
I take off my PJs. Peanut butter jam? No, PJs are
the short form of pajamas or pyjamas. Pajamas are
the clothes you wear at night in your bed. You
can wear them in the daytime too, doesn't matter.
They're usually funky, though. This phrasal verb
we can replace with just the verb "remove". So,
you can say, "I remove my pajamas" or my
PJs, but that sounds very strange. We don't
say that. If you said it, I would understand,
but that's not how we speak naturally. We say,
"I take off my pajamas" or my PJs.
I actually shower, okay? I - it just
wasn't a phrasal verb, so I couldn't put it in
here. But after I take my shower, I need to put
on my clothes. Now, in English, we don't use the
verb "wear" when we're actually getting dressed.
Which means, putting on your clothes. In some
languages, you guys say, "I wear my clothes",
but we don't use the verb "wear". We say,
"I put on my clothes". So, in the morning,
we put on our clothes. I take off my PJ's, I
have a shower, and then I put on my clothes.
Because it's illegal to walk around naked.
The next thing I do is I put in, or I can also say
I put on my contacts. Now, contacts is actually
the short form of contact lenses. We don't need
to bother to say lenses. Everybody knows if you
put in or put on your contacts, those are contact
lenses. Maybe you also like to wear makeup, so
you can say, "I put on my makeup". You could say
apply my makeup, but again, it's not natural.
We always use a phrasal verb "put on". Maybe
you want to wear glasses. Don't, please don't put
on contacts and glasses at the same time. You'll
hurt your vision. But you would definitely put
on glasses and you would put on jewellery. This
is a difficult word for people. Repeat after me:
jewellery. I put in jewellery. As I said before,
rings, earrings, a necklace. All of these things
are jewellery, and we put them on, because they're
outside of our body. So, I put on these things.
Then, just to help with life, I do the most
essential thing. I turn on the coffee
maker. I could say "start the coffee maker",
but because it's a button, I would say
I turn on the coffee maker. "Start"
is too formal. You can start your car, but
you're going to turn on the coffee maker.
Now, one thing that you should do, not every day,
because you can't, but I highly suggest that you
sign up for notifications by ringing the bell
- ding ding ding - on EnglishLessons4U. This is
what you're watching. This is the amazingness of
what you're doing right now. So, if you sign up
for notifications and you ring the bell, this
means that when I make a new video for you,
you get a notification and you can watch it
right away. Because some people say, "Ronnie,
you had a new video and I didn't know!" Did you
ring my bell? You gotta ring my bell to get the
notifications. So, actually, do it now. Do it
now, hit the bell, ring the bell, ding ding.
And I'll see you later. Please don't forget to
shower, though. Essential, essential.