Believe it or not,
English speakers sometimes
yell at each other.
Sometimes we want to say
something loudly and clearly,
or with a little bit of emotion.
Quit it.
Sometimes we, cut it out.
Sometimes when we're trying, stop it.
Sometimes we're trying to make a point,
we say things very clearly
and directly to people.
Again, we say these when
we're speaking with emotion.
We say these, when we
want to speak loudly,
because someone is far away,
or we say these in a way that
just communicates strongly
what we're feeling.
So stick around for this English lesson,
where I'll explain to
you a number of phrases
that you can use in English
when you want to speak clearly,
loudly, and maybe yell a bit.
(bouncy music)
Well, hello and welcome
to this English lesson
where I'm going to teach you how to yell
at other people in English.
Remember when you yell at other people,
it's not always considered polite.
So just be careful if you do
use some of these phrases.
Before we get started, though,
if this is your first time here,
don't forget to click that red
subscribe button over there,
and give me a thumbs up
if this video helps you learn
just a little bit more English.
So right now there's a whole
bunch of flies around me,
and they are bothering me.
They are bugging me.
If a person was here,
and they were bugging me,
or bothering me as well,
there's three English phrases we could use
to tell them to go away.
We can say, leave me alone, leave me be,
or the most forceful one, get lost.
So all of these phrases you would use
in a situation where something
like a fly is bothering you.
You might say, ah, leave me alone.
Or ah, leave me be, or get lost.
You might even say get lost, fly.
In fact, I yelled that this morning
when I was working on my computer.
These are phrases you
would use to tell someone,
and it would be kind of rude to say this,
or something that you
want them to go away.
You do not want them to be in
the same area where you are.
Sometimes when I'm driving in my van,
my kids are in the back, and
sometimes they're really loud.
And there's two things you
could yell in that situation.
One would be really
rude, and not very nice.
It wouldn't be nice for me
as a parent to yell, shut up,
but it would be something
that would be used
to tell people that you
want them to be quiet.
It's probably more likely
that I would say zip it.
I would probably say to my
kids, hey, zip it back there.
I'm trying to focus on my driving,
and all of the noise that you are making
is very, very distracting.
So in English, if you
wanted to yell something
to someone or a bunch of people,
because you wanted them to be quiet,
if you wanted something rude,
you could yell, shut up.
And if you wanted something
that's a little more friendly,
but still communicates
what you're trying to say.
You could say zip it.
I just said zip it to
my kids the other day.
We were in a traffic jam.
It was stop and go traffic,
and I really needed to concentrate.
And so I ended up saying to my kids,
hey, just zip it for a
little bit back there.
Dad is trying to concentrate.
As you can see, someone
is poking me with a stick,
and this is a little bit annoying.
This is aggravating.
If I wanted to yell at the
person who's doing this
that I wanted them to stop,
I would use the same three phrases
that you heard me use at
the beginning of the video.
I might say, quit it.
I might say, stop it.
Or I might say, cut it out.
All of those phrases
communicate to a person
that you want them to stop
doing what they're doing.
If you aren't comfortable yelling though,
because yelling is a little bit rude,
you can actually add the word please
at the beginning of a
couple of these phrases.
In a calm voice, you
could say, please stop it.
In a calm voice, you could
say, please cut it out.
But if you're really, really annoyed,
if it's really, really bothering you,
you would probably yell stop it,
or you would yell, cut it out.
Have you ever been using the bathroom,
and then realize that you
forgot to lock the door?
And then all of the sudden you
see the door start to open,
and someone's foot comes through the door
as they start to enter the room.
There are two phrases
that you should immediately
yell in English.
You should yell, get
out, or get out of here.
They both mean exactly the same thing,
and they will communicate to the person
that you want them to
stop entering the room,
and exit the room instead.
These two phrases, get
out and get out of here,
are phrases we yell in English when,
if we're in a place with someone else,
and we want them to leave.
And we want to communicate that strongly,
or like in the bathroom situation.
If someone is entering a
space where you want privacy,
you could yell, get
out, or get out of here.
In the case of the bathroom,
you should yell it
clearly, and forcefully,
and as quickly as possible,
because that would certainly be
a very embarrassing situation.
In life, we expect adults
to behave like adults.
We expect teenagers to
behave like teenagers,
but sometimes adults and
teenagers behave like children.
Sometimes they do things
that are childish.
In that situation, the phrase
you would yell at them,
if you were annoyed, would be grow up.
When we yell at someone
in English, grow up,
what we're saying is that
we think the way they are acting
is not appropriate for their age.
Little children sometimes
repeat what other people say
to be funny.
Sometimes at the supper table,
my youngest child will start to say
everything that everyone else says
immediately after they say it.
And it's kind of funny.
When adults do this, if I
went to a family reunion,
and my brother started to
repeat everything I said,
after I said it,
I would probably say,
grow up, stop doing that.
It's really, really annoying.
So if people act in a way
that you think is not
appropriate for their age,
you could say to them, or yell
at them in English, grow up.
Have you ever been ready to go somewhere,
but the people who are
going with you aren't ready?
Well, there's two phrases
you could yell in English to express this.
You could yell, come on, and
you could yell, let's go.
When you yell these phrases,
you're encouraging the
other people to hurry up,
to speed up, to get ready faster,
because you're ready to go.
I'm not going to comment
whether this happens in my family or not.
All I will say is that
I have used both these phrases recently,
and I've used them in exactly this manner.
I have yelled come on,
and I've yelled, let's go
to people who were going
to be going somewhere with
me, because I was ready,
I was in the van, and I was ready to go.
So come on, and let's go,
two phrases you can use
to communicate to other
people that you want them
to hurry up, because
you're ready to leave.
Well, there you go.
A few phrases that you can use in English
when you want to yell and
express how you are feeling,
or when you just need to yell,
so someone who's far away
from you can hear you.
Thank you so much for watching.
If this is your first time here,
don't forget to click that red
subscribe button over there,
and give me a thumbs up
if this video helped you learn
just a little bit more English.
And if you have some time,
why don't you stick around,
and watch another English lesson?
(bouncy music)