Hey, welcome to episode two of
the real life English series.
In today's episode, I am going to
teach you real English vocabulary,
real English expressions.
And I'm also going to teach you a fluency
pattern that you can use today and sound
more like a native English speaker.
When you request something.
I also have some quizzes just for you.
So I hope you're  ready.
All right.
I'm teacher
Tiffani. Let's jump right in.
All right.
So we're going to start off by looking at
a situation, a real life situation here.
We have a man and a woman sitting
together looking at their cell phones.
Now the woman is probably saying,
honey, you are more tech savvy than me.
Can you please show me how to work?
This new phone you bought?
Now, this is a very natural
conversation a very natural request
that this woman is making, but
what's the pattern that she used.
Let me show you the pattern she used.
She said his name or a
nickname, which is honey.
And I'll explain.
Then she gave the reason
or the current situation.
And finally she made her request.
She didn't just immediately
make the request.
She followed this
pattern and this formula.
Now I do want to explain something
to you really quickly, honey, you may
be asking teacher, what does honey?
Now honey is just a term of
endearment for someone you love.
So for example, my mother will
call my father, honey, or dear.
Likewise, my father will call
my mother, honey or dear.
So you can call your spouse,
your boyfriend, or your
girlfriend, honey, in English.
We say, honey, good job.
One more time after me, honey.
Excellent.
All right.
Now she also said something that
maybe you haven't heard before.
She said tech savvy after me tech savvy.
Excellent.
Now tech savvy just means well informed
about or good at using modern technology.
So maybe you are tech savvy.
Maybe you are really good at
using computers and cell phones
and other things you can say.
Ah, I'm tech savvy.
It makes sense right now, look again,
at what she said, she said, honey, the
name you are more tech savvy than me.
She's giving the reason
before she makes the request.
You're so good with technology right now.
The request comes.
Can you please show me, right.
So what about this last part work?
This, what does it mean to work something?
This is again a real English
expression, real life English.
Work something means to use something.
Right?
So for example, I have
my cell phone right here.
I am very familiar with my cell phone.
I know how to work it because
I've used it for a while.
So this individual was
telling her husband, Hey baby.
Hey honey, you're tech savvy.
You're really good with technology.
Can you please help me?
I don't know how to.
Makes sense.
Right?
So once again, looking at this image at
this situation, we have the pattern name
plus reason or situation plus the request.
And this is exactly how you
are going to use the pattern.
Now, let me quiz you and see if you
remember the words I just taught you.
Are you ready for our first quiz?
I hope you are.
Here we go.
All right, quiz number one.
Now you only have five
seconds for each question.
Here we go.
Now let's see.
The first question is right here.
I want you to fill in the blank.
Technology is a big part of life.
So little kids are very five seconds.
All right.
Time.
What is the answer?
Yes, you got it.
Exactly.
Little kids are.
Tech savvy makes sense.
Right?
A lot of kids, even my four
year old niece, she's really
good with technology tech savvy.
All right, let's see how you
do with question number two.
Here we go.
Question number two, fill in the blank.
He just bought a new, smart TV
for his office, but he doesn't
know how to what's the answer.
Five seconds.
Here we go.
Do do do, do all right time.
What's the answer.
Come on, you got it.
Exactly.
He doesn't know how to work
it or use it make sense.
Right.
Excellent job.
Excellent.
Now let's see another situation that
uses the pattern that we learned.
Here we go.
Here is the next situation.
We have again, what looks like a husband
and a wife now in this situation, the
woman is probably saying, Michael,
you know that you tower over me.
Would you put the meat on
the top shelf of the freezer?
Pretty please.
All right.
So we're seeing here that a request
is being made, but the woman
is using the fluency pattern.
Let me show you watch right.
She did.
What said his name?
Michael then gave the reason
Michael you tower over me now.
Wait a minute.
What does tower over me mean?
All right.
So tower over just means to be much
taller than someone or something.
The man in the picture is
much taller than the lady.
Actually, my brother-in-law
is about six, two or six.
He towers over us.
He's extremely tall.
So again, following the pattern, when
you're making a request name, then the
reason the woman said you tower over me.
You're so much taller than me.
Now.
It's time for the request.
She says, "Would put the meat
on the top shelf of the freezer?
Pretty please?"
Now, what does pretty please mean?
Again, real life English, English we use.
Here we go.
Pretty please actually means it's used to
ask someone for something or persuading
them to do something by sounding.
friendly.
That's right.
When you say, oh, pretty please,
you're trying to sound friendly.
You're trying to make them see that
I really need your help in English.
We do say pretty, please.
Now guys, you probably don't
want to say it, but women and
children, we do actually say it.
So we say pretty please
after me, pretty please.
Excellent.
Good job.
So she said pretty, please.
Now you already know what time it is.
It's time for your next quiz.
Let's see if you understood
exactly what we just went over.
All right.
So each question again,
remember you have five seconds.
So here is the first question, right?
Fill in the blank.
She likes short guys because tall
guys, usually her, you ready?
Five seconds.
What goes in the blank here?
Time.
All right.
So what goes in the blank?
I know you got it.
Yes, very good tower over her.
She likes short guys because
tall guys tower over her.
Excellent job.
Really good.
All right.
Now let's go to question number two.
Here we go.
Number two.
The little girl wanted ice cream.
What did she say to her mother?
She wanted ice cream.
What did she say?
Here we go.
Timer has started da, da, da time.
All right.
So what did the little girl say?
Come on.
I know.
Excellent.
She said pretty please.
Very good.
Excellent job.
All right.
So again, we had two situations where
the individuals followed the fluency
pattern for making a request, name,
reason or situation, and then the request.
Well, let's see if it happens
in this situation as well.
In this situation, we have a
woman and she's on the phone
and she's probably saying.
Hey, Susan, I'm trying to
knock out my resume, but it's
taking longer than I expected.
I know you are the resume guru.
So would you mind looking over
it for me now in this situation?
She, also used the fluency pattern.
Let me show it to you again.
The pattern name.
Hey, Susan.
Reason or situation.
I'm trying to knock out my resume, but
it's taking longer than I expected now.
That's the reason and her situation.
But what does knock out mean?
So knock out actually means to
complete or finish something.
So to knock something out, for
example, oh, I need to knock out dinner
before I go hang out with my friends.
I need to complete or make dinner.
Before I go out with my friends, we
say, knock out something in English.
Real life English, and
now you can also use it.
So she's trying to knock
out or complete her resume.
She also says it's taking
longer than I expected.
So what does longer than expected mean?
It means to take longer
than you initially.
Thought it would.
So she's giving the reason and
she's also giving her situation
before she makes her request.
This is how you speak
English in real life.
You don't just immediately
make your request.
You need to say the name.
Give the reason, our situation
and then make the request.
So now she's starting to make the
request after she says, I know you
are the resume guru, she then says, so
would you mind looking over it for me?
That's her request.
But what does it mean
to look over something?
Look over something just means to
review or check something for errors.
So she's asking her, Hey, I know you're
the resume guru, that's the situation.
And the reason would you mind
just kind of checking my resume.
That was the request.
So again, she followed the
pattern name plus reason or
situation, and then the request.
So, you know what time it is now,
it's time for your last quiz.
Let's see how you're going to do.
Here we go.
Now we have five questions for this quiz,
and I know that you are going to do well.
Here we go.
First.
Now it's a combination now
of everything you've learned.
My husband loves computers.
He is really what's the answer.
I'm gonna give you five seconds.
Here we go.
Five seconds.
You got it.
Her husband is what?
Come on.
I know you asked, you know, the answer.
Excellent tech savvy,
so good, excellent job.
Her husband is tech savvy.
Very, very good.
All right, now let's go
to question number two.
Here we go.
You're doing great.
So far question number two.
What is a term?
That a woman might use
to call her husband.
What's a term that a woman
might use to call her husband.
Here we go.
Five seconds.
All right.
What's the answer?
What's the term.
Come on.
Yes, honey.
Excellent.
A woman or a man would
call their spouse, honey.
Excellent job.
Real life English.
All right, here we go.
Question number three, the
basketball player is extremely tall.
He blank.
All of his fans.
Whoo.
What's this answer.
Come on.
You know it, five seconds.
Let me know the answer.
Here we go.
Time.
What's the answer.
Yes.
Excellent job.
He towers over all of his fans.
He's extremely tall.
Very good.
Excellent job.
All right, now let's go
to question number five.
Oh, number four, almost skipped one.
Here we go.
The little boy said he had to his homework
before he could play outside with them.
What's the answer.
Five seconds.
Here we go.
Five seconds on the clock time.
Come on.
What's the answer?
Tell me what the answer is.
Exactly.
He had to knock out or complete
his homework before he could
play outside with them.
Now, one more quiz question.
Come on.
You are doing such a great job.
I know you can get this one too.
Here we go.
Question number five.
He bought a new cell phone yesterday,
but he still doesn't know how to yet.
What's the answer.
Five seconds on the clock.
Here we go
time.
All right.
So tell me, come on.
What's the answer.
Yes.
He doesn't know how to work it yet.
Excellent job.
You are amazing.
You passed that quiz with flying colors.
All right.
So I really hope you
enjoyed today's lesson.
Remember we talked about the pattern.
This pattern will help you, and it will
show you how to speak English fluently.
When you want to make a request.
Remember.
Name second part, reason or situation,
and finally make your request.
Now, if you want to keep studying
with me, you can check me out
right here, right here, right here.
Uh, let's see.
Follow a plan by going to speak
English with Tiffani academy.com.
I have plans just for you and
you can join and become a member.
Or if you want to save
time, let's go right here.
Save time, go to study with Tiffani.com
and you can get my eBooks that are amazing
and will help you learn English fast.
Or you can go to English with Tiffani,
the app, start learning and have fun
again I hope you enjoyed today's lesson.
I will see you next week, but
as always remember, English
you still there.
You know what time it is?
It's story time.
Hey, I said it's story time.
Okay.
I have a good story for you today.
This is something that my
family talks about all the time.
I live in Maryland.
Okay.
And you all know how much I love food.
So in Maryland, there are a lot of west
Indians, people from Trinidad, people
from Jamaica and many other islands.
So we have amazing west
Indian food here in Maryland.
Now my family, we're not west Indian, but
we love west Indian food specifically.
Roti.
So the roti we like has
cabbage and potatoes and
garbanzo beans and vegetables.
It's delicious.
And all throughout my high school,
years and college, and even a little
bit after college, there was one
specific restaurant we used to go to.
It was called Caribbean delight.
It wasn't too far from my high school.
And the owner actually worked
with my mother at the hospital.
The restaurant was her side business.
When I say her roti was good.
Oh my goodness.
It would make you lick your fingers.
That's how good the roti was.
Now.
The thing is, my mom
knew the owner very well.
She was the cook.
She was the owner and
they were friends at work.
There was nothing wrong, but there was
one unique quality about this lady.
She did not play any games.
She was extremely serious.
And when you went to her restaurant, you
needed to know exactly what you wanted.
You need to know what your
request was because she didn't
have time for small talk.
So I remember one specific
time I was really craving.
I wanted to eat roti, so I drove
almost 30 minutes from my house just
to pick up some roti from a restaurant.
So I arrived at the restaurant and I
was going to make my request, right.
So I said her name and I
said, Hey, ma'am her name?
And then I won't say her name here.
And then, you know, I said, Hey, I'm here.
I really, really wanted
to eat some of your food.
So I want to order a roti.
You see name?
I told her why I came and then I made the.
But I had a question.
I usually just said what I wanted
and sat down and waited for it
to be given to me after I paid.
But I had a few questions.
I wanted to know if they
could add some vegetable.
So I asked her, I said, Hey, I just
wanted to know, can this be added?
And she looked at me...
"Baby, you get what you pay for.
She really did not want
anything changed on her menu.
Now she was not mean.
But she did not play games and
she did not want small talk.
So she said you want to roti?
You can't change anything.
So I said yes ma'am yes.
Ma'am.
I paid my money and I sat down
and I waited for my roti to come.
So I came home and I told my mom, I was
laughing because the food was so good
now in America, customer service is very
important just to help you understand.
So usually the customer's always right.
If a customer has something they want.
Then the person will kind of
adjust like at subway, you make
it your way and they do things.
So usually if you make a request,
you want some vegetable changed.
People will do that, but not this lady.
She said, you get what's on the
menu or you get nothing at all.
And we all continued to go to her
restaurant because her food was so good.
So we always have jokes about
her because she did not play.
Don't change the menu, get
whatever's on the menu.
And people loved her food.
Now she's no longer here.
She got sick, unfortunately.
And so we're not able to get her food
anymore, but we have these funny memories
of her because she did not really match
the typical American food culture.
She did not let you have what you wanted.
If you wanted to change anything, she
said, no, you get what's on the menu.
So maybe there are some people in
your country that are like that.
Just one way they won't change at all.
I hope you enjoyed this story, guys.
I hope you have an awesome week
and I will see you next time.
Don't forget to check me out.
If you want to keep studying
with me, love you all.
And I'll talk to you later.