How do you get back to speaking
English and English fluency?
After some time,
a way maybe you have some disruption or
problem or something big and exciting
and good happening in your life,
maybe something personal,
something work-related maybe
you moved across country and
English had to take a break.
Maybe at this moment in your
life. It wasn't a priority,
but now you're ready to get back in the
saddle,
which means to return
to your English fluency
goals. I'm Gabby from
go natural english.com.
I'm your American English teacher
and fluency coach here to help you
when you're ready to go back or return to
your English speaking practice. See,
I recently had to take a
break as well from making
English lessons because I
moved across the country.
And to be honest, I was overwhelmed,
but now I'm ready. I'm back.
And I am thrilled to be
here with this new lesson.
That's going to help you to understand
the three steps that you can
take to get back to your English speaking,
regardless of how long it's
been since you spoke English.
So if you're ready to start
speaking English again,
to start practicing and to improve
your English fluency little by little
together, then let's go. Let's
do this. Let's get fluent.
Keep watching until the end of this video,
because I'm going to share a resource
that I made for you with all of my
best English speaking
tips and practice ideas.
It's called the English fluency formula.
I'll tell you more about it at the end,
but first let's talk about the
best and easiest way to jump back
into English. Practice.
Find something fun.
Do you enjoy music? What about movies?
How about books or magazines?
When I want to return
to studying a language,
I always start with something
enjoyable, something light,
something fun for me. That's music.
So I am always working on my Portuguese.
So for example, I'll listen to a song,
maybe a Brazilian song
or a song from Portugal.
Something that is enjoyable to
me and I'll look at the lyrics.
I'll sing along and before I knew it,
I'm practicing my Portuguese,
but it's not so stressful.
I'm not putting so much
pressure on myself to do
it by the books or to go back to a class.
It can be just five or or 15
minutes of doing something
fun.
And this will help you to improve
your fluency quickly, easily,
and in a fun way. So what
is fun for you? Is it music?
Is it a podcast, a movie, something else,
maybe journaling in English.
I would love to know what you consider
to be the most fun activity in
English. Next.
I want to encourage you to take
15 minutes and think about,
or remember your goals
for English speaking.
Because when you remember
why you want English fluency,
maybe for a better job to advance
your career, to make more money,
maybe to work or travel
abroad or even remotely online
nowadays,
why do you want to speak English fluently?
When you remember your reasons,
really your deep down personal reasons,
nobody else's reason, just yours.
This is what will motivate
you to return to your
English practice. Next, you
want to gather your tools.
What do I mean tools are your
materials that help you to learn
English? So this could
be an English textbook.
If you want to learn in a more traditional
way or an English class in person
or online, it could be
videos like this one.
Maybe you bookmark the go natural
English channel or the go natural
english.com website as a
resource to help you learn.
It's important to have
materials to help you learn.
So if you want suggestions on
what materials would be helpful,
just ask in the comments. And of
course, as you probably already know,
there are hundreds of English
lessons over@gonaturalenglish.com.
So we have your materials.
Now we need a plan.
What are you going to do with
these materials? Unfortunately,
it's not enough just to
buy an English textbook.
We actually have to open it.
We actually have to read it.
It's not enough to just subscribe
to go natural English on YouTube.
We actually have to watch
the videos, practice,
ask questions and internalize the lessons.
Maybe review them a few times in
order to really remember what you are
learning. Be patient with yourself.
Learning takes time and repetition,
but it's important to have a
plan. So let's think about it.
How often and for how long each time can
you practice your English speaking
in what situations do you prefer
to study in a classroom or
from home or on your own?
What is your favorite way?
How do you want to learn English?
I think we're so lucky to be living in
a time where we have so many resources
at our fingertips and the ability to learn
independently more now than ever.
So let's take advantage of it.
Now you have your materials and you've
thought about how you're going to get
back into learning English.
There's one last thing I want
to encourage you to think about,
which is who is going to help you.
Who's going to keep you accountable. Now.
I personally have some fun ways
of keeping myself accountable.
For example, yesterday, I was doing
some work that wasn't really fun,
but I had to do it. And I
told myself, I said, Gabby,
if you finish this work,
you get to eat ice cream.
I know it's really silly. It's
I mean, it's just ice cream,
but that made me really excited to finish
the work so that I could treat myself
afterwards. Maybe for you it's ice cream,
maybe for you, it's something else.
Something else that you
enjoy doing or eating,
or maybe some exercise or
time with your friends or just
something fun that you enjoy after
doing the work or the practice that
may not be as fun because let's be
honest. We can start with something fun.
Like I mentioned for the first
tip, but in order to learn,
you're going to have some challenges.
You're going to make mistakes.
You're going to have to push
through them and do the work,
focus on your goals to get
you through those challenges
and treat yourself along the
way. When you do the thing,
maybe it's grammar, maybe
it's speaking practice,
maybe it's working on your pronunciation.
What is your biggest challenge in English?
When you work on those
points, then treat yourself,
reward yourself.
And that's a great way to stay
motivated and get the work done so
you can keep yourself accountable.
But sometimes it's hard.
Let's be honest.
Self discipline is one of the most
difficult skills ever in life.
So you may want to consider
a tutor, a teacher, a coach,
to help you along the way.
Who do you want that to be?
I'm not trying to tell you it
should be me, but it could be.
You can certainly learn with
us@gonaturalenglish.com.
So let's review to get back to return to
your English learning.
We need three things.
I suggest starting with something fun.
And then you need to gather materials.
You need to make a plan and
find the person who's going to
keep you accountable and
cheer you on or motivate you
throughout your learning.
So if you think that this is a good
way to get back into English learning,
or if you have something to add, then
please let me know in the comments.
And I promised that I would tell you.
About the English fluency formula
online ebook that can help you
as a guide to returning
to your English studies.
It's not like a traditional textbook
it's short and really easy to read,
but it gives you suggestions
about where to focus,
what to study and how to
practice your English speaking.
So if you'd like to know more
about it and get your online copy
today, go to go.
Natural english.com/ebook.
Thank you so much for watching.
Thank you for being here for
my return to YouTube English
lessons. Thank you. Thank you. Thank
you. And I will see you again soon.
It won't be so long
this time. Bye for now.