OUR NEXT GUEST IS PROFESSOR OF
SCIENCE AND SOCIETY, AT THE
IMPERIAL COLLEGE IN LONDON, HE
HOLDS 23 HONOREE DOCTORATES AND
THE AUTHOR OF THIS BRILLIANT NEW
BOOK, MY AMAZING BODY MACHINE.
PLEASE WELCOME OUR GOOD FRIEND
PROFESSOR THE LORD ROBERT
WINSTON.
THANK YOU FOR COMING BACK TO SEE
US.
WE LOVE IT WHEN YOU STOP BY.
ALL RIGHT.
SO ROBERT, WE ARE READY, WE'RE
IN THE ZONE.
LET'S GET OUR SCIENCE ON.
WHAT ARE WE GOING TO BE DOING
FIRST.
>> LET'S START WITH THE THING AT
THE END.
>> James: WITH THIS.
>> COME AROUND.
>> James: OKAY.
>> SO BASICALLY YOU HAVE GOT
QUITE A SMART WHITE COAT ON.
>> James: YES, I'M A
SCIENTIST.
>> IT'S TOO SMART.
>> James: WHAT?
ROBERT.
WHAT IS.
>> LOOK, YOU ARE A BIT BLUER.
THAT SUIT ISN'T WORTH ANYTHING,
IS IT?
>> James: WELL, IT'S WORTH A
LITTLE BIT, YEAH.
>> THIS IS A SOLUTION TO DRY
CLEANING.
>> James: RIGHT.
>> THAT WAS ALKALI.
AND IT IS BLUE BECAUSE IT HAS A
BLUE DIE IN IT AND WE ARE GOING
TO SKIRT YOU WITH ACID TO
NEUTRALIZE IT.
>> James: HANG ON.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN.
LOOK AT THAT?
LOOK.
AND THEN IT.
>> IT'S RUBBISH.
THIS IS CARBON DIE OXIDE, SO
CARBONIC ACID IS ACTUALLY MUCH
MORE EFFECTIVE.
>> James: OKAY.
LET ME STAND WELL BACK.
NOW WAIT FOR THE REACTION.
LOOK, ALMOST CLEAN.
(APPLAUSE).
>> James: RIGHT, I FEEL LIKE
THIS ISN'T EVEN A SCIENCE THING,
YOU'VE JUST COME UP WITH SOME
WAY TO DO THAT TO ME.
THAT'S PRETTY INCREDIBLE.
THAT'S AMAZING.
IT'S JUST GONE.
I MEAN IT'S FREEZING COLD, I
WILL GIVE IT THAT.
WHAT ELSE HAVE YOU GOTS FOR US,
WHAT ELSE.
>> LET ME SEE, WE'VE GOT THIS.
>> James: WHAT IS THAT?
>> THAT IS LACAPODIUM POWDER.
AND ST QUITE EXPLOSIVE.
SO YOU CAN-- DO YOU WANT TO TRY
LIGHTING IT.
>> James: NO.
>> GO ON.
>> James: WHEN YOU SAY QUITE
EXPLOSIVE, WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
ON A SCALE OF ONE TO TEN, HOW
EXPLOSIVE IS THIS.
>> SEVEN.
(LAUGHTER).
>> James: THAT FEELS A LOT.
RIGHT.
WHAT AM I DOING, JUST LIGHTING
THIS.
>> THESE ARE EXCEPTIONALLY FINE
PARTICLES THEY ARE ABOUT
1,000th MILL MEETER ACROSS.
ALL PACKED TOGETHER.
THEY COME FROM A PLANT CALLED
LACAPODIUM.
AND IT'S A MOSS AND IT'S USED BY
ALL SORTS OF HOMEOPO, THIS IS TO
CURE DIARRHEA, SUPPOSED TO BE AN
APHRODISIA BUT IT ALSO IS
EXPLOSIVE.
>> James: IT CURES DIARRHEA
AND IS ALSO AN APHRODISIAC.
>> IT IS HOMOPATHIC SO IT
PROBABLY DOESN'T WORK.
>> James: SO WHAT IS GOING TO
HAPPEN WHEN I LIGHT THIS.
>> LET'S JUST HAVE A LOOK.
>> IT'S NOT VERY IMPRESSIVE, IS
IT?
>> James: WELL, I MEAN, IS
THAT IT?
>> YOU SEE, IT'S A VERY FINE
POWDER.
I WILL SHOW YOU HOW FINE IT IS.
IF WE PUT IT IN THIS WATER.
>> James: YEAH, PUT IT ON
WATER, THAT WILL SET IT ON FIRE,
ROBERT.
I MEAN WHO IS THE SCIENTIST.
>> IT'S HIDE DRO PHOBIC NOW.
THIS ISN'T TERRIBLY POISONOUS SO
PUT YOUR FINGER THROUGH THAT
DUST.
>> James: WHEN YOU SAY
TERRIBLY POISONOUS, I WANT IT TO
BE NOT POISONOUS OR POISONNIST
ONCE PUT YOUR PING-- FINGER IN.
>> James: REALLY, ARE YOU
SURE.
>> YES.
GENTLY.
NO, NO, THROUGH THE POWDER, NOT
IN THE WATER.
>> James: WHAT DO YOU MEAN.
>> LIKE THAT.
>> James: OH, LOOK, OH, WOW.
>> SO BASICALLY IT IS COMPLETELY
DRY.
>> James: YEAH.
>> BECAUSE IT IS PROTECTING MY
FINGER AGAINST THE WATER BECAUSE
OF THE SURFACE TENSION.
NOW WHAT WE ARE GOING TO DO.
WE WILL MAKE SOMETHING A LITTLE
BIT MORE CHALLENGING.
>> James: OKAY.
>> I'VE GOT SOME OF THE POWDER
IN THIS SHOE.
AND I WANT YOU TO BE ABSOLUTELY,
YOU MUST PROMISE ME.
>> James: YES.
>> THAT YOU WILL BLOW INTO THIS
SHOE AND NOT SUCK IT.
>> James: SURE, YES.
>> HOLD IT LIKE THAT.
>> James: I HAVE DONE THIS AT
THE SIDE OF THE ROW BEFORE.
>> James: PUT YOUR GOGGLES ON.
>> OKAY.
>> James: ALL RIGHT.
>> I'M GOING IT LIGHT THIS
THING.
>> James: YEAH.
>> AND YOU'RE GOING TO BLOW, NOT
TOO HARD, FAIRLY CONTINUOUSLY
GENTLY AND I AM GOING TO TRY AND
SET THE WHOLE THEATER UPON FIRE.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT, DON'T DO IT
UNTIL I TELL YOU.
>> James: DON'T WORRY, I'M IN
NO RUSH.
>> GO.
(APPLAUSE)
>> SO BASICALLY THAT WORKS CUZ
THOSE PARTICLES, THOSE LITTLE
SEEDS ARE FULL OF FAT.
>> James: YEAH.
>> AND THAT FAT IGNITES AND WHEN
THE PARTICLES ARE MIXING WITH
OXYGEN AND SEPARATED FROM EACH
OTHER THEY CAN OXIDIZE, THEY CAN
BURN.
>> James: THAT'S AMAZING.
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT FOR US NOW,
WHAT HAVE WE GOT HERE.
>> COME ON THE FRONT.
>> James: OKAY.
ALL RIGHT.
>> WATCH THESE TWO BA BE LOOS.
ONE HAS BEEN BLOWN UP WITH
ORDINARY AIR.
>> James: WHAT IS IN THAT ONE.
>> THAT ONE IS REALLY HEAVY.
>> James: YES STRKS.
WHAT IS IN THERE.
>> PICK IT UP AND SEE T IS
SULFUR HEXO FLOUR IDENTIFY WHICH
IS ONE THE HEAVIEST GASES
AVAILABLE, ABOUT SIX TIMES
HEAVIER THAN ATMOSPHERIC AIR.
>> James: RIGHT.
>> WHAT I WANT YOU TO DO BECAUSE
IT IS A VERY, VERY DENSE GAS BUT
NOT UNTIL I TELL YOU.
>> James: OKAY.
>> I WANT YOU TO INHALE IT, AND
THEN-- .
>> James: I DON'T THINK IT'S
THAT SORT OF BALLOON, REG.
GO ON.
YOU WANT ME TO INHALE IT.
>> I WANT TO YOU INHALE IT BUT
YOU MUSTANT INHALE TOO MUCH OF
IT BECAUSE IT WILL FILL YOUR
LUNGS AND DISPLACE ALL THE
OXYGEN AND THAT MIGHT BE A BIT
SAD, REALLY.
>> James: ALL RIGHT, OKAY,
HANG ON.
>>S THAT A ENOUGH.
>> James: OKAY.
OH MY GOD.
OARKSZ MY GOD.
THAT IS RIDICULOUS.
I'M NOT EVEN PUTTING A VOICE ON
MY VOICE.
IS I SOUND LIKE THE STAR OF THE
RUN SO HARD.
>> PLEASE CUFF.
>> James: HOW LONG WILL IT
STAY LIKE THIS, HOW LONG WILL IT
STAY LIKE THIS.
WHEN DOES IT.
>> BREATHE.
>> James: WHEN WILL IT COME
BACK.
>> GIVE IT TO REGGIE, HIS VOICE
IS-- .
>> James: ARE YOU GOING TO DO
SOME REG, ARE YOU?
OKAY.
GO ON.
>> James: I FEEL LIKE MINE IS
COMING BACK.
HAS IT COME BACK OR HAVE I GOT
USED TO IT.
OKAY, REG, NOT TOO MUCH.
>> Reggie: EVERYBODY'S GOT IT
GOING DOWN TO THE STORE AND BUY
SOME-- EVERYBODY NEEDS A LITTLE
CABBAGES, WHAT, IT'S LIKE
INHALING FREEON.
YOU KNOW WHAT, I FEEL LIKE
PUTTING LOTION IN THE BATHROOM.
>> WE HAVE TO MOVE ON.
>> James: ALL RIGHT, WHAT IS
NEXT, WHAT IS NEXT, ROBERT.
>> I THINK WE'RE GOING TO WEAR
PROTECTIVE GEAR, WOULD YOU LIKE
TO PUT THE HELMETS ON.
>> James: ABSOLUTELY.
>> HAND ME THE OTHER ONE.
>> James: THERE YOU G THERE IS
YOUR HELMET AND GLOVES AS WELL.
>> THAT WOULD BE A VERY GOOD
IDEA.
>> James: OKAY.
THERE YOU GO.
>> I GOT IT.
>> James: THERE YOU ARE.
>> RIGHT, OKAY.
>> James: OKAY.
I'VE ALWAYS HAD YOU WORRIED WHEN
YOU COME DOWN AND MAKE US PUT
GLOVES ON WEST LAST TIME YOU
POURED LIQUID NIGHT RO AGAIN ON
MY AGAIN TALES, I REMEMBER.
>> James: YEAH, AND I FEEL
LIKE TODAY'S EXPERIMENT HAS JUST
BEEN ONE LONG YOU TRYING TO GET
BACK AT ME FOR THAT MOMENT.
I DISN DO IT ON PURPOSE.
OKAY.
SO WHAT ARE WE DOING.
>> YOU HAVE SOME GLUE GUN THERE.
>> James: THE ONES ON THE
BOTTOM.
>> YEAH.
YOU PUT ONE THERE,.
>> James: ALL RIGHT.
>> NOW HAVE I SOME LIQUID NIGHT
RO AGAIN, QUITE A LOT OF IT.
>> James: OKAY, ONE EACH IS
IT, THIS ONE.
>> YEAH, OKAY.
AND BEFORE WE POUR IT IN THERE.
>> James: YEAH.
>> WE'RE GOING TO PUT THESE ON
THE BENCH.
>> James: OKAY.
JUST PUT THEM THERE,.
>> James: WHAT IS IN HERE.
>> WELL,.
>> James: IT ALREADY FEELS
DANGEROUS.
>> NOT A LOT.
>> James: OKAY SO WHAT ARE WE
TRYING TO DO HERE, ROBERT.
WHAT ARE WE AIMING FOR.
>> WE WILL TAKE THE LIQUID NIGHT
RO AGAIN.
>> James: THIS IS WHEN WE NEED
THESE ON.
>> WE WILL IN A SECTION.
>> James: OKAY.
>> ALL RIGHT.
I FEEL LIKE I'M IN BREAKING
BALD.
NOW WHAT.
>> TAKE YOUR LIQUID NIGHT RO
AGAIN AND POUR IT RAPIDLY INTO
THE-- .
>> James: IN HERE?
>> YEP.
>> James: HOW MUCH.
>> AS MUCH AS YOU CAN, A LOT.
>> James: I CAN'T REALLY SEE
THE TOP SO-- Z IT REALLY IS LIKE
A GUESSTIMATE.
>> TRY NOT TO GET IT ON YOUR
SHOES.
>> James: OKAY, THANKS FOR
TELLING ME THAT JUST AS I GET TO
THE BOTTOM OF IT.
OKAY, I THINK THAT'S ALL OF IT.
>> YEP, LEVLY.
>> James: ALL RIGHT, OKAY NOW,
SO THIS IS JUST VERY HOT WATER.
>> James: RIGHT.
>> TAKE THE LID OFF.
HOLD IT IN BOTH HANDS.
>> James: OKAY.
>> AND SIMULTANEOUSLY WHEN WE
SAY ONE, TWO, THREE ON THE THIRD
BEAT DROP IT.
>> James: OKAY.
>> ONE, TWO, THREE.
>> James: GO.
WHOA!
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
OH MY WORD!
PROVE CERTIFICATE ROB RTD
WINSTON, WE WILL BE RIGHT BACK.
THAT WAS AMAZING.