Love me like you do
Love, love, love me like you do
Touch me like you do, t-t, touch me like you do
Love me like you do, La La, love me like you do
You're the light, you're the night, you're the colour of my blood
You're the cure, you're the pain
You're the only thing I want to touch
I don't wanna be needing your love
Never knew that it could mean so much
I just wanna be deep in your love (so much)
You're the fear, I don't care, 'cause I've never been so high
Follow me, through the dark, let me take you past our satellites
Cause I really don't care where you are
You can see the world you brought to life
I just wanna be there where you are (to life)
Your sugar
Love me like you do (yes please), lo-lo-love me like you do
Won't you come and put it down on me (lo-lo-love me like you do)
I'm right here, 'cause I need
Little love and little sympathy
I'm hurting baby
I'm broken down
I need your loving, your loving I need it now
When i'm without you
I'm something weak
You got me begging, I'm begging I'm on my knees
I'l let you set the pace
How can we not talk 'bout family when family's all that we got
Everything i will do, you'll be standin' by my side
And now you gonna be with me for the last ride
Its been a long day, without you, my friend
And I'll tell ya all about it (Touch me like you do, to-to-touch me like you do)
When I see you again
We've come a long way
From where we began
Oh, I'll tell you all about it when I see you again
Woah oh oh, Woah oh oh oh oh oh oh
So let the light guide
Your way
Yeh
Hold every memory as you go
And every road you take
Will always lead you home
Home
Ho-ome
Love me like you do
Love, love, love me like you do
A-sugar, yes please
It's been a long day,
Without you my friend
Yeah you showed me good lovin’, make it all right
And I'll tell you all about it when I see you again
When I see you again