What's wrong? Yeah, I know. I have a toothache.
It hurts. I have to go to the dentist. What's
a "dentist"? A "dentist" is a tooth doctor. Do
you hate going to the dentist? I love going
to the dentist. I don't know why. Ever since
I was a child, I have absolutely loved going
to the dentist. Maybe because my dentist gave
me stickers to play with or something to take
home, I don't know. I've just never been afraid
of the dentist. I always thought that it was
really cool to see all the tools that the
dentists use and put them in my mouth. I was
a strange child. Not much has
changed except I've gotten bigger.
My name is Ronnie. Today, I'm going to teach you
about going to the dentist. Oh, the torture.
Oh, the pain. Oh, the fear. Oh, the fun. I'm
going to teach you some basic vocabulary that
you need to know if you go
to the beautiful dentist.
First of all, we have English singular and plural.
So, singular is one "tooth". So you
can say, "My tooth hurts", or "I have a toothache"
-- singular, "tooth". So "tooth" means one.
If you want to talk about more than one tooth, you
would say "teeth". Now, ladies and gentlemen,
boys and girls, please be very careful with
your pronunciation of the word "teeth" and
"tooth", especially "teeth". If you do not
stick your tongue out and say "teeth", it
sounds like you say "tits", "tits". It sounds
like you say "tits". Don't say that. So: "tooth"
and "teeth". You must stick out your tongue to
get the pronunciation of this word correct.
The next word you might know already, but thing
this is strange, and think, "Gum? Chewing
gum? What? What? What is -- dentist? Chewing?
No, I don't know. I don't get it." "Gums"
are basically the pink -- can you get in there?
-- the pink part above your teeth. So if this
is a picture of my black teeth, I have a pink
tissue above my mouth -- or in my mouth
-- that surrounds my teeth like this, and these are called "gums".
It is always plural. We don't
say "gum". We don't say "my gum", we say "gums".
So in your mouth, hopefully you have teeth.
Some of you might not have all of your beautiful
teeth, but that's okay. Don't worry. You have
your teeth, and you have gums.
So "gums" is the pink part here.
Sometimes your tooth is sore. So you might say,
"Oh, my tooth is sore. I have a toothache."
Say this with me: "Toothache. Toothache. I have
a toothache." That means there's something
wrong with your tooth. It's causing you pain.
Uh-oh! Most of the time, the reason why you
have a toothache is because you have a cavity -- "cavity".
Now, "cavity" is simply a hole
in your tooth. So this is a beautiful, red,
healthy tooth, and what happens is a cavity
makes a hole in your tooth, and it begins
to rot right down to the root or the vein
in your tooth, and that causes you pain. So
a "cavity" basically just means a hole in
your tooth. And because this is rotting away,
it causes pain in the nerve in your mouth,
causing you to get a toothache: not a
good feeling, not a good situation.
Unfortunately, the dentist is very expensive
in Canada, so I recommend that you brush your
teeth at least two times a day -- to help
with the bad breath as well. You may have
done a lesson on bad habits, bad breath. We
don't like that. One of the reasons you may
have bad breath -- or someone, not
you -- is because you have a cavity.
So what you're going to do is you're going
to call the dentist. You are going to make
an appointment. Now, you might have noticed
that I have written n-n-v-v-v-n-n-n-n-n-n-n-n;
"n" means "noun". So this means it is a noun,
and "v" means "verb". So what's going to happen
is you're going to call the dentist's office,
and you are going to "make an appointment".
"Make" is a verb, so you're going to call and
make an appointment. The dentist's receptionist
is going to say, "tomorrow at seven." -"No." They
will arrange a time for you. I know sometimes
talking on the telephone is difficult, so if
you can communicate with a dentist through
email, or if you can actually go to a dentist
office, it will be easier for you. But
it doesn't matter if you call, email, or go there.
You're going to make an appointment. What's
going to happen is the doctor is going to
give you a check-up -- or the dentist, sorry.
The tooth doctor is going to give you a "check-up".
This just means he or she will check your
teeth -- check if they're healthy; make sure
you don't have any cavities; make sure your
gums are okay. They may even give you an X-ray.
That's very expensive too. An "X-ray" is a
picture of the bone structure in your mouth.
The X-ray lets the doctor know any additional
things -- cavities you can't see on an X-ray,
but if there's inflammation or something wrong
with the inside of your teeth, the
X-ray will show the dentist this.
Then it's time for the drill. If you have a
cavity, the dentist is going to take a drill...
Now, you may know the word "drill". Let's say
you wanted to hang something in your apartment.
You're going to take a screw and a machine --
that doesn't look like a drill, but that's
okay. And, basically, a "drill" is going to
make a bigger hole in your tooth. Guess what:
This really, really, really hurts. So it's
like taking a hammer or an electrical thing
and going "aah" and drilling your tooth. They
usual give you some kind of help. They usually
give you some kind of drugs or medicine so
you don't feel the drill going in. So what
happens is they take their beautiful dentist
drill; they drill a hole; and they drill all
the bad stuff out of your cavity. Then
they take what's called a "filling".
I forgot to write this down. A "filling" basically
fills your cavity with usually a white or
sometimes silver -- gold if you're really,
really, really rich -- compound and it stops
the hole or it stops the cavity from growing.
So they drill, and then they fill or they
put in a filling to cover your tooth. The
next thing that they're going to do is
they're going to have to put a cap on your
tooth so that food or foreign objects, like
an airplane, doesn't go back into your tooth.
So a "cap" is basically like a lid or a hat.
It's a tooth hat. It's a hat for your tooth
to protect it from all the drilling. So a
"cap" is what happens at the end after the drilling.
After the filling, you get a beautiful
cap. Maybe -- when you
go for your check-up or
your appointment -- you don't have a cavity.
Yay! What they will do is they will clean
your teeth. They usually use a fluoride solution,
and they scrape all the dirty stuff off your
teeth. This is called "tartar". Oh, not "tarnar".
Excuse me. So this is called "tartar", and
it's basically a build-up of dirty, dirty,
dirty stuff on your teeth. So they scrape
it so your teeth are nice and clean. Maybe
there is no help for your tooth. Maybe
the cavity has eaten all of your tooth, and
your teeth -- tooth needs to be taken out.
What happens in this case is you have two options.
You can get an implant. Do you know
another place you can get implants? An "implant"
means a -- basically, a fake tooth. So they
put another drill in your mouth, and they're
going to put, like, a nail or a screw, and
they just put a fake tooth, and they screw it
into your mouth. It looks real. It's wonderful.
Not -- did I forget to mention that the doctor
is very, very, very expensive and painful?
Or the other option you could go with is a
false tooth, or plural, false teeth. A lot
of older ladies and gentlemen have false teeth.
You can take them out -- scare the grandkids.
So you have options. If you have money, you
can have beautiful new teeth. No one will
ever know you had a cavity. Go to YouTube.
Subscribe to my lessons.
Go to www.engvid.com. Leave me a comment. Tell
me if you like or hate the dentist and why.
Don't forget: Brush your teeth. Goodbye.