Hi. My name's Ronnie, and I have a bottle
of water. What? So, sometimes when I go to
a restaurant and I order water, people don't understand me.
I'm in Canada, I'm speaking English, and I said:
"Water", and they look at me strange. And I go: -"Oh, you know? Water?"
-"Oh, water. Yes, water." -"No, no. It's water."
It's a t, right? W-a-t-e-r. This, in Canada,
we call a bottle of water. And I go: "Oh,
that's really crazy because it's a bottle
of water."
Now, I get called out all the time on having
an accent. Everyone has an accent. You have
an accent, depending on where you're from.
Everyone has an accent. So, first of all,
I hate people who go: -"Oh, I don't got an
accent." -"Oh, mister, you have an accent.
Okay?" Everyone has an accent, and I'm going
to teach you how to improve yours or damaged
English-I don't know-to speak with an American/Canadian
accent. Oh my god. Where's this going?
So, I'm going to teach you a trick, and the
trick is about the "t". I am very excited
about this because I've been thinking about
this for, oh, maybe ten years. Why do Canadians
and Americans say "d"? It's a "t". I found
the reason, and I'm going to teach you.
Let's have some water, shall we?
We have three... four. I'm good at counting,
again. We have four rules. Okay? So, the "t"
pronunciation. Sometimes, as I told you,
we actually say the "t" like a "d". So, this
is the rule. Rule number one: If it's between...
If the "t" is between two vowel sounds. So,
check this out. This "i" is a vowel, and "y"-sneaky
bugger-sometimes is a vowel, but it's a vowel
sound. So, we don't say: "ability" in Canadian
and American English; we say: "abilidy". That's
really strange, people. Canadians, Americans,
maybe you were drunk or cold when you were
doing this. I'm not too sure,
but just nonsensical, really.
We don't say: "computer", as we should; we
say: "compuder". Hey, look at that computer,
eh? So Canadian to say "eh" at the end. So,
again, between two vowels-"u" and "e" are
vowels-we're going to pronounce it like: "compuder".
This is crazy.
The next one, as I said in the beginning:
"water". "a", "e" are vowels, and it's going
to be said like: "wader". When I was in Jamaica,
they said: "wata", and I was like: "Yes! Good.
Got it." Again, so what I've done to help
you-you're welcome-is I've just underlined
the vowel. So, "a", "e"; "e", "e"; "er", "er",
"er", "er". And again, this one, watch out:
"i" and "y". "y" is a vowel sound.
So, all of these guys, magically, you're going
to go from speaking your language to speaking
Canadian and American English with the crazy
accent, because we say: "header". The thing
that keeps you warm... Canada's cold in the
winter. We don't say: "heater"; we say: "header".
And this is even more confusing now, because
it looks like "header", but it's actually
this pronunciation: "heeder". Turn on the
heater, eh? It's cold.
This word, if you say it... Not "better" in
my books. If you say it with a Canadian/American
pronunciation; crazy way; we say: "bedder".
Then we say: "madder". And then, even though
we went to "university", we say: "universidy".
Eh? You following? I don't know why it's crazy.
Just say the "t" or write the "d".
The other rule with the "t" sounding like
a "d" is if it's between a vowel and an "l"
or an "r". So, as I said in the beginning...
I can't even say it. "Bottle". It's not a
bottle, Ronnie. So, if it's between an "o"
and an "l", it's going to be said like a "d",
so we say: "boddle". This is my vowel "a",
and this is an "l".
We don't say: "battle"; we say: "baddle".
Into battle, soldiers. One of Ronnie's favourite
words: "dirty". So, we don't say "dirty" because
we have an "r" and a vowel sound. So, this
is the example of a vowel and an "l"; this
is the example of a vowel and an "r". Okay?
So, a vowel and "l"; a vowel and "r". With
our numbers, again, we have a vowel and an
"r", so these ones are going to sound like
a "d". So, we're going to say: "dirdy", "fordy",
and "thirdy".
Have you turned thirty yet? As a joke, we
like to say... Or some people like to say:
"It's my dirty 30." We won't go into detail
with that. About that. I will let your imaginations
run wild on that one. And just make sure you
say: "dirdy" because no one is going to understand
you if you say "dirty". You're a dirty, wee
cow.
Next up. There are some cases-three of them-when
we don't even say the "t". Maybe this is easier.
No, it's not easier. So, we do two things.
First of all, we could change it to a "d"
and then we just completely take it out because
we don't it. We don't want that "t"; that
pesky "t". So, if your "t" comes after an
"n", it's going to be silent. This is mental.
So, we don't say: "interview"; we say: "in'erview".
I got a job interview. That was from... rednecks
represent. So, we say: "in'erview".
We don't say: "interstate"; we say: "in'erstate".
In case you don't know, an interstate in America
is a highway. We do not call them interstates
in Canada; we call them highways. That's fun.
So, interstate is only in America. America.
Welcome to America.
We also have the word "international". So,
if you're an international person, we're going
to take out the "t" and we're going to say...
"international" becomes "in'ernational". There
are many of these. As I said: "want", we say:
"wan'ed". So, all of these, we take out the "t".
This is a fun one. You'll hear people say:
-"I don' know. I don' know." -"What?" -"Don't
know." So, we take out the "t"; we say: "don'
know". This is another reason why "can't"
is confusing. When we say: "cannot"... "Can",
"can't". -"Did you say the 't'?" -"No." -"Oh.
Why didn't you say the 't'? Now I don't know
if it's positive or negative. What are you
doing?" So, we say: "don' know. I don' know."
We don't say: "printer"; we say: "prin'er".
We don't say: "enter"; we say: "en'er". The
number "twenty" we don't say; we say "twen'y".
So, check out our numbers: "twenty", "forty",
"thirty". Yeah, I don't know how we count
here. Don't count; math is crazy.
Rule number three, and this one's crazy as
well. We're going to change two things. First
of all, we are not going to say the "t" if
it is with an "n" and between some vowels;
and we're going to actually take out some
vowel sounds. So, for this one, we're going
to remove two sounds. As an example, we don't
say: "curtain", which it looks like; we actually
say: "cur'in". A curtain is a cover for your
window. So, people might say: "Close the cur'in",
which we said it looks like: "Close the curtain."
You're going to go climb up a "mountain"?
No. You're going to climb up a "mou'in". These
vowels, we're going to take out the "t" and
the "a", and it's going to sound like "mou'in",
"cur'in". Another example of the "a" is we
don't say: "fountain"; we say: "fou'in". It's
an example with the "e": We don't say: "written"-I
do-but we actually say: "wri'in", so we take
out the "t" and the "e", and we change it
to an "in". We don't say: "forgotten"; we
say: "forgo'in". I've forgotten how to say
the "t". I've forgotten to say the "t".
This word is crazy; I always spell it wrong.
I always spell it: "sentance", but the pronunciation,
quickly, is: "sentence". My brain goes: "sentance";
but Americans and Canadians say: "sen'ince".
There's a phrase that people say about English
is that we eat our words or we mumble. This
is why, when you guys listen to English, you
think that we're very hungry and we're eating
our words, because we don't say everything.
[Mumbles] -"Make a sentence." -"What?" -"Sentence."
-"Oh." So, this one: "sen'ince". Again, the
"t" and the "e", we're going to put to "in",
so we're going to say: "sen'ince".
The last one, and maybe the most delicious
for us, because we're eating all of these,
is the "t" at the end of the word - we don't
say it. Sorry, we don't say it. We don't say
it. We don't say it. We don't say it. So,
if your "t" is at the end of the word in English
pronunciation, it actually has a fancy name;
it's called a stopped sound. So, a stopped
sound just means we don't say the "t".
So, we look at this and we say: "hot". And
then you come to Canada and America, and people
say: "ho'". What? "I'm ho'." So, we're going
to take out the "t"; we're going to say: "ho'".
For this one, something you wear on your head,
we're going to say: "ha'", "ha'". Something
on the floor is called a "mat" or also a person's
name. There are many people, many men named
Matthew; it gets shortened to "Matt", but
we don't say "Matt"; we say: "Ma'". "Ma',
ma'"; maybe he's a goat.
This word: If somebody has a lot of weight,
we don't say: "fat"; we say: "fa'". A group
or a parcel of land is called a "lo'"; not
a "lot". There's a pesky animal, it's a rodent,
and it's called a "ra'"; not a "rat". So,
all of these ones... Here's another example.
We don't say: "foot"; we say: "foo'". Foot,
foot, foot. It sounds like we're not saying
the "t".
I've said this before: "want", "wanna". We
don't say: "want"; we say: "wan'. I wan'".
"I want" - we don't say the "t". "Si' down.
Si' down." We don't say: "Sit down"; we say:
"Si' down". And don't smoke it; it's "pot".
So, when we say the word "pot", we don't say
the "t". English; craziness.
Now, if you're studying English in another
country-Australia, England, Ireland, Scotland,
Wales, anywhere that's not Canada or America-you
don't have to worry about this, but it will
help you perfect your American accent. So,
if you want to practice speakin' like an American,
all you have to do is watch out for these
four rules; between two vowel sounds, or between
a vowel and "l" or "r", we change to a "d".
This is the most popular one, I think. After
the... Or the most noticeable, in my brain.
After an "n", we don't say the "t". A "t"
with an "n", we change it to "in"; we don't
say the "t". And, again, we don't say the
"t" at the end of the word. So, I'm out of
here.