Hi, I'm Vanessa from SpeakEnglishWithVanessa.com.
Are you ready to learn a
secret? Let's talk about it.
Today, you are going to learn the number one
secret guaranteed to help you speak English
fluently in only 30 days. That's right, in only
30 days you will know everything you need to know
to be able to speak fluently, and dazzle
other people with your amazing English skills.
Are you ready to learn the number
one secret? Stay tuned to find out.
Okay, here it is. Are you ready? The secret is...
What did you think I was going to say? Is there
a secret to learning English fluently in 30 days?
No, there is no secret that can
guarantee that you will learn English
in only 30 days. A lot of programs make this bold
claim so that you will purchase their product,
watch their video. And, frankly, it's quite
dishonest. In English, we have a phrase,
maybe this exists in your native language too, "If
something is too good to be true, it probably is."
That means if something seems perfect, there's
probably a problem with it. It's probably lying
to you. Sometimes this can be really frustrating,
especially if you spend a lot of time and money
hoping that that bold claim will be true.
But hold on, I'm not here to figuratively rain
on your English learning parade. It may be true
that perfect fluency is not achievable in 30 days,
but that doesn't mean that you can't become
fluent. It just means that your English journey
is going to take a little longer or look a little
different than you expect. And that's great.
There's no perfect way, no set time frame, or
exact learning style that's going to work for
everyone. I'm here today to help you break
out of that mindset and also to help you
along on your English journey to fluency.
But do you know what? Let's use a different
word than fluency. Fluency feels
like there is a definite end point.
Like when you take an exam, the exam is finished,
and you receive a grade, and that's it. You're
finished. But learning a language isn't
like that. Instead of achieving fluency,
I want to use the word confidence. To achieve
confidence speaking in English, because this
is something real, something that you can feel.
You can feel your confidence growing the more
that you learn and the more that you practice.
So, you'll know that you're actually improving
when you feel your confidence improving too.
Do you remember when you were a kid and you
tried to ride a bike for the first time? Or
roller blade or roller skate for the first time?
You were probably a little bit wobbly and
uncertain. You probably fell a lot. Probably
got hurt. Hopefully, not too badly. Well, this
takes time, and a lot of practice and effort,
also making a lot of mistakes. Falling
down and learning how to balance yourself.
Well, learning English is quite similar to
that, except you don't need to wear a helmet,
I don't think so. If you are a beginner,
now, it will take you longer to be able to
speak English confidently. If you are an
intermediate or advanced English learner,
well, with daily practice speaking weekly with a
teacher, or some other English learners it will
take less time for you to be able to feel like you
can speak English confidently. A big determining
factor is how much time and effort you put in
to exercising those English speaking muscles.
Do you know this fable or tale of The Hare and The
Tortoise? Or sometimes we say The Tortoise and The
Hare. The tortoise is a turtle. A hare is a wild
rabbit. In this story, they're going on a race,
and the rabbit or the hare is so certain
that he's going to win. Rabbits are fast,
turtles are slow, it's just a fact. So, the hare
starts running and running, and then he thinks,
"I can take a nap. It's fine. I'll stop. Maybe
I'll go eat some lunch. I'll take another nap,"
and he gets distracted. But what does that
tortoise do? The tortoise just goes slow
and steady, never stopping, but is determined
to make it to the end, slow and steady.
Can you guess who wins the race? Well, of course,
the tortoise wins the race. And I think that this
is a wonderful example of what it means to learn
English. If you are steady, you are consistent and
dedicated. "Every day, I'm going to do something
with English. Maybe it's just listen to a song in
English because I don't have much time today.
Or maybe it's watch one of Vanessa's lessons.
Or maybe it's watch a full movie in English."
Doing something dedicated consistently in English
will help you achieve confidence much quicker.
The problem with the promise fluency in 30 days
is that you feel so much pressure. All right,
I need to achieve fluency in 30 days or else I
lose. And it kind of feels like after 30 days,
you won't need to do anything else ever again.
Well, this can feel like a lot of pressure because
first of all, like we talked about, it is not
possible to become fluent or speak confidently
in 30 days. But also, that feeling of, "I lost.
I failed at learning English because
I couldn't learn it in 30 days,"
that is a terrible feeling and will absolutely
not help you to achieve your goals in English.
This is your journey. I want to help you
to continue to slow and steady feel and
more confident in English without feeling
like mistakes are a problem. Mistakes are
important. They are inevitable. You cannot avoid
mistakes. That is an essential part of learning.
So, while 30 days may be too short of a
time for you to become a confident speaker,
30 days is a great amount of time for building
daily habits. If you do something for 30 days,
great, it will become a normal part of your life.
So, I would love to give you some suggestions.
Suggestion number one, schedule a certain time
each day for English. Make sure that this is
realistic. You cannot say, "I will study for four
hours after I come home from work every day." Do
you know what's going to happen after one week,
maybe less? We call this burnout. You will burn
out. That means you will become so exhausted, and
you will be annoyed at learning English. You won't
want to do it anymore. So, make sure that you set
a realistic time, 15 minutes, 30 minutes. Set this
time aside and make it the most important
thing that you want to accomplish that day.
For that 15 or 30 minutes, you can play a podcast
in English while you are commuting to work.
If you don't commute, you could listen to
a podcast while you're cooking breakfast,
while you're folding the laundry, while you're
taking a walk around your neighborhood. You can
just spend that time doing something with English.
Or you could subscribe to my YouTube channel,
I have over 300 English lessons. Maybe
you have not seen all of them. So,
you could watch one lesson per day, that's
about 30 minutes each day, immerse yourself
in English and learn something new. Great.
And I hope you will enjoy it at the same time.
My first tip was to set aside a specific amount
of time every day. My second tip is to surround
yourself with English. Even if you're not in an
English speaking country, you can still do this.
You can find fun and creative ways to immerse
yourself. Here are some of my suggestions.
You can change the language settings on your
phone, or on your browser on the computer.
That means that just as you are looking at
news articles, or as you are reading a recipe,
whatever you're doing on your phone, all of
the text is going to be in English. Simple,
effective, and doesn't take any extra time.
You could also take some sticky notes,
or little pieces of paper with tape and put
them around your house to label different items.
Write a full sentence, and this will help you
to be able to see English and have your brain
switch over to English for that moment. You could
read your favorite books in English. If you need
any recommendations for good books in English,
I love reading, so I have made, I think, four
videos about book recommendations. You can check
out this one up here, which is beginner books.
Or if you have never read a book in English before
I recommend starting with those books. You can
check out that link up here to get some ideas.
Or you can check out the link in the description,
which is my Amazon storefront. I have listed on
there, all of the books that I recommend, and you
can just click on them and purchase them. I think
I get like 10 cents from each purchase. So, it's
not really that much for me, but it's just a way
to show you the books that you can read and give
some recommendations and where you can get them.
And finally, of course, you can watch some TV
shows or cartoons in English. Sometimes children's
cartoons are a great way to get started. They use
simple language for kids and they speak slowly,
you can see the action developing. It's a good way
to start to immerse yourself more in English. For
some other ways that you can speak English just by
being at home you can check out this video I made
up here, which goes into that topic more in depth.
My first tip was to schedule a certain amount
of time every day. Second tip was to surround
yourself with English. And the third tip is, can
you guess? Do you got it? It is to speak. I didn't
think that you could improve your speaking without
really speaking, right? If you spend all your time
listening to podcasts, watching TV shows, watching
my videos, but never actually speaking in English,
well, you're going to have a lot of head
knowledge, but you won't be able to use it.
So, I want to empower you to be
able to use what you're learning.
If you are like most people, the thought of
speaking in English gives you some stage fright.
Stage fright means anxiety, you are nervous about
speaking in English. Well, you're not alone. Let
me give you some tips to help you get started.
If you have a pet speak in English to them. You
can narrate your day. "This is what I did today. I
went to work and when I was talking with my boss,"
blah, blah, blah, blah. Or as you're cooking, you
can narrate what you're doing. "I need to crack
the eggs. And I need to mix them together. And
chop up some cheese." You are like the star of
a cooking show and no one else is listening.
Or if your family's listening, tell them,
"Don't judge me. I'm doing my own thing." And you
can speak out loud about these daily activities.
I know it's really important to have vocabulary,
to be able to do that, so you can check out
this video that I made up here about specific
words that you can use for daily conversation,
for daily life. It's really great to be able
to look around the room and name everything,
and talk about everything that you see. These
are real things that are in our daily lives.
So, you need to be able to talk about it.
Well, that's one way, to speak in your home.
The next thing you can do to help yourself feel
more comfortable speaking is to record your voice.
The most important thing to know here is that
you don't need to share this with anyone.
You can record your voice, listen to it and
delete it immediately. You don't need to
share this with the internet. You don't need
to share this with a teacher. If you want,
this can be just for you. And that might help you
to relieve a little anxiety, but it's good to be
able to listen to your voice, listen to how
it sounds, be kind to yourself. And also,
hear if there are specific sounds that don't sound
like my voice, well, if you're trying to imitate
the way that I speak, it's a good thing to be
able to improve your pronunciation based on that.
I have a couple videos about shadowing
pronunciation, that's what this is called.
Listening to a native speaker, repeating it and
recording yourself so that you can hear it. You
can check out that lesson up here. I'm mentioning
a lot of previous lessons today. You can check out
this lesson up here about repeating, and saying
some of the most important phrases, or most common
phrases in English. This will help you to be
able to speak out loud and build that confidence.
My final tip for speaking is to just do it. The
first two are a little easy. You talk with your
pet, talk while you're cooking, record yourself,
that's a little isolated. But you can find someone
to speak on Zoom with, to speak on WhatsApp
with, to speak on Facebook Messenger with,
to speak on Skype with, to be able to contact
someone. It could be another English learner,
it could be an English teacher, but just being
able to speak with someone else, even 10 minutes,
simple, straightforward, have a very clear
conversation just a couple minutes can help to
let go of that stress, and to realize guys, "Oh,
I can do this. I have a lot I need to improve,
but I can do this. Okay, just do it."
If you don't know who to speak with a lot
of students in my course, The Fearless Fluency
Club, speak together each week, sometimes three
or four times per week. They can learn the
same lesson material that I send to them.
But they can also connect on Zoom, Skype,
WhatsApp, Facebook Messenger, and talk
together. They can ask questions about the course
together, practicing that vocabulary, and grammar,
and pronunciation. Or they can just get to know
each other and really deepen those friendships
with people around the world in English.
So, if you would like a good place to
start for meeting other people, this is
a great place. Everyone is so kind and so
understanding about what it's like to learn
English and feel nervous. So, I hope that you
will be able to join me. You can click on the
link up here, or in the description to join me
in The Fearless Fluency Club. The first month,
if you use the coupon code NEW, if you write the
word NEW in the coupon code box, the first month
is $5. This is like a trial price. The normal
price is $35 per month. But if you like it after
the first month, $5, great. You can continue in
the course. If you don't like it, if it's not
a good fit for you, no problem. You can just
cancel. And it is easy peasy, as we might say.
Well, I hope today that I was able to impart some
courage to you to give you some information,
and also the strength to know if you didn't
learn English fluently in 30 days that's okay.
In fact, that's impossible. So, I hope that you
will be able to be realistic, take some of these
tips today and go forward on your English learning
journey. I'm here to help you. It's my goal.
I'm your teacher. And I would love to help you.
And, now, I have a question for you. In
the comments, let me know what is another
tip that you would give about learning English
on a daily basis, or how to become a confident
speaker? What are some tips that you would give?
Make sure to read each other's comments, so that
you can learn more and expand your knowledge.
Well, thank you so much for learning English
with me. And I'll see you again next Friday for
a new lesson here on my YouTube channel. Bye.
The next step is to download my free ebook, Five
Steps to Becoming A Confident English Speaker.
You'll learn what you need to do
to speak confidently and fluently.
Don't forget to subscribe to my YouTube channel
for more free lessons. Thanks so much. Bye.