Okay. I have to admit I'm not
really a sports fan at all,
but then the Olympic games or the
World Cup comes around and suddenly
I'm all in. And you
might feel the same way.
As the Olympic games fever hits
or the World Cup final approaches.
You'll probably notice that even
the most unenthusiastic sports
fans suddenly jump on the bandwagon
to discuss what's happening.
So whether you suddenly find yourself
watching a sports event in English,
or you're talking about it with
neighbors, friends, and coworkers,
you might find that there are
times when you feel a bit left out,
or you're not about what's
going on because there was
some idiomatic expression
used or an exclamation that
you've never heard before.
If you don't already know I'm
Annemarie with Speak Confident English,
everything I do here is designed to
help you get the confidence you want for
your life and work in English. In
this Confident English lesson today,
you're going to learn 19
sports-related vocabulary and phrases
that you're likely to hear. Again,
whether you're watching the game on
TV or chatting about it with others,
by the end,
you'll be able to confidently express
your opinion of a game or a team,
and be able to pinpoint the feeling
associated with particular phrases
is when they're used
To help provide some
structure to today's lesson,
I've divided it up into five
different scenarios or phases of
a sporting event.
We're going to look at common vocabulary
and English faces used when your team
or favorite athlete is winning the
game. When there's a turn in events,
when your team's losing and you're
feeling discouraged or disappointed,
when it's a nail biter. And finally,
when you are describing a
particular team or athlete.
Let's start with some high energy phrases
you're likely to hear commenters or
spectators use when their team is winning.
Number one is to have the upper hand.
To have the upper hand means to have
the winning advantage or to have control
over someone else or
something else. For example,
perhaps the Dutch speeds
skating team has greater control
over the bends and curves of the
track. And while watching the game,
you might hear a commentator say the
Dutch team certainly has the upper
hand with this track. And now
phrase number two to take the lead.
Generally speaking to take the lead
means to take charge. For example,
if we use this in a business setting,
you might say that someone takes
the lead in the business meeting,
they've taken charge of
the meeting. However,
in most sports contexts,
it means to move into or
advance into first place.
Imagine you're watching the 100
meter final and your favorite
runner manages to move
ahead of the fastest runner
on the track. The moment that happens,
you might hear the newscaster
cry and he takes the lead.
He just might bring home the gold!
And now phrase number three to land it.
Landing something typically
refers to successfully acquiring
something. For example,
I was so lucky to have landed this
job before the pandemic hit. However,
in a sports context,
it means that someone was successful
in performing a particularly difficult
move. For example,
maybe you're a gymnastics enthusiast and
you love watching Simone Biles perform.
After she completes a difficult move,
you might jump up in your seat and cry.
She landed it.
And now one of my favorite expressions
on today's list to nail it or to nail
something.
This is an expression I love to
use when one of my students is
successful in completing a presentation
or a job interview in English.
I'll often exclaim, you nailed it.
We use this when someone does
something perfectly well.
And in the sports context,
when someone makes the goal
and it's a beautiful kick,
you might say she nailed it.
You'll hear that one often in
highly technical sport events,
such as figure skating,
skiing, and gymnastics.
Now let's move on to phrase number
five, to knock it out of the park.
This phrase is perfect when
you are deeply impressed
with someone's performance. It's precise,
meaning means to perform
beyond expectations and to
do something particularly
well. For example, imagine you're
watching the figure skating finals,
and one of the performers
leaves the entire audience
speechless. It was so beautifully done.
You might hear the commentator
or say that was unbelievable.
He knocked it out of the park.
Now that you have several phrases that
you're likely to hear and that you can
use when your team is
winning and you're cheering,
let's move on to what you can say
when there's a turn of events.
In every major sporting event,
there is inevitably some
surprise twists and turns.
It's what makes watching a sports event
so exciting. When those moments happen,
here's what you can say.
Phrase number six on our
list to throw a curve ball,
to throw a curve ball means when
a situation suddenly becomes
tricky or goes off the
normal or expected path,
something you didn't anticipate
happens. For example,
you're watching a football match and
it's getting down to the final seconds of
the game. The star player of your
team has an easy penalty shot,
and everybody feels calm and
relaxed because of course
he's gonna make it right,
but he misses. That is a curve
ball. Something unexpected happened.
And as a result of missing that
shot, the score stays tied.
And in the final seconds,
the other team wins that entire situation
is having a curve ball thrown in
the game.
Another phrase you might hear
when something unexpected
happens is out of left
field.
This is used when something happens
out of nowhere or unexpectedly,
and it takes us by surprise. For example,
the International Olympics Committee
recently expanded the number of sports in
the Summer Olympics. And in
discussing this decision,
some critics might say,
rock climbing in the Olympics
came out of left field.
We weren't expecting the IOC to
include that activity in the Olympics.
And now one more fantastic expression
when things take an unexpected turn:
to be blindsided. This
expression tends to be negative.
So we use it when there's a
surprise that was unexpected and
unpleasant. For example,
the athletes were completely
blindsided by the IOCs ban.
Now let's move on to a number three,
what you might hear or what you can say
when you're feeling that disappointment
of loss, your team or your
favorite athlete is losing.
Phrase number nine on our
list is to jump the gun.
Sometimes the anxiety of
competing can get to an athlete.
And as a result of that anxiety,
they may start before they're
supposed to, leading to a penalty,
or maybe even being
disqualified. For example,
maybe you're watching an intense hockey
game and while you're cheering for your
favorite team, they begin to
lose due to a missed pass.
So you might say he jumped the
gun and passed the puck too soon,
he should have waited. As
result of jumping the gun,
it may lead to phrase number
10 on our list: to fall behind.
When a winning streak begins to slow down,
or when there's a loss in rank - for
example, maybe during a track event,
you start out in the lead, but then,
and several other runners start to
catch up and get ahead of you - you
may fall behind. While watching
a news story about the Olympics,
you might hear something like
Great Britain was doing well,
but fell behind as Japan surpassed
them with four gold medals.
And now number 11 on our list to withdraw,
to withdraw means to formally
leave or back out of a competition.
For example,
the nation was shocked when the Simone
Biles withdrew from the Summer Olympics.
A similar expression that you
might hear is to drop out,
to drop out of the game or
to drop out of the final.
And now the last one on our list for
what you can say or what you might hear
when your team is losing is Hail Mary.
To attempt a Hail Mary,
to hope for a Hail Mary.
This is used when we hope for a recall,
or when an athlete attempts
to do something miraculous,
something absolutely
unexpected and super difficult.
Typically a Hail Mary attempt
has a very slim chance of
being successful. This expression is
deeply rooted in American football,
and you'll hear it often to
describe someone attempting
a particularly long pass
or kick. Here's an example
of how you can use it.
Although Sarah Davies
was close to passing out,
she made a Hail Mary attempt
to lift 133 kilos. Okay,
we're getting close to the end.
We have just seven more sports-related
phrases to it's time for scenario
number four, when the
game becomes a nail-biter.
Let's talk about that
expression for a moment.
I want you to think about
physical signs of anxiety.
What do people do when they get nervous?
Some people fidget with
their hands or their feet.
Others might start to feel
really hot and some might start
to bite their nails when
they're feeling nervous.
A nail biter is a situation
or a TV show, a movie,
a game that causes great
anxiety or tension like when
there's a tie between two
teams in the World Cup final at
that precise moment,
when you have just a few seconds left in
the game and someone's getting ready to
take that final kick, you could describe
it as a nail biter. Phrase number
14 on our list also can
lead to a nail biter
situation to be down to the wire.
Down to the wire means until
the very last second or coming
very close to the end. During the
last few moments of a sporting event,
you might hear commentators say,
we're coming down to the wire,
but team USA just might pull
through. In other words,
there are just a few seconds
left and in those final seconds,
that particular team may
advance ahead and ultimately win
the game. Similarly,
when someone enters that final
lap in a pool or their final
round around the track, we can say
that they're on the home stretch.
For example, while watching
your favorite swimmer,
you might say she's in the home stretch
and she just needs a few more seconds
of giving it her all to win the gold.
But sometimes in those final
moments of the home stretch,
two players may be neck and neck,
this means that they're
extremely close or even equal.
For example,
Shericka Jackson and Marie-Josee
Ta Lou were neck and neck in the
semi-final. And now we're
down to our last scenario.
Scenario number five is when you want
to describe an athlete or a team.
And we have just three phrases left.
Number 17 on our list is the underdog.
When a team or a player
is underrated and no one
anticipates that they will win, they
may be described as an underdog.
And if that team or player
does win in the end,
you may hear someone say "coming
into this event, she was an underdog,
but she truly is a champion."
Number 18, the dream team.
I'm sure you can imagine
what this expression means.
If your favorite team has proved
to have finesse and to work
extremely well together, win the game.
You might describe them as the dream team.
For example, with Klay Thompson back,
the Golden State Warriors have
been reinstated as the dream team.
And now it's time for our last
phrase on the list. Number 19,
hands down.
Whether it's the underdog
who became victorious or your
dream team that was ultimately successful.
You may explain that
your team is, hands down,
the best team.
Hands down means that something
or someone is exactly as
you describe without question
in talking about your athlete
on a team,
you might say she is hands down the best
player on the team. With that
you have 19 sports-related phrases you
can use the next time you're watching
a major sporting event on TV.
Now today's lesson is by no
means an exhaustive list.
There is a endless number of phrases,
idioms and frail verbs we use while
watching a favorite sporting event on
TV. And there may be a few that you
already know of and that you love.
If you have a favorite expression
that I did not use today,
share it with me below. I
would love to know what it is.
And it's a great way to share your
knowledge with the entire Speak Confident
English community,
the best place that you can share with
me and others is in the comments directly
below. And here's one more question.
What was your favorite
phrase from today's list?
Tell me what it was and
use it in an example,
sentence that you just might say next
time you're watching the World Cup,
the Super Bowl or the Olympics you can
share with me in the comments below the
video. If you found today's lesson
useful to you, I would love to know.
You can tell me in one very simple way,
give this lesson a thumbs up here
on YouTube. And while you're at it,
make sure that you subscribe
to the speed confident channel.
So you never miss one of my
Confident English lessons.
Thank you so much for joining me. And
I look forward to seeing you next time.