Have you got a few minutes of free time? Rather than killing time playing games, let’s have a whale of a time learning 30 time-related idioms.
These are phrases that are used in everyday situations, formal and informal so it’s good to be familiar with them.
This lesson is sponsored by Lingoda but more about them later as it’s high time we started on the list!  Let's go!
1. It’s high time . This phrase can be used to say that it is time to do something that should have happened a long time ago.
“You’ve been struggling with your Maths homework for months. It’s high time we got you a tutor.”
2. Against the clock  If you’re doing something “against the clock”, you are doing it as quickly as possible in order to meet a deadline.
“The party guests will arrive at 6pm so we’re working against the clock to get everything ready in time. Quick!”
3. The eleventh hour . If something happens ‘at the eleventh hour’, that means it happens at the last possible moment.
“I found that question really difficult but I remembered the answer at the eleventh hour, just before the exam finished.”
4. To make up for lost time . To do something faster or more often in order to compensate for not having done it quickly enough or often enough is known as ‘making up for lost time’.
Many of us, because of the pandemic, are now making up for lost time because of all the things we missed.
“We didn’t get to see family much last year so this year, I hope to make up for lost time and spend lots of time with them.”
5. In the nick of time . To do something ‘in the nick of time’, means to do it just in time.
“We almost missed the train but we got here in the nick of time. That was close.”
6. The ship has sailed . We use this phrase informally to discuss an opportunity which has passed or a situation which can no longer be changed.
“I thought about running a marathon this year but I haven’t done any training so that ship has sailed.”
And on the subject of running, Lingoda are running their Language Sprint again soon, so don’t delay if you are keen to challenge yourself to three months of language learning with the opportunity of getting 50% or even 100% cashback as a reward for completing.
Now when it comes to teaching languages Lingoda are a top-notch provider, teaching English, Business English, German, Spanish, and French to over 70,000 students worldwide.
They provide small group classes with qualified teachers and interactive curriculum, 24/7.
This is the last sprint of 2021, so if you want to make some meaningful progress with your language learning this year
then why not take the challenge and motivate yourself with the cash back reward.
How does it work?  Well if you think you are up to the challenge of an intensive language course then you click the link below and sign up.
Sign up must happen before the 15th Oct ready to begin work on October 31st.
Now, you can take the Sprint, which means you need to attend 15 classes a month over 3 months and if you complete all those classes you get 50% cashback
OR Take the SUPER Sprint, which means you attend 30 classes a month for 3 months  and if you do that you'll get 100% cash back.
Learning language intensely in short bursts is highly effective, all you need is the burning desire to improve.
So are you ready to be a champion?  Then hurry, TIME IS OF THE ESSENCE (ah that's another time phrase. This phrase is used when something must be done immediately).
Sign-up with my link and the voucher code CHAMP14 that provides a €20 discount on the deposit. And Don’t forget to check out their FAQ session before joining! Good luck!
7. Around the clock.  If something is done ‘around the clock’, then it is done all day and all night without stopping.
“Oh yes. We have around the clock security. Noboby's getting into this place.”
8. To call it a day.  This means to decide to stop doing something, either permanently or for a while depending on the context.
“I’m too tired to finish my homework so I’m going to call it a day and finish it tomorrow.”
9. In the blink of an eye.  If something happens ‘in the blink of an eye’ then it happens very quickly, just like a blink.
“A calculator can solve the maths problem in the blink of an eye.”
10. To kill time . This phrase is used informally and it means to spend time doing something unimportant, particularly when waiting for something.
“Yes, we’ll go shopping at the airport to kill time before the flight.”
11. Like clockwork . If something happens ‘like clockwork’, then it happens very smoothly and easily.
“The presentation ran like clockwork. Everyone was very happy.”
12. On the dot . This is an informal phrase which means exactly on time. “She starts work at 9am on the dot. Not 9.03am.”
13. To do time (to serve time).  This is a colloquial term meaning to be in prison.
“He’s doing time for money laundering.”
14. To turn back time . To ‘turn back time’ means to recreate, remember, or imagine things as they were before.
“I like to reminisce while looking through old photographs, but I do wish I could just turn back time.”
15. To have a whale of a time . This means to have a brilliant time, to really enjoy oneself.
“I had a whale of a time learning to ski, until I broke my leg.”
16. To lose track of the time . To ‘lose track of the time’ means to be unaware of how much time has passed, or to not be sure of what the time is.
“I’m so sorry I’m late. I lost track of the time!”
17. Free time.  ‘Free time’ refers to time available for hobbies and activities you enjoy.
“In my free time, I like to play football. What do you like to do?"
18. Spur of the moment . Something done in the ‘spur of the moment’ is done impulsively, without planning in advance.
“We aren’t going to Argentina now, instead we’re going to Switzerland! Don’t ask me why, it was a spur of the moment decision.”
19. Behind the times . If something is ‘behind the times’, it is not using the latest technology, ideas or techniques. It could also be referred to as ‘out of date’.
“This library is so behind the times. They don’t even have a computer!”
20. To hit the big time . This is an idiomatic phrase which means to become very successful or famous.
“She hit the big time and got a part in a very successful film after years of hard work.”
21. Hour of need.  An ‘hour of need’ is a time when most help is needed.
“Thank you so much for helping us in our hour of need.”
22. A laugh a minute.  You could use this phrase to describe someone who is very funny.
“John’s great. He’s a laugh a minute, so funny.”
23. Like there’s no tomorrow . To do something ‘like there’s no tomorrow’ means to do it in a quick or careless way without considering the future.
“He’s spending money like there’s no tomorrow!”
24. Long time no see . This is informally used as a greeting to mean ‘it’s a long time since we last met’.
“Christopher, long time no see!”
25. A mile a minute.  If something is happening ‘a mile a minute’, it is happening at a very fast rate.
“I can barely understand Connor because he talks a mile a minute.”
26. Now and then If something happens ‘now and then’, it happens occasionally.
“I don’t see her much but we go for coffee now and then.”
27. The moment of truth.  A time when a person or thing is tested, a decision has to be made, or a crisis has to be faced might be referred to as ‘the moment of truth’.
“Grace has spent hours baking the perfect cake, but now it is the moment of truth: time to taste it.”
28. To have too much time on one’s hands.  To have ‘too much time on your hands’ means to have lots of extra time. We often use this phrase to describe someone who is engaged in unhelpful or useless activities.
“She’s such a gossip. She obviously has far too much time on her hands.”
29. Once in a blue moon
This means it rarely happens.
“I don’t speak to my old uni mates these days. I mean Fernando will call me for a catch-up once in a blue moon, but apart from that we have all lost touch.”
30. Donkey’s years .  ‘Donkey’s years’ is an informal way of saying a long time.
“Adam and I have been friends for donkey’s years!”
So there we have 30 time-related idioms for you to drop into conversation.
If you can think of any time-related idioms then please put them in the comments section for everyone to enjoy!
Now if you are going to take that Lingoda language challenge don't delay time is of the essence. Go and sign up using my link and voucher code below
and if you'd like to double-check your knowledge from what you've learned today then I have interactive activities available on my blog page.
I'll put all the links to everything you need in the description until next time take care, bye!