Hi, I’m Rich. Welcome to Oxford Online English!
In this lesson, you can learn how
to talk about online shopping.
What was the last thing you bought online?
What are the best online shopping websites,
in your opinion? Have you ever had a really good
– or bad – experience when shopping online? You’ll
learn some useful language to talk about these
topics and answer these questions in this lesson.
One more thing: do you want to
watch this video with subtitles?
You can! Turn them on now by
clicking the ‘CC’ icon; on a phone,
find the subtitles by tapping the
settings button on your screen.
Now, let’s start your lesson.
Hey – nice shirt!
Thanks!
Is it new?
Yes, I bought it last week on Asos.
I’ve heard of Asos, but I’ve never
actually ordered anything from there.
Would you recommend it?
Yes, I think it’s great. I use it at least once
a month. They have a huge range of clothes and
the prices are very reasonable. Some people
say their customer service is a nightmare,
but I’ve never had any trouble. Where do
you shop for clothes if you don’t use Asos?
Well, I used to shop at Next, which is a shop
I’ve always liked. Their clothes have always
been quite expensive, but over the last year
or two the quality has been going downhill.
So recently I started shopping at Zara. I think
the clothes are much better value for money.
OK, so you would recommend
Zara as a good place to shop?
Yes. So far, so good. I only started using
their website two months ago, mind you…
Here’s a question: do you know which prepositions
to use when you talk about online shopping?
When we talk about physical shops, we
use ‘at’ – so you can say, for example,
‘I bought it at Walmart’.
When we talk about online shops, we usually use
‘on’ – so you can say ‘I bought it on Amazon’.
This is because we talk
about being *on* a website.
We also say, ‘I bought it online’ or ‘I bought it
on the internet’. We often hear students making
mistakes with these phrases, so be careful!
In the dialogue, you heard some vocabulary
to talk about online shopping.
Look at some phrases you heard.
What do these phrases mean? Could
you explain the meanings in English?
Try it now! Pause the video. Imagine you’re an
English teacher, and you need to explain what
these phrases mean in English. What would you say?
Pause the video and say your definitions aloud.
How was it? Could you do it?
‘A huge range’ means that they have
many different products. For clothes,
this would mean that they offer many different
items, different styles, colours, and so on.
‘Reasonable’ means ‘fair’. If the prices
are reasonable, they’re not too high.
It doesn’t mean that the website is cheap,
but if you use the word ‘reasonable’, you probably
mean that something is good value for money.
A nightmare is, literally, a bad dream, but
you can use it to describe something terrible.
Finally, if something goes downhill, it gets
worse. ‘The quality has been going downhill’
means that the quality of their products
has been getting worse and worse.
There are other useful words and phrases in the
dialogue. We recommend listening to each dialogue
several times and noting down any phrases
you think are useful or interesting.
Next, you heard how to talk about shopping
websites you use for buying clothes.
Look at some questions.
Think about how you could answer these.
When you answer the questions,
try to include some details.
For example, when you answer question one,
don’t just say, ‘I like shopping on Amazon’.
Instead, you could say, ‘I love buying
clothes online. My favourite website is
Asos because the prices are very reasonable,
and their customer service is excellent.’
You
could also say,
‘I usually buy clothes online two or three times
a month. I would recommend staying away from Frox
because the quality of the clothes
has gone downhill recently.’
OK? Pause the video and try
to answer the questions now.
Could you do it? If not, go back
and listen to the dialogue again.
Ready to move on? Let’s look at your next topic.
In this dialogue, you will hear us comparing
two websites – Amazon and AliExpress.
Have you ever used these websites?
If you have, how do they compare?
Think about your answers before you listen.
So, what about things like electrical goods?
Which website would you use if you wanted to buy,
say, a battery for your mobile phone?
Until recently I would have said Amazon
is better without a doubt, but a while ago
a friend of mine introduced me
to a website called AliExpress.
AliExpress? I’ve never heard of
that. How does it compare to Amazon?
I think the main reason people use it is because
it’s cheaper than Amazon, but I’ve also found
that they often have products that you
can’t get hold of on other websites.
OK, that’s interesting. What’s
their customer service like?
Well, it’s true that you’ll see lots of complaints
about it if you read the online reviews – but
I’ve only had to send something back once,
and they sent a replacement straight away.
Right. Well, that sounds pretty reasonable.
Yes, I thought it was fair enough.
The only thing I would say about
AliExpress is that their delivery times
are not the best. You wouldn’t want to order
something from them if you were in a hurry!
Can you see the estimated delivery
times when you place the order?
Yes, you know what to expect – you just have to be
patient! The last thing I bought from AliExpress,
which wasn’t available on Amazon by the way, was
a part for a printer. They said it would take
over a month to arrive, but in fact it
arrived safe and sound after only a week!
So you were a satisfied customer!
How did you get on? Did you agree
with our comparison? Let’s have a
look at some of the language we used.
Look at these sentences. Which words are missing?
You heard them in the dialogue – try to remember.
OK? Let’s check.
You can use ‘without
a doubt’ to emphasise the point you’re
making – you could also say ‘definitely’.
‘Get hold of something’’ means to find something
that you need. If you say ‘Replacement parts are
hard to get hold of’, you mean that it’s difficult
to find a shop or website which sells them.
If someone asks you, ‘What is their customer
service like?’, they are not asking you if
you like it or not. ‘What is it like?’ means
‘tell me about it’ or ‘describe it to me’.
If you’re talking about customer service, or
shopping, you’re probably asking whether the
other person recommends it or not. It’s like
asking: ‘Is the customer service good or bad?’
It’s not exactly the same, but it's similar.
Finally, if you say that something
is not the best, you’re saying that
it’s not so bad, but it could be better.
As before, there is more language in the
dialogue which you might find useful! We won’t
give you every single word and phrase we use.
You should also do your own work to
get the most from these dialogues.
Now, let’s see if you can talk about this topic.
Try to provide a detailed answer, perhaps
using some of the vocabulary you saw before.
For the first question, you could say ‘When
I need to buy electronic products, I usually
use a website called Banggood. They don’t have
as many of the top brands as Amazon, but the
prices are great, and they often have products
that you can’t get hold of anywhere else.’
For the second question, you could say: ‘The
last time I bought something on Banggood
was about three weeks ago. I couldn’t
find the product on any other website,
and it arrived safe and sound after only
two weeks. I was a very satisfied customer.’
Of course, there are many possible answers!
Now it’s your turn. Pause the video
and try to answer the questions now.
How did you get on? Were you
able to express your ideas?
Next, you’ll see how to talk about
good online shopping experiences.
This time, you’ll see some key
phrases before you hear the dialogue.
What are the missing words?
Try to find them as you listen.
Pause if you need more time to
read. Ready? Here’s the dialogue.
Do you find that there are some websites you use
more since you’ve been living outside the UK?
Yeah - absolutely. One of my favourites is a
website called Moonpig where you can buy greetings
cards – like birthday cards and Christmas cards –
and have them delivered in the UK. British people
often send greetings cards to friends and
family on their birthdays, or at Christmas,
and this can be more difficult to
organise if you’re living overseas.
Right. I guess in some countries birthday
cards or Christmas cards are hard to find.
Yes, that’s true, and even if you can get hold
of them, it’s hard to gauge how long they will
take to arrive in the UK. So, some years ago I
got into the habit of ordering cards on Moonpig.
The website is really intuitive,
so it’s easy to find what you need.
That’s always a plus. It
sounds good – how does it work?
First you choose your card, then you can
personalise it with a photo if you want to – or
just write your own message. After that you just
confirm the address that you want it sent to.
Sounds like a good service. I gave
up on trying to send birthday cards;
now I just send people text messages,
but I’ve always felt it’s a little
lazy. It’s nice to get a real
card in the post, you know?
Yep – I’m with you. It’s a good service. The cards
are posted in the UK, so they only take a day or
two to arrive. It’s straightforward
to use once you get the hang of it,
reasonably-priced and they
haven’t let me down yet!
Could you find the missing words? Let’s check.
Do you know what these mean?
‘Intuitive’ means easy to understand. If a
website is intuitive, you can find what you need
and do what you want without difficulties,
and without having to think about it too much.
A ‘plus’ is a conversational way
to say ‘advantage’ or ‘benefit’.
If you ‘get the hang of something’, you
learn how to do something – or you learn
how to use something. You can say, for example,
‘It’s easy when you get the hang of it.’
If someone ‘lets you down’, they disappoint you
by not doing what they said they were going to do.
If a website is very reliable, you can
say, for example ‘They never let me down’.
What about you? Are you usually a
satisfied customer when you shop online?
Tell us about a positive experience.
Pause the video now and try
to make a few sentences.
For example, you could say, ‘Most of the time
I enjoy shopping online. I often order birthday
presents online. Although it’s very convenient,
it makes me a bit nervous because obviously they
need to arrive on the right day. So far, so
good. They haven’t let me down yet! Last year,
I ordered a bunch of flowers for my Mum and I was
worried that they might get damaged. I was very
pleased when she told me that they had arrived
safe and sound – and on the 8th of November!’
Done? Great! Let’s look at our last point.
Speaking of being let down, I’ve just had a
really strange experience shopping online.
Really? What happened?
Well, I have an old laptop that I
bought overseas a long time ago.
Last year, I needed to buy a replacement
battery – and I couldn’t find one anywhere.
No one seemed to stock the exact type I needed.
Yes – I think the manufacturers do that on
purpose. They just want you to buy a new computer.
Right. Well, I persevered and eventually I
found a company which had the battery – but they
said that it would take two months to deliver it.
I didn’t have any alternatives, so I went for it.
OK, and what happened?
Well, first of all the ordering
process was really tricky.
The website was so clunky – it looked like it was
made in the 1990s and hadn’t been updated since.
I hate it when that happens. It’s so annoying!
Yup, but I was determined!
So then, I spent about six weeks tracking my
battery as it made its way around the world.
It showed that arrived in the country, but
then it disappeared off the radar completely.
I contacted the company and they had no idea
what had happened, and they sent me a refund.
OK, well that’s something, at least.
I was ready to just call it quits, but then, last
week, I received a package from the same website.
Don’t tell me… Your battery finally arrived?
Well, not exactly… The
package contained a battery,
but it was for a phone, not for a laptop.
But, it had my name and address, and so on.
That’s kind of weird, isn’t it? Did they
mix up your order with someone else’s?
Who knows? Anyhow, I gave up
on them. It’s too much hassle.
Here are some sentences from the
dialogue. Can you fill the gaps?
Could you remember? Let’s check.
What do these highlighted words mean?
Do you know, or can you guess from the context?
Pause and think about it if you need more time.
‘Stock’ as a verb means to
have something for sale.
You can use it in the verb phrase ‘have something
in stock’. If a shop has something in stock,
it’s available and you can buy it. If something
is out of stock, it’s not available right now.
‘Clunky’ means that something is badly designed
and difficult to use. If you website is made on
a budget, it’ll probably be clunky. It’s mostly
used to talk about technology which is
not well-designed or which is out-of-date.
‘Call it quits’ means that you’ve been
trying to do something for a while,
but now you’re giving up and you’re not going
to try any more. After a long, frustrating
customer service experience, you might
decide to just call it quits and go home!
Finally, ‘hassle’ is a useful word
to talk about bad customer service.
Something which is a hassle is both difficult and
annoying. If you describe something as a hassle,
you’re suggesting that it doesn’t need
to be this difficult. For example,
if a website makes you fill out loads of forms
to get a refund or cancel your subscription,
you can describe that as a hassle – they’re
making it more difficult than it needs to be.
Now, it’s your turn. Have you ever had
a bad experience with shopping online?
Tell us what happened.
When you’re ready, pause the video
and say your answer out loud.
Or, write your answer down and share your
experience with other students in the comments!
That’s it for this lesson. Thanks for watching!
See you next time!