(dramatic orchestral music)
(people chattering)
- [Narrator] The weary gunfighter
walked slowly through the saloon.
The long miles from Cheyenne
had taken their toll.
- Who's saying that stuff?
- [Narrator] He scanned the
room with a suspicious eye.
Years of being on the
wrong side of the law
had taught him that a tough
man can get out of a situation,
but a smart man never
gets himself into one.
- Please quit doing that, I just want to
have a shot of whiskey in peace.
- [Narrator] But the
gunfighter would find no peace.
For the Henderson boys
were waiting in the corner
to kill him for the
$200 bounty on his head.
- Is that true?
You boys trying to kill me
like this voice is saying?
- Uhh...
No.
- [Narrator] Lied the
oldest Henderson boy.
- How do you know I'm lying?
- [Narrator] The oldest
Henderson boy asked of the air.
- No, I didn't ask the air.
I'm asking you, you fuckin' voice.
- [Narrator] Said the
oldest Henderson boy.
- Would you please stop saying
"Said the oldest Henderson boy"?
- [Narrator] Implored Tommy,
the oldest Henderson boy.
Meanwhile, the younger
Henderson's hand twitched
by the Colt Peacemaker on his right hip.
He was thinking of shouting
"Look out behind you"
to trick the gunfighter
into turning around
so he could shoot him in the back.
- No, I was not!
- Come on, Johnny, again
with the "Look behind you"?
What were you gonna say
was behind him this time?
- Uhh, nothing.
- [Narrator] Johnny lied.
He was going to say a bear.
- Oh, come on.
(people laughing)
- A bear, Johnny? In a saloon?
- [Narrator] Johnny's face turned red.
He began wishing he was in a safe place
at home, in bed, with his dolls.
(Johnny scoffs)
Hey, hey, I ain't got no dolls!
- [Narrator] To calm his
nerves, he pictured himself
combing his dolls' hair and
pouring them each a cup of tea.
- No!
- Wait, wait, wait.
You have tea parties with your dolls?
- [Narrator] But something about
the younger Henderson's vulnerability
opened a door in the gunfighter's heart.
- Nope, no it didn't!
- [Narrator] Inside, a
sea of confusing emotions
bubbled to the surface.
- No.
- [Narrator] He started imagining himself
holding the younger Henderson
and stroking his greasy hair.
- No!
- [Narrator] He pictured his first kiss
with the younger Henderson.
- No, that--
- [Narrator] They both
giggle at how clumsy it was.
- No.
- [Narrator] They know the
next one will be even better.
- I'm seriously not picturing that!
- [Narrator] But inside he was.
- No, I'm not!
- [Narrator] But he was.
- No, I'm not and that's the final word.
- Goddamnit!
- Why don't you two go get a room?
- Hey, why should we
trust this voice anyway?
- [Narrator] Just then,
the gunfighter had an idea.
- Hey, you.
- Me?
- Think of a number between one and 100
and then we'll see if this voice
really knows what we're thinkin'!
- Okay, got it.
- [Narrator] Sally the
whore began thinking
of her favorite number, which was 32.
She then thought of her lady
parts and how itchy they were
before deciding to change
her mind and go with 76,
her second favorite number.
- The voice is right!
32 is my favorite number,
but then I changed my
mind and went with 76!
- And your cooch?
- It's been itching something
horrible since Saturday, Bill.
You know anything about that?
- Uhh,
no.
- [Narrator] He did, but
we'll get to that in a minute.
- Looks like that voice
really does know everything.
- [Narrator] The gunfighter
noticed for the first time
that the bartender was black.
This was still unusual in the west,
but the gunfighter decided
he was okay with it.
- Umm, thanks?
- [Narrator] The people in
the town prided themselves
for their progressive
attitudes about race.
- That's right.
- [Narrator] But would
they still feel that way
if they knew that Sam had been sleeping
with Ned Schilling's wife?
- What!?
- Relax, Ned, alright?
I mean, everyone has been with her.
- Guilty.
- Yeah, you're right.
- [Narrator] And Elijah Jessup's sister.
- Welp, it's time for him to die.
(cocking guns)
- Watch yourself, Jessup.
You best put that gun down
or I'll cut you in half.
(ominous music)
- That music,
it seems kind of ominous, don't it?
- Ominous.
What's that mean?
- You know, like, something
bad's about to happen,
like a needless gunfight.
- [Narrator] The stage
was set for an awesome
ballet of death.
Blood would be spilled,
but who would be the first?
- Wait a second.
Ballet of death?
What the hell?
I think this voice wants
us to kill each other.
- [Narrator] Meanwhile, the
gunfighter saw his opening
to shoot Tommy dead.
- No, no, no, wait!
That one really is a lie, see?
My hand's nowhere near my gun.
- [Narrator] Okay, you got me.
That one wasn't true.
But this one is.
Yesterday, Tommy Henderson made sweet love
to Bill Jessup's wife.
- No!
You made sweet love to our mama?
- (laughs uncomfortably)
Here's the thing about that.
- Oh, you're dead, Henderson.
- [Narrator] Said Gabriel,
who had recently delivered
a load of cream to the back
porch of his brother's wife.
He did her in the butt.
- What!?
- How could you? Your own brother!
- [Narrator] Yet even as
Bill reacted with disgust,
the irony was not lost on him.
- You know what, I see
where you're goin' with this
and I'm just gonna retract
my disgust right now
if that's possible.
- [Narrator] For he had
been regularly sneaking
into Paul Valentine's barn.
- Okay, you know, we're
good, we're good here.
I think we should just move on.
- [Narrator] Where he had been having sex
with Paul's favorite sheep Martha.
- Oh boy.
- Marth, Bill!?
Martha!?
- That is why I've been
so itchy? (cocks gun)
- You know what?
We all just need to
take a deep breath here.
We're playin' right
into the voice's hands.
Sure, there's been a surprising amount
of infidelity in this town,
and the bestiality should probably stop,
and I might be gay.
But if we start shootin', the voice wins.
I think the voice is
givin' us an opportunity.
In a world where our
deepest, darkest secrets
are unveiled one by one,
maybe we'll stop doing the
things we're ashamed of
and start to embrace the
things about ourselves
we're afraid to accept.
Hell, this could be the
beginning of a new utopia,
a society based on fairness and tolerance
where it don't matter
if you're rich or poor--
- Or a woman!
- Let's not get carried
away, but the point is,
is that the voice is showing
us the worst side of ourselves
and we need to show it our best.
Now, who's with me?
- [All] Yeehaw!
- [Narrator] It was a good speech
and things might have
turned out differently
if the crowd never found
out that the gunfighter
had just last night shot and killed
the youngest son of John McCullers,
because he "had some
breath that smelled like
"the ass end of a Chinaman."
- Well, you must be Mr. McCullers.
(fires gun)
(guns firing)
- [Narrator] It was a
true ballet of death.
When the gruesome bloodbath was over,
not a single person was left standing,
except for Sally, the itchy whore.
- Yoo!
- [Narrator] Who celebrated
by scratching her front porch.
- [Sally] Whoo!
- [Narrator] Little did she know,
she would be mauled to
death by a rabid wolf
the very next day.
- Well, fuck.
(dramatic orchestral music)