have you noticed whenever you see a
commercial for ham on TV it's often
set in the countryside with a nice family
and a rustic backdrop and the ham is always
pink very pink and 100% natural of course
the best with a quick initial said it looks
so tasty it has your mouth watering
on the couch well that's the point
but what if behind this pretty pink hit one of
the biggest health scandals of our era in 2015 the
world health organization listed processed meats
as carcinogenic for man we decided to investigate
the ingredients used by the Giants of the food
industry it can induce DNA breaks mutate cells
into sort of pre cancer cells we discovered that
to impede or halt regulations on certain additives
food industry lobbies have been working in the
shadows for decades you have to understand it the
industry is a money-making business of they're
very risk-averse they're not going to fund a
study that is bad for their business Tom pommel a
thief is a little bit about safety pay this your
cheek for Jellicle cat escapement at the heart
of this strategy of influence are the scientists
who collaborate the industry paid you for this I
received some compensation from my time as well
as the others how much and the scientists who are
targeted basically we're trying to shoot me down
or discredit me I mean that's what you'd done
means scientifically these efforts to go after
the scientists and to discredit the scientists
is a key element of a much larger strategy to
just gum up the entire policy-making process
between intimidation lies and manipulation we
will uncover proof of a worldwide strategy
we're hitting below the belt is allowed
feeling hungry now then it's time
to eat tonight you are our guests
to find out how ham is made we visited a factory
welcome to flowy mission one of the market leaders
in France and one of the few to play the card of
transparency the ham on your supermarket shelves
starts out like this big lumps of pork meat
to have taste a little vegetable stock it all
goes into a ham shaped mold and it's cooked
and the result perfectly pink rounded
slices have you grasped the basics
well let's rewind a little to see
the detail that changes everything
to obtain this fine ham there's
another very important step
you have to inject the meat a machine with
a dozen syringes injects a liquid into the
lumps of pork meat the liquid contains an
essential additive factory manager Luhan
Hulu shows us these yellow sacks contain
a mixture of salt and sodium nitrite the
additive p250 as a conservation Duchamp ball
a little traditional pathogen you seem to need
a cooler new characteristic donor chakra
inversion oh and kahlúa so woozy of it and
accepted me in fact he's telling us that the
pretty pink of our ham isn't natural at all
it's thanks to sodium nitrite
this additive fixes the pink
of the meat during cooking otherwise
ham would be the color of roast pork
that's why food industrialists can't do without
it as a processed meat producer would confirm
venosus is wrong : that could help us get
back to detail on that all over the Queen
thus casino one just kept asking shook its
apparent unclear supreme Jones has an ashram
hungry mm-hmm for sm64 I sell descriptors and
honesty to do something more personal esteem
it is not only professor Lucifer in the create
a boundary can be said to be on some problem
let's sum up the hams pinkies are natural but
without the pink it would be impossible to
sell the big problem is that sodium nitrite
is believed to be a danger to public health
the additive is suspected of playing a role
in the development of colorectal cancer one
of the deadliest cancers in Europe the cause
a phenomenon that takes place during digestion
it's chemistry but we'll make it simple you
swallow a piece of cured meat you think you're
peacefully digesting it but what you don't
know is the nitrite molecules are reacting
with the meat proteins transforming them
into very dangerous substances nitrosamine
x' we went to the netherlands to learn
more about the effects of this chemical
reaction on our health to the Faculty
of Medicine of Maastricht University
this is where the toxicologist professor Te'o
de Kock works he's been interested in nitrites
for years and by extension nitrosamine nitrogen
means are known to induce damage in the large
intestine so it can induce DNA breaks mutate
cells into sort of pre cancer cells and that's
of course something that you want to want
to prevent them professor to cook notably
wanted to find out what happens inside the
body when we don't eat processed meat and
when we eat a lot of it to do so he conducted an
experiment with human guinea pigs like I'll know
for two weeks this student aid 300 grams
have processed meat a day the equivalent
of eight and a half sausages or seven slices
of ham after 15 days we saw that the exposure
to nitrosamine was considerably increased
so it was up to between two and three fold
increase as compared to the levels that we
measured at start the researcher measured
the impact on the organism of this chemical
mutation of nitrites into nitrates amines
in his lab he tested the fecal water
of big processed meat eaters like Arno
so what you see here is fecal water from
four different individuals to see what
happens inside the body the researchers mixed this
fecal water with human cells the
white deposited in the test tube
then they observed what happened to the cells
you see that if you have no exposure you see
that everything is intact so the material cells
together but if you are exposed to nitrosamine
that induce breakages of the DNA you see this
comet tail appearing so you see that here the
damage is quite extensive so the more damage you
have the more likely it is that a cell like this
will eventually mutate into a pre cancer type
of cell how long does it take for such a damage
well this damage can be induced relatively
quickly so in this essay when we isolate
the cells and we only expose them for half an
hour and then you already see the breakage of
these DNA strands and so that's how fast it can
happen and it can also happen not just in the lab
here but also in an intact human body and if we
stop using nitrites then what that would make a
difference of potentially several thousands of
colic and rectal cancer that's in Europe every
year that's huge that's huge because colorectal
cancer is a very frequent disease already small
changes in a cancer risk can have a big impact
in a large population thousands fewer cancers
and therefore potentially fewer deaths just by
suppressing nitrites but the food industry has
a sledgehammer argument for justifying the
use of nitrites it protects us from botulism
botulism is a form of food poisoning caused by
bacteria that affect our central nervous system
and can be deadly Gary right but there's a
glitch in their argument there are already
companies which do produce processed meats without
nitrites and their customers are in fine form
if you happen to be in Copenhagen in Denmark
just after the Little Mermaid and the case I'd
promenade pop into a supermarket like we
did there you'll find cured meats without
nitrites and for those who's Danish has gone a
bit rusty its food a new treat it's everywhere
you can easily recognize it by its colour more
brownish than pretty pink and the best known
brand is produced 150 kilometres south of the
capital in Denmark's biggest organic processed
meat plant Hennigan the boss a biochemist
started in nitrite free cured meats 25 years ago
since then the Danish health authorities haven't
registered a single case of botulism caused by
processed meat we do not have problems with this
bacteria I would say for the last 50 years this
has not been a reasonable topic in Western
Europe that was a problem in meat industry
hundred years ago where think we're not as clean
as they are slaughterhouses were not as clean as
they are today so no worry about bacteria now we
have to worry about additives that might be into
producing and if they are not necessary for some
very good reasons we should not use them for you
the cancer risk today is the main risk that's
the main risk today definitely and and actually
it has been so for 30-40 years the main reason
is that they are afraid but customers will not
accept products which do not have the red color
that they have been used to for many many years
Hanna Gao is one of the few food industry
companies to do without nitrites and yet
experts have been ringing alarm bells for years
twenty-five years ago a European Union Health
Report already recommended reducing the amounts
of nitrite used in processed meats in 1999 this
report even put forward banning its use altogether
despite the increasing number of studies the
European Commission still allows industrial food
companies to add lots of nitrites to the products
so we went to ask the Commissioner for health and
food safety of former health minister in Lithuania
a few questions one don't get the levels lower
I would like to guarantee you that it is it is
of course in hands of of institutions which are
responsible to follow per se and to present to us
final results notes what's always takes takes
takes time and and and and the responsibility
for over an hour the Commissioner attempted
to pull the wool over our eyes in spite of
all the reports by experts which for 25 years
have warned the authorities about the dangers
of nitrites all these studies you don't think
they're enough you know all those studies are
open that you see what's x22 to transparency six
to possibility to have them to show to people that
we are ready to follow and to see and to do how
to move for us as soon as possible transparency
is good but decisions are better purchase order
all decisions are in in lines of procedures can
you imagine like like that decision to me if
i will be king of the european union oh but I
am NOT king of European Union I mean this story
has been so going on for sole no no no sorry to
say sorry I started this story shows that all
standards are in safety line in this case why
Europe lost against Denmark in the European Court
of Justice in this night right story I don't know
then content says it's gonna be right I would
like to talk do I need more information because
I am NOT one who knows everything so let's
look at the facts mr. commissioner Denmark
wanted to limit the use of nitrites the European
Commission was against it and in 2003 in court
the Danes won in the name of the protection of
public health about European Court decisions when
European Court decision always show that public
health is priority it means that digits hunter
and Commissioner responsible public health is in
better conditions and yet since this Court ruling
EU regulations are just as lacks as ever from my
point of view we must be more energetic asking
industry to change the internal data formulate
food to follow a figure to keep onboard public
health priorities not profit absolute but
it's but it of course it's it's takes time
time perfect that's just what the food
industry wants and what it has built its
strategy on for years because when it comes to
nitrites industrialists have been waiting out
the clock for 40 years forty years of scientific
manipulation blackmail and intense lobbying so the
meat business can carry on bringing home the bacon
and it all began on the other side of the Atlantic
if you think we're exaggerating listen to this
in the late 1970s nitrite was almost banned in
the United States just after the publication of
a large-scale study requested by the government
a relationship between cancer and nitrate was
proved suggested approved and a fairly strong
one there were 2,000 rats involved in the study
it's a very extensive study done by a well
respected scientist the banning of nitrites
was announced in the press but the American
Meat Institute would bring out its big guns
in his office overlooking the Capitol its
President Richard Ling spoke out processed
meats that contain nitrites are a big big
thing the retail value of them about twelve
and a half billion dollars about two-thirds
of the hog production in the United States
goes into cured meats and it presents a problem
for our industry and for the government we're
hopeful that a solution can be found armed
with financial analysis the American Meat
Lobby forced the government to back down the
banning of nitrites would send pork prices
plummeting and cause an apocalypse but it was
a political event that would close the debate
in 1980 Ronald Reagan was elected president of
the United States and guess
who entered into government
Richard Ling the president of the
American Meat Institute himself
the idea of banning nitrite was forever buried
the experiment based study on 2000 rats ended
up in the trashcan and after that the same fate
would await every scientific publication calling
nitrites into question if you're wondering how
the interests of Industry can systematically
win against what's at stake in public health
the following will enlighten you 15 years after
the victory of Ragan and the meat industrialists
a new study shook America to the core if it's
not one thing it's another a study finds a link
between hotdogs now and cancer put yourself in
the shoes of the average American Joe at the
time you and your family are eating hot dogs
at the shopping mall or in the street just as
usual the effect was immediate in a matter
of days hot dog sales fell by 8% and given
the size of the American market that represented
millions of dollars less for the food industry
the author of the hot dog study that
caused sales to plummet was Susan
Preston Martin she's now a retired
scientist living near Los Angeles
in a residential suburban setting
straight out of an American soap
after several tense months of talks she agreed
to see us but we had to insist
right up until the last minute
the lady is very discreet it's from French TV mrs.
Preston Martin yes I'm from
Queens we go from French TV
hello with her discoveries on processed meats the
researcher was the victim of a number of attacks
but she agreed to look back at her work which
showed a link between the excessive eating of
hot dogs and certain rare cancers in children how
did you find the relationship well just the way
we always did when we did case control studies
we started out with a group of children who had
leukemia and compared them to group children who
didn't have to keep me and we asked the mothers
about what they fed the children and sure enough
the kids with leukemia ate more hot dogs what did
you think when you saw this strong relationship
because it was quite a funny she was with hot
dogs I was a little bit surprised and just
reserved judgment it's just what happening me
i watch this too and they find something they
don't expect from that moment on for the food
industrialists Susan Preston Martin became
public enemy number one the meat Lobby they
definitely didn't like what we were doing they
were terribly upset and I could understand that
you know their livelihood was making processed
meats and they didn't want any anything coming
out saying that those were not good for you
basically we're trying to shoot me down or
discredit me I mean that's what shoot done
means scientifically what we discovered when
much farther the scientists had never realized
just whom she was dealing with America made the
hotdogs famous Oscar Mayer gave it Diggity in
the US the undisputed champion of supermarket
sold hotdogs has always been Oscar Mayer a brand
of the Kraft Foods Group a giant of the food
industry so far no surprises but what's less
known is that at the time and until 2007 Kraft
was owned by Philip Morris the world's second
largest tobacco company a lobby which went as
far as lies and manipulation to defend its own
interests notably in the big tobacco lawsuits
of the 1990s you believe nicotine is not addictive
I believe nicotine is not addictive yes I believe
questioning proven scientific facts the strategy
worked perfectly for years with tobacco so Philip
Morris used it again to save Oscar Meyers hot dogs
you understand how the multinational manipulated
science to defend its investments and cured meats
we headed to Northern California to San Francisco
this University library holds what are commonly
known as the tobacco documents millions of
internal tobacco industry documents our guide
stanton glance has spent his life unraveling
the cigarette makers strategies he particularly
remembers one phrase used by a lobbyist in 1969
doubters our product since it is the best means of
competing with the body of fact that exists in the
mind of the general public it is also the means
of establishing a controversy for him everything
is summed up in one word doubt and it was exactly
like that by creating doubt that philip morris set
out to discredit dr. preston martin study
on processed meat and cancer in children
the proof is there in the vast database
of the tobacco documents by typing Susan
Preston Martin you get hundreds of
hits and all in the Philip Morris file
the researchers named crops up regularly in the
titles of memos letters and internal reports
the multinational believed her study on hot dogs
would reopen the debate surrounding nitrites from
the 1970s so it paid scientists to go through
her work with a fine-tooth comb in order to
find any weak points even her contracts
and grant pays past under the microscope
basically anything that could be used against her
and weakened her in the eyes of the government and
the press stanton Glantz only learned of this case
through the documents we showed him the approaches
that they used to attack the person doing the
research linking cured meats with cancer were
the standard things they do one is to go through
her work with a fine-tooth comb and find every
little thing they could possibly complain about
and because the issues tend to be fairly technical
you know if you're a politician if you're a
reporter unless you're a highly specialized
reporter all you hear is well this person said
there was something bad and this other person
said they didn't know what they were talking about
and so these efforts to go after the scientists
and to discredit the scientists there's a key
element of a much larger strategy to just gum
up the entire policy-making process to the
point where nothing happens that translates
into hundreds of billions of dollars of sales and
profits for them so the whole game is just slowed
down in the documents on dr. Preston Martin other
even more Machiavellian scenarios were studied
here it was suggested that talks be held with the
scientist and here a proposed seminar in order to
lure her the aim to influence her and even shape
the conclusions of her future studies the common
point of these documents they all come from the
same lobbying firm multinational business services
inc already hired by philip morris to contest the
effects of passive smoking on health and headed
by a certain gym tot see a master of influence
amazingly in Washington the heart of American
power this lobbyist is still well established as
he never answered our requests for an interview
we went to see him without an appointment with
our documents in hand and a hidden camera yes
she do you have an appointment no no I was just
looking for him because I called from France
the good news American lobbyists can be
welcoming we even managed to have Jim
taught C on his cell phone Jim can you hear me
because you have set up a strategy to discredit
her work for Oscar Mayer so I wanted to know
if you like the welcoming lobbyists you love
the angry one please leave now do I need to
leave yes please leave I am ordering you out
now get the [ __ ] now take the flagon [ __
] outta here and do not come back thank you
pity it had to end like that in the end mr.
tot see did a great job well at least for the
industrialists back then his auntie Preston Martin
arguments were brought into the media spotlight
by this health journalist on a major national TV
channel a few days after the publication of the
famous study let's get back to our hot dog study
remember they asked the people did you eat a hot
dog they didn't ask them did you put it in a bun
did you put ketchup on it did you put mustard on
it now you might be saying who really cares one
way or the other but that's important because
it may be that it's not the hot dog at all that's
causing this increased risk of cancer maybe it's
the bun maybe it's the ketchup maybe it's the
mustard so you have to be careful when you read
these studies not to say oh this causes this the
powers that be didn't go any farther the 1970s
nitrites file which could have resurfaced remained
locked away you're probably wondering what Susan
Preston Martin thinks the woman targeted by the
lobby we showed her the documents and what upset
her the most was seeing that fellow scientists
had played along with the industrialists these
professors will get paid a huge amount to do
a review by in this case probably the American
media Institute I mean thousands and thousands
of dollars they probably get more from doing this
kind of thing than they do from their regular jobs
seeing your name like this in all these documents
my goodness they I gave a lot of people a lot of
work were you aware of this well I was aware that
that the processed meat community was concerned
but I'm not aware of all the extent of this
twenty years on and she had turned the page
not of interests anymore that's how the public
awareness of science goes that's it of interest
and then it's not of interest assuming you did
all that work but today oh but it doesn't it
doesn't matter I mean still in the literature
and it may includes people in future and it has
influence people in the past and that's fine
but another scientist involved in the case
has enjoyed a much more flourishing career
a scientist paid by the American Meat Institute
to shoot down Susan Preston Martin's work david
Clure felt today david kerfeld is head of the US
government's nutrition program and he's invited
all over the world for scientific conferences
where he gives his experts point of view totally
independently I'd like to introduce reasons why I
think meat is important component of healthy diet
on that day he was in France speaking to
scientists from around the world about meat
and the link between processed meat and
cancer in order to denounce backed up by
PowerPoint the climate of fear panic and even
hysteria and we know because we were there it
was right at the start of our investigation
when we barely knew about nitrites and had
the need of enlightened specialists to help
us so there are new reviews published this
year that say nitrite is not harmful and
others that say it is harmful I don't think
anybody really knows definitively what
what the answer is a few months after
this handshake when we had learned more about
the industry of doubt bells started ringing
so we took advantage of our trip to
America to ask him for another interview
only this time with a lot more cards of our sleeve
do you remember being paid by the American
Meat Institute no never no I was interested
in scientists I called Susan Preston
Martin yes do you know her I know who
she is I do not know her personally do you
remember writing a paper on her yes for the
American Meat Institute no I found this and it
was prepared for the American Meat Institute
okay I'm there this is something different yes
I this was done 20 years ago roughly so I I had
forgotten about that do you remember how much
you were paid for this evaluation no I do not as
I said it was 20 or 25 years ago you didn't know
when you were working for the American entities
you that Philip Morris was owning Oscar Mayer
I'm not gonna say yes or no at this point in
time because it's more than 20 years ago did you
know that the tobacco strategy Muto was doubt is
our product no I never heard that no no doubt was
your product - um that was not mine that was not
my intent my intent was to do an evaluation if I
had read these papers and found that there were
not shortcomings in the papers that they were
not deficiencies in the papers I don't think I
would have criticized them but don't you think
that your point of view would be stronger and
your argument stronger if I hadn't found that you
had been once paid by the American Meat Institute
no I don't I don't think that would change it
wouldn't change my point of view it might change
your point of view that you tend to not believe
what I'm saying because 25 years ago I got some
amount of money that I don't remember we're making
progress he can't remember how much but he does
remember getting paid but you have to understand
that the industry is a money-making business so
they're very risk-averse they would not fund a
study that someone were proposed to them that
eating hot dogs increases the risk of childhood
cancer why would they fund that you know they
would only fund something that says proposes that
childhood cancer is prevented by eating more hot
dogs or there's no relationship you know they're
they're not gonna fund a study that is bad for
their business well elite he's honest much of the
meat industry's lobbying depends on collaboration
with paid scientists and that's still how things
work during a conference on processed meats and
cancer in Lyon a French scientist confirmed it
Denis Coffey is a reference on the subject an
internationally renowned expert he speaks and
acts casually and doesn't balk at telling us
how things work at scientific events the source
municipal is equally evil one lawsuit Tillman's
a trick me disabled in each iteration determine
we get to point wiki present of the real in 2d
after they contrast computermen 30 congressional
concern yes systemic moe kamijo dude Famicon costa
heart position did a MOSFET is a pure osseous
with a twig enough a to visit semi-intelligent
contraire took Venusian Chicano can dude meet
Titian and Estella 2d bomba il Moro guy emote
had helped me addition to controlling see 50/50
specialty CDT the socket rod is not contra Israeli
parents people a ad goes on shoe which you didn't
poop on over scope a few days later professor Corp
a sent us some names and photos of scientists
he suspects of being close to the food industry
among them two Americans he came across at a
conference on meat and cancer Angelou Kowski
and Nathan Brian as we checked out these
scientists profiles we discovered a document
which should certainly never have been on the
web an internal report issued by the American
Meat Institute it lays out the strategy for
influencing the decisions of high-profile
organizations this organization is the ia
RC the International Agency for research
on cancer this institution based in the old
France is the worldwide reference on cancer
in 2006 ia RC scientists classified
nitrites in the probably carcinogenic
category of products group 2a
and that was bad for business
so lobbyists are fighting to have
this classification changed page 64
of a document change in the IAR see
nitrate nitrate classification from
2a to 2b or possibly carcinogenic products
the strategy has a name IAS each challenge
it notably involves the two scientists we were
interested in andrew milk
outski and nathan Bryan's
armed with our brand-new file it was time to set
off to meet the meat sectors heavyweights welcome
to Nashville Tennessee the capital of country
music and notably the hometown of Johnny Cash
it's here that the American Meat
Institute is holding its annual
conference in this huge building to
be precise the meat industry in the
US is very very big business all of
the world's biggest players are here
Smithfield number one in Portland with a turnover
of 14 billion dollars a year Cargill the giant
with thirty three billion dollars a year in crude
alone and Tyson the all divisions record holder
this year will make with all of our divisions
between beef pork poultry and prepared between
37 billion and 40 billion dollars in revenue it's
a very small company we checked it's over forty 1
billion dollars after half an hour we spot a face
in the crowd that rings a bell that woman they're
tasting nibbles at every stand that's right page
92 of the IAR sea challenge document here with the
short hair the American Meat Institute senior
vice president of public affairs Janet Riley
excuse me please sorry hello a lieutenant Ilia
yes hello I'm sorry man go I'm working for
force do unprocess Newton dancer and I have
a question about the document I found it is
this document do you know it I'm sorry dude
okay no no actually I wasn't registered but
I have some important question yes of course
I have my journalist card just a question
I wanted to know what do you know about the
ER challenge the a our challenge here until
I know what I'm doing it's about that right
answer thank you no this is mine sorry okay
so much for our interview having been escorted
outside this is my press constant okay and been
ordered to show ID we try one last time it's
close dude it looks like what tobacco industry
did for DK that's your opinion that's your
opinion what we're doing is providing the
science-based peer-reviewed evidence that our
products are safe and you see right there but
are you paying those scientists know you've
got that camera rolling don't you luckily
for such cases we always have a plan B on the
list of ia RC challenge scientists there was
one who agreed to see us the first on the list
Andrew mil Kowski we head to Madison Wisconsin
this city in the north of the United
States is home to Andrew mill Kowski
and the company of hot dog king Oscar Mayer
who we came across in the Preston Martin case
the scientist worked for this company for 30
years he now teaches at the University but
he doesn't hide his proximity to the American
meat lobby presented with our ia RC challenge
documents he acknowledges everything or
almost so did the meat industry paid you
for this I received some compensation from
my time as well as the others how much I
don't know thousands or tens of thousands of
dollars small amounts small amounts can we have
an idea no no defending nitrite seems to be a very
big thing for industry looking for a substitutes
has been attempted and was a a total failure
something as chemically simple as nitrite and
as unique as nitrite having a substitute has not
been possible to anyone's ability but if there is
a small risk of getting cancer don't you think
it's important to try to find a solution that
is where we disagree because I do not believe
that that risk is is true you think there's no
risk at all I think the risk is unquantifiable
and unknown if it had indeed exists on hearing
that we pulled this expression so for Andrew
Malkowski the colorectal cancer the hundreds
of studies on the dangers of nitrites none of
it exists off you go nothing to do with it in
the United States it's thanks to scientists like
milk cows key that the meat industry has been able
to cut another notch in its belt surprisingly
in the health-conscious state of California
this imposing building is home to the state
cabinet-level California Environmental Protection
Agency we have an appointment with Sam Nelson
deputy director for external and legislative
affairs he'll show us a document that doesn't
exist in any other American state so this is the
lists it's a list of substances judged dangerous
to man by the state of California to do business
here manufacturers are banned from using these
substances or they are obliged to warn consumers
and it's very restrictive because there are over
800 products on the list so good example that
would be smoke there's other things like benzene
that would be something you know we have common in
things like exhaust and then here we have aspirin
aspirin yeah it's a special note especially for
pregnant women oh here's kind of a an odd one but
you know things like breath and burn you know if
you want to eat this go for it but be aware that
you maybe don't want to eat it every single day so
we don't find nitrate nitrate is not on the list
it's been years since nitrites have been targeted
but procedures have never been seen through when
we believe the chemical meets the criteria for
listing we post what's known as a notice of intent
to list and that triggers a period in which people
can submit public comments on whether it's desert
does not meet the criteria we review the comments
before making a final decision to complete listing
regarding nitrites here are the comments that
swung the scales of the seven contributions six
come from food industry lobbyists and with 31
pages the winner is Andrew mill Kowski before the
interview we show Sam Delson all our documents on
mil Kowski the ia RC challenge and the attempts at
influencer face was an avalanche of proof gathered
during months of investigation he ends up taking
out his cell phone to take photos however in
answering our questions he seems less inspired
we it's their business if they think that they
can influence a decision beyond the signs but we
we let the science do the talking do you think
it might happen that sometimes you are manipulated
by the industries we do our best to make decisions
based solely on the science regardless of whatever
pressure or attempts at persuasion may be made by
any outside group okay California will re-examine
the dangers of nitrites but not before next year
for the lobby it's a mini victory time gained
and profits not lost in Europe a new study on
nitrites was expected in December 2015 almost
a year later it still has not been published