Get out where I can see you
No problem
Sir there's no need for violence.
I mean, can't we just talk about this
Talk, this ain't no social call
This here's a robbery
Of course but the problem is I don't have money and I don't have much in the way of valuables either
Oh yeah what's the wagon for then boy
It's just it's..
I'm afraid I've run into tough times
How..
How can you have nothing?
I've run into dead people with more than you
You better not be holding out on me
No look, I'm a dentist.
I thought I could make it out here but the problem is.
No one cares  about their teeth.
They'd rather spend all their time in a saloon, or robbing people.
So I'm just trying to get
somewhere where I can finally get the
Respect I deserve, I'm broke, ruined
These for fixing teeth
Yes, but they're not worth anything to you
If I could keep the tools then perhaps I could help you with you tooth?
Shut up
Excuse me but you cannot work on your own teeth
you need someone to do it properly or you
could end up in even worse pain
you won't find anyone else out here to fix
it
But go ahead, try yourself
Do it
I'll get the chair
Ahh
It's infected
We're going to have to pull it, cause if we don't..
Just get it over with
Right
this is going to hurt
Ahhh
(crack)
(groaning in pain)
(moaning in pain)
Do not move or I will shoot
I will do it
(dark music)
(somber piano music)