This man looks like any other tourist – on
a ferry taking in the sights of Istanbul.
But Yörük Isik is actually observing the
ships. Roughly 50,000 pass through the Bosporus
each year. Nothing special for most observers.
But for him each ship tells a story.
For example, freight ships like this one often
travel to the Crimean Peninsula that Russia
has annexed. I’m interested in what’s
going on. Are they really headed where they
say they are? Do they really have the cargo
they say have?
The Bosporus is one of the most important
straits in the world, connecting the Black
Sea with the Mediterranean. Its 30 kilometers
have always played an important role in the
push-and-pull between the world's great powers:
Access to the Black Sea is important to NATO,
and it’s also important for Russia to have
access to the West, to the Aegean and Mediterranean
Sea.
Just a few days later, Isik shows us an example.
When tensions last rose between Russia and
Ukraine, Russian warships passed through the
Bosporus on their way to the Black Sea. He
then discovered a cargo ship that he believes
was transporting NATO military equipment to
a Romanian port in the Black Sea.
When he returns home, he rushes to post his
discoveries and photos on Twitter. There is
a whole community of spotters around the world.
What they point out can be quite sensational
at times.
The fact that Russia was planning to intervene
in the Syrian conflict first became clear
from the increased number of naval ships in
the Bosporus. I was able to record just how
they were equipped on deck. Apart from the
Russian naval ships, there were also civilian
cargo ships. We were able to prove they were
transporting weapons to Syria.
Apart from arms smuggling, Isik – who runs
his own consultancy analyzing maritime activity
- has also observed shipments of illegal waste
or animals being transported in inhumane conditions.
He says it’s not spying, because the information
is freely accessible. He’s also not scared
of getting into trouble, at least not yet.
Turkey is going through a difficult phase
when it comes to freedom of opinion. I share
my observations openly on Twitter. But I try
to refrain from making any political judgment.
Of course, his apartment also has a view across
the Bosporus. And he stays in touch with other
spotters 24/7.
We don’t have to warn each other in advance.
If a ship sets sail somewhere, I know roughly
when it should arrive here. I know how fast
the different models travel.
And so, from his perch, Yörük Isik will
surely be watching the next time history unfolds
at his doorstep.