(bright soft music)
- Hello everyone and welcome
back to "English with Lucy",
today, we are going to be looking at
some really confusing words.
Words that are pronounced
in very similar ways,
words that if you mispronounce them,
you could say one of the worst
swear words or curse words
in the English language.
There's a lot to talk about
today, but don't worry,
I'm here to help you.
Before we get started,
I would like to thank the
sponsor of today's video,
it is Lingoda, Europe's number
one trusted language school
with their language marathon.
You can take the marathon in
English, Business English,
French, German and Spanish,
and gain up to 400 euros in cash back
when you attend at least
90% of your lessons.
There are three different
marathons to choose from,
the quarter marathon, the half marathon
and the full marathon,
three months, six months
and 12 months respectively.
The personal cash back prize
just adds that extra push of motivation
to keep you attending your lessons.
With the full marathon,
the 12 month marathon,
you can progress up to
four language levels.
I'm really happy to share
this opportunity with you
because I have first hand
experience of how effective
the Lingoda language challenges can be,
they've transformed many
of my students' lives.
They love Lingoda because they
can interact in small groups
with amazing qualified teachers.
I actually secretly
joined one of Lingoda's
student Facebook groups
to see how everyone was getting on
and I was blown away by the
amount of students celebrating
their fluency transformations
and their cashback refunds as well.
So, don't sweat about your
language skills this summer,
take the Lingoda language marathon
and transform your fluency in
just three, six or 12 months.
One more thing,
the first 50 of my students
and it is limited to 50,
to sign up with my code, LucySummer,
will get a 30% extra discount
on their first paid month.
Hurry up and click on the link down below
and use the code LucySummer
to claim that offer.
Remember there is also the option to take
the seven day free trial
and gain three classes
completely for free.
Let's get started with
those confusing words.
Remember, as always, I
have created a free PDF
that goes along with this lesson,
if you want to get that,
just click on the link
in the description box,
enter your name and your email address
and then you sign up for our mailing list,
you get all my offers
plus free PDFs every week.
Firstly, let's look at can,
and can't.
Now, these can be really confusing words,
not only in the British pronunciation,
the various forms of
British pronunciation,
but in American English, it
gets even more complicated,
so, we're going to talk
about all of that today.
Firstly, let's talk about
strong and weak forms.
So, with the word, can, we
have can with the a sound,
but we also have cen with the Schwa sound
and this is a weak form.
Weak forms are syllable sounds that become
unstressed in connected speech
and they're often pronounced
as the schwa, a, a.
Can, a,
cen, e.
Take a look at this sentence.
When I'm speaking naturally, I would say,
I can do what I can.
So, the first can is a weak form, cen,
and the last one, it's an
important word so, it's can.
The first can is in its weak form
and the second one is stressed,
so, it's in its strong form.
Cen, can, I can do what I can.
This works for other
words as well, like do,
what do you want to do?
What do you want to do?
The first is unstressed
the second is stressed.
Now, let's take a look at can versus can't
with RP pronunciation, my pronunciation.
A, can
a, can't.
A, is a really short and wide sound, a, a,
with can't, we have a
different mouth shape
and it's a lot longer.
Aw,
Ah, aw, ah, (chuckles),
do I look silly?
Good, because that's how I meant to look
when I'm teaching pronunciation.
Can, can't, ah, aw.
Now, let's talk about a swear word,
I don't normally talk about
swear words on my channel,
in American English, they refer
to them as curse words, but
there is a vowel sound,
it is very similar to the aw sound,
if you use that in can't,
it makes a really bad word.
The vowel sound is, ah, ah,
so, we've got ah can't
and ah...
I'm not going to say it on this channel,
it's a really vulgar word,
but if you would like to search
it and hear it for yourself,
then just replace the a and can't with a U
and I'm sure some robot dictionary will
tell you exactly what it sounds like.
Just be really mindful.
A, it's short and that's the bad version,
ah can't, that's longer and
that's the fine version.
Now, something to notice with
the pronunciation of can't
is that sometimes we don't
release that final T,
instead of saying can't, we might say can.
I can't do it not, I can't do it.
I can do it, I can do it.
I can do it, I can't do it,
I can do it, I can't do it.
So, you can't always
rely on hearing that T
to know if somebody is
saying can or can't.
Now, this is where it gets complicated
because in American English,
they use a very similar
vowel sound for can and can't
and they also avoid
releasing that T at the end.
So, can in American English
and you must excuse my terrible accent,
is cen, cen,
but can't in American
English is can't, can't.
Now, if they don't release that T,
then they sound very similar.
Cen, cen, cen, cen,
okay, brace yourself for this accent,
I can try, I can't try (laughs).
Now, I spoke to a couple
of my friends from the U.S
and they assured me that
they can hear the difference
because when they say can't, can't,
they make the vowel
sound much more abrupt.
Can,
can't,
can,
can't (laughs).
So, I hope you now feel
confident in pronouncing
can and can't
and avoid pronouncing that bad word,
unless you want to pronounce
it, which is fine by me,
just not on my channel,
and I hope you now have a better idea
about the differences between
can and can't in American English.
Now, let's talk about
some more pairs of words
that's even I find tricky
and I really have to clarify
exactly what I'm saying,
especially when I'm talking on the phone.
This is the difference
between teen and ty.
Fourteen, forty.
If I say I want 14 coffees, please,
they might say, is that 14 or 40?
So, don't worry if you mix them up,
native speakers get confused
with it all the time.
It's actually very,
it's very annoying that
those words are so similar,
but in general speech, there
are differences between them.
Take a look at the phonetic transcriptions
of these two words,
let's go on to 16 and 60.
We have sixteen
and sixty.
You can see that in the teens,
the stress is on the second
syllable, but for the tys,
the stress is on the first syllable.
Sixteen, sixty,
fourteen, forty,
fifteen, fifty,
seventeen, seventy,
eighteen, eighty,
nineteen, ninety,
twenteen, twenty, just
joking with that last one,
I hope you didn't write that down, if so,
rub it out.
So, if you want to be really clear,
especially when speaking over the phone
when you can't lip read
or really hear too well,
make sure you really over accentuate
the stress of the word
you're trying to use.
I said 60,
not 16 (laughs).
I'm going to do really quick
quiz for you right now,
just to make sure you
understand the differences,
write your answers in the
comment section down below
and then I'll start correcting
the first ones I see,
you've got to tell me whether
I'm saying teen or ty, okay,
number one,
60 people came to the game last night,
I got my dog when I was 17,
I've been with my husband for 17 years,
and the last one, I'm only
having 18 people at the wedding.
I'm only having 80 people at the wedding.
Right, that is it for today's
lesson, I hope you enjoyed it
and I hope you learned something,
I hope I clarified some of your doubts.
Don't forget to check out Lingoda
with their language marathon,
all the information is
in the description box
and remember that the
first 50 of my students
to click on the link
in the description box
and use my code LucySummer,
will get a further 30% of
their first paid month.
Don't forget to download
the PDF for today's lesson,
just click on the link
in the description box,
enter your name and your email address,
you then sign up to my meeting list,
I'll send the PDF directly to your inbox
and then every week after that,
you'll get all of my free PDFs
plus all of my news updates and offers.
Don't forget to connect
with me on social media,
I've got my Instagram
@Lucy and my website,
Englishwithlucy.co.uk,
where I've got a really
cool pronunciation tool,
you can test out pressing all
of the phonemes and hearing me
say those phonemes and say
words containing those phonemes,
it's great fun.
E.
No.
Air.
And I've also got my vlogging channel
if you want to practise your vocabulary
and improve your listening skills,
all of my vlogs are fully subtitled
and they document my life here
in the English countryside.
I will see you soon for
another lesson (kissing).
There's a lot to talk about today.
With the full marathon, the
one year marathon (mumbles).
Schwa sound and this is a weak form.
(tummy grumbling)
Sorry, that was my tummy (laughs).
Phoneme.
(bright soft music)
(bright upbeat music)