So I'm happy to report we have succeeded in rerouting our flagships.
Way ahead of schedule, yet again.
This has allowed us to improve our USPs by 90%.
That's 9 out of every 10!
Excellent, thank you Samuel.
Timothy, what's the status with the Linear Solutions?
Could you give us the latest on the Square project?
The Linear Solutions department has yet again functioned at full capacity.
And we have fulfilled a 114% of this month's objectives.
You can read the handouts for a detailed account,
but in short, as I reported last week, we've decided to use the right angle for the Square project.
Now, there's still some debate as to how big a right angle is,
so we're testing currently at 90, 97, 100 and 101 degrees.
As agreed, I've ensured Anderson crosschecks the design removing any left angles
and doesn't use them in future.
Overall, we have very good progress with the design.
Are we on track with the schedule? When are we required to start delivering?
I'm happy to report that we are ready to start first deliveries tomorrow
which is way ahead of the requested delivery schedule.
We've only just finished system testing the prototype
and are only halfway through performance testing.
We haven't even released an alpha version, yet!
As I said earlier, we've had very good progress with the design.
Yes, we've had very good progress;
but I'd say the design of the product is only 75% complete.
Well exactly! That's 3 out of every 4
so we're ready to start shipping tomorrow.
What? It... It doesn't work like that!
We'll produce, say, 4 units, but only ship the first 3!
Then when you're finally a 100% complete with the design --
-- we can then ship the 4th.
Excellent work Timothy, you can proceed with the production!
Anderson, send me, please, a revised delivery schedule, so I can share it with the client.
Well, thank you everyone, this was very productive.
Yet again!
FINAL DELIVERY SCHEDULE
REVISED DELIVERY SCHEDULE