I want to start this English
lesson by saying thank you
to everyone who filled in the
survey from last week's video.
Over 1500 English learners
filled in the survey
and let me know what song
they're currently listening to
in English, what book they're reading,
the TV show that they
are currently watching,
and about a movie that
they've recently watched.
I'm sure though, that
you're really curious
to know what the results are.
I've already seen them.
I made some nice graphs to show you.
So in this video, what
I'll do is I'll show you
all of the results of the
survey from last week,
so that you know about
the most popular book,
the most popular song,
the most popular TV show,
and the current most popular movie
that people are listening
to, reading, or watching
in order to improve their English.
(upbeat music)
Well hello, and welcome
to this English lesson
where I'm going to show you
the results of the survey
that many of you filled out last week.
Before we get started though,
if this is your first time here,
don't forget to click
that red subscribe button
and give me a thumbs up
if this video helps you
learn just a little bit more English.
Well, it was interesting when
I looked at the responses
to the question what
your favorite song was
because all of you mentioned
your favorite artist
and your favorite song.
So let's look at the top five artists
before we look at the top three songs.
At number five, we have Olivia Rodrigo,
and many of you mentioned
her song "Good 4 U,"
kind of an angry song,
but it has a good beat,
I really like it.
At number four, we have Lady Gaga.
And many of you mentioned
the song "Shallow"
that I think is a duet
with Bradley Cooper.
At number three, the
third most popular artist,
Justin Bieber, who by the way is Canadian,
and you mentioned a variety
of songs from Justin Bieber.
At number two, we had The
Weeknd, and most of you mentioned
either "Save Your Tears"
or "Blinding Lights."
And at number one, this
was no surprise to me,
the number one artist that
you chose was Ed Sheeran.
And you mentioned about
11 or 12 different songs
from Ed Sheeran, he is
a very popular artist.
But let's look at the most popular songs.
At number three, we had
"Shallow" by Lady Gaga,
again, I think a duet with Bradley Cooper,
a very nice song, very, very cool.
At number two, we had "Love
Yourself" by Justin Bieber.
This was kind of a surprise to me.
It's not a happy song.
It's probably a great song though
to listen to when you're learning English.
He sings very clearly in the song
and you can understand the words.
At number one, we had "Save
Your Tears" by The Weeknd.
This came as no surprise to me.
This was a very clear winner
above all of the other songs.
And it was no surprise
because this song is
actually quite popular.
It's on the radio all the time.
It's in the top 10, I
think, in Canada right now.
It's just a really, really cool song.
So there are your results for
top artists and top songs.
I'm sure you're curious to
know what the top choice was
for book from the survey
that you filled in last week.
And instead of making you
wait, I'll just tell you,
because there was a clear winner.
The book that came out on top
is a book called "The
Alchemist" by Paulo Coelho.
This is an author from Brazil,
and it doesn't surprise me
that an author from Brazil was
the top choice in the survey.
There are many people from Brazil
that watch my YouTube videos,
so maybe they swayed the
results a little bit.
This book is a book that I have not read,
and I promise you, I
will read it this winter.
It looks very, very interesting.
There was no clear second
or third place choice,
but what did show in the results was
that many people read
the Harry Potter books,
so that's a series of books,
and many people read the
books from Jeff Kinney
called "Diary of a Wimpy Kid."
So the Harry Potter series by JK Rowling,
written for teenagers and young adults,
is a very good series to read
if you are learning English,
great books, interesting stories.
And "Diary of a Wimpy
Kid" is actually written
for younger children,
but there is no shame
in reading kid's books when
you are learning a language.
"Diary of a Wimpy Kid,"
my kids read almost all of those books.
Between the age of seven and
eight to about age 11 or 13,
they would read those books,
and they were very interesting.
They're about a little
kid in middle school.
It's just a good little picture,
a humorous picture of American
life for kids in school.
So top choice, "The
Alchemist" by Paulo Coelho,
second place-ish would be
the Harry Potter series,
and third place-ish would
be "Diary of a Wimpy Kid."
When I say ish, it
means, you know, sort of,
it's not really a specific
book that got second or third,
it's kind of a book in a series,
but those are your top three.
I have to be honest,
the results for top TV
show kind of surprised me.
There were a few titles in
there that I was expecting,
but there were a few that were a surprise.
At number five, we have a
show called "Breaking Bad."
This was a surprise to me.
It's about a high school teacher
who begins to lead a life of crime.
It's an interesting
show, I have watched it.
I should warn you though,
it's very violent,
and you'll see a lot of criminal activity.
In fourth place is a show
called "How I Met Your Mother."
I have not watched this show,
but it's about a guy named Ted, I think,
who lives in New York City,
and it's a story about
how he met the person who
he eventually married,
so that's kind of how
the title came about.
The third most popular show,
I have to check my list, is "The Office."
This did not surprise me.
"The Office" is a very popular
English television show.
There's actually two versions, by the way.
There's the original British version
and there's the American version.
The American version is much more popular.
In second place, this surprised me,
was "The Ellen DeGeneres Show."
I've watched this show.
It is called a daytime talk show,
and it's hosted by Ellen DeGeneres.
And it's on, I think
here it's on around 4:00.
I don't watch it very often,
maybe once every few months,
but it's a good show to watch
because you'll see natural
English conversations.
And the number one show, this
show being chosen number one,
this did not surprise me at
all, the top show is "Friends."
"Friends" is a show
about a bunch of friends
that live in New York City.
It's actually starting
to seem a little bit old.
If you do watch it to learn English,
there's a few things that they say or do
that just aren't common anymore.
But "Friends" was the top
show out of all the TV shows
that people mentioned when
they filled out the survey.
The top choices for movies were
not a surprise to me at all.
They almost mimicked the box office
or the most popular movies of 2021.
At number four, we have "Black Widow,"
starring Scarlett Johansson.
This is a movie from the MCU.
MCU stands for the Marvel
Cinematic Universe.
It was a pretty cool movie.
I watched it with my kids
a couple of months ago.
We really enjoyed it.
The third most popular
movie is "No Time to Die,"
the most recent James Bond movie.
No surprise to see that on the list.
At number two was the movie "Free Guy,"
starring Ryan Reynolds.
This, of course, was no surprise either.
I myself just watched this
movie a few weeks ago.
It's really good, it was really funny.
The top movie though came
as a bit of a surprise.
The top movie is the movie "Dune."
This movie just came out in the last week.
It's a movie based on a book
by Frank Herbert called "Dune,"
which I read a long time
ago when I was a kid.
I would suggest you do this.
If you haven't watched the movie,
read the book, and then go see the movie.
So in reverse order, once again,
number four, Scarlett
Johansson in "Black Widow,"
number three, Daniel
Craig in "No Time to Die,"
the most recent James Bond movie,
at number two, Ryan Reynolds
in the movie "Free Guy,"
and at number one, a
whole bunch of actors,
very, very good actors,
in the movie "Dune,"
based on the book by Frank Herbert.
Well hey, thank you so much
for watching this little English lesson
where I gave you the results
of last week's survey.
Don't forget that listening
to music in English,
reading books in English,
watching TV shows and movies in English
are all really good things to do.
A quick recap, listening
to music is awesome
because you can learn all of the lyrics.
You can print out the
lyrics, and memorize them,
and then listen to the
song hundreds of times.
Reading books are awesome
because you can read
fast, you can read slow,
and you can learn a lot of new vocabulary.
Watching TV shows, awesome
because you can hear
the same people speak
episode after episode,
and you can really train
your ear to understand them.
And then movies are just awesome
because you kind of forget
about life for a while
and you immerse yourself
in what's happening.
So do take the time
to do all four of those things regularly.
It will really, really help you.
Thanks again for watching.
Remember, if this is your first time here,
don't forget to click
that red subscribe button
and give me a thumbs up
if this video helped you
learn a little bit of English.
And if you have the time,
why don't you stick around and
watch another English lesson?
(upbeat music)