So yesterday morning, I'm running a
bit late, I grab a piece of toast and
head out to my car, but my car won't
start. So I have to take the bus.
Now, let me pause me right there.
Did you notice anything unusual
grammatically about what she,
I just said?
When did all this happen?
So yesterday morning.
I'm running a bit late .
Yesterday morning.
So it's past, right?
OK, so listen again. How many
past verb forms can you hear?
Thank you, Joanne.
Right, let's look at the score.
Now would you look at that:
zero, nil, nothing,
zilch, nought.
I think we can agree that
this did happen in the past.
So how is it that Joanne
didn't use any past forms?
Did I, she make a mistake?
Well, surprisingly, no.
Let me explain how it's
possible to use the present
to talk about the past.
We call it the historical present,
or it may also be called the dramatic
present or narrative present.
We use it a lot when we tell
jokes or anecdotes, for example,
because using present forms
to describe past actions makes
the story seem more immediate,
more engaging, more personal.
We also see present forms being used
for the past a lot in news headlines,
whether read by news readers
or written in print or online.
And historians might use it to talk
about the ancient past
in a way to make
history more appealing.
In 1066 William the Conqueror invades
and thousands of new
words enter the English language.
Now, in all of these cases, we could
use past forms.
Let's get Joanne back to
tell us the story again,
only this time using past forms.
Let's have a look at the past form
score board,
and we've got a grand total of five.
Exactly the same events,
but using past forms.
It's not quite as involving, not quite as
engaging, but it is still correct.
Now, I want to go back to the car.
My car won't start.
Notice here that we have what might
appear to be a future form being
used in the present to talk about
something that happened in the past.
The first thing to
mention here is that
'will' is not really a future form.
It's a modal auxiliary and we do
use it to talk about an intention
to do something in the future,
say, for example, opening a window.
It's hot. I'll open the window.
The act of opening the window
might be in the future,
but the intention to open it is in the
present, at the moment of speaking.
It might seem weird, but 'will' actually
refers to present time, not future time.
And believe it or not,
it's the same for would and wouldn't.
In the same way that will and
won't are not about future time,
would and wouldn't
aren't about past time.
It's a bit more tricky to get
your head around that point.
So I would prefer to talk about
that another time.
Oh look! I just use 'would' to talk about
something that hasn't happened yet.
Hmm. An example that shows
it can't be the past.
So I'm going to have to knock
off a point from our past-o-meter.
Before I leave you,
one more thing to make you think.
As we've seen,
'will' is used for an intention,
a plan, an idea to do something.
So when we say:
My car won't start!
Are we suggesting the car
doesn't have the will to start,
it has chosen not to start just to
wind us up, just to make us angry?
It may be we choose to give the
human quality of stubbornness to
an inanimate object as a way to
express our frustration.
Well, my car certainly is inanimate at the
moment, and that is very frustrating.