Well hey there I'm Emma from mmmEnglish
and today we are going to find out the answer to this question:
What's my English level?
It's a question that my students ask me all the time.
How do I find out my English level?
Well firstly nothing will beat a personal English level assessment
with a qualified English teacher
but I wanted to help you to get an idea about your level
and find out where you need to improve your skills.
So I've created an online English level test that you can do
right here today.
Are you ready to find out your English level?
Let's go!
To help you find out your English level today,
I've created an English test that gets progressively
more challenging at every step. The first fifteen questions are
basic levels. You should get most of them right.
If you get more than five of these wrong in this section
then you're probably at about this level.
Then the next fifteen questions are intermediate.
If you get more than five of these questions wrong then your level
is going to be somewhere around
intermediate, upper-intermediate.
Then the last fifteen questions are advanced
and these should really challenge you.
If you get less than five of these answers wrong
wow!
Amazing! You're quite an advanced English learner,
particularly when it comes to your vocabulary range and your
use of grammar.
But here's the thing
even if you're not an advanced English learner yet,
I still think that you should watch through to the end of the test
so that you can learn some new vocabulary and some new
expressions as you go.
All of it is going to help you to improve your English
and push closer to that next level.
Hey ladies!
Do you want to practise English in real conversations?
With really lovely speaking partners?
Stop watching lessons at home on your own and come join us
at Hey Lady!
Hey Lady! is an online community for women.
We'll help you to meet new speaking partners and practise
real conversations in English.
We offer a free trial so that you can experience everything on offer
in a full membership and it's free for ten days.
I've put the link down in the description below so that you can start
your free trial today.
As we go through the questions you'll see a little countdown timer
which is going to show you
how long you have to answer that question.
Grab your notebook, grab a pen,
make sure you take note of the ones that you get wrong
and let's get started!
Sally goes to school every day.
I'm sorry! Stop being so angry with me.
Some people are really afraid of spiders.
After I drank my coffee, I stood up to leave.
Yes, we are.
Yes, it does.
I do yoga on Monday at 8am.
I don't have any more money.
Amanda is shorter than Steve.
We enjoy visiting the beach on the weekend.
How many packets of nuts do you want?
Margaret's been married since she was 17.
We have known each other for many years.
Tom used to wear shorts all the way through winter!
If I go to the party, I will pick you up on the way.
Okay how are you doing so far?
We're gonna move on to the next set of questions now.
We're gonna take things up a notch.
These questions are at the B1, B2 levels. That's intermediate,
upper-intermediate level.
They'll get progressively more challenging.
You haven't seen him perform on stage, have you?
I prefer spending time with people who respect me.
It's not the same as mine.
I don't need to be back at work until three
so we should have enough time to visit the gallery.
Since we live and work together,
we see each other every hour of every day!
He might have visited China before I met him.
If you had told me you needed a lift, I would have left earlier.
He lives on the other side of the country.
My brother borrowed my car over the weekend.
It was such a beautiful sunset.
Has she spoken to me about it?
You had better start looking for a new job.
Neither do I.
I had been living in Penang for a year before I even
tried asam laksa.
What amazes me is where you get all of your energy from!
Woohoo! So you've made it to the last section of this test.
If these questions are starting to get a little trickier
that's because they are.
We're starting to focus on some common expressions and some
fixed phrases so you'll need to have a really good understanding
of English to confidently move through this next section.
Now if you're not super confident about your answer if you just
take a lucky guess and you happen to get it right
good for you but still make sure you add a little star
next to that question and just decide if you really should
count it as an accurate answer.
Just do it for you. You're doing this test for you,
no one else needs to find out about how it was or if you got
all of them right,
just be truthful to yourself, okay?
On the whole,
I think you provided a good summary of what transpired today.
I agree with you to a point
but there has to be more to the story.
We had made plans to drive Granny to the hospital together.
And then for no apparent reason, Samuel decided not to come!
An electric car is a really economical way of
driving across Australia because they don't require as much fuel.
This kind of web application,
which is often used by remote teams,
provides the opportunity for informal interactions
throughout the working day.
There's no point trying to get everything done today.
We'll just need to finish it off in the morning.
I had expected the airport to be deserted.
But on the contrary, I'd never seen it so crowded!
Thank you so much for helping us get organised before we depart.
At the very least, let me buy you dinner to show my appreciation.
I would ask you to stop using such strong language,
you're offending our guests.
I know you're excited to get started but it's a delicate negotiation.
Let's just take it one step at a time.
I've read this article three times over
and I'm still not sure what it's getting at.
He will certainly not be invited to our wedding.
After the way he treated Martha, he's not welcome.
When in social situations, try to avoid using
technical jargon when you're talking about your work.
The two parties had such differing views,
they required a mediator to help settle their differences.
Mary has some quirks.
Even so, I quite like spending time with her.
Well done for making it all the way through!
Why don't you tally up your answers and see how you went?
If you want to, let me know down in the comments.
Let's just jump on to the last part of this lesson.
I want to talk to you.
Here's the thing.
I despise English levels.
Your English level on paper, the results that you get from a test
is really helpful. It's useful to know that information
but they do not define
who you are or what you're capable of doing in the future
and so often the way that we think about our results
or the way that we think about ourselves after we get those results
actually stops us from improving or moving forward.
It really messes with our self-belief
and it messes with our self-esteem
and our motivation to keep going, to continue
and sometimes it's that thinking that convinces us to give up
or to reduce our ambitions, to settle for less you know.
I was aiming for this and
I don't think that I can do it.
I am very lucky to know many, many incredible English students
and I can confirm that those who score well on paper
are not always the best communicators
and that intermediate English speakers can be
vibrant and effective communicators as well.
Even if they don't have the
vocabulary range or the accuracy with their grammar,
they can still use the language that they have
to communicate clearly and to communicate well.
So now that you have completed this English test make sure
please for goodness sake, please make sure
you take note of the questions that you got wrong
including the ones that you just took a lucky guess
and you got right.
And learn from them.
This is the opportunity that you have right now.
Thank you for stopping by at mmmEnglish today.
If you liked this video make sure you give it a thumbs up
and you subscribe to the channel for more English lessons
in the future.
I will see you next time!