Hi, it's your American English teacher Gabby from gonaturalenglish.com
Today we're going to test your English skills, but this test is not your typical
English test see there are no right or wrong answers
It's an assessment of your English level and I need you to be
Honest about what you can and cannot yet do the purpose of taking this test is to help you
Understand how far you've come and how far you have to go if our goal is
English fluency
Confidence in speaking skills and the ability to understand native English speakers
then it's important to see where you are now and
how to get to your goals how to achieve
Your English speaking goals. So I'd like to ask you to take this test with me if you are up to the challenge
All right. Well, let's begin the quiz and see how you do for each of these questions. I'm going to ask you to rate yourself
Would you say?
rarely
sometimes or often
Here we go. Number one, you can speak English without
translating in your head
rarely
Sometimes or often if you have to stop to translate into your native language
Before you speak English. This is a real problem for many reasons
first of all, it really slows you down because you have to translate which is actually a lot of work and
Second the problem is that a lot of words and phrases lose their meaning or get lost in translation
So it's quite dangerous to do this actually because you might not get the true
Feeling of a word when you translate number two
You make very few errors and when you do you can catch your own mistakes
rarely some or often, you know that you're becoming aware of
English and mastering English when you can actually catch your own mistakes look
Everybody makes mistakes, even native English speakers even fluent English speakers even advanced English speakers
We all make mistakes at some point, but the important thing is to stop yourself and correct yourself
Be aware that you're making mistakes and improve on them
Now if you're still learning if you make a lot of mistakes
you're gonna need help to catch your mistakes and correct them 3 you can use a wide variety of
phrases and expressions
Including phrasal verbs idiom and sometimes slang
rarely sometimes or often the
Trouble is when you're an intermediate english learner you often reuse the same vocabulary
over and over and well this may get your point across it's not as
Expressive and you don't have as many options and you may not understand what native English speakers are saying when they use more
interesting or advanced or
colloquial expressions for you can talk about
technical or
specific topics
this is important if you're using English in your career, maybe a specific field like science or medicine or
Technology, if you can't talk about technical aspects of your career in English
Then that's a problem
And if you can't talk about specific interests that you're into with friends who speak English, that could be a problem
Too you'll be stuck at a lower level of English
If you can only make small talk, which is important, but we want to be able to communicate in a variety of situations
5 you can use all grammar tenses past present and future
easily with confidence
rarely sometimes or often in order to express yourself fully we need to have
mastery of a full range
of grammatical
Expressions. So if you're not really confident about all the tenses yet then keep going keep practicing until you can use
Them all with ease question six native and non-native
English speakers are impressed by your English
Rarely sometimes or often when someone is impressed by your English
They might say that you have great English skills
But just someone telling you that you're good at English doesn't necessarily mean that you really are good at English
they might just be giving you a compliment or wanting to encourage you or
They might be sincere and you might be really good at English
you know someone's really impressed when they understand what you're saying and
You can communicate what you want to express with ease
Maybe you help other people to understand who you are and what you do and what your goals are
Maybe you even teach people other things in
English if you can impress people with the way that you express yourself using
advanced vocabulary and interesting idiomatic expressions
Then you are at the advanced level of English seven
You understand humor and jokes in English the way a native speaker. Would have you ever been in a conversation?
Sitting around with a group of friends. Someone tells a joke and everyone laughs
But you just don't get it and maybe it's because you didn't get the joke in English
Well English is much deeper than just
Vocabulary and grammar its cultural and humor is part of culture, too
so we need to learn what people might consider funny in English as well as
Just grammar rules and other things like that
Once you understand why people are laughing you're at the advanced level of English and if you can tell jokes
Yourself you're at the advanced level of English eight. You don't usually get stuck in English
but when you do you find a way around it, if you don't know a specific vocabulary word you're able to
Describe it in other words and get your point across or get other people to understand you. Would you say rarely sometimes or
Often this is important because we all forget words. Sometimes we all get a little
Brain fog and can't think of a specific word
But the important thing is that you don't stop trying that you keep trying to get your point across
With other words and you have other words to do that number nine you are not uncomfortable or not
very afraid of speaking English with native English speakers rarely sometimes or
often
Fear is a big part of what holds us back
with English fluency because if you are afraid to approach native speakers or you are afraid to
participate in conversations with native speakers, you don't get that practice that you really need and so exposure and
Immersion to native English will help you break through to fluency number ten
You feel like you can express your true self in English. You don't feel fake you feel natural
rarely sometimes or often
This is really important even though sometimes people say that when they speak another language
They feel like another person. This is sometimes a side of you that comes out through the new language
It doesn't mean that it's fake. It's just another part of your natural self
So if you can express that that means you've mastered English if you feel like you're stuck or people don't really know
Who you truly are in English, then that can be something to work on
eleven English speakers
Easily understand you. This is about your pronunciation. It's
important that other people understand you
Also, of course, you have to understand other people, but in order to be fluent, you have to be understood as well
So if you notice that people are looking really confused when you speak English
Or maybe you don't get a response that makes sense. It could be that you need to improve your pronunciation
also, if people don't talk to you for a very long time that could mean maybe they just don't want to tell you that they
Don't understand what you're saying. Number 12, you understand TV shows movies the news
materials intended for native English speakers without
using subtitles
This is a big one many of you tell me that one of your goals in English is to be able to understand these
materials like movies TV shows music
the news all in English without
The help of subtitles or reading along. So if you can do this your English is
Advanced now if you answered mostly
Rarely, that means that we have quite a bit of work to do now
Don't stress out because you have already come a long ways and you can do a lot
But it's a good idea to think about what your goals are in
English and how you can improve your skills in order to reach those goals that are most important to you if you answered mostly
Sometimes then keep going you're doing good work
You're on the road to fluency
And I'm sure that if you just keep going you will break through to fluency soon
And if you answered mostly
Often well. Congratulations
You're doing a fantastic job and you may already feel that you have broken through to fluency
Now you might need to fine-tune your skills a little bit
We're always learning new words and new ways of expressing ourselves in English as a second language
But you're doing a fantastic job and I commend you for your efforts
so
I hope that this helped you to
Understand your level of English and maybe to think about where you need to or want to improve your skills in
The coming months in order to reach your goals in English like speaking fluently and with confidence
I've created the complete go natural English course that has helped thousands of English learners from over a hundred and thirty four countries
To reach their goals in English together with my help and with our amazing
Community from all over the world. So if you would like to get more information
about how the course works the benefits and the details like the price and how to join then I highly suggest that you join the
waitlist now at gonaturalenglish.com
slash
Pre-reg I only open registration a couple of times a year
So it's important that you get on the waitlist to get a notification and information so that you don't miss your opportunity
Alright, I hope to see you there. Thanks so much for watching. Bye for now