♪ Many nights we've prayed
With no proof anyone could hear
In our hearts a hopeful song
We barely understood
Now, we are not afraid
Although we know there's much to fear
We were moving mountains
Long before we knew we could
There can be miracles when you believe
Though hope is frail,
it's hard to kill
Who knows what miracles
you can achieve
When you believe, somehow you will
You will when you believe
In this time of fear
When prayer so often proves in vain
Hope seems like the summer birds
Too swiftly flown away
Yet now I'm standing here
My heart's so full, I can't explain
Seeking faith and speaking words
I never thought I'd say
There can be miracles when you believe
Though hope is frail,
it's hard to kill
Who knows what miracles
you can achieve
When you believe, somehow you will
You will when you believe
They don't always happen when you ask
And it's easy to give in to your fears
But when you're blinded by your pain
Can't see your way
clear through the rain
A small but still resilient voice says
Help is very near
There can be miracles when you believe
Though hope is frail,
it's hard to kill
Who knows what miracles
you can achieve
When you believe, somehow you will
Now, you will, you
will when you believe
You will when you believe
You will when you believe ♪