♪♪
-Look at all those people
walking around down there,
not working.
It's all because of me.
You're welcome, walking people.
[ Laughter and applause ]
Why won't they
let me build my wall?
All the other presidents
can do whatever they wanted.
They let JFK build his airport.
They let Lincoln
build his town cars.
[ Laughter ]
This view is incredible.
I can see the National Mall,
the Washington Monument,
the Jefferson Memori--
Wait.
Why can't I see the White House?
W-Where's the White House?
[ Laughter ]
Oh, look.
It's some TSA agents.
And they're waving.
And now they're holding up
one finger to say,
"We're number one."
How nice.
[ Laughter ]
She loves me,
she loves me not.
Oh, Nancy Pelosi,
why do you have to go
and make things so complicated?
[ Laughter ]
I can't believe BuzzFeed
told everyone I lied.
I hate BuzzFeed.
One time, I took a quiz to find
out which Jonas Brother I was.
I was the Bonus Jonas!
[ Laughter ]
Look, there's Melania.
Wonder where she's going.
And why she has so many bags.
And why she's running so fast.
Wait. She's escaping!
Melani-a-a-a-a!
[ Laughter ]
Uh-oh. I think I might have
to call Secret Service again.
[ Laughter ]
It's starting to rain.
I love the rain.
It reminds me of...Stormy.
[ Thunder crashes ]
Hush money!
[ Cheers and applause ]