[ Cheers and applause ]
-Oh, God. [ Laughs ]
What -- What --
-[ Coughs ] I'm sick, dawg. -I know you're sick.
-I just want to make sure, you know....
-You're spraying -- Is that, like, Purell?
-Yeah, you know, but don't you hate it
when people are sick and they still embrace you?
-Yeah, you're right. -Yeah, I can't stand that.
-You don't want to make any of us sick.
-i don't want to get anybody -- [ Coughs ] sick.
-That's right. Thank you very much, Jamie.
I appreciate that, buddy. Thank you very much.
-But you guys make me feel good. The Roots.
You guys make me feel good.
-Yeah. Come on. [ Cheers and applause ]
[ Laughter ]
Dude, come on.
You can't walk out and hit a pose and then --
-You got to get the pose. You know what I'm sayin'?
I got my LeBron James beard and my --
-Yeah, you do. Yeah. You're looking good.
[ Cheers and applause ]
♪♪
You just made your face look like him. I like that, man.
I want to tell you,
we were just talking about the wildfires in California.
-Oh, God.
-I know it's hitting you pretty close to home.
-Man, listen, by not being there,
you can't really recognize
how really terrifying and devastating it is.
I mean, Malibu is almost gone,
and people are losing everything.
So, please, if you see any place where you can give money
or just prayers and good energy,
and especially to all of the first responders.
Like, a lot of those -- That's in my neighborhood.
So a lot of, like -- Whistling Pete,
who comes by all the time with his firetruck
and hangs out with the kids --
These guys are working 48 hours with no breaks.
And like I said, people are losing everything.
We had to evacuate my house.
Luckily, my family was okay, and our house was spared.
But everybody else -- Gerard Butler --
I mean, Robin Thicke. And others.
Not just celebrities. I mean people in communities.
So, you know, just give them good energy, man.
Sorry, but...
-No, I wanted to bring it up because I was just there.
And it's real. Terrible.
-Also, too, I got to say this, too.
I live in Thousand Oaks.
And those people --
I mean, those children. These kids, man.
And I know we -- A lot of times
we're afraid to speak out on things because of --
you never know who may be affiliated with what.
But all I can tell you is that
to hear in the fourth-safest place in the world
something tragic like that happened.
So we have to voice,
because, like I said, those are our kids and our family.
And that police officer, I mean, we see that guy every time
we go down right off of Hampshire in Thousand Oaks.
He's a hero, so please give your prayers for that.
I got to take this time.
And, also, this -- Coming into the new year,
look for the good in people, man.
I feel like sometimes we're in such a --
looking for bad.
Look for the good in people. [ Applause ]
-That's right. Good decision. -Wow.
-Please. I'm thankful that you're saying that.
Thank you so much.
Every time you come on our show, you make people laugh,
you entertain, and you bring the good to people.
So thank you for bringing that up.
-As much as -- Oh, man, it's tough. Anyway.
-We have things to talk about.
I want to talk about your film, as well.
But you're just such a talented guy.
I was saying to Higgins just before the show.
You can sing. You can -- I mean, you've won Grammys.
-Yeah. -I mean, you can sing.
-And you can -- -Male exotic.
-What is that? -Male exotic.
-Male exotic. Yeah. -I can do that, as well.
[ Laughter ]
A lot of times, people leave that off.
-Yeah, they do leave that off.
No, but you can do any genre, any voice, any band, any group.
I've seen you.
-♪ There's magic in these hips of mine ♪
No. Anyway.
-You must be a fun dude to go do karaoke with.
-Oh, man. Hey, come on, now. Yeah.
-Do you do it? -Karaoke. Come on, now.
[ Cheers and applause ]
Yeah. -What is your go-to?
What do you do?
-What's my go-to? Wow. "Poison."
-Like the band Poison?
[ Laughter ]
-Nah, man.
♪ It's driving me, it's driving me ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ It's driving me out of my mind ♪
-♪ The J, the I, the M, the M, the Y ♪
♪ Y'all, I need a body bag ♪
♪♪
Was that "Poison"?
-That was "Do Me."
-I was doing "Do Me." -Oh, "Do Me."
Yeah, right, right, right.
♪ Take one look at me every day ♪
♪ You like what you see? ♪
♪ Do you think you can ♪
♪ Do you think you can do me? ♪
-♪ Kiss me, pretty -- ♪
-Anyway, anyway, anyway. -That's the same song.
-Same song.
Yeah, same song. They got two checks on that.
On the production.
-I heard you used to have these raging karaoke parties.
And celebrities would just walk in and just show up?
-I remember we had the celebrity --
Speaking of Bell Biv DeVoe, we had --
I used to do a karaoke back in the day,
and everybody would come.
I had -- Hugh Hefner would show up.
I had NSYNC singing Backstreet Boys songs
and vice versa.
But the one night that was crazy,
Whitney Houston and Bobby Brown show up to my karaoke, bro.
And this was when she was, like,
the female R&B singer of the millennium or whatever.
And so, you know, me and Bobby get up,
and we're singing "Don't Be Cruel."
And he forgets the words.
And I said, "The words, they're right there on the thing."
-[ Laughs ] It's karaoke.
That's the whole point of karaoke, yeah, yeah.
-And then as I'm going -- as I'm going to the bathroom,
I hear, "Man, y'all know I don't sing this for anybody.
I get a million dollars for singing this."
And Whitney Houston got up and sung, and it was cra--
-Which one? -Everybody had --
We didn't have social media at that time,
so people just called their answering machines.
That's how long ago it was.
So they just had the phone up, and she said...
♪ And I ♪
♪ Will always love you, ooh ♪
And just killed, right?
-No way! -Yes, but here's the thing.
So, I film that, you know?
I had that on my -- That was camcorder back then.
It had a light. It had an extra battery.
-Shoulder hurting. -Shoulder bag. You know.
-You had that the thing on your head.
-It had a microphone.
-I'm holding another box behind you.
"We're rolling, Jamie. We got it."
-So, anyway, I film it,
and then later on that night, I'm at the crib.
We having a little after spot 3:00 or 4:00 in the morning.
I hear this...at my door.
That means somebody must have jumped my gate.
I just hear this. And it's Bobby Brown.
And Bobby Brown is like, "Yo, I got to get that tape."
I said, "Well, I don't -- I don't have the tape here."
He said, "Well, I got to take something."
So...
[ Laughter ]
So, I was like,
"That's weird as hell. I don't know what that means."
But he just busts in my house, and he goes into my closet
and starts picking out clothes
and, like, putting out clothes and stuff.
I was like, "This is crazy.
Bobby Brown is taking clothes out of my closet."
And then this little girl came in, and she was like,
"Oh, my God! Bobby! Oh, my God! I love you!
I recorded you guys tonight!"
He says, "Really? Let me hear it."
She said, "Oh, I didn't get you. I only got Whitney."
And that didn't go over too --
That didn't go over too well. Right?
So, after I calmed Bobby down, I said,
"Bobby just calm down. Just get more clothes."
So he got the clothes.
And he left. -What?!
-Bobby Brown left with clothes.
And then about eight weeks later,
I look on "People" magazine, it says "Clothes..."
It was Bobby Brown and Whitney Houston on the magazine.
It said, "Clothes by Dolce and Gabbana."
I said, "No, it ain't. That's my..."
[ Laughter ]
-"Clothes by Jamie Foxx. Clothed by Jamie Foxx."
"Clothes by Jamie Foxx." Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-Do you still have the tape?
-He knows -- Yeah, I still got the tape.
I still got the tape. I put it in my safe deposit box.
[ Laughter ]
That's old-school, right?
-Exactly. That's old-school right there.
Do you ever freak out -- flip out --
'Cause that sounds like a crazy story to me.
But has there ever been an artist where you're like,
"I-I-I-I can't talk."
-Oh. Prince. When I first saw Prince, yeah.
When I first saw Prince.
'Cause they know -- the real musicianship.
I mean, when I was growing up and listening to Prince,
my grandmother thought -- First of all, my grandmother
thought that Prince, it was the devil music for whatever reason.
'Cause, you know, it's sort of suggestive.
S-S-S-Sexy.
It's porcelain. That's what they...
[ Laughter ]
It's these Denzels I got.
[ As Denzel ] All right. All right. Okay. All right, now.
[ Laughter ]
Okay, so, you like Prince, huh?
So, you like Prince? So, you like Prince?
All right. You like Prince?
Tee-hee.
You like Prince. All right. So, you like Prince.
[ Laughter ]
-Oh, my God. Oh, man, that's good.
[ Normal voice ] I saw Prince...
1998, December 31st.
-Wow! Where were you?
-Why is that significant? -It was New Year's.
-Because it was about to be 1999.
-No! -Yeah. Saw him in Las Vegas.
And I cried a little bit.
-Me too. I might cry now. I wasn't even there.
-I usually look at people cry.
I really felt a little of that, "Ah, man. Hey.
I really love your stuff."
-[ Laughs ] That's how you talked to Prince?
-I was like, "Man..."
And then I asked him for --
His voice is, you know,
just extra sexy, but I don't know why.
"I love your stuff." "Oh, thank you so much."
I was like -- That's hella extra sexy, right?
-That really is his voice.
-"Thank you very much. Hee-hee."
I asked to take a picture, and I couldn't get the picture
because he believed that it would --
I don't know. Some spiritual thing. I don't know.
But later that night, The Time was playing.
-Morris Day?
-Morris Day and The time were playing.
And, man, they were playing, kicking it.
They were doing "Cool."
And Morris goes,
"And now I'm going to bring this fella out here.
He ain't gonna sing or nothing. He's just gonna play."
And he came out in, like, a feather --
He just came out in all purple feathers
and some, like, stretch pants
with an incredible, like, purple guitar and killed it.
-Yeah, and then just kind of -- He just, like, vanishes.
-He disappeared.
-That's what he does. He's a magician.
-And he was gone. -He poofs, and he's gone.
I love hearing those stories. Thanks for telling me.
-Didn't you play Ping-Pong with him or something, I heard?
[ Laughter ]
Which is odd. That's odd, right?
-It's the weirdest story ever.
It's long. I'll tell you the whole story.
I got a call -- I got a text. I was at dinner.
It said, "Prince wants to play Ping-Pong with you."
[ Laughter ]
-What the hell?
-Yeah. So I go, "I got to go, dudes.
Prince wants to play Ping-Pong with me."
[ Laughter ]
So I went to this place, Spin in Manhattan.
-Okay, okay. Yeah.
-And I went down the thing, and I go "Hey, is there a..."
And she goes, [Whispers] "Prince."
[ Laughter ]
"He's in that room over there. He's waiting for you."
I go, "I don't even play Ping-Pong."
I don't know what his obsession is.
He wanted to play Ping-Pong with me. I go whatever.
So I walk in, and he's standing there
in the crushed blue velvet suit, double breasted,
and he goes, "You ready to do this?"
[ Laughter ]
Oh, my God.
So, dude, we played Ping-Pong. And he's great.
He killed me.
-In the boots? -In the boots.
That was just his boots doing... [ Laughter ]
He's hitting the Ping-Pong, like, double time.
[ Laughter ]
So, we're hitting the thing. [ Clicking tongue ]
And then -- -How'd it go?
-[ Clicking tongue ] [ Laughter ]
-That's hilarious.
-So, then he's -- It's 20-10 or something.
He goes, "Game point."
[ Laughter ]
And he hits the ball and it goes...
It's spinning.
Flames are coming off, like, the perfect Ping-Pong hit.
It hits the corner of the table. It's impossible to hit back.
It goes somewhere else.
I go, "Oh, my God." He goes -- I go, "You won."
And I'm looking around.
I go to pick up the Ping-Pong ball.
I find the ball.
Oh, you -- "Prince? Prince?"
[ Laughter and applause ]
Gone. Gone. -Gone. That's crazy.
-Left. Gone. It's like it never happened.
Like, I didn't play.
But then I saw Questlove outside.
I told you about it.
You heard about that I was playing Ping-Pong.
-Hey, man, I rolled up to him in Grey Poupon style.
I was like, "What happened?"
And he rolled down.
He was like, "Ask your boy."
[ Laughter ]
-"Ask your boy."
-Let's talk about "Robin Hood", please.
Thanksgiving weekend "Robin Hood" comes out.
And this is good.
I got to say, the action scenes in this are fantastic.
-Thanks.
It's a different take -- this is a different take on Robin Hood.
It was actually called "Hood" at first.
[ Light laughter ]
That's true. I know you're laughing.
[ Laughter ]
'Cause there's a brother in it, but yeah, it was --
[ Laughter and applause ]
I'm serious. Check the history.
It was actually called "Hood."
It's nothing like the Robin Hood you think.
It ain't no tights, nothing like that.
We going off in there.
-You don't wear tights?
-No. I don't wear --
I have on tights now, but we don't --
No, I don't wear tights.
-They're bummed out a little bit. Yeah.
-No, no, I can't. Not with these calves.
[ Laughter ]
'Cause you know, brothers don't have -- brothers don't have --
I don't do calves. I don't do legs.
Brothers just -- I just bench press.
[ Laughter ]
I've never seen brothers doing legs in the gym.
It's all...
It's like jailhouse.
-Then the white dude?
-Yeah, yeah, the white dude. [ Laughter ]
-Ain't doing that. -You know what I'm saying?
I'd be like, "Man, I ain't doing all that."
[ Laughter ]
My legs are so tiny, I don't even wear -- I wear shants.
You know how they come all the way down to here,
and then there's socks and just a little bit of meat.
[ Laughter ]
A little bit of meat. I have on shants.
'Cause I don't have calf muscles.
It's like I could beat you up, but I can't chase you.
[ Laughter ]
You take off, I'm like, "I'll catch up."
-You and Taron Egerton, who is --
Man, oh, man, this is a talented guy.
The last time he was on the show,
I remember, I made him sing.
He's got a beautiful voice.
Talented kid.
-He's incredible, and that's what's great about this.
It's a new, fresh take on it.
Leonardo DiCaprio is producer on it.
Otto Bathurst is director.
So Thanksgiving, you all come please, check it out.
-It's a family movie, but it's got some action.
It's for everybody. I want to show a clip.
He's Jamie Foxx and Taron Egerton in "Robin Hood."
Take a look at this.
-I can fire two arrows a second. -Yeah.
-You could fire two arrows a second.
-You think you're faster?
Shoot me.
-Beg your pardon? -You've killed hundreds of us.
What's one more?
-Okay.
-Please. I said shoot me!
Too slow!
Fast as you can!
Again! Come on, English!
Again.
Too slow.
-Yeah! [ Cheers and applause ]
Jamie Foxx, everybody!